<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par56">
 <list list-type="bullet">
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par57">Serious medical comorbidities precluding radiotherapy. These include interstitial lung disease in patients receiving lung radiotherapy, Chron's disease in patients where the gastrointestinal tract will receive radiotherapy, ulcerative colitis where the bowel will receive radiotherapy, or connective tissue disorders such as lupus or scleroderma.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par58">For patients with liver metastases, moderate/severe liver dysfunction (Child Pugh B or C)</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par59">Inadequate baseline bone marrow function (i.e. symptomatic anemia, neutropenia and/or thrombocytopenia which may interfere with the ability to deliver radiotherapy)</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par60">Chronic kidney dysfunction (eGFR less than 30) where a significant dose of radiation is expected to be delivered to the kidneys.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par61">Substantial overlap with a previously treated radiation volume. Prior radiotherapy in general is allowed, as long as the composite plan meets dose constraints herein. For patients treated with radiation previously, biologically effective dose calculations should be used to equate previous doses to the tolerances doses listed in Additional file 
    <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par62">Prior treatment with systemic radiopharmaceuticals (i.e. Radium-223 or Lutetium-177)</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par63">Any single lesion greater than 5 cm in size.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par64">More than 50 metastases (count excluding equivocal lesions &lt; 5 mm in size)</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par65">Any brain metastasis greater than 3 cm in size, or a total volume of brain metastases greater than 30 cc.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par66">Polymetastatic cancer limited to the brain.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par67">Brainstem metastases.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par68">Evidence of epidural disease on baseline imaging.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par69">Clinical or radiologic evidence of spinal cord compression.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par70">Dominant brain metastasis requiring surgical decompression.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par71">Inability to treat all sites of disease, which may include disease involving the gastrointestinal tract, mesenteric lymph nodes, or skin. This may also include diffuse/miliary metastatic disease (i.e. brain, bone, lung, liver) or other sites where it would be impossible to deliver radiotherapy at the intended dose level (i.e. lymphangitic spread, malignancy pleural effusion/ascites, leptomeningeal metastases).</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par72">Systemic therapy use 2 weeks prior to radiotherapy delivery.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par73">Pregnant or lactating women.</p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
