<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par109">All participants will be registered at trial entry and will receive re-induction therapy with four to six 28-day cycles of ixazomib (4 mg/day on days 1, 8 and 15), thalidomide (100 mg/day on days 1–28) and dexamethasone (40 mg/day on days 1, 8, 15 and 22) (ITD), in order to reach maximum response. At the end of re-induction, participants will be assessed for response and will be asked to complete the pre-randomisation QoL questionnaires, unless participants have not consented or withdrawn from the QoL study element of the trial. Participants will then go on to peripheral blood stem cell (PBSC) mobilisation and harvest, which may be omitted if adequate PBSCs are available from previous mobilisation and harvest. Following this, participants who achieve at least stable disease (SD) will be randomised on a 1:1 basis to receive either conventional ASCT (ASCT
 <sub>Con</sub>), using melphalan (200 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup>/day on day −1), or augmented ASCT (ASCT
 <sub>Aug</sub>), using melphalan with ixazomib (ixazomib 4 mg/day on days −4 and −1 and melphalan 100 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup>/day on days −3 and −2). Participants will then be assessed for response 100 days post-ASCT and asked to complete the QoL questionnaires. All participants achieving or maintaining MR or better following trial ASCT will undergo R2 to consolidation and maintenance or no further treatment. Participants randomised to R2 will receive consolidation with two 28-day cycles of ITD (ixazomib (4 mg/day on days 1, 8 and 15), thalidomide (100 mg/day on days 1–28) and dexamethasone (40 mg/day on days 1, 8, 15 and 22)) and maintenance with ixazomib (4 mg on days 1, 8, and 15) given as a 28-day cycle until disease progression. Participants will be asked to complete QoL questionnaires at 12 and 24 months post-R2 at their clinic visit, unless participants have not consented or have previously withdrawn from the QoL study (See Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref> for assessment schedule details).
</p>
