<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Overall, an iterative design process was undertaken for this project. An initial list of potential attributes (e.g., leadership, scholarship, clinical skills, advocacy) was compiled during a brainstorming exercise led by project team members with the Executive of the DCYMH, at a half-day meeting dedicated to this purpose in March 2016. In June 2016, the project and goals were introduced to Divisional faculty and learners who attended the Divisional retreat. This event occurs annually and is attended by faculty and learners from the Division as an opportunity to reflect on and celebrate the previous academic year and plan for the year ahead. Educational theories, emerging concepts in medical education and evidence related to established best practices in selection processes were summarized for participants (
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>–
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>–
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>). Following these didactic sessions, participants gathered in small groups to discuss the initial list of priority attributes and brainstorm further ideas. Over the summer &amp; fall of 2016, further feedback was solicited from the DCYMH Residency Program Committee (RPC) and from key informants and stakeholders from within the DCYMH and the Department of Psychiatry. Subsequently, the project team reviewed the feedback that was gathered and identified eleven "branding attributes,” ten "generic attributes,” and seven "end products.” The team determined that the "end products” category could be eliminated for the purposes of this project, as these would be outputs of the training process rather than attributes to be assessed for selection into the program. Examples of "end products” included: academic psychiatrist, community-based psychiatrist, and researcher. "Branding attributes” were viewed as attributes that would contribute to brand identity (
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>), while "generic attributes” were defined as attributes that would be important for successful applicants to possess, but would not be specific to brand identity.
</p>
