<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par38">In recent years, increasing interest in reducing RT treatment volumes has emerged, with the objective of reducing toxicity while maintaining LC. In fact, in the era of IMRT and image-guided radiotherapy (IGRT), it is appealing to mirror surgical approaches and evaluate vocal-cord radiotherapy (VC-RT). Focal vocal cord RT for T1N0 glottic cancer has been assessed in dosimetric studies which confirmed adequate target volume coverage [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR58">58</xref>], homogeneity of planning target volume (PTV) coverage [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR50">50</xref>], as well as sparing of various laryngeal structures (including the contralateral vocal cord and arytenoid), the carotids and thyroid gland compared to conventional RT [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR50">50</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR59">59</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR60">60</xref>]. The group from Erasmus Medical Center Cancer has reported clinical outcomes from a retrospective analysis of 30 patients with T1aN0 glottic cancer treated with VC-RT [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>]. They reported excellent 2 year LC of 100% as well as lower rates of acute toxicities and improved voice outcomes compared to a similar cohort of patients treated with CL-RT [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>]. In fact, VC-RT was associated with clinically significant voice preservation compared to CL-RT immediately after RT, at 6–12 weeks and at 6–12-18 months after RT [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>]. By maximally avoiding structures involved in voice preservation, VC-RT has the potential to reduce the rate and severity of acute and chronic toxicities and minimize voice impairment, while maintaining current excellent local control rates. While some institutions have adopted a partial larynx RT approach in early glottic cancer, there is currently no prospective evidence on efficacy or safety of VC-RT and many academic institutions continue to consider treating the entire larynx as standard of care. The hypothesis of the current phase II study is that VC-RT would lead to non-inferior LC compared to historical outcomes of CL-RT in patients with T1N0 glottic cancer.
</p>
