<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Out of six IGRA converters, two (Patient 3 and Patient 6) received LTBI treatment at the treating physician's discretion. As IGRA tests cannot distinguish recent from remote infections, the IGRA conversions in Patient 4 and Patient 5 were regarded as insignificant and probably associated with their previous history of TB (TB pleurisy in Patient 4 and LTBI in Patient 5). Although, Patient 1 and Patient 2 did not receive LTBI treatment, their clinical features, and serial follow-up chest radiographs did not reveal active TB development in both patients. This might be explained by test variability. As shown in 
 <xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>, most IGRA converters had low-positive QFT results, which ranged from 0.35 to 0.99 IU/ml. Among the converters, Patient 1 did not receive any LTBI treatment, but a follow-up IGRA after 5.5 months showed reversion to negativity, and the negative result was replicated twice more after reversion (at 4.7 and 17.5 months). This suggests that positive IGRA conversion could have been due to test variability rather than true positive conversion. Another plausible explanation is the possibility of an insignificant impact of non-TNF inhibitors on LTBI reactivation. According to post-marketing data as well as vedolizumab clinical trial results and those of the IM-UNITI study of ustekinumab (
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>), it is anticipated that the risk of TB is low among IBD patients treated with vedolizumab or ustekinumab, similar to the incidence rates of TB in the respective areas of origin. This can also be supported by the Psoriasis Longitudinal Assessment and Registry (PSOLAR) data, which reported no cases of LTBI reactivation among ustekinumab-treated patients with psoriasis (
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>). Furthermore, previous national database study from Korea, which evaluated the risk of active TB disease among psoriasis patients treated with ustekinumab, revealed only three out of 2,803 patients (0.1%) developed active TB related to ustekinumab treatment (
 <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>). Overall, even if the cases of positive IGRA conversion were true conversions, the risk of LTBI reactivation appears to be low under non-TNF inhibitor therapy among IBD patients.
</p>
