<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="para290">The data cutoff date for this analysis was Oct 23, 2017. We present here the results of the co-primary endpoints, some secondary endpoints (progression-free survival 2 and toxicity), and prespecified subgroup analysis for the maintenance randomisation of this trial. Response (secondary endpoint) and other exploratory endpoints will be reported elsewhere. The hypothesis of the maintenance randomisation was that lenalidomide treatment could improve progression-free survival and overall survival compared with observation in adult patients with multiple myeloma. For progression-free survival, the trial was designed to demonstrate a 6·7-month increase in median progression-free survival in the lenalidomide group (median 26·7 months) compared with the observation group (median 20·0 months, hazard ratio [HR] 0·75) when 509 progression-free survival events had been observed. For overall survival, it was designed to demonstrate a 10% increase in 5-year overall survival in the lenalidomide group (60% at 5 years) compared with the observation group (50% at 5 years, HR 0·74) when 458 overall survival events had been observed. Each of these calculations assumed the time to event was exponentially distributed and that recruitment would last 3·25 years with 4 years of further follow-up, a two-sided 5% significance level, and 90% power. A minimum recruitment target of 1013 patients randomly assigned to (1:1) lenalidomide and observation was specified, allowing for a 2% dropout. Efficacy analyses were done by intention to treat, including all patients randomly assigned to either lenalidomide alone or observation. The safety population included all patients who received at least one dose of maintenance therapy or those were assigned to observation. Patients randomly assigned during a transient period of the trial to the combination of lenalidomide and vorinostat (n=307), as per the protocol modification on Sept 14, 2011, were excluded from this analysis and will be reported elsewhere.</p>
