<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract>
 <title>Abstract</title>
 <sec sec-type="background">
  <title>Background:</title>
  <p>Breast cancer is the most familiar cancer and the major cause of the cancer death in women worldwide. The breast cancer patients may suffer from severe mental and physical trauma. At present, there are few studies on the music therapy for patients with breast cancer. The objective of our paper is to assess the effect of music intervention on mental and physical state of breast cancer patients.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec sec-type="methods">
  <title>Methods:</title>
  <p>The experiment will be implemented from June 2021 to June 2022 at Jinan Central Hospital. The experiment was granted through the Research Ethics Committee of Jinan Central Hospital (no.08847765). The inclusion criteria requires that the age of female patients ranges from 25 to 65 years old, and the pathological diagnosis of breast cancer requires radical mastectomy (containing extensive radical mastectomy and modified radical mastectomy). Patients who do not like to listen to music or have severe debilitating diseases or are allergic to the sound will be excluded. Patients in the intervention group are given music intervention, and in control group, patients do not receive any information about the music therapy in the period of this study. The primary outcome is quality of life, psychological distress. The secondary outcomes are the heart rate, blood pressure, as well as Visual Analog Scale (VAS).</p>
 </sec>
 <sec sec-type="results">
  <title>Results:</title>
  <p>Table 1 will illustrate the postoperative outcomes after music interventions between groups.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec sec-type="conclusion">
  <title>Conclusion:</title>
  <p>Music intervention can improve the mental and physical health of the breast cancer patients.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Trial registration:</title>
  <p>This study protocol was registered in Research Registry (researchregistry6168).</p>
 </sec>
</abstract>
