<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In addition, another study had found (
 <xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>) that IGF-2 played a certain role in the diagnosis of the large breast borderline PTs with hypoglycemia. IGF-2 was detected in the tumor and corresponding normal tissues and the measured high serum IGF-2 level led to a preoperative diagnosis. Following mastectomy, the postoperative levels of IGF-2 in the serum gradually returned to normal. Masahiro Hikichi et al. (
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>) measured the high molecular weight IGF-2 in the serum and tumor tissues of a giant borderline PTs with hypoglycemia through western blotting and immunohistochemical analysis. The western blotting showed that significant levels of high molecular weight IGF-2 were accumulated in tumors at the preoperative stage, but not in the serum obtained 3 days after tumor resection. This confirmed that the core factor of hypoglycemia is caused by the high molecular weight IGF-2. Therefore, for patients with breast PTs with severe hypoglycemia in whom high levels of IGF-2 are detected in tumor cells or serum, the diagnosis of NICTH can be considered. Nevertheless, Jannin A et al. (
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>) considered that an IGF-2/IGF-1 ratio &gt; 10 was much more useful than the measurement of Big IGF-2, they measured the IGF-2/IGF-1 ratio in six patients with NICTH, found that all of the ratio are more than 10 and the median is 31.8. Unfortunately, we were unable to detect the level of IGF-2 and IGF-1 in serum before and after surgery in our study. However, we excluded the possibility of islet cell tumor by the preoperative examination. According to the perioperative blood glucose changes, the postoperative immunohistochemical staining results and the relevant literature reports. We inferred that preoperative hypoglycemia was most likely caused by the high expression of IGF-2 in the phyllodes tumor. It provides experience for the diagnosis of NICTH.
</p>
