<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The first-choice treatment of breast PT is surgical resection (
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>). Without adjuvant treatment, patients with borderline and malignant PT do not experience recurrence after local tissue resection, and the two conditions are similar (
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>). The PTs that caused NITCH will no longer produce IGF-2 after surgical resection, the symptoms of NICTH will resolve, and blood glucose levels will return to normal (
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>–
 <xref rid="B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>). Of note, hypoglycemia caused by NICHT is serious, and intravenous glucose infusion is used prior to surgery to regulate blood glucose levels (
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>–
 <xref rid="B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>). Surgical resection requires negative margins. Many studies have confirmed this view. A study of 164 cases of PTs (
 <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>) showed that the length of the margin is not associated with local recurrence, whereas a positive margin is related to recurrence. Another study of 183 cases of PTs (
 <xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>) also suggested that the size of the surgical margin is not linked to local recurrence. Noordman PCW et al. (
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>) stated that the primary treatment for borderline and malignant PTs is extensive local excision with tumor-negative resection margins. In addition, if the skin cannot be preserved, it can be filled with the method of rectus abdominis musculocutaneous or latissimus dorsi, which is important for reconstruction after mastectomy (
 <xref rid="B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>). Considering that the risk of axillary lymph node metastasis is extremely low, routine lymph node dissection is not recommended (
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>). In our present case, there was no axillary lymph node enlargement found in the preoperative imaging. Therefore, this patient did not undergo axillary lymph node dissection during left breast resection, and the results of the intraoperative frozen section diagnosis showed negative margins. As a result, the patient recovered well after operation and no recurrence occurred during 3 months follow-up, which proved our treatment was effective for PTs with NICTH.
</p>
