<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par96">
 <list list-type="bullet">
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par97">There will be evaluation immediately post-treatment, as well as at 6, 12 and 24 months post-treatment as part of the study. Other follow-ups will be as per institution standard of care, but suggested schedule of assessments detailed in Table 
    <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref> is encouraged.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par98">Alternate follow-ups between the head and neck surgeon and the radiation oncologist will be mandatory.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par99">Physical examination will involve flexible laryngoscopy or/and videostrobe or/and mirror examination with adequate visualisation of vocal cords.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par100">Clinical follow-up will involve documentation of LC and survival status as well as reporting of CTCAE V4.03 toxicities.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par101">Patients will be asked to fill patient-reported outcome questionnaires at baseline and at each visit, as detailed in Table 
    <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>. The questionnaires will be administered in the following order: VHI-10, MDADI and MDASI-HN. The questionnaires could be filled in paper format, or online using the anonymized CASTOR EDC system. The questionnaires will not be reviewed during the study and will be analysed only at the pre-specified timepoints.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par102">There will be an 
    <italic>optional</italic> assessment of acoustic and objective measures of voice analysis by a speech pathologist at baseline, immediately post-treatment and at 6 months post treatment. The assessments will consist in a digital recording of a standard oral reading passage and a short monologue, which would later be analyzed for specific acoustic variables and microacoustic measures of the cycle-to-cycle variation of acoustic parameters (in frequency and intensity domains). The voice quality will be graded as per then GRBAS scale (grade, roughness, breathiness, asthenia, strain).
   </p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
