<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="para30">
 <boxed-text id="cetextbox10">
  <caption>
   <title>Research in context</title>
  </caption>
  <p id="para40">
   <bold>Evidence before this study</bold>
  </p>
  <p id="para50">A search of PubMed for clinical trial reports published in English before May, 2010, using the terms "lenalidomide” and "myeloma” and "maintenance” revealed no published randomised studies of lenalidomide maintenance in patients with newly diagnosed myeloma.</p>
  <p id="para60">
   <bold>Added value of this study</bold>
  </p>
  <p id="para70">To our knowledge, the Myeloma XI trial recruited more patients with newly diagnosed multiple myeloma than any previous interventional study in myeloma. We showed a significant benefit of lenalidomide maintenance therapy in terms of progression-free survival, which was consistent across both patients eligible for transplantation and those who were ineligible, as well as patients across all cytogenetic risk groups, even those with high-risk disease. The primary endpoint analysis of overall survival was not met. However, a preplanned subgroup analysis indicates an overall survival benefit in transplantation-eligible patients across all cytogenetic risk groups, even those with high-risk disease, when treated with lenalidomide maintenance therapy after transplantation.</p>
  <p id="para80">
   <bold>Implications of all the available evidence</bold>
  </p>
  <p id="para90">The results of the Myeloma XI trial contribute to a body of evidence that suggests that the use of lenalidomide as maintenance therapy should be considered for patients with newly diagnosed multiple myeloma, of all cytogenetic risk groups, after autologous stem-cell transplantation. With the addition of these new data from the Myeloma XI trial, a meta-analysis of all published trials of lenalidomide maintenance after autologous stem-cell transplantation, including 3179 patients, confirmed the overall survival benefit of lenalidomide maintenance therapy compared with observation in this setting (hazard ratio 0·72 [95% CI 0·56–0·91]). Future studies examining combinations of agents with lenalidomide are needed to further improve outcomes for high-risk patients with multiple myeloma. In transplantation-ineligible patients, novel approaches to improve overall survival are warranted.</p>
 </boxed-text>
</p>
