<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>This study was a single-center, prospective, double-blind, randomized controlled trial. The protocol was approved by the Ethics Committee of the Affiliated Hospital of Xuzhou Medical University (XYFY2020-KL160-01) and was registered at the Chinese Clinical Trial Registry (ChiCTR1900026910). This study complies with the Declaration of Helsinki and adheres to CONSORT guidelines. All patients and their families signed an informed consent form. Between January 2020 and June 2020, patients who underwent thoracoscopic radical resection of lung cancer in the Department of Thoracic Surgery of our hospital were evaluated for eligibility. In this study, the types of operation include sleeve lobectomy, wedge lobectomy resection, segment resection, and lobectomy, while pneumonectomy was not included in the study. All operations were performed by uniportal VATS according to the different location of the tumor and the standardized treatment according to the guidelines. The operation was performed by Hao Zhang group, Department of Thoracic Surgery, Affiliated Hospital of Xuzhou Medical University. Two surgeons, Chief Physician Hao Zhang and Attending Doctor Teng Sun, worked together to complete more than 1000 thoracic surgeries. Residents are not included. All male and female patients aged between 45 and 65 with an ASA grade II–III, were included in the study. The exclusion criteria were: a previous history of other malignant tumors, it is impossible to determine whether this lung cancer is primary; use of radiotherapy, chemotherapy, anti-inflammatory drugs, analgesics, and hormone drugs before surgery; tumor metastasis to other organs; allergies to local anesthetics; liver dysfunction (defined as serum total bilirubin ≥ 2 mg/dl); renal dysfunction (defined as glomerular filtration rate &lt; 90 mL/min/1.73m
 <sup>2</sup>); sinus bradycardia; atrioventricular block of more than a second degree; chronic pain; mental illness, communication disorder; refusal to receive lidocaine infusion. Patients were excluded from the analysis if the: surgery was canceled; converted to thoracotomy; if local anesthetic poisoning or adverse reactions occurred during surgery; if they were admitted to the intensive care unit (ICU) following surgery; surgery took more than 6 h and if intraoperative blood transfusion was required. The eligible patients were randomly divided into Group L and Group C by a computer-generated random allocation sequence (1:1). The patients in Group L were given a lidocaine bolus of 1.5 mg/kg before induction anesthesia which was then maintained at a rate of 2.0 mg/kg/h until the end of the operation. The patients in Group C were injected using a load and pump with an equal volume of normal saline. The grouping information was kept in a sealed envelope by a nurse who did not participate in the experiment. Patients, anesthesiologists, and surgeons were blinded in the grouping of the experiment. After the patient entered the operating room, another anesthesiologist opened the sealed envelope and prepared related drugs according to the assigned patient group. The anesthesiologist did not participate in the follow-up data collection and data analysis. The data were then analyzed by a statistician who was not aware of the assigned patient group.
</p>
