<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In this study we analyzed the 25(OH)D plasma levels in patients with COVID-19 divided accordingly to their sex and age and we found a positive correlation between vitamin D status and respiratory functionality only in young patients, regardless of their sex. This result was consistent to previous studies on the association of serum 25(OH)D concentration with the improved lung function, in both females and males (
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">Ganji et al., 2020</xref>). We asked whether in young patients, sex hormones could impact vitamin D status and effects. Actually, estrogen has been suggested to enhance vitamin D actions, by increasing the expression of the nuclear vitamin D receptor gene (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">Cheema et al., 1989</xref>) and by decreasing the expression of CYP24A1, the cytochrome P450 component of the 25-hydroxyvitamin D(3)-24-hydroxylase enzyme which catabolizes the active form of vitamin D. In turn, vitamin D influences peripheral estrogen metabolism modulating in a tissue-specific way the function of the cytochrome P450 19 aromatase (CYP19), the enzyme that produces 17β-estradiol from testosterone (
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">Lundqvist et al., 2011</xref>). Moreover, low levels of vitamin D have been also independently associated with low levels of testosterone in healthy middle-aged men (
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">Giagulli et al., 2021</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">Papadopoulos et al., 2021</xref>). Accordingly, we found a significantly positive correlation between 17β-estradiol and 25(OH)D in elderly women and between testosterone and 25(OH)D in elderly men supporting the role of sex hormones in preserving 25(OH)D levels. A relationship between hormones of the hypothalamic–pituitary–testicular (HPT) axis and vitamin D status has been established (
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">Lee et al., 2012</xref>). In this context, further studies are needed to evaluate gonadotropin levels in male patients in order to clarify the role of vitamin D/HPT axis in COVID-19.
</p>
