<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par72">It is therefore scientifically appropriate to utilise a proteasome inhibitor and IMiD combination as re-induction therapy to set the platform to assess the impact of conditioning augmentation and post-transplant consolidation/maintenance strategies. In designing the trial, we sought to evaluate the impact of a novel proteasome inhibitor that will facilitate both the clinical benefit and the patient experience with regards to deliverability of the treatment schema. Ixazomib, an orally active boronate-based reversible inhibitor of the proteasome, has shown single agent activity in phase I/II studies alongside combination therapy with dexamethasone and more recently IMiDs [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>]. More recently, the combination of ixazomib and the IMiD lenalidomide was reported by Kumar and colleagues in combination with dexamethasone in the first-line setting [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>]. The TOURMALINE-MM1 study on the use of oral ixazomib, lenalidomide and dexamethasone for relapsed MM showed that at approximately 15 months follow-up the ixazomib regimen group had a statistically significant PFS advantage over the group taking the placebo-containing comparison (21.4 months vs. 9.7 months, respectively), with an HR of 0.54 and a 95% CI [0.32, 0.92] favouring ixazomib, with OS data not yet mature for analysis [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>]. Thalidomide, the first-in-class IMiD, is more affordable and a justifiable choice given that the only other phase III randomised controlled trial (RCT) in the setting of first relapse post-ASCT demonstrated that bortezomib gave added benefit to the combination of thalidomide and dexamethasone [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>]. In addition, a significant proportion of patients entering this proposed trial could have received lenalidomide maintenance in the first-line Cancer Research UK-funded NCRI study (Myeloma XI). Ixazomib in combination with thalidomide and dexamethasone is currently being studied in the HOVON 126MM study (
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.hovon.nl/studies/studies-per-ziektebeeld/mm.html?action=showstudie&amp;studie_id=103&amp;categorie_id=3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">http://www.hovon.nl/studies/studies-per-ziektebeeld/mm.html?action=showstudie&amp;studie_id=103&amp;categorie_id=3</ext-link>), which is currently open to recruitment amongst patients not suitable for high-dose therapy. The use of ixazomib in the maintenance setting was reported by Kumar and colleagues at the American Society of Haematology meeting in December 2014, demonstrating efficacy and tolerability in previously untreated patients (
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.bloodjournal.org/content/124/21/82" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">http://www.bloodjournal.org/content/124/21/82</ext-link>). The HOVON 126MM study also includes a maintenance phase randomisation comparing ixazomib and a placebo.
</p>
