<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>After allogeneic stem cell transplantation (alloSCT), severe graft-versus-host disease (GVHD) can be induced by donor T-cells recognizing normal tissues of the recipient. T-cell depletion (TCD) of the stem cell graft is an effective strategy to prevent GVHD, and alloSCT regimens using the CD52 antibody alemtuzumab for TCD or using infusion of purified CD34 cells demonstrate efficient engraftment and reduced acute GVHD (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>–
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>). Since graft-versus-tumor reactivity is reduced after TCD alloSCT, postponed donor lymphocyte infusions (DLIs) are frequently administered after transplantation to promote antitumor reactivity with a lower risk of GVHD (
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>–
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>). Reduced incidence of GVHD after TCD alloSCT with postponed DLI may partly be explained by gradual repair in time of the tissue damage caused by the pretransplant conditioning regimen. Tissue damage can accelerate the development of acute GVHD by causing release of pro-inflammatory cytokines such as TNF-α, IL-1β, and IL-6. These danger signals can activate host or donor antigen-presenting cells (APCs) that in turn present alloantigens to donor T-cells, which can activate and amplify alloreactive donor T-cell responses (
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>). Although tissue damage may be restored at the time of postponed DLI, GVHD after DLI applied 3–6 months after alloSCT is not uncommon (
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>). Furthermore, although CD4 T-cells recognize peptides presented in HLA class II molecules and HLA class II is only expressed on non-hematopoietic cells under inflammatory conditions, infusion of purified donor CD4 T-cells 3 months after TCD alloSCT with an HLA 10/10 matched, but HLA-DP mismatched donor can also result in severe GVHD caused by CD4 T-cells directed against the mismatched HLA-DP molecule from the patient (
 <xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>). These findings suggest that, as a result of tissue damage after the conditioning regimen, even several months after alloSCT, activated APCs of patient origin may still be present in target tissues like skin, which may result in the initiation of an alloreactive T-cell response causing GVHD.
</p>
