<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="para10">Secondary CNS dissemination is a rare but potentially lethal event in patients with diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. CNS dissemination might present de novo, synchronously with systemic disease, or as early CNS relapse (isolated or with concomitant systemic disease).
 <xref rid="bib1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref> Secondary CNS lymphoma involves the brain parenchyma in 40–50% of patients, leptomeninges in 30–40%, and both in 10–15%, but the prevalence and timing of these events vary due to the diversity of CNS prophylaxis strategies.
 <xref rid="bib1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref> Neurological symptoms are the first indication of CNS disease in many patients, and clinical presentation is influenced by the site of the CNS lesions.
 <xref rid="bib6" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>6</sup>
 </xref> Secondary CNS lymphoma is frequently associated with systemic lymphoma progression, concomitantly or shortly afterwards; thus, its treatment should be effective against both the systemic and the CNS components of the disease. Rationally designed treatment protocols should use drugs that can be delivered in a dose-intensive and time-intensive schedule and are effective at penetrating the blood–brain barrier, such as methotrexate and cytarabine administered at high doses. On the basis of retrospective studies,
 <xref rid="bib7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref> it is believed that potential cure is only achievable if patients have autologous haematopoietic stem-cell transplantation (HSCT) consolidation after remission of CNS disease. Accordingly, conditioning regimens currently used in primary CNS lymphoma, which include drugs with excellent CNS penetration, such as carmustine, busulfan, and thiotepa,
 <xref rid="bib9" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>9</sup>
 </xref> have been adopted in patients with secondary CNS lymphoma.
</p>
