<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="para20">
 <boxed-text id="cetextbox10">
  <caption>
   <title>Research in context</title>
  </caption>
  <p id="para30">
   <bold>Evidence before this study</bold>
  </p>
  <p id="para40">We searched PubMed between Jan 1, 1990, and Dec 31, 2019, for prospective trials investigating the treatment of patients with secondary CNS lymphoma. We used the search terms "central nervous system”, "CNS”, "lymphoma”, "secondary CNS lymphoma”, "SCNSL”, AND "diffuse large B-cell lymphoma”, and restricted the results to articles published in English. Publications in non-English languages with abstracts in English were also considered. Abstract-only data from international meetings during the past 3 years (up to Dec 31, 2019) were considered. There is little evidence in this field; secondary CNS lymphoma is a rare lymphoma and randomised trials are not feasible, hence the paucity of data to inform practice. Existing literature comprises only three single-arm phase 2 trials including at most 38 patients. These are non-comparable trials as they have used different eligibility criteria with variation in the upper limits of age and performance status as well as in considered lymphoma entities, previous treatment, and response status in the selection of candidates for autologous haematopoietic stem-cell transplantation (HSCT). In addition, data on some subgroups, such as patients with CNS involvement at initial diagnosis and patients with disease refractory to the first-line treatment, are scarce because these patients were considered in only one of the published prospective studies and accounted for less than a fifth of the patients enrolled. The reviewed literature does not allow the identification of a standard treatment for patients with secondary CNS lymphoma.</p>
  <p id="para50">
   <bold>Added value of this study</bold>
  </p>
  <p id="para60">To our knowledge, the MARIETTA study is the largest prospective trial focused on patients with secondary CNS lymphoma; it was done in 24 centres in four countries, representing the most geographically extensive trial to date, which supports the generalisability of the results. This trial showed that the sequential combination of MATRix (rituximab, methotrexate, cytarabine, and thiotepa) and RICE (rituximab, ifosfamide, carboplatin, and etoposide) followed by autologous HSCT was active in this population of patients with a very poor prognosis. Patients aged up to 70 years and with an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance Status of 3 or less were included, representing a real-world cohort of patients. The MARIETTA programme is active in every subgroup of secondary CNS lymphoma, with 1-year progression-free survival of 58% (95% CI 55–61) and encouraging 2-year progression-free survival of 71% (63–79) in patients with CNS disease at initial lymphoma diagnosis. Moreover, the MARIETTA programme included two standardised regimens (ie, MATRIX and RICE) used in routine practice in several countries, and showed a good safety profile.</p>
  <p id="para70">
   <bold>Implications of all the available evidence</bold>
  </p>
  <p id="para80">Combined with existing evidence, the results of the MARIETTA trial show that a growing proportion of patients with secondary CNS lymphoma can have durable remissions with intensified chemoimmunotherapy. Patients with CNS disease at initial lymphoma diagnosis and patients who had CNS dissemination during or after upfront R-CHOP therapy have different outcomes, suggesting that these two populations of patients with secondary CNS lymphoma might benefit from different treatments. Patients with CNS involvement at initial diagnosis seemed to benefit from treatment with debulking R-CHOP followed by MATRix–RICE and autologous HSCT. Further efforts are required to improve remission rates before autologous HSCT, especially in patients with CNS involvement at first relapse.</p>
 </boxed-text>
</p>
