<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract>
 <sec>
  <title>BACKGROUND</title>
  <p>Malignant obstructive jaundice is mainly caused by cholangiocarcinoma. Only a few patients are indicated for surgical resection, and the 3-year survival rate is &lt; 50%. For patients who are not eligible for surgery, biliary stent placement can relieve biliary obstruction and improve liver function and quality of life. However, restenosis after biliary stents has a poor prognosis and is a clinical challenge. Biliary stent combined with iodine-125 (
   <sup>125</sup>I) seed implantation can prolong stent patency and improve survival.
  </p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>AIM</title>
  <p>To evaluate the safety and efficacy of biliary stent combined with 
   <sup>125</sup>I seed strand implantation in malignant obstructive jaundice. 
  </p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>METHODS</title>
  <p>We enrolled 67 patients between January 2016 and June 2018 with malignant obstructive jaundice and randomized them into a biliary stent combined with 
   <sup>125</sup>I seed strand treatment (combined) group 
   <italic>(n = </italic>32) and biliary stent (control) group (
   <italic>n </italic>= 35). All patients underwent enhanced computed tomography and magnetic resonance imaging and were tested for biochemical and cancer markers. Twelve patients underwent pathological examination before surgery. All patients were followed up by telephone or clinical visit. Postoperative liver function improvement, postoperative complications, stent patency time, and survival time were compared between the two groups. Prognostic risk factors were evaluated. 
  </p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>RESULTS</title>
  <p>Technical success was achieved in all patients in both groups. Postoperative liver function improved significantly in all patients (total bilirubin, direct bilirubin, alanine aminotransferase, and aspartate aminotransferase decreased significantly in all patients, the 
   <italic>P </italic>values were less than 0.05). There was no significant difference in preoperative or postoperative indexes between the two groups for changes in total bilirubin (
   <italic>P </italic>= 0.147), direct bilirubin (
   <italic>P </italic>= 0.448), alanine aminotransferase (
   <italic>P </italic>= 0.120), and aspartate aminotransferase (
   <italic>P </italic>= 0.387) between the two groups. The median stent patency time of the combined group was 9.0 ± 1.4 mo [95% confidence interval (CI): 6.3-11.8 mo], which was significantly longer than the that of the control group (6.0 ± 0.3 mo, 95%CI: 5.5-6.5 mo, 
   <italic>P </italic>= 0.000). The median survival time of the combined group was 11.0 ± 1.4 mo (95%CI: 8.2-13.7 mo), which was significantly longer than that of the control group (7.0 ± 0.3 mo, 95%CI: 6.4-7.6 mo, 
   <italic>P </italic>= 0.000). Location of obstruction and number of stents were independent risk factors affecting prognosis.
  </p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>CONCLUSION</title>
  <p>Biliary stent combined with 
   <sup>125</sup>I seed strand implantation is safe and effective in malignant obstructive jaundice and improves stent patency time and median survival time.
  </p>
 </sec>
</abstract>
