<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The patient was diagnosed with end-stage renal disease (ESRD) 6 years ago. She had no other disease history. In the past 6 years, the patient had regular hemodialysis twice a week 
 <italic>via</italic> a right internal carotid artery catheter. On January 25, 2020, the patient began to have fever with the highest temperature of 39.6°C. There was no cough, sputum, rash and joint pain. The patient visited the local county people's Hospital, and the chest Computed Tomography (CT) results showed that the patient had pulmonary infection (Multiple nodules in the lower lobe of the right lung). The COVID-19 throat swabs PCR result and antibody result were both negative. Blood culture results of paired blood samples taken from bilateral arms prior to the empirical use of antibiotics were also negative. Due to the long-term use of catheter dialysis, the local hospital doctors considered that the fever might be caused by bacterial catheter infection. Therefore, the patient was given intravenous meropenem 500 mg 12 hourly and vancomycin 750 mg 24 hourly for empirical anti-infection treatment. However, the treatment effect was not good, and the patient still had fever. After 3 days of hospitalization, the doctor pulled out the patient's dialysis catheter and changed to direct puncture dialysis. The results of microbial culture on the tip of the removed catheter were also negative. After the removal of the catheter, the patient's condition was still not improved and still had fever, so she was transferred to our hospital to continue treatment. The venous blood samples of the patient was sent for PACEseq metagenomic next-generation sequencing (mNGS) (Hugobiotech, Beijing, China) on a Nextseq550 platform (Illumina), with results indicating 
 <italic>A. flavus</italic> infection. So we adjusted the treatment to voriconazole 400 mg 12 hourly for 2 doses then 200 mg every 12 h (target trough concentration of 1.5–4.0 μg ml
 <sup>−1</sup>) and moxifloxacin 400 mg 24 hourly for anti-infection treatment, and the patient's fever symptoms were finally controlled.
</p>
