<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par58">
 <list list-type="order">
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par59">Asian patients aged 2 to 17 years on obtaining informed consent.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par60">Those definitively diagnosed with CD30-positive HL or sALCL based on histological findings. A report or its copy describing that a specimen collected at the time of initial diagnosis or relapse was evaluated as positive for CD30 using an immunohistochemical procedure or flow cytometry is stored in the hospital.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par61">Those with PD during standard chemotherapy or without CR/partial remission (PR) after treatment, or those with relapse or additional exacerbation after standard chemotherapy.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par62">Those with an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance status (PS) of 0 to 2.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par63">Those whose laboratory data on screening meet the following criteria. The administration of a gene recombinant human granulocyte-colony stimulating factor (G-CSF) preparation or blood transfusion is not performed within1 week before neutrophil and platelet count tests:</p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
 <list list-type="bullet">
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par64">Neutrophil count: ≥1500 × 10
    <sup>6</sup>/L
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par65">Platelet count: ≥75,000 × 10
    <sup>6</sup>/L
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par66">Hemoglobin level: ≥8 g/dL</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par67">Serum bilirubin level: ≤1.5-fold the upper limit of normal (ULN) in the facility</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par68">Serum creatinine level: ≤1.5-fold the ULN</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par69">Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST): ≤2.5-fold the ULN</p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
 <list list-type="simple">
  <list-item>
   <label>6)</label>
   <p id="Par70">Those who are expected to survive for ≥3 months on obtaining informed consent.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>7)</label>
   <p id="Par71">Written informed consent regarding participation in this clinical study could be obtained from subjects and/or representatives</p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
