<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The impact of COVID-19 on mental health reported in the current study is consistent with concurrent research reporting elevated levels of depression and anxiety during the early stages of COVID-19, compared to pre-pandemic data (
 <xref rid="ref8" ref-type="bibr">Fisher et al., 2020</xref>; 
 <xref rid="ref11" ref-type="bibr">Huckins et al., 2020</xref>). The current study provides further insight into the evolution of mental health outcomes in response to the consecutive bushfire and pandemic community threats. Anxiety symptoms appeared to maintain at levels similar to those as during the baseline reference period despite a severe and protracted bushfire season; but then significantly increased in response to the COVID-19 pandemic and its associated restrictions. While this contrasts with the findings in relation to bushfires reported previously (
 <xref rid="ref3" ref-type="bibr">Biddle et al., 2020</xref>), this indicates possible resilience to feelings of anxiety in response to bushfires present in Australian communities borne from past experiences with drought and bushfires. Such resilience may be generated through a sense of communal support community “togetherness,” or “mateship” deeply ingrained within Australian cultural values (
 <xref rid="ref157" ref-type="bibr">Wilson et al., 2020</xref>). Supporting this interpretation, feelings of social connectedness also remained intact during the bushfire period (though did not buffer against symptoms of depression, discussed below). In contrast, the unique challenges and restrictions presented by COVID-19 deprived Australians of the ability to marshal or facilitate social support in conventional ways. This may have suppressed key strategies of community and individual resilience typically utilized in response to disasters (
 <xref rid="ref153" ref-type="bibr">Emergency Management Victoria, 2020</xref>). The novelty of the threat posed by COVID-19 to Australian communities, who usually enjoy comparatively high standards of health, public safety, and public freedom, may have, therefore, rendered the population ill-equipped to effectively cope with feelings of stress and anxiety, as compared to more familiar disasters experienced historically.
</p>
