<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>It is notable that many of the effect sizes reported are small relative to those found in clinical mental health research. While caution is, therefore, advised when drawing conclusions, small effects are not unexpected given the naturalistically sampled population and may still be relevant in addressing public health concerns. Another consideration is that study outcomes may be related to regular, yearly variations in mental health and well-being. Both observed (e.g., seasonal variation) or unobserved events may naturally occur concurrently with the dates defining each time period and may better explain changes observed across time periods. Supplementary analyses examined this possibility by examining whether the changes observed across the bushfire and COVID-19 time periods also occurred in the equivalent time periods of the previous year. These analyses revealed no such changes in the previous year, and also showed that the current bushfire and COVID-19 periods were significantly worse across most mental health outcomes than their respective equivalent time period in the previous year. These findings indicate that the source of change in outcomes observed in this study were unlikely due to any seasonal variations in mental health and well-being, and provide confidence that bushfire and COVID-19 community disasters were more probable causes. Finally, it is important to acknowledge potential self-selection biases in the study sample, as the “smartphone,” “mental health,” and “app” features of the study might have attracted particular groups of participants. This may include younger populations who are more experienced and familiar with smartphone technology, or individuals already experiencing existing symptoms of depression and anxiety (e.g., 
 <xref rid="ref2" ref-type="bibr">Bakker et al., 2018</xref>). While not confirmed in the present study, this possibility would limit the generalizability of study findings to such samples, and indicate that normative mental health responses to consecutive community disasters could differ from those presented hitherto.
</p>
