<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>For the treatment and prognosis of thyroid metastases from breast cancer, Surgery for thyroid metastases is debatable. Some authors stated that thyroidectomy seem to be effective for alleviating dysphagia and dysphonia resulted by large metastatic thyroid lesions (
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>). Thyroidectomy was recommended for isolated thyroid metastases from breast carcinomas (
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>). Other cases suggested that thyroidectomy has no efficacy in patients with thyroid metastases from breast cancer combined with multiple distant metastases and chemotherapies should be performed (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>). With the limitation of the small number of patient data, there is no definitive evidence to support surgery or chemotherapy or radiotherapy for thyroid metastases from breast cancer (
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>). In addition, several studies have suggested that the prognosis of thyroid metastases is poor (
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>). Zhou et al. (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>) reported that two of eight patients with thyroid metastases from breast cancer died at less than 22 months post-thyroid metastases diagnosis. Kim et al. (
 <xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>) reported one of five patients died at 26 months after diagnosis of thyroid metastases from breast cancer. Lacka et al. (
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>) reported that one patient with thyroid metastases from breast cancer had metastases in liver, and lung at 5 months after thyroidectomy, and died at postoperative 36 months. Metastases in bone at 32 months after hemithyroidectomy were observed in a patient with thyroid metastases from breast cancer who died at postoperative 45 months (
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>). The characteristics of thyroid metastases from breast cancer are presented in 
 <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">
  <bold>Table 1</bold>
 </xref>.
</p>
