<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par6">This was a single arm Phase II open label, single agent, multicenter clinical trial for subjects with HRNB who had completed standard therapy or therapy for refractory/relapsed disease. Subjects were enrolled onto the Beat Childhood Cancer Trial NMTRC003/003B from June 2012 to February 2016. This trial was approved by the Western Institutional Review Board as well as by local Institutional Review Boards at 22 enrolling hospitals across the United States (Saint Louis University Institutional Review Board, University of California San Diego Human Research Protections Program, Orlando Health/Orlando Regional Healthcare System Institutional Review Board, Medical University of South Carolina Institutional Review Board for Human Research, Chesapeake Research Review, Inc., Spectrum Health Institutional Review Board, Connecticut Children’s Medical Center Institutional Review Board, Children’s Mercy Hospital Pediatric Institutional Review Board, Institutional Review Board for Human Subjects for Baylor College of Medicine and Affiliated Hospitals, Vanderbilt University Human Research Protection Program, Phoenix Children’s Hospital Institutional Review Board, Seton Healthcare Institutional Review Board, Tufts University Health Sciences Institutional Review Board, University of Utah Institutional Review Board, Institutional Review Board of Children’s Hospitals and Clinics of Minnesota, Penn State Milton S. Hershey Medical Center – Penn State College of Medicine – Human Subjects Protection Office - Institutional Review Board, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center Institutional Review Board, Johns Hopkins Medicine All Children’s Hospital Institutional Review Board, Albert Einstein College of Medicine Institutional Review Board and The Research Institute at Nationwide Children’s Hospital). Prior to study entry, written informed consent from the subject (if 18 or over), or from a parent and/or legal guardian (if under 18 y.o.) for study participation was obtained on all subjects. All methods were performed in accordance with relevant guidelines and regulations. ClinicalTrials.gov Identifiers: NCT01586260 Unique ID: NMTRC 003 Released 4/24/2012 as well as NCT02395666 Unique ID: NMTRC003B Released 3/5/2015.</p>
