<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A 34-year-old male patient was admitted with a 1-month history of headache in June 14, 2016. The patient has no fever and no other symptoms. In 2012, he had recurrent oral aphthous ulcers, epididymitis, uveitis, papulopustular lesions, and arthritis, then he was diagnosed as BD according to the International Criteria for Behçet Disease (ICBD). Although he used prednisolone (8 mg per day) and thalidomide (50 mg per day) regularly, he had recurrent epididymitis. Other past medical history and family history were unremarkable. Physical examination on admission showed papulopustular lesions on the back, and no abnormality was found in the nervous system. Brain magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) showed no abnormality. Brain magnetic resonance venography (MRV) showed that venous thrombosis of bilateral transverse sinus, sigmoid sinus, and superior sagittal sinus (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1A</xref>). Lumbar puncture showed that the pressure was elevated significantly (&gt;400 mmH
 <sub>2</sub>O). Cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) analysis showed normal cellularity (4 cells/μl), protein (43 mg/dl), glucose (3.98 mmol/L), and chloride concentrations (118.9 mmol/L). Ink staining was negative. CSF culture was negative. CVST was considered. Coagulation profile was normal. Protein C, Protein S, and antithrombin III were normal. C-reactive protein (CRP) and erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR) levels were 89 mg/L (normal 0–5 mg/L) and 31 mm/h (normal 0–20 mm/h), respectively. Antinuclear antibody (ANA), antiphospholipid antibodies and antineutrophil cytoplasmic antibodies were negative. TPPA antibody of syphilis and HIV antibody were negative. CVST related to the BD was considered. Ultrasonography revealed epididymal inflammatory lesions. Ultrasonography of lower extremity artery and vein, CT angiography of pulmonary artery, and cranial MRA were all normal. Intravenous pulse methylprednisolone (1,000 mg per day for 3 days, then 500 mg per day for 5 days, then prednisone 60 mg per day) combined with low molecular weight heparin (LMWH) was added. Mannitol and glycerol fructose were used to reduce intracranial pressure when necessary. The patient's headache improved slightly. In June 22, 2016, brain MRV showed that the CVST was not improved (not shown). Lumbar puncture was repeated and showed that the pressure was elevated significantly (360 mmH
 <sub>2</sub>O). Warfarin and prednisone (60 mg per day) were maintained. Azathioprine (2 mg/kg) was added. Then the patient was transferred to another hospital for the treatment. In August 16, 2016, the patient was readmitted to our department because of severe headache. Brain MRV showed that the venous thrombosis was similar to that of June 22, 2016. Lumbar puncture was repeated and showed that the intracranial pressure was still elevated significantly (&gt;400 mmH
 <sub>2</sub>O). The benefits and risks of catheter-directed endovascular thrombolysis for the refractory CVST was discussed with the patient. In September 1, 2016, brain digital subtraction angiography (DSA) (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1B</xref>) showed that venous thrombosis of right transverse sinus, sigmoid sinus and superior sagittal sinus. Then catheter-directed endovascular thrombolysis was performed. Through the right femoral vein, a 6F 90 cm guiding catheter (Cook Corporation) was introduced into the right internal jugular vein. Then, under the guidance of a guidewire, a microcatheter was placed into the superior sagittal sinus. Urokinase (42,000 U/h, total 1,000,000 U per day) was used and administered continuously into the sinus by microcatheter. Heparin was also administered continuously through the guiding catheter. After 5 days of thrombolysis, the headache was relieved, and brain MRV was repeated and showed that venous thrombosis of superior sagittal sinus, bilateral transverse sinus, and sigmoid sinus was improved significantly (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1C</xref>). The patient was discharged. Warfarin, corticosteroids, and azathioprine were maintained. The dose of the corticosteroids was reduced gradually and low dose corticosteroids (10 mg per day) was maintained. Brain MRV was repeated in August 2017, April 2019, and June 2020, respectively, and showed that there was no new sinus thrombosis (not shown).
</p>
