<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Further studies on personality in sport in terms of the five-factor personality model known as the Big Five (
 <xref rid="ref32" ref-type="bibr">McCrae and Costa, 2003</xref>) show that physically active people differ in conscientiousness from those who do not train (
 <xref rid="ref35" ref-type="bibr">Mirzaei et al., 2013</xref>; 
 <xref rid="ref3" ref-type="bibr">Allen and Laborde, 2014</xref>). Through physical activity, people are able to direct their life goals and be ambitious in life. It has also been proven that sportsmen who train professionally are distinguished from physically active and nontraining people with a higher level of extraversion and conscientiousness, and a lower index of neuroticism (
 <xref rid="ref1" ref-type="bibr">Allen et al., 2011</xref>, 
 <xref rid="ref2" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>; 
 <xref rid="ref42" ref-type="bibr">Piepiora and Witkowski, 2018</xref>; 
 <xref rid="ref39" ref-type="bibr">Piepiora, 2019</xref>). Hence, sportsmen are distinguished by the quality and quantity of social interactions as well as the level of activity, energy, and the ability to experience positive emotions. Therefore, sportsmen like to surround themselves with people with a positive attitude. In addition, they are well organized, persistent, and motivated in activities aimed at achieving the intended goal. Sportsmen are also less prone to experience negative emotions and less susceptible to psychological stress. These differences are visible in the level of anxiety, aggressive hostility, tendency to depression, impulsiveness, oversensitivity, or shyness due to involvement in sport. In turn, openness to experience and agreeableness were on a similar level among people representing the area of physical culture. Features, such as trust, straightforwardness, altruism, submissiveness, modesty, tendency to be emotional, imagination, aesthetics, affection, ability to act, idealism, and valence, do not distinguish sportsmen from physically active people.
</p>
