<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>What is missing is a clear understanding of eventual laterality of hippocampal radioinjury. Some preliminary evidence, however, suggests differential changes in the left and in the right hippocampus after radiotherapy or surgery [
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>–
 <xref rid="B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]. In our previous prospective study, we observed a correlation between post-WBRT verbal memory impairment and changes in the left hippocampus measured by
 <italic> in vivo</italic> magnetic resonance spectroscopy, whereas no such correlation was observed in the right hippocampus [
 <xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]. In another recent study focused on hippocampal radiation dose volume effects and memory deficits, in which combined data from another three prospective studies were analyzes, the left hippocampus appeared more sensitive to radiation than the right one [
 <xref rid="B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]. For example, a 20% risk of decline in verbal memory was associated with the maximal delivered dose of 28.8 Gy to the right hippocampus, but with only 23.7 Gy to the left one. Considering that post WBRT cognitive impairment (represented mainly by verbal memory deficits) would have been associated predominantly with unilateral hippocampal radioinjury, only unilateral (left) sparing during WBRT may be judged. This novel approach of unilateral hippocampus sparing WBRT would be associated with reduced concern regarding subtherapeutic dose in spared regions and with the possibility of improved sparing of single hippocampus. In our pilot dosimetric study, left unilateral sparing yielded lower doses in spared hippocampus with a more homogenous irradiation of the remaining brain [
 <xref rid="B21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. To justify clinical testing of this radiotherapy technique, it would be useful to evaluate whether there is some difference in the incidence of BM within left versus right hippocampus; however, no prior study has assessed the laterality of hippocampal BM seeding.
</p>
