<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fn-group>
 <fn fn-type="other" id="fn1-0963689718820271">
  <p>
   <bold>Ethical Approval:</bold> This study was approved by the the Comisión Federal para la Protección de Riesgos Sanitarios (COFEPRIS, CMN2012-027) and by the ethics committee of the Hospital Angeles Pedregal (HAP 2330). Fetal tissue was obtained in 1998 at Good Samaritan Hospital (Los Angeles, CA) with institutional approval #97-11-01, within their neuro-transplantation program.
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other" id="fn2-0963689718820271">
  <p>
   <bold>Statement of Human Rights:</bold> All of the procedures involving human subjects were conducted in compliance with the Declaration of Helsinki.
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other" id="fn3-0963689718820271">
  <p>
   <bold>Statement of Informed Consent:</bold> Human fetal brain tissue donor informed consent forms were obtained in accordance with NIH guidelines for use of fetal tissue (available from: 
   <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://stemcells.nih.gov/staticresources/news/newsArchives/fr25au00-136.htm" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">http://stemcells.nih.gov/staticresources/news/newsArchives/fr25au00-136.htm</ext-link>), as well as US federal, and CA state laws. PD patients selected for the study signed letters of informed consent of their own free will, after the protocol had been carefully described to them, emphasizing the use of human fetal tissue, and the requirement for their commitment to lengthy pre- and post-surgery evaluations. Tissue donors and NPC recipients remained unknown to each other.
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="COI-statement" id="fn4-0963689718820271">
  <p>
   <bold>Declaration of Conflicting Interests:</bold> The author(s) declared the following potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article: Oleg Kopyov is a co-owner and CSO of Celavie Biosciences, LLC. Alex Kopyov is Vice-President of Celavie Biosciences, LLC. Celavie Biosciences LLC owns the following patents pertaining to the stem cells used in the trial: (1) Compositions and Methods for Propagation of Neural Progenitor Cells. Issued patents: United States 7632681, China ZL200480039675.1, Japan 4676442. Pending Patents: Canada 2547827, European Union 04812676.7, India 1807/KOLNP/2006. 2) Pluripotent Cells. Issued patents: United States 8367406. Pending Patents: United States 13/744,262.
  </p>
  <p>No fees were charged to patients who received no payment either; tissue donor and center performing the abortion received no payments; researchers were not paid for their work.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="financial-disclosure" id="fn6-0963689718820271">
  <p>
   <bold>Funding:</bold> The author(s) disclosed receipt of the following financial support for the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article: Authors received material and logistic support from Celavie Biosciences, LLC. Partial research support was also received from an UNAM grant, UNAM-DGAPA-PAPIIT IT201115.
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other" id="fn7-0963689718820271">
  <p>
   <bold>ORCID iD:</bold> A. Kopyov 
   <inline-graphic xlink:href="10.1177_0963689718820271-img1.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
   <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://orcid.org/0000-0003-0420-138X" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">https://orcid.org/0000-0003-0420-138X</ext-link>
  </p>
 </fn>
</fn-group>
