<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>We performed a retrospective observational study including patients with IBD who had been treated with vedolizumab and/or ustekinumab at the Asan Medical Center, a tertiary-care teaching hospital in South Korea, between August 2017 and December 2020. During this period, patients who had negative baseline IGRA results by QuantiFERON
 <sup>®</sup>-TB Gold In-tube (QFT-GIT; QIAGEN, Hilden, Germany), or QuantiFERON
 <sup>®</sup>-Gold Plus (QFT-Plus; QIAGEN, Hilden, Germany) were included. Vedolizumab was prescribed for patients with active Crohn's disease (CD) or ulcerative colitis (UC) and ustekinumab for patients with active CD, according to the approved indication of drugs in Korea. In total, 91 eligible patients were enrolled in our study. Among them, 11 patients had a history of LTBI and eight had a history of pulmonary TB prior to non-TNF inhibitor therapy. All patients were included in the study regardless of the history related to TB considering that (1) there is a possible risk of reinfection of TB for the residents in Korea, a country with an intermediate TB burden, and (2) the adequacy of TB treatment was not thoroughly documented in the medical records of some patients. Following the prospective registry protocol, IGRAs were performed at 30, 54, and 110 weeks after vedolizumab initiation, and at 26, 52, and 104 weeks after ustekinumab initiation. However, some IGRAs deviated from the above protocol, and those performed at the physician's discretion were also collected and analyzed. Categorical variables were expressed as numbers and percentages, and continuous variables were expressed as median and interquartile range (IQR). The crude and cumulative rates of positive IGRA conversion were calculated, and the patients' clinical characteristics were analyzed and compared according to IGRA conversion. For comparisons between IGRA positive converters and non-converters, the chi-squared test was used for categorical variables and the Mann-Whitney 
 <italic>U</italic>-test was used for continuous variables. The ethics committee of Asan Medical Center approved the study protocol (IRB Number: 2021-0058).
</p>
