<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par81">Patients with cancer who have a CVC implanted are at special risk of developing CRBSI. Infection rates of 2.66 per 1000 line-days have been found in adult haematology/oncology and bone marrow transplant units [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>]. Recently, lock solution technique as a preventive strategy for CRBSI in patients with cancer has been systematically reviewed [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>]. The great majority of studies were performed in paediatric patients (10 studies), and only three were carried out in the adult population. Vancomycin was the most frequently studied solution because the great majority of infections are caused by Gram-positive bacteria. The results of vancomycin studies were variable; some studies showed a reduction of CRBSI in paediatric patients with cancer [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>], while others failed to do so [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>]. Moreover, Carratalà et al. [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>] demonstrated a significant reduction of CRBSI in neutropenic haematological patients using vancomycin as lock solution in the single study carried out in adults. Nevertheless, the widespread use of prophylactic antibiotics as catheter lock solutions may contribute to the development of antibiotic-selective pressure and resistance. In addition, the emergence of Gram-negative bacteria as an important cause of CRBSI raises the doubt about the current utility of vancomycin. Furthermore, three studies investigating ethanol as a lock solution in paediatric and adult patients with cancer showed discordant results [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>]. Moreover, relatively frequent adverse effects have been reported with the use of ethanol-based solutions, which limits its use for this purpose [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>].
</p>
