<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fig id="Fig2">
 <label>Fig. 2</label>
 <caption>
  <p>Histological analysis of the critical-sized mouse calvarial defects at 4 weeks post surgery. 
   <bold>a</bold> Representative Alcian Blue images of the entire defect site for control and SSRI-exposed sham, scaffold, and BMP2 surgical groups. 
   <bold>b</bold> Quantification of cartilage within the defect site showing a significant interaction effect between the treatment and surgical groups (
   <italic>P</italic> = 0.017). The sertraline-exposed scaffold and BMP2 animals were found to have increased cartilage formation compared to sham (
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.01 and 
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.001, respectively). 
   <bold>c</bold> Quantification of the collagen fibers within the regenerate contained in the defect site. Sertraline-exposed animals contained significantly more collagen fibers (
   <italic>P</italic> = 0.022), with both the scaffold (
   <italic>P</italic> = 0.028) and BMP2 surgical groups (
   <italic>P</italic> = 0.017) having increased collagen within the regenerate compared to sham for both groups. 
   <bold>d</bold> Quantification of bone within the regenerate contained in the defect site. Sertraline-exposed animals contained significantly decreased bone (
   <italic>P</italic> = 0.010), while the scaffold and BMP2 surgical groups had increased bone within the regenerate compared to sham (
   <italic>P</italic> = 0.003). 
   <bold>e</bold> Representative Masson's Trichrome images of the entire defect site for control and sertraline-exposed sham, scaffold, and BMP2 surgical groups. 
   <bold>f</bold> Representative-polarized Picrosirius Red images of the entire defect site for control and sertraline-exposed sham, scaffold, and BMP2 surgical groups. 
   <bold>g</bold> Quantification of the immature (green) collagen fibers within the site. 
   <bold>h</bold> Quantification of medium thickness (yellow) collagen fibres within the regenerate, indicating that sertraline-exposed animals had increased numbers of maturing collagen fibres (
   <italic>P</italic> = 0.002). 
   <bold>i</bold> Quantification of mature, thick (red) collagen fibers within the regenerate, showing that sertraline-exposed animals had increased mature, thick collagen fibers (
   <italic>P</italic> = 0.001). Black arrows indicate cartilage formation, and black/white outlines indicate the regenerate analysed. Higher magnification images were taken of the endocranial (left) and surgical margin (right). Scale bar is 40 µm; 
   <italic>n</italic> = 3 per group; *
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.05; **
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.01; ***
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.001. Data are means ± standard errors
  </p>
 </caption>
 <graphic xlink:href="41368_2018_26_Fig2_HTML" id="d29e791" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
</fig>
