<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fig id="Fig3">
 <label>Fig. 3</label>
 <caption>
  <p>Immunohistochemical analysis of the critical-sized mouse calvarial defects 4 weeks post surgery. 
   <bold>a</bold> TRAP images of the entire defect site for control and sertraline-exposed sham, scaffold, and BMP2 surgical groups. 
   <bold>b</bold> Quantification of the number of TRAP-positive osteoclasts within the defect, which indicates that sertraline exposure decreases osteoclast activity (
   <italic>P</italic> = 0.001). 
   <bold>c</bold> Alkaline phosphatase immunohistochemistry photomicrographs of control and sertraline-exposed sham, scaffold, and BMP2 surgical groups. 
   <bold>d</bold> Quantification of the alkaline phosphatase-positive cells within the defect, demonstrating that the exposed scaffold and BMP2 groups had increased levels of alkaline phosphatase activity compared to the sham group (
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.001). 
   <bold>e</bold> Proliferating cell nuclear antigen photomicrographs of control and sertraline-exposed sham, scaffold, and BMP2 surgical groups. 
   <bold>f</bold> Quantification of the PCNA-positive cells within the defect, showing that the exposed animals had decreased proliferation (
   <italic>P</italic> = 0.05) compared to the control animals, while the exposed BMP2 group had increased levels of PCNA activity compared to the sham group (
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.05). 
   <bold>g</bold> Caspase immunohistochemistry photomicrographs of control and sertraline-exposed sham, scaffold, and BMP2 surgical groups. 
   <bold>h</bold> Quantification of the caspase-positive cells within the defect, indicating that the exposed scaffold and BMP2 groups had increased levels of apoptosis compared to the sham group (
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.05). Black arrows indicate examples of positive staining. Higher magnification images were taken of the endocranial (left) and surgical margin (right). Scale bar is 40 µm; 
   <italic>n</italic> = 3 per group; *
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.05; ***
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.001. Data are means ± standard errors
  </p>
 </caption>
 <graphic xlink:href="41368_2018_26_Fig3_HTML" id="d29e896" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
</fig>
