<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fig id="Fig5">
 <label>Fig. 5</label>
 <caption>
  <p>Immunohistochemical analysis of serotonin (5-hydroxytryptamine, 5HT) and tissue transglutaminase (TG2) levels in mouse critical-sized calvarial defects 4 weeks post surgery. 
   <bold>a</bold> 5-Hydroxytrptamine (5HT) immunohistochemistry photomicrographs of control and sertraline-exposed sham, scaffold, and BMP-2 surgical groups. 
   <bold>b</bold> Quantification of the 5HT-positive cells within the defect. Sertraline exposure results in a significant decrease in serotonin within the defect when compared with untreated control samples (
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.001), and the BMP-2-treated groups showed significantly more 5HT positivity compared to both the sham and scaffold groups (
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.001). 
   <bold>c</bold> Tissue transglutaminase (TG2) immunohistochemistry photomicrographs of control and sertraline-exposed sham, scaffold, and BMP-2 surgical groups. 
   <bold>d</bold> Quantification of the TG2-positive cells within the defect. Sertraline exposure resulted in a significant decrease in TG2 levels within the defect when compared to untreated control samples (
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.001). Higher magnification images were taken of the endocranial (left) and surgical margin (right). 
   <bold>e</bold> Gene expression of 
   <italic>Tph1</italic> and 
   <italic>Slc6a4</italic> showed downregulation at 7 days with sertraline treatment in E1 and BMSC cells, while WT cells showed a significant upregulation in these genes at 7 days with high-dose sertraline treatment (
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.05). C2C12 cells did not amplify either gene. 
   <bold>f</bold> E1 and C2C12 cells showed a significant downregulation of 
   <italic>Col1a1</italic> and 
   <italic>Col1a2</italic> at 7 days with sertraline treatment (
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.05). 
   <italic>n</italic> = 3 per group; *
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.05; ***
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.001. Data are means ± standard errors
  </p>
 </caption>
 <graphic xlink:href="41368_2018_26_Fig5_HTML" id="d29e1154" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
</fig>
