<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Among the studied population of team sports players, significant differences were found between particular sports disciplines, i.e., in neuroticism, extraversion, agreeableness, and conscientiousness. It was found that there are differences in the intensity of individual personality traits between sports disciplines within team sports. This indicates the existence of differences in the personality of players depending on their sports discipline. The obtained data indicate significant effects of sport on the personality shaping of the assessed players and confirm the reports of other authors (
 <xref rid="ref7" ref-type="bibr">Chirivella and Martinez, 1994</xref>; 
 <xref rid="ref26" ref-type="bibr">Kajtna et al., 2004</xref>; 
 <xref rid="ref48" ref-type="bibr">Tok, 2013</xref>; 
 <xref rid="ref27" ref-type="bibr">Kang et al., 2016</xref>; 
 <xref rid="ref33" ref-type="bibr">McEwan et al., 2019</xref>; 
 <xref rid="ref41" ref-type="bibr">Piepiora et al., 2020</xref>). Sports activity shapes the personality, and the formed personality traits have an impact on taking solutions in the starting situation. It should be related to the specificity of sports competition and the slightly different psychological requirements that sports disciplines impose on competitors. However, these dissonances have not been noted in openness to experience. Taking into account the specificity of acceptable contact in team sports, it was assumed that the lack of differences in openness to experience was revealed primarily in the divergent thinking and creativity of players (
 <xref rid="ref11" ref-type="bibr">Costa and McCrae, 2007</xref>). Moreover, the previous experiences of the surveyed players from the earlier periods of their sports careers and the impact of many years of sports training on possible modifications of personality traits should be taken into account. Apart from the influence of the coach and other entities from the players' closest social environment. Therefore, social and cultural factors must also be taken into account.
</p>
