<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par80">We will also collect a number of additional measures, as well as data regarding participant descriptive characteristics, health services usage and cytokine and growth factor profiles:
 <list list-type="simple">
  <list-item>
   <label>i)</label>
   <p id="Par81">
    <italic>Additional measures</italic>: these include participant weight, drug/supplement use, adverse events, the success of participant and doctor blinding, use of co-interventions and number of injections.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>ii)</label>
   <p id="Par82">
    <italic>Descriptive data</italic>: including participant height, body mass index, age, gender, duration of symptoms, radiographic disease severity, knee alignment (measured from the knee x-ray and reported in degrees [
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>]), current employment, symptom laterality, symptoms in other joints, treatment expectation on a 5 point Likert scale (from "no effect at all” to "complete recovery”), neuropathic pain using the painDETECT questionnaire [
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>], and physical activity using the Physical Activity Scale for the Elderly (PASE) [
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>, 
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>]. The cross-sectional area of the medial tibial plateau from MRI [
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>] will be measured for use as a covariate.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>iii)</label>
   <p id="Par83">
    <italic>Health economic evaluation data</italic>: measured using data collected at baseline, and 2, 6, 9 and 12-months. Data include health care costs estimated from healthcare service usage and Quality Adjusted Life Years (QALYs) calculated using the AQoL-8D, and work performance data obtained from the World Health Organisation Health Performance Questionnaire (WHO HPQ) [
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>iv)</label>
   <p id="Par84">
    <italic>Cytokine and growth factor concentrations:</italic> aliquots of PRP will be analysed in a subset of participants to determine the concentration of key growth factors and cytokines, such as platelet-derived growth factor, transforming growth factor beta 1, connective tissue growth factor, interleukin 1 receptor agonist, interleukin 1 beta, interleukin 6 and matrix metallopeptidase 9.
   </p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
