<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par68">A previous study by Zahreddine reported for the first time that Ara-C is a substrate of UGT1A enzymes and could be inactivated through glucuronidation [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]. Increased UGT1A expression in Ara-C resistant M5 AML THP-1 cells and relapsed AML after standard Ara-C therapies were observed, and elevation in GLI1 expression is sufficient to drive UGT1A dependent glucuronidation of Ara-C and drug resistance [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]. However, by analyzing the mRNA expression profile of the Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA) dataset, we observed that the expression of 
 <italic>UGT1A1</italic> in blast cells from AML patients was nearly negligible in contrast to the main Ara-C inactivating enzyme 
 <italic>CDA</italic> (Additional file 
 <xref rid="MOESM5" ref-type="media">5</xref>: Fig. S3) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>]. These findings suggest that the observed influence of 
 <italic>UGT1A1*28</italic> and 
 <italic>*6</italic> polymorphisms on Ara-C response in AML patients is less likely to be explained by decreased Ara-C detoxification in AML blast cells. As the UGT1A subfamily is mainly expressed in human liver, we speculate that the 
 <italic>UGT1A1*28</italic> and 
 <italic>*6</italic> polymorphisms may improve Ara-C response and OS of the AML patients through decreasing hepatic glucuronidation and increasing the systemic exposure of Ara-C. It's a pity that we failed to detect the plasma concentrations of Ara-C during Ara-C infusion. Of note, AML is usually treated by combined therapy with Ara-C and anthracyclines, and whether UGT1A1 is involved in the metabolism of anthracyclines remains unknown. Therefore, we could not rule out the possibility that difference in disease outcomes among 
 <italic>UGT1A1</italic> genotypes is due to difference in anthracycline metabolism. Influence of both 
 <italic>UGT1A1</italic> polymorphisms on pharmacokinetics and systemic exposure of Ara-C and glucuronidated Ara-C (AraC-Glu) deserved further study in future.
</p>
