<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Patients with visual snow (VS) describe continuous, mostly black and white tiny flickering dots in their entire visual field, comparable to the old TV-static noise when missing the analog signal. When accompanied by other visual symptoms such as afterimages (palinopsia), impaired night vision (nyctalopia), or increased light sensitivity (photophobia), it is called visual snow syndrome (VSS) (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>–
 <xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>). Its pathophysiology is still under discussion, and although it is highly associated with migraine with and without aura and may partially overlap with these, recent research strongly suggests that VS is a distinct disorder (
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>–
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>). The visual disturbance sums up to a clinical picture that is best explained by dysfunction of the higher-order visual cortex. Consistently, fluorodeoxyglucose-positron emission tomography (PET) investigations showed hypermetabolism in the lingual gyrus, an area of the higher visual association cortex (
 <xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>). Importantly, these findings from functional neuroimaging were confirmed by voxel-based morphometry by two independent groups which demonstrated increased gray matter volume in the same cortical area (
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>). A possible neurophysiological correlate of the involvement of higher visual areas could be the significantly prolonged latency of the late N145 potentials with normal P100 potentials in visual evoked potentials (
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>). However, the picture is likely more complex with studies pointing to a dysfunction of the primary visual cortex, considering thalamocortical dysrhythmia as the origin of VSS (
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>) and demonstrating alterations also in non-visual, acoustic, and limbic areas (
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>).
</p>
