<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Treatment of breast cancer with chemotherapy is remarkably effective, but it is associated with side effects. The disruption in the function of the intestine is a common clinically side effect. Chemotherapy-induced gastrointestinal toxicity (CIGT) is associated with a variety of clinical complications, including anorexia, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, constipation. CIGT affected more than half of cancer which will lead to the break and/or reduction of treatments patient, and has huge clinical and economic implications. Patients who experience severe CIGT have twice the infection risk leading to a fourfold higher chance of death and threefold longer hospital stays, compromising survival and creating a burden on patients' quality of life.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]
 </sup> CIGT is considered to be an important factor affecting the recovery of cancer patients with chemotherapy treatment. But current evidences do not support widespread implementation of probiotics for CIGT.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,
  <xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]
 </sup> Acupoint therapy is one of the therapeutic methods in TCM based on acupoints and meridians theory, including acupuncture, electroacupuncture, moxibustion, acupoint application, acupoint injection, and catgut embedding. Acupoint application is an external treatment based on the theory of TCM. It applies Chinese herbal medicines to the skin at corresponding acupoints and has superior efficacy and fewer side effects than using Western medicine alone.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]
 </sup> Our previous studies observed that SHP can improve gastrointestinal toxicity, intestinal mucosal damage induced by chemotherapy.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
  <xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,
  <xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]
 </sup> Each herb in SHP has been verified to regulate intestinal function, promote the increase of probiotics in the intestine, reduce the inflammation of the smooth muscle of the small intestine and accelerate the secretion of serum Ghrelin.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>–
  <xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]
 </sup> Moreover, our another study suggests that the SHP was absorbed better through CV8 than non-acupoint.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]
 </sup> The efficacy and safety of the SHP on shenque to regulate gastrointestinal toxicity in breast cancer patients after chemotherapy will be observed in the current study.
</p>
