<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The results obtained in our study are comparable to results published in other species, including humans (
 <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>), horses (
 <xref rid="B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>), dogs and cats (
 <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>). Only a few previously published papers provide some references concerning BAL cytology in different macaque species (
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>–
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>). They were established from 5 to 20 individuals and reported as mean or median ± standard deviation (SD). The present study complies with the recently published recommendations concerning small reference sample groups (
 <xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>), resulting in much wider reference intervals. Conflicting results concerning macrophages were previously published as Tate et al. (
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>) reported a high percentage of macrophages of 98.33 ± 1.14 (mean ± SD) whilst others obtained results comparable to ours (
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>). Also, we obtained slightly higher percentages of lymphocytes. This discrepancy may be related to breeding conditions or explained by several differences during BAL collection and processing. Collection by video-endoscopy vs. endotracheal tube could have resulted in the collection of different segments of the lung with slightly different populations of cells. In our study, processing was kept to a minimum: BALs were centrifuged, and the pellets were directly smeared on slides. In previous studies (
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>–
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>), macaques were of different origin, sample collection was slightly different with some performing lavages at necropsy or performing BAL cells centrifugation and resuspension steps and sometimes hemolysis, that may have resulted in an alteration from the original cell population. Also, in our study, the slight blood contamination could be responsible for a small overestimation of lymphocytes as those cells are one of the predominant leukocyte population in peripheral blood. Indeed, from the author's experience, rare red blood cell and oropharyngeal contaminants are frequently found in BAL from healthy mammals (dogs, cats, and horses) and are technique-dependent. Oropharyngeal and slight blood contamination may result from slight scratches of the oropharyngeal and tracheobronchial walls by the endoscope or the endotracheal tube. Hemorrhage can also occur secondary to depression during aspiration of the fluid especially if a small airway is sampled. Although blood contamination was not reported in the other studies (
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>–
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>), more contamination is expected with the endotracheal tube as this procedure is blinded. Yet, this technique is frequently used in practice as fiberoptic endoscope is not always available in facilities.
</p>
