<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The QoR-40
 <xref rid="cit0007" ref-type="bibr">7</xref> questionnaire is a reliable multi-dimensional assessment tool used to assess the patient’s health status after surgery and anesthesia. Several studies have shown that the QoR-40 questionnaire can be used to assess the postoperative quality of recovery. Currently, there is no “gold standard” for postoperative analgesia after thoracic surgery, and perioperative multimodal analgesia is the recommended method for enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS).
 <xref rid="cit0008" ref-type="bibr">8</xref> Inadequate postoperative analgesia may cause severe postoperative pain, stress, circulatory, and respiratory dysfunction, increase the risk of developing perioperative complications, and directly affect the patient’s emotional state and daily life. The pain can become chronic and affects the quality and outcome of the postoperative recovery of patients. This study found that the use of intraoperative intravenous lidocaine can significantly improve the quality of the patients’ postoperative recovery as shown by the improvement in the total QoR-40 score particularly in the three sub-aspects of physical comfort, physical independence, and pain. Furthermore, the application of lidocaine significantly reduced the consumption of opioids in the operation, shortened the time of first flatus and defecation after the operation, reduced the use of remedial analgesia, and accelerated the recovery of gastrointestinal function. However, the influence of lidocaine on the quality of recovery and the analgesic effect is still controversial for different surgical methods. Previous, studies have shown that the use of lidocaine during surgery can significantly relieve postoperative pain, especially in open or laparoscopic abdominal surgery. Cui
 <xref rid="cit0009" ref-type="bibr">9</xref> applied lidocaine in thoracic surgery and found that the pain score of patients was significantly reduced 24 h after surgery. Lidocaine was also used in thyroid surgery,
 <xref rid="cit0010" ref-type="bibr">10</xref> but the acute postoperative pain and the quality of postoperative recovery did not improve. Martin
 <xref rid="cit0011" ref-type="bibr">11</xref> reported that the use of intravenous lidocaine in total hip replacement surgery did not result in a significant reduction in the use of opioids and postoperative pain scores within 24 h. The variation between these studies may be related to the surgical site and the dose of lidocaine applied during the operation. Abdominal surgery and thoracic surgery lead to different levels of visceral damage, while thyroid surgery and total hip replacement surgery are inflicting mostly physical pain. This may be because lidocaine is better at relieving visceral pain than physical pain.
</p>
