<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Publishing DTD v1.1d1 20130915//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName JATS-journalpublishing1.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 39.96?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName jp2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Clin Appl Thromb Hemost</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Clin. Appl. Thromb. Hemost</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">CAT</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="hwp">spcat</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Clinical and Applied Thrombosis/Hemostasis</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">1076-0296</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1938-2723</issn><publisher><publisher-name>SAGE Publications</publisher-name><publisher-loc>Sage CA: Los Angeles, CA</publisher-loc></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6714858</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/1076029618792302</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">10.1177_1076029618792302</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Original Articles</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Genetic Polymorphism of <italic>VKORC1-1639</italic> in Children With
Intracranial Hemorrhage Due to Vitamin K Deficiency</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Berber</surname><given-names>U&#x0011f;ur</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1-1076029618792302">1</xref><xref ref-type="corresp" rid="corresp1-1076029618792302"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>&#x000d6;zdemir</surname><given-names>Mehmet Akif</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2-1076029618792302">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Unal</surname><given-names>Ekrem</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2-1076029618792302">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Taheri</surname><given-names>Serpil</given-names></name><degrees>MSc, PhD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3-1076029618792302">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Yildiz</surname><given-names>Serkan</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff4-1076029618792302">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Bayramov</surname><given-names>Keziban Korkmaz</given-names></name><degrees>MSc, PhD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3-1076029618792302">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>G&#x000fc;ler</surname><given-names>Yunus</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1-1076029618792302">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Per</surname><given-names>H&#x000fc;seyin</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff5-1076029618792302">5</xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff1-1076029618792302">
<label>1</label> Faculty of Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, Erciyes University,
Kayseri, Turkey</aff><aff id="aff2-1076029618792302">
<label>2</label>Division of Pediatric Hematology and Oncology, Department of
Pediatrics, Faculty of Medicine, Erciyes University, Kayseri, Turkey</aff><aff id="aff3-1076029618792302">
<label>3</label> Faculty of Medicine, Department of Medical Biology, Erciyes
University, Kayseri, Turkey</aff><aff id="aff4-1076029618792302">
<label>4</label> Faculty of Medicine, Department of Public Health, Erciyes
University, Kayseri, Turkey</aff><aff id="aff5-1076029618792302">
<label>5</label> Faculty of Medicine, Division of Pediatric Neurology, Department of
Pediatrics, Erciyes University, Kayseri, Turkey</aff><author-notes><corresp id="corresp1-1076029618792302">U&#x0011f;ur Berber, Faculty of Medicine, Department
of Pediatrics, Erciyes University, Talas, Kayseri 38039, Turkey. Email:
<email>drugurberber@gmail.com</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>13</day><month>8</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><month>12</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><volume>24</volume><issue>9 Suppl</issue><fpage>89S</fpage><lpage>93S</lpage><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2018</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2018</copyright-year><copyright-holder content-type="sage">SAGE Publications Inc. unless otherwise noted.
Manuscript content on this site is licensed under Creative Commons
Licenses</copyright-holder><license license-type="creative-commons" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/"><license-p>This article is distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons
Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 License (<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">http://www.creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</ext-link>) which
permits non-commercial use, reproduction and distribution of the work
without further permission provided the original work is attributed as
specified on the SAGE and Open Access pages (<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://us.sagepub.com/en-us/nam/open-access-at-sage">https://us.sagepub.com/en-us/nam/open-access-at-sage</ext-link>).</license-p></license></permissions><abstract><p>Intracranial hemorrhage due to vitamin K deficiency is a serious disease that can
lead to morbidity, mortality, and mental retardation. Our goal in this study is
to determine the frequency of <italic>VKORC1-1639 G&#x0003e;A</italic> polymorphism
in patients who have undergone intracranial hemorrhage due to vitamin K
deficiency bleeding (VKDB). To study <italic>VKORC1-1639 G&#x0003e;A</italic>
polymorphism, blood was drawn from patients (n = 51, age 8:0 &#x000b1; 6:5 years)
followed at the Pediatric Neurology and Hematology section, Faculty of Medicine,
Erciyes University, between 1990 and 2016, diagnosed with VKDB as idiopathic or
from patients diagnosed with intracranial hemorrhage due to secondary vitamin K
deficiency and also from volunteers (n = 51, age 11 &#x000b1; 4.5 years). Intensive care
and nutrition needs of patients and the laboratory radiological imaging results
and treatments that were applied were analyzed through scanning the files of the
patients and information received from families. Through detailed physical
examination, patients with neurologic sequelae and ongoing epilepsy were
determined. The results were compared to clinical and laboratory results with
control group. Eight (15.7%) of the patients were normal, 29 (56.9%)
heterozygous carrier, and 14 (27.5%) homozygous mutants. In the control group,
19 (37.3%) were normal, 19 (37.3%) heterozygous carriers, and 13 (25.5%)
homozygous mutants. The VKOR1-1639&#x0003e;A (SNP:rs9923231) mutant positivity
(homozygous plus heterozygous mutant) was significantly higher in the patient
group when compared to controls. There were no significant differences between
patient and control groups in terms of the prognosis.</p></abstract><kwd-group><kwd>vitamin K prophylaxis</kwd><kwd><italic>VKOR1-1639G&#x0003e;A</italic> polymorphism</kwd><kwd>intracranial hemorrhage</kwd></kwd-group></article-meta></front><body><sec sec-type="intro" id="section1-1076029618792302"><title>Introduction</title><p>Vitamin K deficiency bleeding (VKDB) is one of the most common hemostatic disorders
at neonatal period and leading preventable cause of mental retardation, epilepsy,
and cerebral palsy.<sup><xref rid="bibr1-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="bibr2-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">2</xref></sup> There are 3 types of VKDB. Early-onset VKDB is seen on the first day of life
and associated with maternal use of drugs that disrupt vitamin K metabolism, while
classical type results from insufficient vitamin K production that occurs between
days 2 and 7 of life and has poor prognosis. Late-onset VKDB occurs due to
insufficient vitamin K intake between 2 and 8 weeks of age.<sup><xref rid="bibr3-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">3</xref></sup> The late-onset VKDB in newborns is characterized by intracranial bleeding
that may occur between week 1 and month 6.<sup><xref rid="bibr4-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">4</xref></sup> Vitamin K is a cofactor for gamma-glutamyl carboxylase (GGCX) that is
involved in formation of tertiary structure and posttranslational modification of
coagulation factors and some proteins. The reduced form of vitamin K (hydroquinone)
is converted to vitamin K epoxide reductase (VKOR) and vitamin K epoxide (VKE),
while glutamate (glu-) residues are converted to &#x003b3;-carboxyglutamate in carboxylation
process during hepatic synthesis of factors II, VII, IX, X and proteins S, C, and Z.
To maintain this cycle, hydroquinone should be regenerated from VKE, which is
controlled by an enzyme called vitamin K 2, 3 epoxide reductase complex (VKORC).</p><p>Bleeding predisposition develops due to inability to activate coagulation factors in
case of vitamin K deficiency or VKOR polymorphism. &#x003b3;-GK gene encoding VKOR was
isolated on chromosome 16 in 2014.<sup><xref rid="bibr5-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="bibr6-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">6</xref></sup> Currently, it is known that single-nucleotide polymorphism 1639G&#x0003e;A at
promoter region of VKOR gene causes up to 50% decrease in VKOR enzyme.<sup><xref rid="bibr7-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">7</xref></sup> This is implied in the variation in doses of warfarin, a vitamin K antagonist.<sup><xref rid="bibr8-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">8</xref></sup> Carboxylation is essential for normal activity of coagulation system.
&#x003b3;-carboxylation occurs in endoplasmic reticulum, and it is thought that
carboxylation is catalyzed by GGCX. The carboxylated proteins are transferred to
Golgi apparatus where they are secreted.</p><p>Vitamin K is the major cofactor for GGCX that adds carbon dioxide during conversion
of glu-residues to gla-residues.<sup><xref rid="bibr9-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="bibr10-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">10</xref></sup> The GGCX enzyme was first isolated in 1991. The VCORK was first described in
1976; however, it was fully characterized in 2004<sup><xref rid="bibr11-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">11</xref></sup> Gamma-glutamyl carboxylase and VKORC are involved in posttranslational
modifications of proteins. In our study, it was aimed to investigate the molecular
etiology in patients with late-onset VKDB who were followed in Pediatric Neurology
and Pediatric Hematology departments of Erciyes University Medicine School and to
identify <italic>VKOR1-1639G&#x0003e;A</italic> polymorphism encoding VKORC that is
thought to cause VKDB in Turkish population.</p></sec><sec sec-type="subjects|methods" id="section2-1076029618792302"><title>Patients and Methods</title><p>All the participating children and parents were informed about the study, and
informed consent was received. The study was approved by the Ethics Committee of
Erciyes University Medical Faculty with no: TTU2016-6579 and was also supported by
the Erciyes University Research Project Management Unit under the project designated
as TTU2016-6579.</p><p>This study included 51 patients diagnosed with VKDB at Pediatric Neurology and
Pediatric Hematology departments of Erciyes University Medicine School between 1990
and 2016 and 51 volunteers with normal platelet count. Patients with congenital
malformation, chromosome anomaly, cholestatic liver disease, congenital valve
defects, prenatal diagnosis, and periventricular leukomalacia were excluded.
Neurological sequels and coagulation disorders were taken into account while
selecting control group. The data regarding birth parameters such as clinical age,
gender, form of feeding, and treatment were tabulated by reviewing medical charts.
Psychomotor and neurological assessments were performed. In both patient and control
groups, blood samples (4 mL) were drawn into EDTA tubes in order to study
<italic>VKOR1-1639G&#x0003e;A</italic> polymorphism and stored at &#x02212;80&#x000b0;C until DNA
isolation. The DNA isolation, polymerase chain reaction (PCR) preparation, and
restriction fragment length polymorphism (RFLP) procedures were performed at Genome
Unite of Genome and Stem Cell Center of Erciyes University.</p><sec id="section3-1076029618792302"><title>DNA Isolation</title><p>The EZ-10 Spin Column Genomic genomic DNA Minipreps isolation kits (Biobasic Inc,
Markham, Ontario, Canada) were used to extract genomic DNA from blood samples.
Overall, blood samples (0.4-5 mL) were drawn from 102 participants. For DNA
extraction, 500 &#x000b5;L of complete blood sample was placed in the centrifugation
tubes (2 mL) with addition of 800 &#x000b5;L tris borate phosphate buffer, which was
then vortexed and kept for 1 minute at room temperature (The mixture should be
bright red and red blood cells should be resolved). The mixture was centrifuged
at 4000 rpm for 3 minutes, and the supernatant was removed. If the supernatant
and blood pellet was still red, the second step and subsequent steps were
repeated. Then, 500 &#x000b5;L Tris-borate magnesium buffer was added to tube, which was
vortexed briefly. Again, 3 &#x000b5;L proteinase K was added to the tube, which was kept
at 55&#x000b0;C for 30 minutes for incubation. If there was any unsolved material, the
tube was centrifuged at 5000 rpm for 2 minutes. The supernatant was transferred
to another tube (2 mL), and 260 &#x000b5;L absolute ethanol was added, which was then
transferred to column and centrifuged at 10 000 rpm for 2 minutes. After adding
500 &#x000b5;L wash solution, the column was recentrifuged at 10 000 rpm for 1 minute.
The collection tube was poured, and 500 &#x000b5;L wash solution was added for further
centrifugation at 10 000 rpm for 1 minute. Then, to remove residual wash
solution, tube was recentrifuged at 10 000 rpm for 1 minute. Spin was continued
until purification was achieved. The column (1.5 mL) was placed to an Eppendorf
tube, and 50 &#x000b5;L elution buffer was applied to center of column. After incubation
at 37&#x000b0;C for 2 minutes, the tube was centrifuged at 10 000 rpm for 1 minute to
extract DNA. The purified DNA was stored at &#x02212;20&#x000b0;C until PCR analysis.</p></sec><sec id="section4-1076029618792302"><title>Polymerase Chain Reaction Preparation</title><p>The isolated DNA was used for PCR analysis. In each PCR tube, 22 &#x000b5;L of the
mixture was placed and 3 &#x000b5;L DNA was added to this mixture, resulting in 25 &#x000b5;L of
final volume. The samples were placed in the PCR device. Samples obtained from
PCR device were run at 2% agarose gel at 90 V for 2 hours. Then, the PCR bands
were imaged using Molecular Imager Gel Doc XR System device (Bio-Rad, Hercules,
California). The PCR products with 290 base pair (bp) were assigned for PCR RFLP
protocol. The PCR products were stored at 4&#x000b0;C until RFLP analysis.</p></sec><sec id="section5-1076029618792302"><title>Restriction Fragment Length Polymorphism</title><p>HpaII restriction enzyme (New England Biolabs, Beverly, Massachusetts) was used
for <italic>VKORC1-1639G&#x0003e;A</italic> polymorphism. RFLP was performed as
follows. The PCR product (15 &#x000b5;L) was delivered to tubes according to patient
number and then other substrates (10&#x000d7; Buffer Tango [33 mmol/L Tris-acetate, pH
7.9, 10 mmol/L magnesium acetate, 66 mmol/L potassium acetate, 0.1 mg/mL BSA],
Hpa II restriction enzyme and water) were added at appropriate volumes. The
mixture was incubated overnight at 37&#x000b0;C. The incubated samples were run on 3%
agarose gel at 85 V for 2 hours. The PCR products and restriction enzymes were
assessed by Molecular Imager Gel Doc XR System device. The products with 168 bp
and 122 bp were considered as homozygous normal, while those with 290 to 168 bp
and 122 bp were considered as heterozygous normal. The PCR products with 290 bp
were considered as homozygous mutant.</p></sec><sec id="section6-1076029618792302"><title>Statistical Analysis</title><p>All statistical analyses were performed by using Statistical Package for Social
Sciences (SPSS) for Windows version 11.0. In our study, we only compared
categorical variables, so normality of the variables was not tested. In
comparing categorical variables, the Pearson &#x003c7;<sup>2</sup> test was used.
<italic>P</italic> value &#x0003c;.05 was considered statistically significant.
Odds ratios are calculated with 95% confidence intervals.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="results" id="section7-1076029618792302"><title>Results</title><p>By reviewing history, data were tabulated for 51 patients (range: 1 month to 27
years) who were diagnosed with intracranial bleeding secondary to VKDB at neonatal
period and 51 healthy volunteers (range: 1 month to 20 years). Median age was 8
years (1-27) in the patient group whereas 11 years (1-18) in the control group.
Based on mutational analysis, normal GG was considered to have no mutation, while
heterozygous GA and homozygous AA mutants were considered to have a mutation. There
were 22 (43.1%) girls and 29 (56.9%) boys in the patient group, whereas 28 (54.9%)
girls and 23 (45.1%) boys in the control group.</p><p>When genetic mutations were assessed, it was found that 8 (15.7%) patients had no
mutation, while 29 (56.9%) patients were heterozygous carrier and 14 (27.5%)
patients were homozygous mutant in the patient group. It was found that 19 (37.3%)
patients were normal, while 19 (37.3%) patients were heterozygous carrier and 13
(25.5%) patients were homozygous mutant in the control group (<xref rid="table1-1076029618792302" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>). These findings indicate
significant differences between patient and control groups. The
<italic>VKOR1-1639&#x0003e;A</italic> mutant positivity (homozygous plus heterozygous
mutant) was significantly higher in the patient group compared to controls
(<italic>P</italic> = .037). There was significant difference between patient
and control groups regarding no mutation and heterozygous mutation
(<italic>P</italic> &#x0003c; .05) but not homozygous mutation (<italic>P</italic>
&#x0003c; .05).</p><table-wrap id="table1-1076029618792302" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Results Mutational Analysis in Patient and Control Groups.<sup>a</sup></p></caption><alternatives><graphic xlink:href="10.1177_1076029618792302-table1"/><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th colspan="6" rowspan="1">Mutation</th></tr><tr><th rowspan="2" colspan="1"/><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">Normal</th><th colspan="4" rowspan="1">Mutant</th></tr><tr><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">Normal (%)</th><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">Heterozygous (%)</th><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">Homozygous (%)</th><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x003c7;<sup>2</sup></th><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<italic>P</italic>
</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Patient (n = 51)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8 (15.7%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">29 (56.9%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">14 (27.5%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">6.60</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">.037</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Control (n = 51)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">19 (37.3%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">19 (37.3%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">13 (25.5%)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">OR (95% CI)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x02013;</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.63 (1.32-9.94)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.56 (0.84-7.83)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr></tbody></table></alternatives><table-wrap-foot><fn id="table-fn1-1076029618792302"><p>Abbreviations: CI, confidence interval; OR, odds ratio; VKOR, vitamin K
epoxide reductase.</p></fn><fn id="table-fn2-1076029618792302"><p><sup>a</sup>&#x0200a;In terms of VKORC1-1639 mutation: (a) Those with the
heterozygous genotype were 3.63 times more risky than those with the
normal genotype. (b) Homozygous group has 2.56 times more disease risk
than normal genotype group. (c) No significant difference between
heterozygous and homozygous mutant group. (d) No significant difference
between normal and homozygous mutant group.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><p>In our study, there was neurological sequel in 35 (68.6%) patients, whereas no
neurological sequel in 16 (31.4%) patients. There was need for intensive care unit
(ICU) care in 37 (72.5%) patients, while 14 (27.5%) patients did not require ICU
care. Subsequent epilepsy was developed in 33 (64.7%) patients in the patient group.
It was found out that 1 patient died due to convulsion after enrollment ito the
study. The need for ICU care and epilepsy indicated that the disease has poor
prognosis.</p><p>When effects of polymorphism on prognosis were assessed, no significant difference
was detected between mutant group (AA and GA) and homozygous normal group (GG)
regarding need for ICU need, neurological sequel, and epilepsy (<xref rid="table2-1076029618792302" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>).</p><table-wrap id="table2-1076029618792302" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Table 2.</label><caption><p>Comparison of Prognostic Factors Genetic Mutant and Normal Groups in the
Patient Group.</p></caption><alternatives><graphic xlink:href="10.1177_1076029618792302-table2"/><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th rowspan="2" colspan="1">Patient</th><th colspan="2" rowspan="1">Patient (AA vs GA)</th><th colspan="2" rowspan="1">Normal (GG)</th><th rowspan="2" colspan="1">
<italic>P</italic>
</th></tr><tr><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">+ (%)</th><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x02212; (%)</th><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">+ (%)</th><th rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x02212; (%)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Neurological sequelae</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">31 (%72.1)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">12 (%27.9)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4 (%50.0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4 (%50.0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">.240</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Epilepsy</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">29 (%67.4)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">14 (%32.6)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4 (%50.0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4 (%50.0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">.430</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Intensive care need</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">33 (%76.7)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">10 (%23.3)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4 (%50.0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4 (%50.0)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">.192</td></tr></tbody></table></alternatives></table-wrap><p>The results of imaging studies were available only for 29 patients. On imaging
studies, there was intraventricular bleeding in 2 (6%), subdural hemorrhage in 6
(20%), subarachnoid hemorrhage in 3 (10.3%), and intraparenchymal hemorrhage in 12
(41.3%) patients.</p><p>Time of presentation, presenting complaint, platelet count and PT, and aPTT values
were extracted from medical records. We failed to access imaging studies in all
patients, since hospital database was replaced with a newer version. Time at first
presentation to hospital was available in 25 patients. It was found that 13 patients
presented to hospital at 15 to 30 days of life, while remaining 12 patients
presented beyond first month of life. The patients were screened for presence of
underlying etiology. No known reason was found in these patients. Presenting
complaint was irritability and difficulty in feeding in 10, convulsion in 9,
fontanel bulging in 2, fadedness in 2, and jaundice in 1 patient.</p></sec><sec sec-type="discussion" id="section8-1076029618792302"><title>Discussion</title><p>There was significant difference in <italic>VKOR1-1639G&#x0003e;A</italic> polymorphism
between patient and control groups. <italic>VKOR1-1639G&#x0003e;A</italic> mutant
positivity was higher in the patient group when compared to controls. The rates of
neurological sequels, epilepsy, and need for ICU care at neonatal period were higher
than anticipated. No significant difference was found in the prognosis between
mutant (heterozygous plus homozygous mutants) and normal group (no
polymorphism).</p><p>Vitamin K deficiency is a major cause of morbidity and mortality at neonatal period.<sup><xref rid="bibr12-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">12</xref></sup> Vitamin K deficiency bleeding is bleeding that occurs due to insufficiency of
vitamin K-dependent coagulation factors and resolves by vitamin K replacement. In
vitamin K-dependent coagulation factor deficiencies, onset and variation in findings
and symptoms are associated with factor levels. Clinical presentation tends to
progress with increased bleeding predisposition in vitamin K deficiencies. The
addition of acquired reasons causing vitamin K deficiency such as drug use
(antibiotics, anticonvulsants, etc), liver failure, or malabsorption may lead more
severe and eventful course of hemorrhage than anticipated. In 2014 in a Turkish
study by Unal et al,<sup><xref rid="bibr1-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> it was suggested that reported VKDB rates didn&#x02019;t reflect true incidence,
resulting underestimation of VKDB incidence. It was reported that the incidence in
Turkey was rather high, and lack of vitamin K prophylaxis in home-based deliveries
or decreased activity of prophylactic vitamin K vials used in some hospitals were
potential causes.<sup><xref rid="bibr1-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> Thus, more comprehensive studies are needed in our country. In Turkey,
vitamin K (1 mg, intramuscular [IM]) is routinely administered at time of delivery.
In recent years, it is hospital-based delivery; thus, vitamin K prophylaxis has been
increased as a result of increased cesarean deliveries. Solely breast-feeding,
chronic diarrhea, or long-term antibiotic use predisposes infants to VKDB. Unal et al<sup><xref rid="bibr1-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> published that the reporting system of the vitamin K prophylaxis is not
solid; and prophylactic vitamin K injections were prepared in syringes, and we
speculate that these previously prepared syringes may be a possible reason of
decreased coverage of VK prophylaxis in Turkey.Therefore, we have reported that
Turkish health-care providers, pediatricians, and the National Ministry of Health
should be aware for the importance of prophylactic measures of VK, especially for
infants born at home in rural areas. American Pediatrics Academy recommends IM
injection of a single dose of vitamin K (0.5 to 1.0 mg) in all newborns. In this
study, we retrospectively analyzed results of neuroimaging studies, blood tests, and
PT and aPTT test performed at neonatal period. In VKDB, it is important to
demonstrate prolonged PT and its normalization following vitamin K injection in
confirming diagnosis.<sup><xref rid="bibr13-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">13</xref></sup> Site of bleeding is one of the most important factors influencing on
prognosis in VKDB. In newborns, bleeding due to vitamin K deficiency occurs in
several sites; however, intracranial hemorrhages are those causing highest
mortality. In previous studies, subdural hemorrhage was reported most frequently on
CT scans. In 2012, Ozdemir et al<sup><xref rid="bibr2-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">2</xref></sup> reported that subdural hemorrhage (28%) was most common intracranial bleeding
followed by intracranial hemorrhage (23%), subarachnoid hemorrhage (14%), and
intraventricular hemorrhage (8%). It was reported that fontanel bulging (70%),
irritability (50%), convulsion (49%), bleeding and ecchymosis (47%), difficulty in
feeding, vomiting, and feeding intolerance (46), diarrhea (34%), jaundice (11%), and
fadedness (9%) were presented as complaints.<sup><xref rid="bibr2-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">2</xref></sup> In our study, rates of subdural hemorrhage, intracranial hemorrhage,
subarachnoid hemorrhage, and intraventricular hemorrhage were 20%, 41.3%, 10.3%, and
6%, respectively. The presenting complaints included irritability and difficulty in
feeding (41.6%), convulsion (37.5%), fontanel bulging (8.3%), fadedness (8.3%), and
jaundice (4.1%) in our study.</p><p>In recent years, after discovery of <italic>VKOR1-1639G&#x0003e;A</italic> involved in VKE
gene system, several studies have been conducted about this gene. Most of these
studies focused on investigation of anticoagulant activity in human. In the study by
Nowak-Gottle et al,<sup><xref rid="bibr14-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">14</xref></sup> it was shown that VKORC polymorphism accounts for dose variation in vitamin K
antagonist anticoagulants. In the study by Schreiner et al,<sup><xref rid="bibr15-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup> it was shown that infants with VKORC 1639A allele are at high risk of
intraventricular hemorrhage. In a rat study by Spohn et al,<sup><xref rid="bibr16-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">16</xref></sup> VKORC homozygous rats which were healthy at birth died mainly due to
intracerebral hemorrhage 2 to 20 days after birth. In our study, VKOR/1639G&#x0003e;A
polymorphism was found to be significantly higher in the patient group than
controls, and there was significant relationship between
<italic>VKOR1-1639G&#x0003e;A</italic> and VKDB.</p><p>Although VKDB is a sporadic phenomenon in developed countries, it has considerable
morbidity and mortality. It is more frequently seen in Turkey when compared to
developed countries, and some studies were conducted to establish its mortality. In
2008, Cekinmez et al<sup><xref rid="bibr17-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">17</xref></sup> reported that there were neurological findings in 21% to 73% of patients with
mortality rate of 19% to 57%. In the literature, in a study by McNinch et al,<sup><xref rid="bibr18-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">18</xref></sup> it was reported that 2 of 10 patients without vitamin K prophylaxis who
received solely breast-feeding died in United Kingdom in 1991. When compared to the
1639 G-A distribution in the normal Turkish population. In our control group, we
found the VKORC genotype as 19 (37.3%) for GG, 19 (37.3%) for GA, and 13 (25.5%) for
AA alleles. Silan et al<sup><xref rid="bibr19-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">19</xref></sup> found that the genotype of VKORC was detected as follows: 64 (21.9%) for GG,
220 (75.4%) for GA, and 8 (2.7%) for AA alleles 55% in the study conducted in
2012.</p><p>The implementation of routine prophylaxis program and lack of new cases due to
paucity of delivery at home in Turkey are major causes for failure to include
preplanned study population of 75 patients. Thus, majority of patients were old
cases in this study. Some patients couldn&#x02019;t be included due to replacement of
hospital database and incomplete data gathered from parents. We think that limited
number of patients precluded showing poorer prognosis in VKOCRC allele carriers than
those without VKORC allele.</p><p>In conclusion, it has proven that VKDB is a cause of significant morbidity and
mortality in previous studies. It was reported that survivors of intracranial
bleeding secondary to VKBD displayed severe psychomotor retardation, cerebral palsy,
hydrocephaly, microcephaly, and convulsions. Given the burden of VKDB which is a
preventable disease with poor prognosis, it is apparent that etiology, prognosis,
and outcomes should have to be established in our country. In this study, we
attempted to demonstrate VKDB and its prognosis in our country. We think that an
additional dose of vitamin K in first months of life will considerably decrease
intracranial bleeding secondary to VKDB in infants receiving breast-feeding solely.<sup><xref rid="bibr20-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">20</xref></sup> We think that the finding of higher rate of <italic>VKOR1-1639G&#x0003e;A</italic>
polymorphism in the patient group will be guiding for future research. Higher
incidence of <italic>VKOR1-1639G&#x0003e;A</italic> polymorphism in our society may imply
additional dose of vitamin K.</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn fn-type="COI-statement" id="fn1-1076029618792302"><p><bold>Declaration of Conflicting Interests:</bold> The author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the
research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</p></fn><fn fn-type="financial-disclosure" id="fn2-1076029618792302"><p><bold>Funding:</bold> The author(s) received no financial support for the research, authorship, and/or
publication of this article.</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="bibr1-1076029618792302"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Unal</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name><surname>Ozsoylu</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Bayram</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Intracranial hemorrhage in infants as a serious,
and preventable consequence of late form of vitamin K deficiency: a selfie
picture of Turkey, strategies for tomorrow</article-title>. <source>Childs
Nerv Syst</source>.
<year>2014</year>;<volume>30</volume>(<issue>8</issue>):<fpage>137582</fpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr2-1076029618792302"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ozdemir</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name><surname>Karakukcu</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Per</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Unal</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name><surname>Gumus</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Patiroglu</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Late-type vitamin K deficiency bleeding:
experience from 120 patients</article-title>. <source>Childs Nerv
Syst</source>.
<year>2012</year>;<volume>28</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>247</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>251</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21928065</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr3-1076029618792302"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Danielsson</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Hoa</surname><given-names>DP</given-names></name><name><surname>Thang</surname><given-names>NV</given-names></name><name><surname>Vos</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Loughnan</surname><given-names>PM</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Intracranial haemorrhage due to late onset
vitamin K deficiency bleeding in Hanoi province, Vietnam</article-title>.
<source>Arch Dis Child Fetal Neonatal Ed</source>.
<year>2004</year>;<volume>89</volume>(<issue>6</issue>):<fpage>F546</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>F550</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15499152</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr4-1076029618792302"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Per</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Kumanda&#x0015f;</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Ozdemir</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name><surname>G&#x000fc;m&#x000fc;&#x0015f;</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Karakukcu</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Intracranial hemorrhage due to late hemorrhagic
disease in two siblings</article-title>. <source>J Emerg Med</source>.
<year>2006</year>;<volume>31</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>49</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>52</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16798155</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr5-1076029618792302"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>CY</given-names></name><name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>DY</given-names></name><name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>PJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Khvorova</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Stafford</surname><given-names>DW</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Identification of the gene for vitamin K epoxide
reductase</article-title>. <source>Nature</source>.
<year>2004</year>;<volume>427</volume>(<issue>6974</issue>):<fpage>541</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>544</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14765195</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr6-1076029618792302"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fregin</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Rost</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Wolz</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name><surname>Krebsova</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Muller</surname><given-names>CR</given-names></name><name><surname>Oldenburg</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Homozygosity mapping of a second gene locus for
hereditary combined deficiency of vitamin K-dependent clotting factors to
the centromeric region of chromosome 16</article-title>.
<source>Blood</source>.
<year>2002</year>;<volume>100</volume>(<issue>9</issue>):<fpage>3229</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3232</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12384421</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr7-1076029618792302"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Oldenburg</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Bevans</surname><given-names>CG</given-names></name><name><surname>Fregin</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Geisen</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>M&#x000fc;ller-Reible</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Watzka</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Current pharmacogenetic developments in oral
anticoagulation therapy: the influence of variant VKORC1 and CYP2C9
alleles</article-title>. <source>Thromb Haemost</source>.
<year>2007</year>;<volume>98</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>570</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>578</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17849045</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr8-1076029618792302"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wadelius</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>LY</given-names></name><name><surname>Downes</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Common VKORC1 and GGCX polymorphisms associated
with warfarin dose</article-title>. <source>Pharmacogenomics J</source>.
<year>2005</year>;<volume>5</volume>(<issue>4</issue>):<fpage>262</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>270</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15883587</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr9-1076029618792302"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Presnell</surname><given-names>SR</given-names></name><name><surname>Stafford</surname><given-names>DW</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>The vitamin K-dependent
carboxylase</article-title>. <source>Thromb Haemost</source>.
<year>2002</year>;<volume>87</volume>(<issue>6</issue>):<fpage>937</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>946</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12083499</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr10-1076029618792302"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Huber</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Schmitz</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Griffin</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Identification of amino acids in the
gamma-carboxylation recognition site on the propeptide of
prothrombin</article-title>. <source>J Biol Chem</source>.
<year>1990</year>;<volume>265</volume>(<issue>21</issue>):<fpage>12467</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>12473</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2373701</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr11-1076029618792302"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zimmermann</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Matschiner</surname><given-names>JT</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Biochemical basis of hereditary resistance to
warfarin in the rat</article-title>. <source>Biochem Pharmacol</source>.
<year>1974</year>;<volume>23</volume>(<issue>6</issue>):<fpage>1033</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1040</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">4824903</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr12-1076029618792302"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Per</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Arslan</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>G&#x000fc;m&#x000fc;&#x0015f;</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Coskun</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Kumanda&#x0015f;</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Intracranial hemorrhages and late hemorrhagic
disease associated cholestatic liver disease</article-title>. <source>Neurol
Sci</source>.
<year>2013</year>;<volume>34</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>51</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>56</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22327309</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr13-1076029618792302"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name><surname>Fukushima</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Meguro</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Intracranial hemorrhage in an infant owing to
vitamin K deficiency despite prophylaxis</article-title>. <source>Childs
Nerv Syst</source>.
<year>1999</year>;<volume>15</volume>(<issue>6-7</issue>):<fpage>292</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>294</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10461777</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr14-1076029618792302"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Nowak-G&#x000f6;ttl</surname><given-names>U</given-names></name><name><surname>Dietrich</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name><surname>Schaffranek</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>In pediatric patients, age has more impact on
dosing of vitamin K antagonists than VKORC1 or CYP2C9
genotypes</article-title>. <source>Blood</source>.
<year>2010</year>;<volume>116</volume>(<issue>26</issue>):<fpage>6101</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>6105</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20833980</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr15-1076029618792302"><label>15</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Schreiner</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Suter</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Watzka</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Genetic variants of the vitamin K dependent
coagulation system and intraventricular hemorrhage in preterm
infants</article-title>. <source>BMC Pediatr</source>.
<year>2014</year>;<volume>14</volume>:<fpage>219</fpage>
<comment>doi:10.1186/1471-2431-14-219</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25179312</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr16-1076029618792302"><label>16</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Spohn</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Kleinridders</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Wunderlich</surname><given-names>FT</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>VKORC1 deficiency in mice causes early postnatal
lethality due to severe bleeding</article-title>. <source>Thromb
Haemost</source>.
<year>2009</year>;<volume>101</volume>(<issue>6</issue>):<fpage>1044</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1050</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19492146</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr17-1076029618792302"><label>17</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Cekinmez</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Cemil</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Cekinmez</surname><given-names>EK</given-names></name><name><surname>Altin&#x000f6;rs</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Intracranial hemorrhages due to late-type
vitamin K deficiency bleeding</article-title>. <source>Childs Nerv
Syst</source>.
<year>2008</year>;<volume>24</volume>(<issue>7</issue>):<fpage>821</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>825</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18046559</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr18-1076029618792302"><label>18</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McNinch</surname><given-names>AW</given-names></name><name><surname>Tripp</surname><given-names>JH</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Haemorrhagic disease of the newborn in the
British Isles: two year prospective study</article-title>.
<source>BMJ</source>.
<year>1991</year>;<volume>303</volume>(<issue>6810</issue>):<fpage>1105</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1109</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1747578</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr19-1076029618792302"><label>19</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Silan</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Dogan</surname><given-names>OT</given-names></name><name><surname>Silan</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>The prevalence of VKORC1 1639 G&#x0003e;A and
CYP2C9*2*3 genotypes in patients that requiring anticoagulant therapy in
Turkish population</article-title>. <source>Mol Biol Rep</source>.
<year>2012</year>;<volume>39</volume>(<issue>12</issue>):<fpage>11017</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>11022</lpage>.
<comment>doi:10.1007/s11033-012-2004-2</comment>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23065265</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="bibr20-1076029618792302"><label>20</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Van Hasselt</surname><given-names>PM</given-names></name><name><surname>de Koning</surname><given-names>TJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Kvist</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Prevention of vitamin K deficiency bleeding in
breastfed infants: lessons from the Dutch and Danish biliary atresia
registries</article-title>. <source>Pediatrics</source>.
<year>2008</year>;<volume>121</volume>(<issue>4</issue>):<fpage>e857</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>e863</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18381514</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>