<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A notable finding in this study was the very low incidence of aGvHD that occurred in the lower GI tract. Specifically, there were no cases within the first 100 days, and only one case which occurred by day 180. Pre-clinical studies have shown that IL-6 messenger ribonucleic acid (mRNA) levels are significantly increased in the colons of mice,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b7-1030717" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>
 </sup> and the blockade of the IL-6 signaling pathway is able to significantly reduce the severity of GvHD in this tissue site.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b7-1030717" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
  <xref rid="b8-1030717" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>
 </sup> IL-6 has also been identified as a plasma biomarker that predicts for severity and non-relapse mortality in patients with GI GvHD.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b31-1030717" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>
 </sup> Our findings further support the premise that IL-6 plays an important role in mediating tissue damage in the lower GI tract. Given that the incidence of liver GvHD has been declining over time,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b32-1030717" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>
 </sup> involvement of the GI tract has emerged as the primary driver of morbidity and mortality in patients with this disease. In fact, the development of lower GI tract GvHD carries significant prognostic implications for OS. Patients with lower tract GvHD are more likely to be steroid-resistant,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b33-1030717" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>
 </sup> which itself is associated with increased mortality.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b34-1030717" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>
 </sup> Furthermore, patients with higher clinical and histological grades of lower GI tract GvHD have an increase in non-relapse mortality that results in reduced OS.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b35-1030717" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>,
  <xref rid="b36-1030717" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>
 </sup> Thus, given the poor prognosis associated with severe GI GvHD,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b37-1030717" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>,
  <xref rid="b38-1030717" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>
 </sup> therapeutic strategies that are focused on preventing the development of this complication have the potential to impact the overall course of this disease and improve transplant outcome. While we observed patients with upper GI tract GvHD, recent studies have shown that disease in this tissue site is generally responsive to modest doses of steroids, and does not impact OS.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b39-1030717" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>,
  <xref rid="b40-1030717" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
