<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>We observed that IL-6 was the only measured serum cytokine that was significantly increased above baseline in a control population of patients that received Tac and MTX but not Toc. The administration of Toc resulted in much higher serum IL-6 levels, above that seen in the control population, in recipients of both MA and RIC regimens. This was likely due to decreased consumption of IL-6 when Toc binds to the IL-6R. IL-6 signaling occurs through two distinct mechanisms; IL-6 can bind to a membrane receptor that is expressed on hematopoietic cells and hepatocytes,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b41-1030717" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>
 </sup> and also bind to a soluble form of the IL-6 receptor, which can in turn bind to glycoprotein (gp)130, which is ubiquitously expressed on most cells.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b42-1030717" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>,
  <xref rid="b43-1030717" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>
 </sup> As further support for this premise, we observed that sIL-6R levels were also significantly augmented in patients who received both MA and RIC regimens. Of note, the immunoassay used to detect sIL-6R levels captures free sIL-6R, IL-6R bound to IL-6, and IL-6R bound to Toc.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b44-1030717" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>
 </sup> Therefore, we cannot distinguish the composition of the sIL-6R complex, but it is likely that a significant component is attributable to the binding of Toc to IL-6R, given that a prior study showed that Toc can be detected for up to one month in allogeneic stem cell transplant recipients.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b18-1030717" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>
 </sup> This would therefore also explain the high IL-6 levels in these patients, as free IL-6 may have been precluded from binding to the Toc/sIL-6R complex. The fact that IL-6 levels were higher in patients treated with MA 
 <italic>versus</italic> RIC, however, suggests that the conditioning regimen itself also contributed to the increase in IL-6 levels. Notably, we did not observe meaningful increases in any of the other cytokines that we examined (i.e., IL-2, IL-4, IL-10, TNF-α, IFN-γ and IL-17) in control or Toc-treated patients, providing evidence that dysregulation of IL-6 is an important early event post-transplantation. Toc had no discernible adverse effect on immune reconstitution, as patients achieved near normal T-cell and B-cell subset numbers by 6-12 months post-transplantation.
</p>
