<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="protocol"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Publishing DTD v1.1 20151215//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName JATS-journalpublishing1.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 1.1?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName jp2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">BMJ Open</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">BMJ Open</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="hwp">bmjopen</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">bmjopen</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>BMJ Open</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2044-6055</issn><publisher><publisher-name>BMJ Publishing Group</publisher-name><publisher-loc>BMA House, Tavistock Square, London, WC1H 9JR</publisher-loc></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6224728</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">bmjopen-2018-021993</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2018-021993</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Oncology</subject><subj-group><subject>Protocol</subject></subj-group></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="hwp-journal-coll"><subject>1506</subject><subject>1717</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Protocol for a randomised controlled trial to study cryoprevention of chemotherapy-induced oral mucositis after autologous stem cell transplantation</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib id="author-60470733" contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">http://orcid.org/0000-0001-5660-1348</contrib-id><name><surname>Walladbegi</surname><given-names>Java</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib id="author-60476450" contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Svanberg</surname><given-names>Anncarin</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib id="author-41861057" contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Gellerstedt</surname><given-names>Martin</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3">3</xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff1">
<label>1</label>
<institution content-type="department">Department of Oral Medicine and Pathology</institution>, <institution>Institute of Odontology, The Sahlgrenska Academy, University of Gothenburg</institution>, <addr-line content-type="city">Gothenburg</addr-line>, <country>Sweden</country>
</aff><aff id="aff2">
<label>2</label>
<institution content-type="department">Department of Hematology, Faculty of Medicine</institution>, <institution>Institute for Medical Sciences, Uppsala University Hospital</institution>, <addr-line content-type="city">Uppsala</addr-line>, <country>Sweden</country>
</aff><aff id="aff3">
<label>3</label>
<institution content-type="department">School of Business, Economics and IT</institution>, <institution>University West</institution>, <addr-line content-type="city">Trollh&#x000e4;ttan</addr-line>, <country>Sweden</country>
</aff><author-notes><corresp><label>Correspondence to</label> Dr Anncarin Svanberg; <email>anncarin.svanberg@medsci.uu.se</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2018</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>24</day><month>10</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><volume>8</volume><issue>10</issue><elocation-id>e021993</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>01</day><month>2</month><year>2018</year></date><date date-type="rev-recd"><day>02</day><month>5</month><year>2018</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>15</day><month>6</month><year>2018</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; Author(s) (or their employer(s)) 2018. Re-use permitted under CC BY-NC. No commercial re-use. See rights and permissions. Published by BMJ.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2019</copyright-year><license license-type="open-access"><license-p>This is an open access article distributed in accordance with the Creative Commons Attribution Non Commercial (CC BY-NC 4.0) license, which permits others to distribute, remix, adapt, build upon this work non-commercially, and license their derivative works on different terms, provided the original work is properly cited, appropriate credit is given, any changes made indicated, and the use is non-commercial. See: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xlink:title="pdf" xlink:href="bmjopen-2018-021993.pdf"/><self-uri content-type="reviewers-comments-pdf" xlink:href="bmjopen-2018-021993.reviewer_comments.pdf"/><self-uri content-type="draft-revisions-pdf" xlink:href="bmjopen-2018-021993.draft_revisions.pdf"/><abstract><sec><title>Introduction</title><p>A majority of patients who receive myeloablative therapy prior to hematopoetic stem cell transplantation develop oral mucositis (OM). This adverse cytotoxic effect manifests as oral mucosal erythema and ulcerations and frequently necessitates high doses of morphine for pain alleviation. OM may also interfere with food intake and result in parenteral nutrition, weight loss and impaired quality of life. To date, there have been a few studies of evidence-based interventions for prevention of OM. Cooling the oral mucosa using ice chips in conjunction with chemotherapy is known to reduce the severity of OM although clinical application is still limited due to several disadvantages. The primary endpoint of this study is therefore to evaluate the efficacy of an innovative intraoral cooling device (Cooral) compared with ice cooling in reducing the degree of OM, in patients with myeloma or lymphoma.</p></sec><sec><title>Method and analysis</title><p>A total of 180 patients from four different university hospitals in Sweden will be randomised to ice or Cooral in a proportion of 1:1. The degree of OM will be assessed at eight intraoral locations, in accordance with the Oral Mucositis Assessment Scale and WHO scale. Patients will be registered beginning at admission and will continue until discharge or until day +28. The primary variable is analysed in a multiple linear regression model. The significance level used is 5%.</p></sec><sec><title>Ethics and dissemination</title><p>The study protocol, questionnaire, diaries and letter of invitation to participants have been reviewed by the local ethical board in G&#x000f6;teborg. The trial results will be published in a peer-reviewed journal and disseminated to participants.</p></sec><sec><title>Trial registration number</title><p><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="NCT03203733" specific-use="clinicaltrial pre-results">NCT03203733</ext-link>; Pre-results.</p></sec><sec><title>Protocol version</title><p>Version 4, 2017-06-05</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group><kwd>chemotherapy</kwd><kwd>myeloma</kwd><kwd>lymphoma</kwd><kwd>bone marrow transplantation</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group id="funding-1"><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="FundRef">http://dx.doi.org/10.13039/501100001858</institution-id><institution>VINNOVA</institution></institution-wrap></funding-source></award-group><award-group id="funding-2"><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="FundRef">http://dx.doi.org/10.13039/501100005293</institution-id><institution>G&#x000f6;teborgs Tandl&#x000e4;kare-S&#x000e4;llskap</institution></institution-wrap></funding-source></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>special-feature</meta-name><meta-value>unlocked</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><boxed-text id="BX1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><title>Strengths and limitations of the study</title></caption><list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p>Prospective randomised multicentre study with 180 patients evaluating the efficacy and tolerability of two cooling methods.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Blinded assessment of oral&#x000a0;mucositis by dentists specialised in orofacial medicine and pathology.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Longitudinal study lacking an untreated control group.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Patients younger than 16 years of age are not included in this study.</p></list-item></list></boxed-text><sec id="s1"><title>Introduction</title><sec id="s1a"><title>Background and rationale</title><p>Hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (HSCT) is successfully used for a number of malignant blood diseases. In autologous stem cell transplantation (ASCT), the patient&#x02019;s own blood stem cells are used in order to preserve bone marrow function after administration of high doses of cytostatics.</p><p>Chemotherapy has many side effects, one of which is oral mucositis (OM). OM is a lesion which involves the mucous membrane of&#x000a0;the oral cavity and affects&#x000a0;up to 80% of patients who receive high doses of cytostatics in preparation for HSCT.<xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1 2</xref> The lesion of the oral mucosa manifests itself as painful&#x000a0;erythema and&#x000a0;ulcerations <xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref> and may require high doses of morphine for pain alleviation.<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref> Furthermore, OM may interfere with food intake, which can lead to undernourishment, weight loss and impaired quality of life.<xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>
</p><p>Today, there are few treatment methods intended to prevent OM. An extensive literature search shows that the best-documented preventive method is cooling of the oral mucous membrane with ice, before, during and after chemotherapy.<xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>
</p><p>Despite well-substantiated documentation, there is limited use of ice cooling as a method to prevent&#x000a0;OM in clinical practice. As ice can give rise to shooting pains in the teeth and other discomfort for the patient, this may lead to lower cooperation. In addition, it is important that the ice is made from water of good quality to minimise the risk of infections.</p><p>To prevent OM, an intraoral cooling device (Cooral) has been developed.<xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref> Cooral consists of closed conduits&#x000a0;with continuously circulating water, to cool the cheeks, lips, floor&#x000a0;of the&#x000a0;mouth, tongue gums and hard palate. By offering Cooral, we intend to prevent&#x000a0;OM.</p><p>Therefore it&#x02019;s of interest to conduct a randomised controlled study to evaluate Cooral for prevention of OM.</p></sec><sec id="s1b"><title>Specific objectives or hypotheses</title><p>The objectives are to compare Cooral and ice cooling with&#x000a0;regards to&#x000a0;efficacy and tolerability.</p></sec><sec id="s1c"><title>Trial design</title><p>An open randomised controlled trial with blinded evaluation of OM.</p></sec></sec><sec id="s2"><title>Methods: participants, interventions and outcomes</title><sec id="s2a"><title>Study setting</title><p>Patients with myeloma or lymphoma at Karolinska University&#x000a0;Hospital (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1 F2">figures 1 and 2</xref>), and&#x000a0;Uppsala University Hospital (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3 F4">figures 3 and 4</xref>), and patients with myeloma at the University Hospitals in Link&#x000f6;ping and &#x000d6;rebro (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">figure 3</xref>) who are to undergo ASCT will be asked to participate in the study.</p><fig id="F1" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>Flowchart for patients with myeloma at Karolinska University Hospital. Day 0: admission, chemotherapy conditioning, oral mucosal cooling along with completion of quality of life (QoL) questionnaire (FACT-G) and evaluation of cooling method. Day 1: autologous stem cell transplantation (ASCT). Follow-up (green box) and perception of oral problems using a diary begins at admission and continues until discharge or day +28. QoL (FACT-G) is evaluated again at discharge. CRP, C reactive protein; NRS, Numeric Pain Rating Scale; OM, oral mucositis; OMAS, Oral Mucositis Assessment Scale; WBC, white blood cell.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="bmjopen-2018-021993f01"/></fig><fig id="F2" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>Flowchart for patients with lymphoma at Karolinska University Hospital. Day &#x02212;1: admission, along with completion of quality of life (QoL) questionnaire (FACT-G). Day &#x02212;1 to 4: chemotherapy conditioning, oral mucosal cooling along with completion of evaluation of cooling method. Day 5: recovery. Day 6: autologous stem cell transplantation (ASCT). Follow-up (green box) and perception of oral problems using a diary begins at admission and continues until discharge or day +28. QoL (FACT-G) is evaluated again at discharge. Days highlighted in black indicates the timescale used in this study while grey is routinely used at the hospital. CRP, C reactive protein; NRS, Numeric Pain Rating Scale; OM, oral mucositis; OMAS, Oral Mucositis Assessment Scale; WBC, white blood cell.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="bmjopen-2018-021993f02"/></fig><fig id="F3" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>Flowchart for patients with myeloma at Uppsala University Hospital and University Hospitals in Link&#x000f6;ping and &#x000d6;rebro.&#x000a0;Day &#x02013;1: admission. Day 0: chemotherapy conditioning, oral mucosal cooling along with completion of quality of life (QoL) questionnaire (FACT-G) and evaluation of cooling method. Day 1: autologous stem cell transplantation (ASCT). Follow-up (green box) and perception of oral problems using a diary begins at admission and continues until discharge or day&#x000a0;+28. QoL (FACT-G) is evaluated again at discharge.&#x000a0;CRP, C reactive protein; NRS, Numeric Pain Rating Scale; OM, oral mucositis; OMAS, Oral Mucositis Assessment Scale; WBC, white blood cell.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="bmjopen-2018-021993f03"/></fig><fig id="F4" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>Flowchart for patients with lymphoma at Uppsala University Hospital.&#x000a0;Day &#x02212;1: admission, along with completion of quality of life (QoL) questionnaire (FACT-G). Day 0 to 4:&#x000a0;chemotherapy conditioning, oral mucosal cooling along with completion of evaluation of cooling method. Day 5: recovery. Day 6: autologous stem cell transplantation (ASCT). Follow-up (green box) and perception of oral problems using a diary begins at admission and continues until discharge or day&#x000a0;+28. QoL (FACT-G) is evaluated again at discharge. Days highlighted in black indicates the timescale used in this study while grey is routinely used at the hospital.&#x000a0;CRP, C reactive protein; NRS, Numeric Pain Rating Scale; OM, oral mucositis; OMAS, Oral Mucositis Assessment Scale; WBC, white blood cell.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="bmjopen-2018-021993f04"/></fig></sec><sec id="s2b"><title>Eligibility criteria</title><sec id="s2b1"><title>Inclusion criteria</title><list list-type="order"><list-item><p>Patients aged 16 or over diagnosed with myeloma or lymphoma.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Able to communicate in Swedish.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Treated with melphalan (myeloma), BEAM/BEAC (lymphoma), before ASCT.</p></list-item></list></sec><sec id="s2b2"><title>Exclusion criteria</title><list list-type="order"><list-item><p>Patients who do not understand oral and written information in Swedish.</p></list-item><list-item><p>The patient is taking part in another study which, in the doctor&#x02019;s judgement, can affect the result of this study.</p></list-item><list-item><p>The patient is receiving post-treatment care at a different hospital than where the stem cell transplant took place and follow-up is not possible.</p></list-item><list-item><p>The doctor judges that the patient is for some reason not suitable for the study.</p></list-item></list></sec></sec><sec id="s2c"><title>Interventions</title><sec id="s2c1"><title>Ice</title><p>Patients will be provided with ice cubes/crushed ice or ice pop 30&#x02009;min prior to the start of chemotherapy. Once&#x000a0;the ice melts, the liquid is rinsed around the mouth to cool as large surface as possible of the oral mucosa. In addition, to achieve cooling of the hindmost part of the throat, the liquid is gurgled for a few seconds before it is swallowed or spat out. The procedure is repeated until&#x000a0;30 min after the termination of the cytostatic infusion. During treatment the patient may if necessary rest for a maximum of 5 min.&#x000a0;Food and drink should, whenever possible, be consumed either before or after the cooling&#x000a0;session. Cooling continues throughout conditioning with cytostatics in the treatment schema melphalan (myeloma) and BEAM/BEAC (lymphoma). In lymphoma conditioning cures with a 12-hour infusion time (e.g., cytarabine), the cooling starts initially 30&#x02009;min prior to&#x000a0;the start of cytostatic treatment and continues 30&#x02009;min after the start of the&#x000a0;12-hour cytostatic infusion.&#x000a0;Then the patient is provided with ice cubes/crushed ice or ice pop for 30&#x02009;min every 4&#x02009;hours during the infusion. It is important to end with 30&#x02009;min cooling of the oral mucous membrane after each completed cytostatic administration.</p></sec></sec><sec id="s2d"><title>Cooral</title><p>Prior to treatment, the patient receives clear oral instructions and a demonstration&#x000a0;on the use of Cooral by the nurse responsible for the patient. When the patient him/herself is able to administer the intraoral component until it feels comfortable,&#x000a0;the responsible nurse will&#x000a0;check to ensure that it has good contact with the oral mucous membrane. Cooling begins 30&#x02009;min before the start of chemotherapy and continues until&#x000a0;30 min after the termination of the cytostatic infusion.&#x000a0;During treatment, the patient may if necessary take out the component, for a maximum of 5 &#x02009;min, and&#x000a0;replace it again.&#x000a0;Food&#x000a0;and drink should, whenever&#x000a0;possible, be consumed either&#x000a0;before or after the cooling&#x000a0;session. Cooling continues throughout conditioning with cytostatics in the treatment schema melphalan (myeloma) and BEAM/BEAC (lymphoma).&#x000a0;In lymphoma conditioning cures with a 12-hour infusion time (e.g., cytarabine), the cooling starts initially 30&#x02009;min before the start of cytostatic treatment and continues 30&#x02009;min after the start of the&#x000a0;12-hour cytostatic infusion. Then the patient is provided with Cooral for 30&#x02009;min every 4&#x02009;hours during the infusion. It is important to end with 30&#x02009;min cooling of the oral mucous membrane after each completed cytostatic administration.</p></sec><sec id="s2e"><title>Outcomes</title><p>The primary objective is to study patients with myeloma or lymphoma undergoing ASCT, to evaluate whether cooling with Cooral compared with ice cubes/crushed ice or ice pop succeeds in reducing the degree of OM according to the Oral Mucositis Assessment Scale (OMAS total).</p><p>The secondary objectives are to evaluate OMAS total divided according to OMAS ulceration, OMAS erythema, degree of OM according to WHO, tolerability of either cooling method, subjective experience of OM, rating of general quality of life and oral pain, number of days with total parenteral nutrition (TPN), number of hospital days, total dose of opioids and C reactive protein (CRP) during time in care.</p><p>The tertiary objectives are to evaluate weight loss, leucocyte plasma concentration&#x000a0;(LPC), number of days until bone marrow response, S-albumin and body temperature.</p></sec><sec id="s2f"><title>Participant timeline</title><p>Total cooling time for myeloma&#x000a0;1.5&#x02009;hours and lymphoma 3&#x02013;6&#x02009;hours. All patients are followed beginning at admission and will continue until discharge or until day&#x000a0;+28.</p></sec><sec id="s2g"><title>Sample size</title><p>A sample size of 90 patients per group will give a power of 80% to discover an average difference of at least 0.42 OMAS units.<xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref> The analysis is based on the SD for OMAS being 1 in both groups, and the use of an independent t-test with a significance level of 5%.</p></sec><sec id="s2h"><title>Recruitment</title><p>All patients with myeloma or lymphoma at Karolinska University Hospital and&#x000a0;Uppsala University Hospital, and patients with myeloma at the University Hospitals in Link&#x000f6;ping and &#x000d6;rebro who are to undergo ASCT will be asked to participate in the study. Information&#x000a0;will be given at the time of stem cell apheresis and in material sent to the patient in connection with the invitation letter, with information about admission to the ward for ASCT. Inclusion in the study will take place after written consent on arrival at the ward to be admitted for ASCT. For underage patients (16&#x02013;17 years), parents will also be informed and asked if they consent to their children&#x02019;s participation. Estimated time for inclusion is approximately 1.5 years starting from 12<sup>th</sup> June 2017.</p><p>A total of 180 patients will be recruited and randomised to ice or Cooral in a proportion of 1:1. Expected number of patients: from Karolinska University Hospital (70),&#x000a0;Uppsala University Hospital (80), Link&#x000f6;ping University Hospital (15) and &#x000d6;rebro University Hospital (15).</p></sec><sec id="s2i"><title>Patient and public involvement</title><p>Comparison of the balance between efficacy and safety for Cooral and ice in the prevention of OM is in the best interest of patients. Patients were not involved in the design of this study or in the recruitment or conduct of the study. The study results will be disseminated to study participants orally and in writing. The burden of the interventions will be assessed by the patients themselves. No patient advisers were involved in the design or conduct of the study.</p></sec></sec><sec id="s3"><title>Methods: assignment of interventions</title><sec id="s3a"><title>Sequence generation</title><p>Randomisation will be managed centrally by the study administration in connection with admission to treatment. Each hospital will be given randomisation lists to follow. Randomisation will be stratified with regard to department and diagnosis.</p></sec><sec id="s3b"><title>Allocation concealment mechanism</title><p>The patients will undergo balanced randomisation with randomly varying block sizes (two, four or six patients) where one, two or three experiments are distributed in sequences and one, two or three controls. A block can be, for example,&#x000a0;&#x02018;ce&#x02019; if there are two patients,&#x000a0;and &#x02018;ceec&#x02019; and&#x000a0;&#x02018;eeccec&#x02019; if there are four or six patients, respectively. Each hospital is blinded to the size of the blocks.</p></sec><sec id="s3c"><title>Implementation</title><p>Participants will be assigned by the responsible healthcare providers.</p></sec><sec id="s3d"><title>Blinding (masking)</title><p>The dental staff in charge of assessing OM and the statistician will be blinded to the interventions.</p><p>Data collection, management and analysis will be done by Karolinska Trial Alliance (KTA) and Uppsala Clinical Research (UCR), two independent contract research organisations.</p></sec></sec><sec id="s4"><title>Methods: data collection, management&#x000a0;and analysis</title><sec id="s4a"><title>Data collection methods</title><p>All measurements, with the exception of the patient&#x02019;s subjective assessment of the cooling method, will be registered beginning at admission and will continue until discharge or until day&#x000a0;+28. Cytostatic infusion generally starts on the day after admission. Grading of OM according to OMAS and WHO is done three times a week, for example, Monday, Wednesday&#x000a0;and Friday, by a dentist/dental hygienist. For each day the patient is hospitalised, assessment with WHO is also performed by nurses/assistant nurses who are not blinded to the treatment group. Clinical routines differ between study centres and therefore the number of assessments can be lower during the week of admission, depending on when patients are admitted.</p><p>The degree of OM is assessed at eight intraoral locations, in accordance with the OMAS (graded 0&#x02013;3 for ulceration and 0&#x02013;2 for erythema). Zero corresponds to &#x02018;normal&#x02019; while 3 and 2 are &#x02018;sore&#x000a0;&#x0003e;3&#x02009;cm<sup>2</sup>&#x02019; and &#x02018;severe erythema&#x02019;, respectively. The assessment generates both an average for OMAS ulceration (0&#x02013;3) and OMAS erythema (0&#x02013;2) and a total average OMAS (0&#x02013;5), which is the mean of both ulceration and erythema.</p><p>Besides OMAS, ulceration and erythema are also assessed with the WHO scale (graded 0&#x02013;4) where 0 is &#x02018;no mucositis&#x02019; and 4 is &#x02018;ulceration, total parenteral nutrition&#x02019;.</p><p>Prior to myeloablative therapy, all patients at each of the four study sites undergo a complete oral/dental examination by a dentist specialised in orofacial medicine and pathology followed by an odontological decontamination. Meticulous information and instructions for oral hygiene maintenance is also received. Patients who develop OM are initially treated with paracetamol or opioids, depending on degree of symptoms, and further assisted by healthcare professionals to maintain a good oral hygiene. In more severe cases, a dentist or a dental hygienist is contacted for assistance and further support with oral care maintenance.</p><p>The dental staff responsible for OM assessment were calibrated prior to study start. ICC coefficient: OMAS=0.94 (excellent); WHO=0.67 (good). Following inclusion of 100 patients a second ICC will be performed to assess inter- and intra-rater reliability.&#x000a0;All other staff involved in the study have undergone a solid education in assessing oral health status according to WHO.</p><p>Rating of pain is done with the Numeric Pain Rating Scale (NRS) one to two times daily if the patient is kept on the ward. Alternatively, it is done every other day according to the respective department&#x02019;s routine for outpatient care if the patient is at home or in a home-like environment. In the case of outpatients, the subjective rating of pain is noted in the patient documentation through daily telephone contact with the responsible nurse. Body temperature is registered in the oral cavity, ear or axillary region in accordance with the department&#x02019;s routines.</p><p>Furthermore, the patients, after cooling ends, assess the tolerability of the respective cooling method with the aid of a questionnaire (online <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SP1">supplementary file 1</xref>) developed for the study. The questionnaire is intended to give some idea of any discomfort or side effects the patients feel as a result of the cooling method.</p><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="SP1"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2018-021993.supp1</object-id><label>Supplementary file 1</label><p><inline-supplementary-material id="ss1" xlink:href="bmjopen-2018-021993supp001.pdf" mimetype="application" mime-subtype="pdf" content-type="local-data"/>
</p></supplementary-material><p>The patients assess their perception of oral problems daily with the aid of specific questions in a diary (online <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SP2">supplementary file 2</xref>) developed for the study. The questions are intended to give a picture of the effect of OM on the patient&#x02019;s general status.</p><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="SP2"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2018-021993.supp2</object-id><label>Supplementary file 2</label><p><inline-supplementary-material id="ss2" xlink:href="bmjopen-2018-021993supp002.pdf" mimetype="application" mime-subtype="pdf" content-type="local-data"/>
</p></supplementary-material><p>General quality of life is assessed twice during the study period, before the start of treatment and at discharge, with a validated quality of life instrument (online <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SP3">supplementary file 3</xref>).</p><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="SP3"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2018-021993.supp3</object-id><label>Supplementary file 3</label><p><inline-supplementary-material id="ss3" xlink:href="bmjopen-2018-021993supp003.pdf" mimetype="application" mime-subtype="pdf" content-type="local-data"/>
</p></supplementary-material><p>Information about TPN, number of hospital days, total dose of opioids, weight loss and body temperature will be retrieved from patient records. Laboratory results of blood tests will be retrieved from each department&#x02019;s register of test results.</p><p>The result of the assessments is documented on special CRF (case report forms) for the purpose, referred to in the study as &#x02018;checklists&#x02019;.</p></sec><sec id="s4b"><title>Participant retention</title><p>Complete follow-up of patients who discontinue cooling prematurely or otherwise deviate from the intervention protocol.</p></sec><sec id="s4c"><title>Data management</title><p>Data will be collected on paper-based checklist created by the&#x000a0;sponsor. Each checklist will be identified by a pre-printed trial number and a combination of patient study number (assigned at registration). The investigator or an authorised staff member will complete the checklist on site. The checklist must be dated and signed by the investigator on completion.</p><p>The PheedIt&#x000a0;system will be used for data capture of clinical data and this will serve as the clinical database for the study. UCR will be responsible for set-up of the clinical database, support, programming of logical computerised checks, data management plan and management of the PheedIt system. Data from the checklist will be entered, cleaned and validated by the sponsor-appointed person. This appointed person should have signed a secrecy agreement with each study site and have the task delegated to enter/edit data into the database. The completed patient questionnaires (online <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SP1 SP2 SP3">supplementary files 1&#x02013;3</xref>) will also be entered into the clinical database by the sponsor-appointed person. The entered data will be subject to logical computerised checks, and the output from these checks will be sent to the sponsor-appointed person for review and action. Actions to be taken by study staff as a result of the review of the check output should be documented, for example, on a data clarification form (DCF). The DCF must be signed and dated by the investigator, thereafter the clinical database can be updated. Any corrections made to entered data will be audited.</p><p>The original checklists and questionnaires are source data and will be kept on site. Copies of the checklists and questionnaires will be collected by the sponsor-appointed person.</p></sec><sec id="s4d"><title>Statistical methods</title><p>All analyses are at population level: intention to treat.</p><sec id="s4d1"><title>Analysis of the primary variable</title><p>The primary endpoint is peak OMAS (total), that is, the highest measured OMAS total during the time in care. The primary variable is studied in a multiple linear regression model. Fixed explanatory variables are treatment group, type of cancer and centre. An initial model also includes interaction between treatment and type of cancer and interaction between treatment and centre. If the interaction effects are not significant, these are excluded from the final model. The significance level used is 5%.</p></sec><sec id="s4d2"><title>Analyses of the secondary variables</title><p>OMAS ulceration and OMAS erythema indices, analysed in the same way as peak OMAS (total), that is, peak value, is used as a target variable in a multiple regression model. The same explanatory variables are used as in the final model for peak OMAS (total).</p><p>Incidence of OM (grades 1&#x02013;4 according to WHO) and incidence of severe OM (grades 3&#x02013;4 according to WHO) are analysed with the aid of logistic regression with the same explanatory variables as in the final model for peak OMAS (total). Significance level is&#x000a0;5%.</p><p>Tolerability. Incidence of problems (grades 1&#x02013;3) and severe problems (grades 4&#x02013;7) are analysed in the same way as the incidence of OM and severe OM. Significance level is&#x000a0;5%.</p><p>Subjective ratings of OM, general quality of life and oral pain are analysed non-parametrically, above all with the help of Mann-Whitney U test.</p><p>Quantitative data such as number of days with TPN, number of hospital days, total dose of opioids and CRP are analysed with independent t-test or with Mann-Whitney U test if the observed data material shows a significant skew. Descriptive statistics and explorative analysis will be used to study any differences between centres.</p></sec><sec id="s4d3"><title>Analysis of the tertiary variables</title><p>Weight loss, LPC, number of days until bone marrow response, S-albumin and body temperature are analysed with independent t-test or with Mann-Whitney U test if the observed data material shows a significant skew. Descriptive statistics and explorative analysis will be used to study any differences between centres.</p></sec><sec id="s4d4"><title>Additional analyses</title><p>Separate analyses will be conducted with regard to study site and with regard to diagnosis (myeloma/lymphoma).</p></sec></sec><sec id="s4e"><title>Missing data</title><p>OMAS (total) and WHO performed by dentists/dental hygienist after treatment are replaced with WHO performed by nurses. WHO replacing OMAS (total) will be translated into OMAS (total).<xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref> In the final analysis, the dentist assessment is primarily used. For OMAS subindex, the highest value is used as the peak OMAS subindex if at least one OMAS subindex is available after treatment. If there is no OMAS subindex after treatment, the patient&#x02019;s baseline is used as peak OMAS subindex.</p><p>For other secondary/tertiary variables, the strategy is to use the mean value of the preceding and following value. If the preceding value is missing, the following value is used. If the following value is missing, the technique used is last value carried forward.</p></sec></sec><sec id="s5"><title>Methods: monitoring</title><sec id="s5a"><title>Data monitoring</title><p>To protect the patients&#x02019; safety during the trial, the results will be monitored by a Data Monitoring Committee (DMC), consisting of an experienced biostatistician and a clinician with long experience of clinical trials. Both are independent of the sponsor and will provide an impartial recommendation for the continuation of the study. Separate working instructions will be provided as a &#x02018;charter&#x02019; to the DMC. A conservative stopping rule according to the O&#x02019;Brien-Fleming boundary will be applied to minimise the effect of the interim analysis on the statistical strength at the end of the trial.</p></sec><sec id="s5b"><title>Interim analysis</title><p>The DMC will have two members, an experienced biostatistician and a clinician with considerable experience of clinical trials. The CRO will provide the DMC with a first interim analysis when 100 patients have been treated. Based on the results, the DMC will recommend the sponsor to continue or terminate the trial without communicating any results. The DMC will decide about further interim analyses. Before the DMC recommends early termination of the trial, it will try to get advice from the Food and Drug Administration.</p></sec><sec id="s5c"><title>Harms</title><p>Adverse events related to the Cooral/ice treatment sessions will be assessed by the questions addressed in the patients&#x02019; questionnaires&#x000a0;&#x02018;Cooral cooling&#x02019;, &#x02018;Cooling with ice/crushed ice/ice pop&#x02019;. The adverse events will be summarised and included in the final rapport of the clinical study. Serious adverse events that are related to the Cooral/ice treatment sessions will be reported to all sites and principal investigators will be informed/updated. Any errors of the medical device will be documented and taken care of/repaired by the sponsor.</p></sec><sec id="s5d"><title>Auditing</title><p>The study will be monitored by KTA to ensure that it is carried out in accordance with the established study protocol, Helsinki declaration, ISO14155:2011 and other applicable guidelines and regulations. A monitoring plan has been established.</p></sec></sec><sec id="s6"><title>Ethics and dissemination</title><sec id="s6a"><title>Protocol amendments</title><p>Important protocol modifications will be communicated by KTA to investigators, trial participants, trial registries, review board, journals and regulators.</p></sec><sec id="s6b"><title>Consent or assent</title><p>Written informed consent (online <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SP4">supplementary file 4</xref>) will be obtained from all patients included in the study.</p><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="SP4"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2018-021993.supp4</object-id><label>Supplementary file 4</label><p><inline-supplementary-material id="ss4" xlink:href="bmjopen-2018-021993supp004.pdf" mimetype="application" mime-subtype="pdf" content-type="local-data"/>
</p></supplementary-material></sec><sec id="s6c"><title>Confidentiality</title><p>Patients will have patient study number, which is linked to their identity for traceability. The study number is used for all documents to ensure that the patient identity is not disclosed. Only the healthcare staff in charge at the clinic have access to journals and&#x000a0;&#x02018;Subject Enrolment and Identification Log&#x02019;&#x000a0;where the patient&#x02019;s identity appears. All data will be confidential and password protected throughout the study. Patient identity is protected in the final report and on publication of the study.</p></sec><sec id="s6d"><title>Access to data</title><p>KTA and UCR, authors and investigators.</p></sec><sec id="s6e"><title>Ancillary and post-trial care</title><p>Usual care according to the clinical standard. Participants are insured by QBE and Chubb insurances. Compensation will be given to those who suffer harm from trial participation.</p></sec><sec id="s6f"><title>Dissemination policy</title><p>The plan for the investigators and sponsors is to publish a full scientific article in a peer-reviewed journal. The sponsor has no intention to use professional writers. Public access to the full protocol, participant-level dataset and statistical code will be provided on request.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Material</title><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="d35e178"><caption><title>Reviewer comments</title></caption><media mimetype="application" mime-subtype="pdf" xlink:href="bmjopen-2018-021993.reviewer_comments.pdf"/></supplementary-material><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="d35e179"><caption><title>Author's manuscript</title></caption><media mimetype="application" mime-subtype="pdf" xlink:href="bmjopen-2018-021993.draft_revisions.pdf"/></supplementary-material></sec></body><back><ack><p>The authors would like to thank Sajjad Saffari, BMSc, for contributing with the design of the flowcharts.</p></ack><fn-group><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Contributors:</bold> JW was involved in initial study conception, trial design, intervention development, protocol and manuscript preparation, and ethics application. AS was involved in trial design and input to protocol preparation. MG was involved in statistical advice, input to trial design and protocol preparation. All authors have fulfilled the ICMJE criteria for authorship.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Funding:</bold> This work was supported by BrainCool AB, VINNOVA, grant number 2016-04171 and Gothenburg Dental Society, grant number 2017-12-21.</p></fn><fn fn-type="COI-statement"><p><bold>Competing interests:</bold> JW is currently in receipt of a PhD scholarship funded by BrainCool AB. AS is employed part-time at BrainCool AB.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Ethics approval:</bold> Regional review board in Gothenburg (Dnr: 586-15).</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Provenance and peer review:</bold> Not commissioned; externally peer reviewed.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Patient consent for publication:</bold> Not required.</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="R1"><label>1.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Peterson</surname><given-names>DE</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Bensadoun</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Roila</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>Management of oral and gastrointestinal mucositis: ESMO clinical practice guidelines</article-title>. <source>Ann Oncol</source>
<year>2011</year>;<volume>22</volume>(<issue>Suppl 6</issue>):<fpage>vi78</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>84</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdr391</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21908510</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R2"><label>2.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Naidu</surname><given-names>MU</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Ramana</surname><given-names>GV</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Rani</surname><given-names>PU</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>Chemotherapy-induced and/or radiation therapy-induced oral mucositis&#x02014;complicating the treatment of cancer</article-title>. <source>Neoplasia</source>
<year>2004</year>;<volume>6</volume>:<fpage>423</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>31</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1593/neo.04169</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15548350</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R3"><label>3.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>McGuire</surname><given-names>DB</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Altomonte</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Peterson</surname><given-names>DE</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>Patterns of mucositis and pain in patients receiving preparative chemotherapy and bone marrow transplantation</article-title>. <source>Oncol Nurs Forum</source>
<year>1993</year>;<volume>20</volume>:<fpage>1493</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>502</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8278277</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R4"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Rubenstein</surname><given-names>EB</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Peterson</surname><given-names>DE</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Schubert</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>Clinical practice guidelines for the prevention and treatment of cancer therapy-induced oral and gastrointestinal mucositis</article-title>. <source>Cancer</source>
<year>2004</year>;<volume>100</volume>:<fpage>2026</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>46</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/cncr.20163</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15108223</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R5"><label>5.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Elting</surname><given-names>LS</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Keefe</surname><given-names>DM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Sonis</surname><given-names>ST</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>Patient-reported measurements of oral mucositis in head and neck cancer patients treated with radiotherapy with or without chemotherapy: demonstration of increased frequency, severity, resistance to palliation, and impact on quality of life</article-title>. <source>Cancer</source>
<year>2008</year>;<volume>113</volume>:<fpage>2704</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>13</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/cncr.23898</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18973181</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R6"><label>6.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lalla</surname><given-names>RV</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Bowen</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Barasch</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>MASCC/ISOO clinical practice guidelines for the management of mucositis secondary to cancer therapy</article-title>. <source>Cancer</source>
<year>2014</year>;<volume>120</volume>:<fpage>1453</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>61</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/cncr.28592</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24615748</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R7"><label>7.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Walladbegi</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Gellerstedt</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Svanberg</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>Innovative intraoral cooling device better tolerated and equally effective as ice cooling</article-title>. <source>Cancer Chemother Pharmacol</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>80</volume>:<fpage>965</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>72</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00280-017-3434-2</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28975429</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R8"><label>8.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Peterson</surname><given-names>DE</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Barker</surname><given-names>NP</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Akhmadullina</surname><given-names>LI</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>Phase II, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study of recombinant human intestinal trefoil factor oral spray for prevention of oral mucositis in patients with colorectal cancer who are receiving fluorouracil-based chemotherapy</article-title>. <source>J Clin Oncol</source>
<year>2009</year>;<volume>27</volume>:<fpage>4333</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>8</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1200/JCO.2008.21.2381</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19636011</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R9"><label>9.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Legert</surname><given-names>KG</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Remberger</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Ringd&#x000e9;n</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>Reduced intensity conditioning and oral care measures prevent oral mucositis and reduces days of hospitalization in allogeneic stem cell transplantation recipients</article-title>. <source>Support Care Cancer</source>
<year>2014</year>;<volume>22</volume>:<fpage>2133</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>40</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00520-014-2190-7</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24647488</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>