<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Case 1 was a 59-year-old male with a history of rhabodomyolysis. The patient was referred to our hospital because of gradually progressive dyspnea on exertion. His height was 155.5 cm, the body weight was 51.8 kg and the percentage of oxygen saturation (SpO2) was 95%. His respiratory test results are shown in 
 <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>. Chest computed tomography (CT) demonstrated subpleural fibrotic opacities with traction bronchiectasis in the upper and lower lung fields. He was clinically diagnosed as IPF with pleuroparenchymal fibroelastosis-like lesions based on the guidelines (
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>) (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1</xref>). He was treated with nintedanib ethanesulfonate and 7.5 g (divided into two doses) of ninjin'yoeito. The appetite score [Simplified Nutritional Appetite Questionnaire, SNAQ (
 <xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>)] showed improvement, increasing from 15 before administration to 16 after both 4 and 12 weeks of administration (SNAQ consists of four items related to appetite. All questions are scored from 1 to 5 points, with a total score ranging from 4 to 20 points. The lower the score, the poorer the appetite). Similarly, the lassitude score [Chalder Fatigue Scale, CFS (
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>)] improved from six before administration to four after 4 and 12 weeks of administration (CFS consists of 11 items related to physical and mental fatigue. All questions are scored from 0 to 3 points, with a total score from 0 to 33 points. The higher the score, the stronger the fatigue). The breathlessness score [Modified Medical Research Council dyspnea scale, mMRC (
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>)] also improved from two before administration to one after both 4 and 12 weeks of administration (mMRC scale uses a 5-grade scale, with Grade 0 representing almost no breathlessness and Grade 4 representing severely impaired activities of daily living due to breathlessness. The higher the grade, the stronger the breathlessness). Body weight increased from 51.8 kg before administration to 54.5 and 55.2 kg after 4 and 12 weeks of administration, respectively. The blood albumin level increased from 3.6 g/dL before administration to 4.5 g/dL after both 4 and 12 weeks of administration, and the Hb level showed an increasing trend, changing from 14.9 g/dL before administration to 15.6 and 15.4 g/dL after 4 and 12 weeks of administration, respectively. The CONUT scores were zero before and 12 weeks after ninjin'yoeito administration. A trend for improvement was also observed with respect to respiratory function test results. Serum KL-6 decreased from 499 to 481 U/ml. LDH increased from 162 to 181 IU/L (
 <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>). There was no occurrence of transaminitis during the treatment. He had an increase in walking distance from 383 to 440 m in a 6-min walk test (6MWT) 12 weeks after administration. The value of the lowest SpO2 at 6MWT remained unchanged at ~90% for 12 weeks. The CT finding did not show significant changes before and after treatment with ninjin'yoeito.
</p>
