<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par23">Peritoneal recurrence often occurs in gastric cancer patients after radical gastrectomy. Prognosis of the patient with peritoneal recurrence is very poor, median survival time of which is less than 7 months [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>]. During the progression of locally advanced gastric cancer, cancer cells are likely to seed on the peritoneum that results in peritoneal dissemination after they invade through serosal layer of gastric wall [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>]. Therefore, the deeper the depth of gastric cancer invasion, the more likely to occur peritoneal metastasis or recurrence. HIPEC is an effective method can be used to treat peritoneal metastasis of some cancers. Whether HIPEC can be used to prevent or delay peritoneal recurrence of locally advanced gastric cancer, especially when cancer cells have infiltrated into serous layer of gastric wall, is still obscure. This study was a randomized controlled trial to clarify the safety and tolerability of HIPEC after curative resection for locally advanced gastric cancer. Results showed that administration of HIPEC with cisplatin was safe and well tolerated with low complications and short duration of hospitalization. The thermal effect of HIPEC can enhance the cytotoxicity of chemotherapeutic agents [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>]. However, combination of thermal effects and drug toxicity can lead to more side effects. The most common complications in the literature are anastomotic leakage, bone marrow suppression and wound infection. In our study, anastomotic or intestinal leakage occurred in 5 patients, 1 in control group and 4 in experimental group. Four patients showed grade II bone marrow suppression, 2 in each group. No would infection occurred in either group. There was no marked difference between the occurrence rates of postoperative complications. Prophylactic HIPEC with radical D2 gastrectomy was relatively safe for locally advanced gastric cancer.
</p>
