<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par39">Notably, 1928zT2 T cells used in this study were incorporated with TLR2 domain, which showed improved anti-leukemia efficacy of CARs [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>]. These 1928zT2 T cells not only could eradicate the CD19-expressing NALM6 cells and K562 cells specifically and potently in vitro, they could significantly promote the remission of NALM-6 subcutaneous tumors ex vivo, indicating the TLR2 incorporation enhanced the anti-leukemia effects of CAR T cells. Of note, the patient 1 was infused with a dose of 1928zT2 T cells as low as 5 × 10
 <sup>4</sup> cells/kg and still achieved CR. As we know, the receptor of TLR2, an essential bridge of innate and adaptive immunity, has the potential to mobilize antigen-presentation response and promote specific activation and expansion of T cells, exhibiting critical regulation of overall immune responses [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. Previous studies have reported that TLR2 costimulation would promote adhesion and immune synaptic signaling between CAR T cells and target cells [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>]. In this study, we also found the obvious elevations of MCP-1 [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>] and HGF [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>], the critical chemokines for directing migration of lymphocytes, in the patient 2 after 1928zT2 T cells infusion, indicating the possible involvement of TLR2 in adhesive signaling. In addition, the elevations of MCP-1 and HGF were coincident with the expansion and trafficking of 1928zT2 T cells, suggesting possible roles of MCP-1 and HGF in regulating the trafficking of 1928zT2 T cells. Further studies are required to investigate the mechanisms how TLR2 incorporation promote CAR T cells to infiltrate into tumors and disrupt tumor microenvironment, which are the major challenges for treating CNS and extramedullary leukemia.
</p>
