<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fig id="Fig1">
 <label>Fig. 1</label>
 <caption>
  <p>Patient disposition. 
   <sup>a</sup> For 1 patient (
   <italic>n</italic> = 1), this occurred after primary data cut of 21 March 2014. 
   <sup>b</sup> For the BTH1677 arm, 'Other' included investigator decision (
   <italic>n</italic> = 2), patient ineligibility (
   <italic>n</italic> = 2), radiotherapy following response (
   <italic>n</italic> = 1), tumor necrosis (
   <italic>n</italic> = 1), and sponsor ended study (
   <italic>n</italic> = 1); For the Control arm, 'Other' included planned surgery (
   <italic>n</italic> = 2), administrative decision (
   <italic>n</italic> = 1), investigator decision (
   <italic>n</italic> = 1), and sponsor ended study (
   <italic>n</italic> = 1). 
   <sup>c</sup> Final data lock for OS analysis (16 March 2016) was performed approximately 3 years after the randomization date of last patient enrolled into the study. 
   <sup>d</sup> Reasons for exclusion from efficacy analyses related to central radiology review in the BTH1677 arm were no evaluable baseline and/or post-baseline CT scan (
   <italic>n</italic> = 10; none of these patients had a best response of disease progression ie, clinical progression, reported by the investigator), and additionally 1 patient did not have histologically-confirmed NSCLC; in the Control arm, the primary reason for exclusion was no evaluable post-baseline CT scan (
   <italic>n</italic> = 8; 2 of these patients had a best response of disease progression ie, clinical progression, reported by the investigator). 
   <sup>e</sup> Per protocol, to be "response evaluable” patients with best response of stable disease had to exhibit this response for at least 42 days (6 weeks) post randomization – if last scan occurred prior to this they were not "response evaluable”. Two patients in the BTH1677 arm were not evaluable for objective response, as their only on-study scan showed stable disease &lt; 6 weeks post randomization. 
   <italic>Abbreviations: CT</italic> computed tomography, 
   <italic>N</italic> overall sample size, 
   <italic>n</italic> number of patients, 
   <italic>NSCLC</italic> non-small cell lung cancer, 
   <italic>OS</italic> overall survival
  </p>
 </caption>
 <graphic xlink:href="40425_2018_324_Fig1_HTML" id="MO1" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
</fig>
