<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Vitamin K deficiency is a major cause of morbidity and mortality at neonatal period.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="bibr12-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>
 </sup> Vitamin K deficiency bleeding is bleeding that occurs due to insufficiency of vitamin K-dependent coagulation factors and resolves by vitamin K replacement. In vitamin K-dependent coagulation factor deficiencies, onset and variation in findings and symptoms are associated with factor levels. Clinical presentation tends to progress with increased bleeding predisposition in vitamin K deficiencies. The addition of acquired reasons causing vitamin K deficiency such as drug use (antibiotics, anticonvulsants, etc), liver failure, or malabsorption may lead more severe and eventful course of hemorrhage than anticipated. In 2014 in a Turkish study by Unal et al,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="bibr1-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>
 </sup> it was suggested that reported VKDB rates didn't reflect true incidence, resulting underestimation of VKDB incidence. It was reported that the incidence in Turkey was rather high, and lack of vitamin K prophylaxis in home-based deliveries or decreased activity of prophylactic vitamin K vials used in some hospitals were potential causes.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="bibr1-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>
 </sup> Thus, more comprehensive studies are needed in our country. In Turkey, vitamin K (1 mg, intramuscular [IM]) is routinely administered at time of delivery. In recent years, it is hospital-based delivery; thus, vitamin K prophylaxis has been increased as a result of increased cesarean deliveries. Solely breast-feeding, chronic diarrhea, or long-term antibiotic use predisposes infants to VKDB. Unal et al
 <sup>
  <xref rid="bibr1-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>
 </sup> published that the reporting system of the vitamin K prophylaxis is not solid; and prophylactic vitamin K injections were prepared in syringes, and we speculate that these previously prepared syringes may be a possible reason of decreased coverage of VK prophylaxis in Turkey.Therefore, we have reported that Turkish health-care providers, pediatricians, and the National Ministry of Health should be aware for the importance of prophylactic measures of VK, especially for infants born at home in rural areas. American Pediatrics Academy recommends IM injection of a single dose of vitamin K (0.5 to 1.0 mg) in all newborns. In this study, we retrospectively analyzed results of neuroimaging studies, blood tests, and PT and aPTT test performed at neonatal period. In VKDB, it is important to demonstrate prolonged PT and its normalization following vitamin K injection in confirming diagnosis.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="bibr13-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>
 </sup> Site of bleeding is one of the most important factors influencing on prognosis in VKDB. In newborns, bleeding due to vitamin K deficiency occurs in several sites; however, intracranial hemorrhages are those causing highest mortality. In previous studies, subdural hemorrhage was reported most frequently on CT scans. In 2012, Ozdemir et al
 <sup>
  <xref rid="bibr2-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>
 </sup> reported that subdural hemorrhage (28%) was most common intracranial bleeding followed by intracranial hemorrhage (23%), subarachnoid hemorrhage (14%), and intraventricular hemorrhage (8%). It was reported that fontanel bulging (70%), irritability (50%), convulsion (49%), bleeding and ecchymosis (47%), difficulty in feeding, vomiting, and feeding intolerance (46), diarrhea (34%), jaundice (11%), and fadedness (9%) were presented as complaints.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="bibr2-1076029618792302" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>
 </sup> In our study, rates of subdural hemorrhage, intracranial hemorrhage, subarachnoid hemorrhage, and intraventricular hemorrhage were 20%, 41.3%, 10.3%, and 6%, respectively. The presenting complaints included irritability and difficulty in feeding (41.6%), convulsion (37.5%), fontanel bulging (8.3%), fadedness (8.3%), and jaundice (4.1%) in our study.
</p>
