<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>MSC manufacturing was performed by Waisman Biomanufacturing at the University of Wisconsin‐Madison, Madison, Wisconsin. Clinical grade bone marrow was purchased from Lonza (Walkersville, MD, 
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.lonza.com" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">https://www.lonza.com</ext-link>). Bone marrow was harvested from a male, 18–45‐year‐old, blood type O, healthy donor who had undergone physical examination and had completed a standardized Donor Health History Questionnaire. Communicable disease testing was performed by a laboratory that is registered with the FDA to perform testing in accordance with Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments of 1988 and 42 code of federal regulation (CFR) 493. Testing was performed that included the following: HIV‐1/2 antibody, HIV‐1 nucleic acid test (NAT), hepatitis B virus (HBV) surface antigen, HBV core antibody, HBV NAT, hepatitis C virus (HCV) antibody, HCV NAT, human T‐cell lymphotropic virus types I/II antibody, cytomegalovirus total antibody, West Nile virus NAT, rapid plasma reagin (RPR), and fluorescent treponemal antibody absorption (tested only if RPR is reactive). Donor eligibility determination was performed by the Lonza medical director after full medical evaluation of the donor and review of the donor history questionnaire and the infectious disease test results. Allogeneic bone marrow‐derived MSCs from this single healthy donor were manufactured using standard manual tissue culture flasks with Minimal Essential Medium Alpha Medium (15‐012‐CV; Mediatech, Inc., Manassas, VA, 
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.cellgro.com" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">https://www.cellgro.com</ext-link>) and 9.8% HyClone Characterized Fetal Bovine Serum, U.S. Origin (SH30071.031 IR; GE Healthcare, Chicago, IL, 
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.gehealthcare.com" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">https://www.gehealthcare.com</ext-link>). Cryopreserved bags of the final product were stored in vapor base liquid nitrogen at less than −130°C 
 <xref rid="sct312264-bib-0013" ref-type="ref">13</xref>. MSCs were shipped from the manufacturing facility using qualified vapor shippers with calibrated temperature logger to the Human Cell Therapy Laboratory at our facility, where they remained frozen and stored in vapor‐phase liquid nitrogen. Each bag contained 5 × 10
 <sup>6</sup> MSCs per mL in 2.5% dimethyl sulfoxide (total of 20 mL). The final product plus an additional eight aliquots (5 mL each) were cryopreserved in a similar bag for Quality Control Testing on the final product. Testing performed is disclosed in an appendix table (Supporting Information Table 
 <xref rid="sct312264-tbl-0001" ref-type="table-wrap">1</xref>).
</p>
