<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract id="Abs1">
 <sec>
  <title>Background</title>
  <p id="Par1">The surgical treatment options for low rectal cancer patients include the Abdominoperineal Resection and the sphincter saving Low Anterior Resection. There is growing evidence towards better outcomes for patients being treated with a Low Anterior Resection compared to an Abdominoperineal Resection.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Objective</title>
  <p id="Par2">The aim of this study was to evaluate the short term and oncological outcomes in low rectal cancer treatment.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Design</title>
  <p id="Par3">This is a retrospective cohort study of prospectively collected data.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Setting</title>
  <p id="Par4">Rectal cancer patients from a single center in the United Kingdom.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Patients</title>
  <p id="Par5">Patients included all low rectal cancer patients (≤ 6 cm from the anal verge) undergoing Low Anterior Resection or Abdominoperineal Resection between 2006 and 2016.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Outcome measures</title>
  <p id="Par6">To identify differences in postoperative complications and disease free and overall survival.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Results</title>
  <p id="Par7">A total of 262 patients were included for analysis (Low Anterior Resection n = 170, Abdominoperineal Resection n = 92). Abdominoperineal Resection patients were significantly older (69 versus 66 years), had lower tumours (3 versus 5 cm), received more neo-adjuvant radiation, had longer hospital stay and more complications (wound infections and wound dehiscence). Low Anterior Resections had a significantly higher number of harvested lymph nodes (17 versus 12) however there was no difference in nodal involvement and R0 resection rate. No significant difference was found for recurrence, overall survival and disease free survival.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Limitation</title>
  <p id="Par8">Retrospective review of cancer database and single center data.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Conclusion</title>
  <p id="Par9">In the treatment of low rectal cancer Abdominoperineal Resection is associated with higher rates of postoperative complications and longer hospital stay compared to the Low Anterior Resection, with similar oncological outcomes.</p>
 </sec>
</abstract>
