<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>To our knowledge, this is the first study reporting time till viral clearance of SARS-CoV-2 RNA in asymptomatic individuals and is the first of its kind analysis to uncover the finding that duration of viral positivity is similar for subclinical and overt infections after controlling for age and sex. Chang et al. (
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>) have reported the median time till viral in symptomatic patients to be 10.5 days, which is similar to our finding of 11 days in symptomatic individuals and not too different from that of asymptomatic individuals (10 days). Hu et al. (
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>) have reported the median time till negative convergence in symptomatic patients to be 14 days, which makes sense given the study participants were all highly symptomatic hospitalized patients. The authors also reported age of more than 45 years to be significantly associated with longer duration of viral clearance (HR: 0.37) in these patients. Although the present study saw an increasing trend in time till viral negativity with increasing age categories (HR = 0.8 for age category 40–50 years, HR = 0.7 for 50–60 years, HR = 0.6 for &gt;60 years category), the trend was not statistically significant. This could be partly explained by the difference in severity between participants in our study and those studied by Hu et al., our study sample consisted of non-critical symptomatic and asymptomatic individuals, whereas participants of Hu et al. were symptomatic to the point of being hospitalized. When viewed in conjunction with the finding that asymptomatic and symptomatic individuals have similar viral loads as reported by Zou et al. (
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>), our results raise questions on similarities in duration of infectiousness between symptomatic and asymptomatic subjects. However, recent reports suggest that viral nucleic acids are still present in patient samples; therefore, asymptomatic patients may shed non-viable virus (especially those with low viral loads/high CT values threshold) that may culture negative though persistently test RT-PCR positive (
 <xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>). One of the limitations in the present study is that in individuals who were symptomatic upon arrival, it was not possible to ascertain how long they would have been presymptomatic before they landed in Bahrain. This could have affected the estimates of duration of viral positivity in symptomatic patients and warrants further research. Aside from this, these insights shed light on why asymptomatic spread is still very much a substantial risk and underscore the importance of not easing public health preventative measures as yet, such as restrictions on mass gathering, social distancing, and especially opening of businesses that would make population adherence to these measures difficult.
</p>
