<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract id="Abs1">
 <sec>
  <title>Background</title>
  <p id="Par1">BTH1677, a beta-glucan pathogen-associated molecular pattern molecule, drives an anti-cancer immune response in combination with oncology antibody therapies. This phase II study explored the efficacy, pharmacokinetics (PK), and safety of BTH1677 combined with bevacizumab/carboplatin/paclitaxel in patients with untreated advanced non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC).</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Methods</title>
  <p id="Par2">Patients were randomized to the BTH1677 arm (
   <italic>N</italic> = 61; intravenous [IV] BTH1677, 4 mg/kg, weekly; IV bevacizumab, 15 mg/kg, once each 3-week cycle [Q3W]; IV carboplatin, 6 mg/mL/min Calvert formula area-under-the-curve, Q3W; and IV paclitaxel, 200 mg/m
   <sup>2</sup>, Q3W) or Control arm (
   <italic>N</italic> = 31; bevacizumab/carboplatin/paclitaxel as above). Carboplatin/paclitaxel was discontinued after 4-6 cycles and patients who responded or remained stable received maintenance therapy with BTH1677/bevacizumab (BTH1677 arm) or bevacizumab (Control arm). Efficacy assessments, based on blinded central radiology review, included objective response rate (ORR; primary endpoint), disease control rate, duration of objective response, and progression-free survival. Overall survival and adverse events (AEs) were also assessed.
  </p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Results</title>
  <p id="Par3">ORR was higher in the BTH1677 vs Control arm but the difference between groups was not statistically significant (60.4% vs 43.5%; 
   <italic>P</italic> = .2096). All other clinical endpoints also favored the BTH1677 arm but none statistically differed between arms. PK was consistent with previous studies. Although a higher incidence of Grade 3/4 AEs occurred in the BTH1677 vs Control arm (93.2% vs 66.7%), no unexpected AEs were observed. Serious AEs and discontinuations due to AEs were lower in the BTH1677 vs Control arm.
  </p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Conclusions</title>
  <p id="Par4">Improvements in tumor assessments and survival were observed with BTH1677/bevacizumab/carboplatin/paclitaxel compared with control treatment in patients with advanced NSCLC.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Trial registration</title>
  <p id="Par5">ClinicalTrials.gov registration ID: 
   <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT00874107?term=NCT00874107&amp;rank=1" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">NCT00874107</ext-link>. Registered 2 April 2009. First participant was enrolled on 29 September 2009.
  </p>
 </sec>
</abstract>
