<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract>
 <title>Abstract</title>
 <sec>
  <title>Objectives:</title>
  <p>The purpose of this study is to investigate the effect of the comprehensive oral care program on oral health status and symptoms in head and neck cancer (HNC) patients undergoing radiotherapy.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec sec-type="methods">
  <title>Methods:</title>
  <p>This was a quasi-experimental study using a non-equivalent control group in non-synchronized design. All participants including control and experimental group were asked for the European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer Quality of Life Questionnaire H&amp;N35 (EORTC QLQ-H&amp;N35) and given an oral health education 4 times at baseline, immediate postradiotherapy, 3 months after radiotherapy, and 6 months after radiotherapy. In each visit except for final, the experimental group was given fluoride varnish application and fluoride mouth rinsing solution for daily use. Oral health examination for dental caries, plaque score (PS), bleeding on probing (BOP), and salivary flow rate was performed in baseline and 6 months after radiotherapy. Statistical analyses were done by paired 
   <italic>t</italic>-tests and mixed ANCOVA repeated-measures analysis.
  </p>
 </sec>
 <sec sec-type="results">
  <title>Results:</title>
  <p>From November 1, 2013 to October 31, 2015, a total 61 patients undergoing radiotherapy for HNC cancer were enrolled (30 in control and 31 in experimental groups). Decrease in salivary flow rate was comparable between 2 groups. Dental caries increased in control group (
   <italic>P</italic> = .006); PS and BOP were decreased in experimental group (
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; .001 and .004, respectively). Experimental group showed lower swallowing, speech problems, and less sexuality scores in EORTC QLQ-H&amp;N35 than control group.
  </p>
 </sec>
 <sec sec-type="conclusion">
  <title>Conclusion:</title>
  <p>We found improvement in oral health and the quality of life in HNC patients with comprehensive oral care intervention by dental professionals. Communicating and cooperating between the healthcare and dental professionals is needed to raise the quality of health care services for HNC patients receiving radiotherapy.</p>
 </sec>
</abstract>
