<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>All enrolled patients underwent the same intervention. MR imaging-guided bilateral stereotactic intraputaminal implantation of NPCs into the brains of PD patients was performed using a Leksell Stereotactic System and Stealth Station Surgical Navigation System (Fridley, MN, USA). Ropivacaine was the local anesthetic used for frame placement. For target locations, measurements were made using computed tomography (CT) scan images fused with previous MR images (both in DICOM format, in axial sections 1.0 mm thick). Patients were operated on one a week schedule, four in August and four in October, 2014. With the patient under general anesthesia, the stereotactic frame was fixed to the operating table with a Mayfield head holder. Bilateral parasagittal incisions and corresponding 14 mm burr holes (one for each hemisphere) were made in preparation for cell suspension injections. A gamma sterilized stereotactic needle with external diameter of 2.1 mm, and 180 mm long, compatible with Leksell stereotactic equipment and Medtronic DBS kit attached to a 1 cc Hamilton syringe was used to deploy 1 cc of suspension per needle track. Two different needle tracks through the same burr hole were selected for each side. Target locations were determined by height and length of putaminal nuclei. The lowest Z-coordinates of each track were located in the ventral putamen and spaced 4 mm apart in the Y-direction. Each needle track received 1×10
 <sup>6</sup> cells in 1 ml of culture medium. To ensure complete cell suspension delivery, injections were carried out slowly for 2 min with reciprocal withdrawal of the delivery needle to avoid both damage to stem cells and brain tissue, as well as to avert reflux or bubble formation. The first injection was carried out in the posterior putamen followed by the injection to the middle putamen. Post-operative care was given by R.R., an internist specialized in critical care medicine. The day following surgery, MR images were obtained to confirm correct placement of cell suspensions. All patients were discharged 24 h after surgery.
</p>
