<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par16">So far as we know, there is no clinical practice guidance for the appropriate treatment of bullosis diabeticorum. Based on the case findings and literature reports, appropriate management of lower limb ischemia is fundamental for preventing its recurrence. Conventionally, the treatment of severe ischemic lower extremity vascular disease mainly involves both medical and/or early revascularization intervention, either endovascular or open surgery. In some cases, pharmacotherapy alone could not fully address the lower limb ischemia while open surgery or endovascular treatment is contradicted in others due to pre-existing cardiovascular and cerebrovascular diseases. In this case, the patient declined any revascularization treatment but was willing to try conservative treatment. As such, the novel cell therapy was assigned to this patient to eradicate its potential recurrence. Since 2005, our team has been dedicated to the therapeutic use of different stem cells for diabetic wound repair and limb salvage [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>]. Both BMMSCs and bone marrow-derived mononuclear cells have been used for diabetics with critical limb ischemia and foot ulcer, the former producing better clinical outcomes [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>]. In a basic study, we explored the regulatory mechanism of peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor-γ coactivator-1α (PGC-1α) and found that it could enhance engraftment and angiogenesis of mesenchymal stem cells [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]. In another study by Wang et al., the authors observed that PGC-1α also regulates the expression of B-cell lymphoma/leukemia-2 (Bcl-2) and stimulates the survival of mesenchymal stem cells via PGC-1α–ERRα interaction without the influence of serum, hypoxia, and high glucose conditions [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>]. In addition, adipose-derived stem cells were also employed for the regulation of diabetic microenvironment [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>].
</p>
