<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par108">In the global position paper of the TACTICS group [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref>], a recommendation has been made to incorporate CT mechanistic endpoints into newly designed clinical trials to corroborate unanswered hypotheses on the MoA. Since a consistent body of evidence suggests paracrine activity of angiogenic cells as the principal MoA [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref>], there is the need to investigate the link between cell potency and function for ATMP-CD133. To our knowledge, no such previous information is available in the RA context. Our findings correlate for the first time the ATMP-CD133 secretome profile with SSS changes, a recognized perfusion index impacting cardiac prognosis [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR50">50</xref>]. Specifically, a positive correlation with SSS improvements was found with the proangiogenic growth factors HGF and PDGF-bb, whereas the proinflammatory cytokines RANTES and IL-6 correlate negatively. Interestingly, cardiotrophic growth factors, such as HGF and PDGF-bb, have been consistently described as the main components of the paracrine MoA of BM-derived endothelial progenitors concurring to cooperative neovasculogenesis and exerting chemoattractants as well as stimulatory effects on endothelial and muscle cell growth [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR54">54</xref>]. Conversely and notably, RANTES has been described as a marker of refractory symptoms in plasma of patients with unstable angina [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR55">55</xref>]. Moreover, proinflammatory chemokines, as IL-6 and RANTES, have been shown to play detrimental inflammatory direct effects on the myocardium [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref>] as well as to impair survival and differentiation of transplanted endothelial progenitors in the ischemic heart substrate [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR56">56</xref>]. In our study, we found no correlation with other well-known cytokines related to angiogenesis and inflammation, such as VEGF, and neither we were able to dissect the exact contribution of proinflammatory and anti-inflammatory factors (i.e., IL-6 or MCP-1) to produce the angiogenic effect. Further analyses are required on a larger sample size for a comprehensive assessment of the biological background of cell potency. Nevertheless, we can speculate that our data support the rationale for linking up a cell-specific secretion signature with a potential therapeutic benefit.
</p>
