<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par34">The primary endpoint will be the change in the number of colorectal ACF after 8 weeks of treatment. A magnifying colonoscope will be used in all cases (H260AZI, PCF-Q260AZI, PCF-Q290AZI, HZ290; Olympus Co., Tokyo, Japan), with carbon dioxide insufflation. Bowel preparation for the colonoscopy will be initiated one day before the procedure. Each patient will be instructed to consume a low-residue diet and take 5 mg of oral sodium picosulfate on the evening before the procedure. On the day of the procedure, each patient will be given 1500 ml of polyethylene glycol (PEG). If the stools are not sufficiently clear, an additional 500 ml of PEG will be given to ensure sufficient bowel cleaning. For conscious sedation, midazolam and pentazocine will be administered at the beginning of the procedure. Intramuscular glucagon or scopolamine will be administered to reduce colonic movements. At the time of the first colonoscopy, the endoscope will be inserted into the cecum, and the entire colorectum will be carefully observed as the endoscope is pulled back. Rectal epithelial samples will be obtained. The number of rectal ACFs will be counted as follows. First, the rectum will be washed with warm water, then sprayed with 0.25% methylene blue solution and stained for 2 min, washed again with warm water, and finally examined by magnifying endoscopy for ACFs. At the end of 8 weeks of administration, the same endoscopists will perform the polypectomy and counting of the ACF. All procedures will be recorded on DVD, and all of the ACF will be photographed. The number of ACF in each patient will be counted by the endoscopists during the colonoscopy. To further ensure validity, the number of ACF will be counted again through observation of the recorded DVD by 3 blinded expert endoscopists (H.T, A. J and A.K). If there was a discrepancy among the blinded specialists, we adopted the consent of at least two of the three. Additionaly if these expert endoscopists judge the colonoscopy examination as inadequate, that case will be excluded.</p>
