<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>We demonstrated with our case a potential impact of Covid-19 infection on endothelial dysfunction. Prior investigations of endothelial changes in Covid-19 infection have demonstrated direct viral infection of endothelial cells and endothelial inflammation with microthrombi and microangiopathy (
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>). As the vascular endothelium is essential for the maintenance of vascular homoeostasis, dysfunction of the endothelium may result in cardiovascular changes. So far, there are only limited data about the pathophysiological mechanisms how SARS-CoV-2 contributes to endothelial dysfunction. While potential interactions of SARS-CoV-2 with ACE2 receptors have been suggested initially, recent data indicate that there is lacking evidence of ACE2 receptors expression on human endothelial cells assuming thus that direct infection of endothelial cells by SARS-CoV-2 is unlikely (
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>). Besides potential microvascular damage, also macrovascular damage may be promoted by Covid-19 infection since low values of FMD and NMD of the brachial artery were present in our patient. Additionally, amelioration of NMD, aortic PWV and Aix were observed after Covid-19 infection which indicates that Covid-19 infection may influence vascular homeostasis also in large arteries. Brachial FMD and NMD as well as aortic PWV are proven predictors of cardiovascular events and mortality and changes of those parameters are also associated cardiovascular events and mortality (
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>). So far, data evaluating vascular reactivity or arterial stiffness in Covid-19 infection are very limited. Only one study investigated FMD and PWV in young adults 4 weeks after positive testing for SARS-CoV-2 revealing significantly lower values of FMD and higher values of PWV in the group of subjects with a suffered SARS-CoV-2 (
 <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>). However, data about vascular reactivity and arterial stiffness in acute Covid-19 infection are still lacking and follow-up changes of these parameters during a Covid-19 infection have not been investigated yet.
</p>
