<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>It is notable that CESS members often do not understand this type as an ethical problem or do not feel equipped to deal with it. Problems are not perceived as ethical issues but rather as organizational questions. In addition, CESS members are very reluctant to include this area as part of their ethical responsibility. Different expectations of CESS members and mental health professionals regarding this issue bear a severe risk of misunderstandings and frustration on both sides. However, this finding must be seen against the background that intersystem problems particularly pose great challenges for CESS. Furthermore, it must be argued that, from a conceptual perspective, this type of ethical problem does not correspond to the types of problems in medicine for which CESS was developed originally. These problems are more complex than other types of ethical problems on other levels and clearly depart from the individual relationship between patients and professionals. They include, for example, more stakeholders and institutions from the healthcare sector and can even reach out beyond this system. Including intersystem problems into the responsibility of CESS comes at the price of extensive adaptations in processes and structures. Bringing all perspectives involved to the table and finding solutions on this more systemic level requires high organizational efforts. This includes more sophisticated communication and moderation skills to bridge fundamentally different perspectives and is, doubtless, resource-intensive if it is ever possible at all for simple practical reasons. Moreover, a second point must be added to these pragmatic considerations: Some ethical problems might not even be open for a solution on the level of CESS due to the lack of competencies, power or the addressee of moral complaints. This results in a practical and conceptual challenge for dealing with ethical problems. On the one hand, it is the primary goal of CESS to develop concrete recommendations for ethically justifiable clinical decisions and, thereby, to prevent intersystem problems from being returned to practice as unmanageable. Failure to do so would equal the inability to react to the moral distress of mental health professionals and simply reproduce it on the level of CESS. On the other hand, from a theoretical perspective, recommendations given under such circumstances must be classified as non-optimal moral solutions. They are only justified because the actual problem is out of range. Challenges are, therefore, 2-fold. Firstly, in a practical perspective, ways to communicate this status of advice as non-optimal but justified by circumstances need to be developed. The awareness in CESS members and mental health professionals of the provisionary nature of this advice needs to be raised. Secondly, from a conceptual perspective, structures have to be improved to ensure that intersystem problems can be taken up at higher levels. This is necessary to ensure that implications of ethical problems concerning the systematic level are not left unprocessed once a case on the clinical level has been handled. For these cases, a much stronger network with superior ethical bodies (e.g., at the level of medical associations, or regional or national ethics councils) and policymakers would have to be created. Such a network might be able to counteract the loss of the systematic implications.</p>
