<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par64">The primary aim of this trial is to exploratively investigate the effect of SRS compared to WBRT in patients with BM from SCLC. Currently, according to national guidelines, the recommendation for patients with BM from SCLC, regardless of the number of BM, is WBRT [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>]. The actual evidence behind those recommendations is low and mainly based on retrospective studies from the last three decades and is analogically reasoned by previous PCI studies [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>]. In a recent Japanese trial, prophylactic cranial irradiation did not result in longer overall survival compared with observation in patients with ED SCLC and PCI is therefore no longer recommended for patients with extensive disease SCLC when patients receive regular MRI examinations during follow-up. Furthermore, if SCLC patients are regularly checked with MRI, the actual number of patients with limited number of BM might rise. The general use of WBRT in SCLC patients is additionally supported by the general paradigm of a diffuse intracranial disease pattern; even so, these beliefs derive from a pre-MRI era. The EORTC conducted a prospective, phase II study between 1989 and 1995 that included patients (
 <italic>n</italic> = 22) with brain-only metastases SCLC to evaluate the efficacy of WBRT [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>]. The median response duration in patients with an objective response was 5.4 months, and the median survival of all patients was 4.7 months. A number of retrospective studies investigated prognostic factors and identified subgroups of SCLC patients with a favorable prognosis [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>]. In a recent report [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>], we investigated 229 SCLC patients with BM from SCLC; median overall survival after WBRT was 6 months. The main prognostic factors associated with overall survival were performance status, time of appearance of intracranial disease (synchronous vs. metachronous), initial response to chemotherapy, and higher RPA class. Interestingly, patients in RPA class I showed a median survival after WBRT of 17 months and had a comparable outcome to patients with non-cerebral disease treated with PCI. Furthermore, 39% of patients had 1–5 BM and the majority of patients received staging with cerebral MRI prior to treatment [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>]. The recently developed disease-specific prognostic score for patients with BM from 
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/medicine-and-dentistry/small-cell-lung-cancer" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">SCLC</ext-link> was even more prognostic than RPA score and diagnosis-specific graded prognostic assessment score [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>] and revealed a subgroup of patients with a very short survival (class I) and a subgroup with a favorable prognosis (class II) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>]. The disease-specific prognostic score for patients with BM from 
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/medicine-and-dentistry/small-cell-lung-cancer" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">SCLC</ext-link> will be validated within the ENCEPHALON trial. Because of the multiple prognostic factors and differences in outcomes in patients with BM from SCLC, a one- fits-all treatment framework, in which all patients are automatically recommended for WBRT, is no longer appropriate and the actual evidence for this recommendation is missing.
</p>
