<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par47">Patients will undergo baseline tumour imaging including computed tomography (CT) scan of the chest, abdomen and pelvis, and by contrast enhanced magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scan of the liver at screening. At post-treatment time-points prior to surgery (on Day 43), after surgery (on Day 127) and 4-monthly thereafter, tumour imaging will be repeated using contrast enhanced MRI. A triple-phase CT of the liver is an acceptable alternative for intrahepatic staging in patients with contraindications to MRI. Baseline CT/MRI scans do not need to be repeated if obtained within 35 days of first dose. The same method used for assessment at baseline must then be used at all subsequent time points. RECIST v1.1 criteria will be used to determine patient response to treatment, progression-free survival (PFS) and ORR. A baseline core tumor biopsy will be collected from participants at screening and patients will have a parcel of leftover tissue from their LR specimen stored for correlative studies. Treatment will consist of a maximum of 2 cycles of nivolumab 3 mg/kg and 1 cycle of ipilimumab 1 mg/kg administered intravenously Q3W. Patients will be reviewed following completion of IMP treatment (Follow-up visit 1; FU1) on Day 43 +/− 3, prior to surgery. LR will be performed as per standard of care. The safety FU2 will be conducted 126 days (± 7 days) after the first dose of the investigational medicinal product (IMP). All AEs that occur prior to the visit will be recorded. Participants with on-going AEs at the visit will be followed up by principal investigator (PI) or delegate until resolution or stabilisation of the event. Following FU2, participants will be assessed every 4 months (± 7 days) thereafter to collect information regarding disease status and survival. Long-term follow-up will continue, for each patient, for a total of 2 years. The Standard Protocol Items: Recommendations for Interventional Trials (SPIRIT) schedule of enrolment, interventions, and assessments is provided in Supplementary Table 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>
 <bold>.</bold>
</p>
