<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In this phase I open‐label study, we explored whether EEG biomarkers show evidence of change after intravenous treatment with autologous umbilical cord blood in young children with autism. In addition, we tested whether measures derived from spontaneous EEG were useful in predicting degree of improvement in social communication abilities. In this sample of 25 children who were found to exhibit improvements in social communication (VABS), expressive language (EOWPVT), and overall clinical improvement, as assessed via the CGI‐I 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0041" ref-type="ref">41</xref>, we first explored whether there was any evidence of change in the spectral characteristics of the EEG, as assessed via recordings of spontaneous EEG taken while children watched movies with differing content at baseline, and 6 and 12 months post‐treatment. Of particular interest is the U‐shaped power profile of ASD characterized by excessive power in low‐frequency (delta, theta) and high‐frequency bands (gamma) and reduced power in midrange frequency bands (alpha, beta) 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0021" ref-type="ref">21</xref>. Interestingly, the children in this study showed a "normalization” of spectral features of their EEG, characterized by significant reductions in both absolute and relative theta power over the posterior regions and significant increases in absolute frontal alpha power and in relative frontal and central alpha power, as well as increases in relative posterior beta power (11–20 Hz) by 12 months post‐treatment. Evidence of increases in relative posterior beta power at 12 months were also found. Evidence suggests that autism is associated with disruptions in GABAergic interneuron development 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0055" ref-type="ref">55</xref>, 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0056" ref-type="ref">56</xref>, 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0057" ref-type="ref">57</xref> which may be caused by an excitatory/inhibitory imbalance 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0058" ref-type="ref">58</xref>. Such disruptions have been posited as an explanation for reduction in alpha frequencies often found in autism, as this would reflect higher than normal levels of excitation 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0021" ref-type="ref">21</xref>. Increased power in lower frequencies, such as theta and delta, might reflect compensatory mechanisms. In this study, this atypical pattern shifted toward a more normal pattern (increased alpha and decreased theta power).
</p>
