<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<list list-type="roman-lower">
 <list-item>
  <p>The 15-item Chinese Machiavellianism Personality Questionnaire compiled by Tang (
   <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">2011</xref>), was used (5-point scale: 1 = 
   <italic>absolutely disagree</italic>; 5 = 
   <italic>absolutely agree</italic>). The total score summed across the items was divided by 15 to yield a score ranging from 1 to 5. Higher scores indicate higher levels of Machiavellian personality. The Cronbach's α coefficient was 0.79 in this study.
  </p>
 </list-item>
 <list-item>
  <p>The 10-item Moral Identity Scale modified by Chi (
   <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">2009</xref>) was used (5-point scale: 1 = 
   <italic>absolutely disagree</italic>; 5 = 
   <italic>absolutely agree</italic>). Five of the items measure internalization (e.g., It's important for me to have these beautiful qualities) and five measured symbolization (e.g., I choose clothes that make me look good). The correlation between the two subscales was 0.68, so we combined them into a single scale; Cronbach's α was 0.89 in this study. Higher scores indicate higher levels of moral identity.
  </p>
 </list-item>
 <list-item>
  <p>The short version of the Marlowe-Crowne Social Desirability Scale (Ballard et al., 
   <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">1988</xref>), which consists of 10 items, was used in this study (1 = 
   <italic>yes</italic>, 0 = 
   <italic>no</italic>). Higher scores indicate higher social desirability. Cronbach's α was 0.83 in this study.
  </p>
 </list-item>
 <list-item>
  <p>We developed five dilemmas (e.g., to maintain bitter long distance love with a girlfriend or give up and marry a more beautiful and rich girl) manifesting a conflict between Machiavellianism and moral identity (see 
   <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM1">Supplementary Material</xref>). In a pilot study, 12 psychology PhD students evaluated the dilemmas before the actual experiment began. In the Chinese cultural background, other directedness (communality) is a value that individuals are encouraged to cultivate and self-directedness (agency) is a value that is discouraged; benevolence, justice, courtesy, wisdom, and trust are also promoted. The evaluation was conducted using a 7-point scale (one indicated 
   <italic>completely unrelated</italic>; seven indicated 
   <italic>completely related</italic>). Each scenario was rated based on the extent to which it was related to manifestations of Machiavellianism (e.g., trying to get ahead, being unscrupulous, manipulating others, taking advantage) and to issues of moral identity (e.g., emphasizing morality and kindness, valuing others' feelings, and harmonious relationships between people). The 
   <italic>t</italic>-test for paired samples was performed on the evaluation scores, and the results revealed that the scores for Machiavellianism and moral identity were not significantly different for any of the five scenarios (
   <italic>M</italic>
   <sub>Mach1</sub> ± SD = 4.65 ± 0.36, 
   <italic>M</italic>
   <sub>moral1</sub> ± SD = 4.71 ± 0.40, 
   <italic>t</italic> = 1.20, 
   <italic>p</italic>
   <sub>1</sub> = 0.32; 
   <italic>M</italic>
   <sub>Mach2</sub> ± SD = 4.34 ± 0.33, 
   <italic>M</italic>
   <sub>moral2</sub> ± SD = 4.38 ± 0.38, 
   <italic>t</italic> = 0.85, 
   <italic>p</italic>
   <sub>2</sub> = 0.40; 
   <italic>M</italic>
   <sub>Mach3</sub> ± SD = 5.61 ± 0.56, 
   <italic>M</italic>
   <sub>moral3</sub> ± SD = 5.58 ± 0.53, 
   <italic>t</italic> = 0.42, 
   <italic>p</italic>
   <sub>3</sub> = 0.53; 
   <italic>M</italic>
   <sub>Mach4</sub> ± SD = 4.78 ± 0.44, 
   <italic>M</italic>
   <sub>moral4</sub> ± SD = 4.84 ± 0.55, 
   <italic>t</italic> = 0.91, 
   <italic>p</italic>
   <sub>4</sub> = 0.35; 
   <italic>M</italic>
   <sub>Mach5</sub> ± SD = 5.10 ± 0.46, 
   <italic>M</italic>
   <sub>moral5</sub> ± SD = 5.13 ± 0.49, 
   <italic>t</italic> = 0.48, 
   <italic>p</italic>
   <sub>5</sub> = 0.63). These results indicate that all the scenarios were related to a similar extent to both Machiavellianism and ethical values.
  </p>
 </list-item>
 <list-item>
  <p>The seven-item Chinese version of the State Anxiety Inventory (STAI) compiled by Wang et al. (
   <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">1999</xref>) was used to measure all five dilemmas. A 4-point scale was used, where one indicated "not at all,” two "somewhat,” three "moderately,” and four "very much.” The Cronbach's α was 0.90 in this study.
  </p>
 </list-item>
</list>
