<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>There is thus a need to at least partially automate AMS interventions. The 2016 AMS guidelines by the Infectious Diseases Society of America and the Society for Healthcare Epidemiology of America indicate moderate-quality evidence for the incorporation of computerised decision support system (CDSS) at the time of prescribing.
 <xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref> CDSSs to improve antimicrobial use have been implemented before, but there is clearly a lack of high-quality studies assessing their impact on actual antimicrobial prescribing and patient outcomes. The vast majority of studies in this area are uncontrolled before–after studies which have a much higher risk of bias and lower external validity.
 <xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref> A recent systematic review of computerised decision support for antibiotic use in hospitals identified only 6 randomised controlled studies among the 81 studies included in the review, of which half (3) were single-site studies.
 <xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref> Another earlier systematic review, also mostly identified low-quality, single-centre, before–after studies and concluded that 'high quality, systematic, multisite, comparative studies are critically needed to assist organisations in making informed decisions about the most effective IT interventions.'
 <xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref> Furthermore, existing studies often limited assessment to specific situations and settings, such as increasing guideline compliance in the treatment of urinary tract infection
 <xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref> and critically ill patients,
 <xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref> and to improve empirical antibiotic treatment for patients with suspected bacterial infections.
 <xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref> CDSSs are also often overly complex, poorly designed, not integrated into the workflow, expensive or difficult to implement in heterogeneous clinical settings.
 <xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>
</p>
