<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par15">The current recommended treatment for hypertension or diabetes mellitus is multiple drug combination therapy, which requires a lower dose of each drug to achieve a maximum therapeutic effect while avoiding toxic effects. Here, we hypothesize that aspirin and metformin combination therapy is more effective than single use of these drugs for CRC prevention. To test this hypothesis, this proposed study will investigate whether the combined use of aspirin and metformin shows a stronger chemopreventive effect than aspirin or metformin alone. In CRC chemoprevention trials, in general, the incidence of adenomas or the cancer itself is set as the study endpoint. Although the incidence rate of CRC is the most reliable endpoint, the use of this endpoint would be unsuitable for chemoprevention trials because of the relatively low occurrence rate of CRC in the general population [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>] and the long-term observation period that it would require. ACF are defined as lesions containing crypts that are larger in diameter and stain more darkly with methylene blue than normal crypts [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>]. They have been reported to be more prevalent in patients with cancer and adenomas, are reduced by the use of chemopreventive drugs such as NSAIDs, are considered a reliable surrogate biomarker of CRC [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. We previously reported the usefulness of ACF as a biological marker of CRC [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>], and conducted a chemoprevention trial for colorectal ACF [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>]. The advantages of chemoprevention trials using colorectal ACF as the primary endpoint are that long-term observation is not required to evaluate the drug effect, and ACF can be estimated quantitatively. Thus, we set ACF as a suitable endpoint for this trial. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first clinical trial to investigate aspirin and metformin combination therapy as a chemopreventive strategy in patients with colorectal ACF.
</p>
