<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract>
 <p>The purpose of this trial was to evaluate the efficacy of 2-year consolidation therapy with nilotinib, at a dose of 300 mg twice daily, for achieving treatment-free remission in chronic myeloid leukemia patients with a deep molecular response (
  <italic>BCR-ABL1
   <sup>IS</sup>
  </italic> ≤0.0032%). Successful treatment-free remission was defined as no confirmed loss of deep molecular response. We recruited 96 Japanese patients, of whom 78 sustained a deep molecular response during the consolidation phase and were therefore eligible to discontinue nilotinib in the treatment-free remission phase; of these, 53 patients (67.9%; 95% confidence interval: 56.4–78.1%) remained free from molecular recurrence in the first 12 months. The estimated 3-year treatment-free survival was 62.8%. Nilotinib was readministered to all patients (n=29) who experienced a molecular recurrence during the treatment-free remission phase. After restarting treatment, rapid deep molecular response returned in 25 patients (86.2%), with 50% of patients achieving a deep molecular response within 3.5 months. Tyrosine kinase inhibitor withdrawal syndrome was reported in 11/78 patients during the early treatment-free remission phase. The treatment-free survival curve was significantly better in patients with undetectable molecular residual disease than in patients without (3-year treatment-free survival, 75.6 
  <italic>versus</italic> 48.6%, respectively; 
  <italic>P</italic>=0.0126 by the log-rank test). There were no significant differences in treatment-free survival between subgroups based on tyrosine kinase inhibitor treatment before the nilotinib consolidation phase, tyrosine kinase inhibitor-withdrawal syndrome, or absolute number of natural killer cells. The results of this study indicate that it is safe and feasible to stop tyrosine kinase inhibitor therapy in patients with chronic myeloid leukemia who have achieved a sustained deep molecular response with 2 years of treatment with nilotinib. This study was registered with UMIN-CTR (UMIN000005904).
 </p>
</abstract>
