<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par46">BTH1677 (Imprime PGG; β(1,6)-[poly-(1,3)-D-glucopyranosyl]-poly-β-(1,3)-D-glucopyranose; Biothera Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Eagan, MN) is a yeast-derived, water-soluble, 1,3-1,6 beta-glucan purified from the cell wall of a proprietary, non-recombinant, strain of 
 <italic>Saccharomyces cerevisiae.</italic> It functions as a pathogen-associated molecular pattern (PAMP) molecule to support a coordinated innate and adaptive anti-cancer immune response in combination with oncology antibody therapies. When BTH1677 enters the blood, it is bound by endogenous plasma anti-beta-glucan antibodies (ABA) resulting in complement activation and opsonization with complement protein iC3b [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>]. The BTH1677/ABA/iC3b complex initially binds to innate immune effector cells through complement receptor 3 and Fc gamma receptor IIA (FcγIIA) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>], activating innate immune cells and enabling direct killing of antibody-targeted tumor cells [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>]. BTH1677 also enables remodeling of the tumor microenvironment, shifting the normally suppressive M2-state macrophages to a more M1 (pro-inflammatory) state [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>], and promoting depletion and/or maturation of myeloid-derived suppressor cells in the tumor microenvironment [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. BTH1677 additionally activates antigen-presenting cells, driving co-stimulatory marker expression on macrophages and dendritic cells, as well as dendritic cell maturation, CD4 and CD8 T-cell expansion, and production of key anti-tumor cytokines (e.g., interferon gamma) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>]. In murine syngeneic and xenogeneic tumor models, BTH1677 combined with various tumor-targeting MAbs [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>], PD-1 and PD-L1 checkpoint-inhibiting MAbs [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>], or VEGF/VEGFR2-targeted MAbs [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>] has resulted in greater suppression of tumor growth and longer survival than with either agent alone. In particular, 3 of these later studies have demonstrated synergy of BTH1677 when used in combination with bevacizumab in multiple lung cancer models [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>]. Thus, the combination of BTH1677 and bevacizumab is a rational immunotherapy for treatment of cancer.
</p>
