<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Acute myeloid leukemia (AML) carries a dismal prognosis in older patients, especially those with adverse cytogenetics and/or poor performance status. The median age at diagnosis is 67 years, with 5-year survival less than 10%.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b1-1031308" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>
 </sup> Standard induction chemotherapy with cytarabine and an anthracycline can achieve remission in selected older AML patients, but this regimen is often not feasible due to toxicity and poor tolerability. Furthermore, long-term survival after initial intensive chemotherapy is rare in these patients, even in the setting of initial complete remission (CR). Decitabine (5-aza-2'-deoxycytidine), a DNA methyltransferase inhibitor, has shown efficacy with an acceptable extramedullary toxicity profile in newly diagnosed older AML patients, with 25% CR, 7% 30-day mortality, and a median overall survival of 7.7 months when administered using a schedule of 20 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup> over one hour (h) daily for five days. Of note, patients in this multicenter study received a median of 3 cycles of treatment (range 1–25 cycles).
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b2-1031308" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>
 </sup> Blum 
 <italic>et al</italic>. treated 53 AML patients with a median age of 74 years (range 60–85 years) with decitabine 20 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup> daily for ten days every four weeks.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b3-1031308" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>
 </sup> The CR rate was 47% after a median of 3 cycles of therapy, with 2% 30-day and 15% 8-week induction mortality, mostly due to disease progression. Median overall and disease-free survival were 55 and 46 weeks, respectively.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b3-1031308" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>
 </sup> Similar results have been achieved in other single-center trials using single-agent decitabine in a 10-day schedule, including at our own center.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b4-1031308" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,
  <xref rid="b5-1031308" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>
 </sup> Still, since most newly-diagnosed AML patients treated with decitabine generally relapse within 6–18 months, and overall median survival is less than one year, a variety of potentially synergistic agents are under investigation.
</p>
