<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Acute myeloid leukemia originates from a rare population of leukemia stem cells (LSCs) that are capable of self-renewal, proliferation, and differentiation into malignant blasts. LSCs and leukemic blasts can persist after treatment and contribute to disease relapse.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b6-1031308" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>
 </sup> Drugs that release LSCs and blasts from their protective microenvironment may leave them more vulnerable to therapy, as they are strongly dependent on the bone marrow niche for proliferation and survival.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b7-1031308" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>
 </sup> CXCR4, the chemokine receptor for stromal cell-derived factor 1 (CXCL12/SDF-1), is a critical component of the bone marrow niche and is expressed on both normal stem cells and AML blasts. The CXCR4/SDF-1 axis in AML promotes leukemic cell homing to the marrow, as well as 
 <italic>in vivo</italic> growth.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b8-1031308" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
  <xref rid="b9-1031308" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>
 </sup> Plerixafor, a small molecule antagonist of CXCR4, is commercially available as a stem cell mobilizing agent and is approved by the US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) for use in combination with granulocyte-colony stimulating factor (G-CSF) for patients with multiple myeloma or non-Hodgkin lymphoma undergoing autologous stem cell transplantation (Mozobil, Sanofi-Aventis). Plerixafor blocks CXCR4-mediated signaling and significantly decreases the survival of AML cells 
 <italic>in vitro</italic>. Plerixafor has been safely combined with cytotoxic chemotherapy in several studies of patients with relapsed/refractory AML.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b10-1031308" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>–
  <xref rid="b12-1031308" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>
 </sup> While mobilization of leukemic blasts was achieved, these trials were not randomized and, thus, the impact of plerixafor on clinical outcomes was unclear. The objective of this investigator-initiated clinical trial was to investigate the safety and efficacy of adding plerixafor to decitabine in newly diagnosed older patients with AML. Extensive correlative scientific studies were performed to determine the effects of plerixafor on the mobilization of LSCs and leukemic progenitor cells.
</p>
