<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>One characteristic of lineage-depleted cell products requiring additional study is the presence and impact of other supporting cells on engraftment. Especially for BM-derived products, our procedure does not include a marker to deplete mesenchymal stem cells (MSC). While the engraftment potential of MSC manipulated 
 <italic>ex vivo</italic> in CD34
 <sup>+</sup> cell supportive media is unexplored, two recent reports suggest that these cells are integral to BM function in FA, and can be LV-transduced and functionally corrected to facilitate hematopoietic recovery and function in a mouse model of FA.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b26-1031806" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>,
  <xref rid="b27-1031806" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>
 </sup> For mAPH-derived products, such as that infused into Patient 3, additional follow up will be required to determine if a selective advantage is observed 
 <italic>in vivo</italic>. The improved transduction efficiency of lineage-depleted cell products could reflect non-repopulating CD34
 <sup>−</sup> cell uptake of LV. However, we still observed a benefit in transduction of hematopoietic CFC, even at the lower MOI of 5 IU/cell. One other possible explanation is the age and clinical condition of Patient 3. To address this concern we compared our results in Patient 3 to the 4 FA patients enrolled in the FANCOSTEM clinical trial in Spain (
 <italic>
  <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://clinicaltrials.gov" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">clinicaltrials.gov</ext-link> identifier: 02931071
 </italic>).
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b28-1031806" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>
 </sup> These 4 patients were aged 3–7 years and demonstrated higher baseline blood cell counts at the time of collection. All 4 patients received the same mobilization regimen as Patient 3 reported here, but resulting mAPH products were subjected to direct CD34 enrichment prior to transduction at an MOI of 100 IU/cell. The reported mean VCN was 0.4±0.1 and ranged from 0.1 to 0.4 copies in individual CFC. Our data with a higher VCN at lower MOI suggest that the mixed cell culture supports transduction of hematopoietic progenitor cells, at least.
</p>
