<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Anti-angiogenic agents, which have been increasingly used in cancer patients with progressive malignant brain tumors, can improve the tumor vascular structure and permeability, thus reducing brain edema. Anti-angiogenic agents, therefore, may be useful alternatives to glucocorticoids in treating intractable brain edema. In recent years, several studies have described the efficacy of anti-angiogenic agents, especially bevacizumab. The first retrospective analysis of the use of bevacizumab in the treatment of radiation-induced brain necrosis and brain edema was published in 2007 (
 <xref rid="B21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>). The results showed a significant improvement in radiation-induced brain edema in eight patients after four cycles of bevacizumab treatment. Furtner et al. (
 <xref rid="B22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>). identified a total of 34 patients with recurrent WHO II and III meningiomas who had been treated at six European institutions. Compared to other types of therapy, such as cytotoxic chemotherapy, somatostatin analogs, and tyrosine kinase inhibitors, bevacizumab had the most pronounced inhibitory effect on anti-edematous activity. The volume of peritumoral brain edema in the bevacizumab-treated group was found to decrease by an average of 20.007 cm
 <sup>3</sup> compared to the other treatment groups which increased by 0.107 cm
 <sup>3</sup> on average. Some serious adverse reactions of bevacizumab should not be ignored, including gastrointestinal perforations, surgery and wound healing complications, hemorrhage, thromboembolism, proteinuria, and hypertension (
 <xref rid="B23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>). The efficacy of small molecular tyrosine kinase inhibitors has also been reported. Song et al. (
 <xref rid="B25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>) documented a heavily treated breast cancer patient with intractable vasogenic brain edema after radiotherapy of BM. High dose steroids and dehydration produced no improvement. Surprisingly, the brain MRI demonstrated remarkable shrinkage of edema after taking apatinib for about one month. Another small molecular tyrosine kinase inhibitor, cediranib, has also been shown to reduce edema in a mouse glioblastoma model (
 <xref rid="B26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>).
</p>
