<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>It is likely that the words “experience” and “leadership” are mentioned multiple times in a typical advising appointment that is focused on career goals. Twenty-five years ago, most lectures consisted of a one-sided, continuous dialog by the instructor and laboratories were designed to provide specific results through a cookie-cutter-type design; thus, students were most likely instructed to gain experience and leadership through extracurricular formats 
 <italic>via</italic> undergraduate research opportunities, jobs, and organizations/clubs. The idea of including these opportunities within the classroom was at the heart of the 
 <xref rid="ref2" ref-type="bibr">American Association for the Advancement of Science’s (2011)</xref> report. By embedding real research projects within classroom laboratories, all students were inevitably pushed into the driver seat of their education through the exploration of novel research questions. Active engagement within these CUREs works to build strong science foundations by focusing on students gaining a deeper understanding of the scientific process as well as analytical/technical skills (
 <xref rid="ref16" ref-type="bibr">Thiry et al., 2011</xref>; 
 <xref rid="ref4" ref-type="bibr">Auchincloss et al., 2014</xref>). However, to provide students with the best resume for success, undergraduate experiences should not be confined by classroom/laboratory walls and should inspire biologists to become leaders not only within their field but also within their community (
 <xref rid="ref11" ref-type="bibr">Hart, 2015</xref>; 
 <xref rid="ref18" ref-type="bibr">Webb, 2016</xref>; 
 <xref rid="ref13" ref-type="bibr">McGowin and Teed, 2019</xref>). This is especially important in current times where most would not disagree that there is a disconnection between scientific research and the media. Explanations for the disconnection involve a general underestimation of how difficult it is to connect with diverse audiences, perceptions that the public does not want to understand science, a lack of recognition for outreach/community engagement, and the lack of formal training in undergraduate and graduate curricula (
 <xref rid="ref8" ref-type="bibr">Brownell et al., 2013</xref>; 
 <xref rid="ref9" ref-type="bibr">Devonshire and Hathway, 2014</xref>; 
 <xref rid="ref17" ref-type="bibr">Varner, 2014</xref>). Following the success of CUREs, it seems that including community engagement within the curricula could provide a new dignity within the field of biology. Service-learning projects aim to fill a need on both sides; a community need is satisfied, and the students gain a wider perspective of their course content and build a connection with their community (
 <xref rid="ref7" ref-type="bibr">Bringle and Hatcher, 1996</xref>). This paper briefly describes the incorporation of a service-learning project into a microbiology laboratory course in which students developed a campaign to increase awareness toward two important factors regarding human health, handwashing, and vaccinations.
</p>
