<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ack>
 <title>Authors' contributions</title>
 <p>JM and HM contributed to conception and design of the study and drafted the manuscript; QC and LT participated in data collection and literature research; NL, FH, LG, SG, JW, HL, YY, LZ, LL, PW, YL, QH, XY, QT, YL, YL, XS, CX, YM, YG, RS, HM, KC, XG and MZ contributed to data analysis and interpretation. All authors read and approved the final manuscript.</p>
 <sec id="FPar1">
  <title>Acknowledgements</title>
  <p id="Par34">Not applicable.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="FPar2">
  <title>Competing interests</title>
  <p id="Par35">The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="FPar3">
  <title>Availability of data and materials</title>
  <p id="Par36">The datasets used and/or analyzed during the current study are available from Jiangsu Hengrui Medicine Co., Ltd. on reasonable request. The key raw data have been deposited into the Research Data Deposit (
   <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.researchdata.org.cn" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">http://www.researchdata.org.cn</ext-link>), with the Approval Number of RDD2018000823.
  </p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="FPar4">
  <title>Consent for publication</title>
  <p id="Par37">Not applicable.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="FPar5">
  <title>Ethics approval and consent to participate</title>
  <p id="Par38">The clinical trial protocol was approved by the Sun Yat-sen University Cancer Center. Each subject provided written informed consent before enrolment.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="FPar6">
  <title>Funding</title>
  <p id="Par39">The trial was supported by Jiangsu Hengrui Medicine Co., Ltd [The National Natural Science Foundation of China (Grant No. 81230056), The National Science &amp; Technology Pillar Program during the Twelfth Five-year Plan Period (Grand No. 2014BAI09B10, The Natural Science Foundation of Guangdong Province (Grand Nos. S2013010012220, 2017A030312003), the Science and Technology Project of Guangzhou City, China (Grand No. 132000507), The Health &amp; Medical Collaborative Innovation Project of Guangzhou City, China (Grand No. 201400000001), The Innovation Team Development Plan of the Ministry of Education (Grand No. IRT_17R110), the Program of Introducing Talents of Discipline to Universities (Grand No. B14035)].</p>
 </sec>
</ack>
