<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Our study has several limitations. First, the three groups were heterogeneous with respect to the patients' age, gender, race, underlying disease and conditioning regimen intensity. Among these factors, only the patients' age has been associated with an increased incidence of chronic GvHD. An association of older patients' age with higher risk of chronic GvHD has not been consistently observed after UCB HCT, and very few data addressing this issue are available for Haplo/PTCY recipients.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b32-1040835" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>–
  <xref rid="b37-1040835" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>
 </sup> A second limitation of the study is that the small numbers of patients with chronic GvHD in the UCB and Haplo/PTCY groups precluded a direct comparison of outcomes between these two groups. Third, we included both one-antigen and allele-mismatched unrelated donor peripheral blood stem cell recipients irrespective of the "direction” of mismatching. However, there was no significant difference in incidence of chronic GvHD between these mismatched unrelated donor groups (
 <italic>data not shown</italic>), consistent with the results of a large, previous study from the Center for International Blood and Marrow Transplant Research.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b38-1040835" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>
 </sup> Fourth, the incidence of chronic GvHD in the 1-mMUD group in our study may not be representative of results with T-cell depleted 1-mMUD grafts.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b26-1040835" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>,
  <xref rid="b34-1040835" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>,
  <xref rid="b39-1040835" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>,
  <xref rid="b40-1040835" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>
 </sup> Moreover, considering that mobilized blood stem cells were the graft source used for the 1-mMUD HCT group in our study, the risk and morbidity of chronic GvHD with unrelated donor bone marrow grafting might not differ from those for UCB or Haplo/PTCY HCT. Fifth, we were unable to assess quality of life in this study, because very few patients had outcomes based on validated measurement instruments. Sixth, the duration of immunosuppression may be driven ultimately by the selection of stem cell sources associated with a higher risk of severe chronic GvHD (i.e., unrelated mobilized blood cells) or with a lower risk of severe chronic GvHD (i.e., UCB or Haplo/PTCY). Seventh, some manifestations of chronic GvHD may have been underreported in this retrospective study (e.g., genital or lung involvement) Lastly, the analysis of functional endpoints at 3 years is limited by the small numbers.
</p>
