<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>At the RP2D, twice‐weekly ixazomib‐Rd was associated with a high ORR (95%) in patients with NDMM; in particular, the CR + VGPR rate (phase 2 primary endpoint) was 68%. Responses were rapid in onset and deepened with increasing duration of treatment. Approximately one‐third of patients discontinued early to undergo ASCT, thereby potentially limiting further deepening of responses in these patients. Response rates with twice‐weekly ixazomib‐Rd are similar to those seen with weekly ixazomib‐Rd (ORR, 92%; ≥VGPR 58%) (Kumar 
 <italic>et al</italic>, 
 <xref rid="bjh15394-bib-0029" ref-type="ref">2014b</xref>). Although cross‐trial comparisons should be interpreted with caution, these response rates and PFS are also similar to those seen with other triplet regimens incorporating a proteasome inhibitor and an immunomodulatory drug in NDMM (Richardson 
 <italic>et al</italic>, 
 <xref rid="bjh15394-bib-0041" ref-type="ref">2010</xref>; Kumar 
 <italic>et al</italic>, 
 <xref rid="bjh15394-bib-0027" ref-type="ref">2012</xref>; Dytfeld 
 <italic>et al</italic>, 
 <xref rid="bjh15394-bib-0013" ref-type="ref">2014</xref>; Durie 
 <italic>et al</italic>, 
 <xref rid="bjh15394-bib-0012" ref-type="ref">2017</xref>). Furthermore, responses were long‐lasting, with a median DOR of 36·9 months. The overall rate of MRD negativity in response‐evaluable patients who achieved CR, sCR, VGPR or nCR was 23%. Other studies in NDMM have reported MRD‐negativity rates of around 40% for triplet regimens including a proteasome inhibitor and an immunomodulatory agent. In NDMM patients treated with KRd, with median follow‐up of 13 months and median treatment duration of 12 cycles, MRD‐negativity was seen in 20/22 patients with CR or suspected CR (including nCR) for an MRD‐negativity rate in all response‐evaluable patients (
 <italic>n </italic>=
 <italic> </italic>53) of 38% (Jakubowiak 
 <italic>et al</italic>, 
 <xref rid="bjh15394-bib-0022" ref-type="ref">2012</xref>). In 98 NDMM patients treated with bortezomib in combination with thalidomide and dexamethasone with or without cyclophosphamide, with median follow‐up of approximately 65 months, 42 patients (43%) with &gt;PR, including 34 patients (35%) with bone‐marrow confirmed CR, were MRD‐negative (Ludwig 
 <italic>et al</italic>, 
 <xref rid="bjh15394-bib-0033" ref-type="ref">2015</xref>). However, any comparison of these findings must be interpreted with caution given differences in treatment regimen, duration of follow‐up, timing of MRD assessment, the numbers of patients tested and the sensitivity of the MRD assays used. For example, considering treatment regimen, in the Jakubowiak 
 <italic>et al</italic> study, patients could receive maintenance therapy with KRd for up to 24 cycles, and in the Ludwig 
 <italic>et al</italic> study 90% of patients underwent ASCT following initial treatment with 4 cycles of bortezomib plus thalidomide and dexamethasone +/‐ cyclophosphamide (Jakubowiak 
 <italic>et al</italic>, 
 <xref rid="bjh15394-bib-0022" ref-type="ref">2012</xref>; Ludwig 
 <italic>et al</italic>, 
 <xref rid="bjh15394-bib-0033" ref-type="ref">2015</xref>).
</p>
