<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Patients aged 18–70 years (both males and females) with chronic mid-portion AT (defined by pain and tender swelling in mid-portion of AT, &gt;1 cm proximal to the insertion), with symptoms for longer than 6 months who have failed conservative treatment (at least a full course of physiotherapy) and for whom surgery is being considered. All participants must be able to provide written informed consent. Females of childbearing age and potential must be willing to use two forms of effective contraception from the time of consent to 6 months postinjection (
 <xref ref-type="boxed-text" rid="B1">box 1</xref>).
 <boxed-text id="B1" position="float" orientation="portrait">
  <label>Box 1</label>
  <caption>
   <title>Inclusion and exclusion criteria for the study</title>
  </caption>
  <sec>
   <title>Inclusion criteria:</title>
   <list list-type="order">
    <list-item>
     <p>Aged ≥18 and ≤70 years (both males and females).</p>
    </list-item>
    <list-item>
     <p>Participants with chronic mid-portion Achilles tendinopathy (AT) (as defined by pain in region of AT and tender swelling in mid-portion of the AT with symptoms for longer than 6 months who have failed conservative treatment (at least a full course of physiotherapy) and for whom surgery is being considered.</p>
    </list-item>
    <list-item>
     <p>Able to provide written informed consent.</p>
    </list-item>
    <list-item>
     <p>Females of childbearing age and potential must be willing to use two forms of effective contraception from the time of consent to 6 months postinjection.</p>
    </list-item>
   </list>
  </sec>
  <sec>
   <title>Exclusion criteria:</title>
   <list list-type="order">
    <list-item>
     <p>Previous bony surgery (eg, reconstructive pelvic osteotomy) at or in proximity to the bone marrow harvest site.</p>
    </list-item>
    <list-item>
     <p>Pregnancy or lactation (self-declaration at screening visit with follow-up urine pregnancy test to be confirmed not beyond 7 days prior to mesenchymal stem cell (MSC) harvest and administration).</p>
    </list-item>
    <list-item>
     <p>Current use of steroids, antitumour necrosis factor drugs, methotrexate or ciprofloxacin (or use within 4 weeks of assessment for eligibility).</p>
    </list-item>
    <list-item>
     <p>Positive for hepatitis B virus, hepatitis C virus, HIV-1 and HIV-2, syphilis and human T-cell lymphotropic virus.</p>
    </list-item>
    <list-item>
     <p>Previous AT surgery on the tendon to receive MSC implantation.</p>
    </list-item>
    <list-item>
     <p>Inflammatory arthritis.</p>
    </list-item>
    <list-item>
     <p>Known or suspected underlying haematological malignancy.</p>
    </list-item>
    <list-item>
     <p>Other active malignancy in the past 3 years.</p>
    </list-item>
    <list-item>
     <p>Bovine or antibiotic allergy (since these are in the culture medium).</p>
    </list-item>
   </list>
  </sec>
 </boxed-text>
</p>
