<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par21">Connect MM is the first and largest prospective registry of patients with NDMM in the USA. The collection of longitudinal data on clinical practice and treatment outcomes in both clinical and nonclinical trial settings among patients predominantly treated in community-based practices provides a rich understanding of real-world clinical practices. Because of the large volume of data, findings from this study reflect real-world clinical practice; therefore, the generalizability of findings and potential to inform patient care represent major strengths. Registry study analyses can be confounded by limitations in data entry or data reporting and by the observational, nonrandomized nature of the study. Since these patients were treated at their physicians’ discretion, using HRQoL assessments collected immediately prior to the initiation of maintenance therapy could increase the variability of HRQoL scores among patients; therefore, analytical baseline for HRQoL assessments was immediately prior to ASCT. Post-baseline assessments began at 100 days post-ASCT and were conducted quarterly. However, our post-baseline completion rates for HRQoL instruments (ranging from 56 to 82% for EQ-5D through Quarter 8) were similar to those reported in a phase 3 clinical trial (MM-015) of lenalidomide maintenance therapy versus no maintenance therapy after lenalidomide-melphalan-prednisone treatment in older patients (aged ≥ 65 years) with newly diagnosed MM [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>], as well as in a phase 3 trial (MM-020) of lenalidomide-dexamethasone versus melphalan-prednisone-thalidomide in newly diagnosed MM (EQ-5D 65–92% through month 18; data on file). Another limitation of this study is that the impact of AEs on PROs was not assessed. Finally, there is a drop-off in patients with clinical and HRQoL data during the follow-up period (as is expected for a registry study); however, patient demographics and disease characteristics were similar at baseline between those completing and not completing HRQoL assessments.
</p>
