<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The length of the illness varies from patient to patient. It can vary between 7 and 15 days when there are single aphthae, but the illness can go on for up to a month if there are multiple aphthae. In the most serious cases a scar can form where the lesion was, but this tends to disappear in time. The aphthae are not contagious, and a differential diagnosis has to be made considering simple herpes, other autoimmune diseases such as Vulgaris Pemphigus, viral diseases, candidiasis, ACLE (acute cutaneous lupus erythematosus), Allergic Contact Dermatitis, Cancers of the Oral Mucosa, Cicatricial Pemphigoid, Contact Stomatitis, Mucosae Aspects of Behcet's Disease, Oral Mucosae Manifestations of Gastrointestinal Disease, Oral Mucosae Manifestations of Hand-Foot-and-Mouth Disease, Oral Mucosae Manifestations of Hematologic Disease, Drug-Induced Bullous Disorders, Drug-Induced Lupus Erythematosus, Drug-Induced Pemphigus, Erythema Multiforme, IgA Pemphigus, Irritant Contact Dermatitis, Langerhans Cell Histiocytosis, Lichen Planus, Linear IgA Dermatosis, Paraneoplastic Pemphigus, and Pediatric Syphilis [
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]. The aphthous lesions are not caused by a virus. The causes are not well known even though it seems likely that it is a disorder of the bacterial flora in the oral cavity associated with immunity problems. Among the factors that raise the risk of developing aphthae are contact of the mucosal membrane with dirty objects and domestic animals [
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]. Aphthae can be caused by many situations among which are stress, poor oral hygiene, disorder of the bacterial flora in the intestine, immune deficiency, lack of iron and zinc, and lack of vitamins from the "B” group [
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>–
 <xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>].
</p>
