<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>For patients with previous history of lumbar disc herniation, the symptoms of neuralgia caused by herpes zoster are very similar to those of lumbar disc herniation, and it is very easy to be confused by ignoring the inquiry of medical history, physical examination, and differential diagnosis, leading to wrong diagnosis and therapeutic error, or even Performing the operation mistakenly. The characteristic of sciatic herpes zoster is the absence of LBP. In LDH, the patient often complains LBP to some degree (
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>). It was reported that LBP in LDH may be caused by multiple factors such as discogenic LBP, radicular LBP that is relieved by nerve root decompression, and the LBP due to endplate degeneration (
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>). Most patients with lumbar disc herniation will have paresthesia, but this patient has no paresthesia on foot. In addition, symptoms are not relieved by rest or change of posture, but are persistent pain. These findings do not support the diagnosis of lumbar disc herniation. This patient did not have back pain and paresthesia on foot on admission this time which did not support the diagnosis of lumbar disc herniation. For pathologic neuralgia caused by herpes zoster, it also has its own unique symptoms and signs: lower limb pain does not relieve or aggravate due to changes in body posture or limb position; After the onset of sciatic nerve transit area, skin lesions such as skin rash gradually appeared. Pain in the lower extremities always show as knife-cutting. Patients often have a history of fatigue, infection and decreased immunity. Collecting medical history comprehensively, repeatedly performing physical examination, and not missing each suspicious symptom will help us to confirm the diagnosis, and to avoid misdiagnosis and missed diagnosis. This is a case report that described a case of suspected lumbar disc herniation with sciatic herpes zoster to reduce the rate of misdiagnosis. The major limitation of the present article is not case series but single case report. The lower extremity sciatic herpes zoster with previous history of LDH is rare clinically. When we have accumulated some cases, we will further analyze the onset characteristics of sciatic herpes zoster in the form of case series.
</p>
