<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Interestingly, the attribute of "clinical strength/expertise” was labeled by participants as a branding attribute. Later discussions by the project team led to the realization that perhaps this attribute should have been considered a generic attribute, as all training programs would intend to train excellent clinicians and so this attribute does not necessarily contribute to brand identity 
 <italic>per se</italic>. Given UT's history as an institution with a significant research focus, it was somewhat surprising that scholarship was ranked fourth out of the five branding attributes, as it might have been anticipated to be more highly ranked. We note that we strove to involve respondents from a variety of Divisional sites, including affiliated community-based sites, which may explain the relative value placed on clinical abilities over scholarship in this iteration of the ranking. This serves as a lesson for those considering a brand development process that is collaborative and influenced by organizational culture – that it is important to gather a wide range of opinions and use established methodology such as a paired comparison to develop the actionable brand. Finally, the idea of leadership ranking so highly was initially questioned by some faculty members, who were concerned that selecting for future leaders would result in narrowing applicants to those with administrative or academic leadership aspirations. However, we would argue that the operationalization of leadership can and should be sufficiently broad as to enhance diversity and richness by selecting applicants who have the potential for formal and informal leadership in a wide variety of spheres including, but not limited to, research, advocacy, systems change, education, and equity. We anticipate that many graduates may not end up in formal leadership roles, but will still benefit from leadership skills that they can apply within their practices and the health care system.
</p>
