<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ack>
 <title>Acknowledgements</title>
 <p>We thank all participating (research) nurses and physicians at all trial sites and the PACER trial participants.</p>
 <p>Study collaborative:</p>
 <p>
  <sup>5</sup>A van Leent, MD, Department of Intensive Care
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>6</sup>M Koeman, MD, PhD, Department of Intensive Care Medicine
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>6</sup>PF Ypma, MD, PhD, Department of Haematology
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>7</sup>MS Arbous, MD, PhD, Department of Intensive Care
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>8</sup> AMP Demandt, MD, PhD, Department of Haematology
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>8</sup>WNKA van Mook, MD, PhD, Department of Intensive Care
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>8</sup>JHM Tordoir, MD, PhD, Department of Surgery
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>9</sup>E Wolthuis, MD, PhD, Department of Intensive Care
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>10</sup>JGAM Blomjous, MD, Department of Interventional Radiology
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>10</sup>RM Determann, MD, PhD, Department of Intensive Care
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>10</sup>H Endeman, MD, PhD, Department of Intensive Care
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>10</sup>ED Kerver, MD, PhD, Department of Haematology
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>11</sup>WJFM van der Velden, MD, PhD, Department of Haematology
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>12</sup>R Vink, MD, PhD, Department of Intensive Care
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>13</sup>RPH Bokkers, MD, PhD Department of Interventional Radiology
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>13</sup>ABU Mäkelburg, MD, PhD, Department of Haematology
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>13</sup>WM van den Bergh, MD, PhD, Department of Intensive Care
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>14</sup>PR Tuinman, MD, PhD, Department of Intensive Care
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>5</sup>Albert Schweitzer Hospital, Dordrecht
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>6</sup>HAGA Teaching Hospital, the Hague
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>7</sup>Leiden University Medical Centre, Leiden
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>8</sup>Maastricht University Medical Centre, Maastricht
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>9</sup>Netherlands Cancer Institute, Amsterdam
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>10</sup>Onze Lieve Vrouwe Gasthuis, Amsterdam
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>11</sup>Radboud University Medical Centre, Nijmegen
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>12</sup>Tergooiziekenhuizen, Hilversum
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>13</sup>University Medical Center Groningen, Groningen
 </p>
 <p>
  <sup>14</sup>VU University Medical Center, Amsterdam
 </p>
 <sec id="FPar1">
  <title>Funding</title>
  <p id="Par62">Funding source: This study is an investigator-initiated trial, funded by ZonMW (Zorgonderzoek Medische Wetenschappen) (part of the NWO (Nederlandse Organisatie voor Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek; the Dutch Organisation for Scientific Research), Den Haag, The Netherlands).</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="FPar2">
  <title>Availability of data and materials</title>
  <p id="Par63">Data will be available from the corresponding author on reasonable request. The trial will be reported in peer-reviewed journals.</p>
 </sec>
</ack>
