<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Motor dysfunction in PD has been attributed to the loss of dopaminergic innervation in the caudate nuclei. Notably, however, the reduced RAC binding we have observed here in the patients’ caudate nuclei after bilateral putaminal NPC grafting does not appear to be related to enhanced motor performance. P1, for example, showed the greatest RAC uptake decrease in the caudate nuclei (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3-0963689718820271">Fig. 3</xref>) compared with baseline without motor function improvement (UPDRS III). Furthermore, although it is becoming increasingly clear that this striatal structure may have an even greater role in patients’ neuropsychological condition
 <sup>
  <xref rid="bibr66-0963689718820271" ref-type="bibr">66</xref>
 </sup>, P1’s neuropsychological scores at both his 1- and 2-year post-surgery evaluations also remained basically unchanged. Therefore, it may be reasonable to speculate that reduced post-surgery RAC does not necessarily signify enhanced endogenous dopamine availability (as we suggest occurs in the putamen to explain motor function improvement), but rather an inability of the ligand to bind to down-regulated post-synaptic D2 receptors in the caudate nuclei
 <sup>
  <xref rid="bibr67-0963689718820271" ref-type="bibr">67</xref>
 </sup>. D2 receptor down-regulation has been attributed to chronic dopaminergic therapy or to the need for structural adaptation of the post-synaptic dopaminergic system in response to the progressive loss of nigrostriatal neurons. In fact, the increasing loss of DTBZ uptake in the caudate nuclei of all our grafted patients at their 1- and 2-year post-surgery PET evaluations suggests significant pre-synaptic deterioration, greater in fact than that seen in the putamen (contrary to the PD subjects described by Bohnen et al.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="bibr52-0963689718820271" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>
 </sup>). This state of neurodegeneration in the caudate nuclei of our patients is further supported by the decreased levels of FDOPA uptake (an index of dopaminergic pre-synaptic nerve terminal activity) at all times 1 and 2 years post-surgery for patients P2 and P4; patient P7 showed a short-lived 20% rise in FDOPA uptake 1 year after surgery but then a 65% loss (the greatest loss in the group) at his 2-year follow-up.
</p>
