<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>This work's most notable strength is its inclusion of an international expert panel. We had a high response rate. However, our sampling approach might have resulted in underrepresentation of IS experts from Canada or Australia and underrepresentation from some regions (e.g., Africa, Asia, or South America) as we were not able to identify IS experts in the latter continents. Our difficulty to identify experts in certain parts of the world might point to the major potential for IS activities in those areas (
 <xref rid="B28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>). Further, we carefully selected our 12 pre-defined journals based on a prior systematic literature search. However, as mentioned by our experts, the survey list focused almost exclusively on IS-specific journals, excluding subject-specific journals, which are also publishing increasingly articles on IS. To maintain a flexible perspective, we provided a free text box to add further journals perceived as relevant by the experts. But no major additions appeared, despite the journals Implementation Science Communications and Administration and Policy in Mental Health and Mental Health Services Research. By that, our search strategy provides a very pragmatic approach to assessing relevant IS evidence effectively. To ensure a more comprehensive identification of specific subject related IS studies, further journals might be added to our list. In that regard, a network analysis might be an objective way forward to evaluate journal's influences and relationships. Network analysis requires a subset of all possible IS-related journals. However, identification of all relevant journals through a literature search in a field as scattered and as fast evolving than IS would be prohibitive. Therefore, our list of ranked journals might inform network analysis about IS journals as already published in the field of information systems (
 <xref rid="B30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>). In accordance with the regulations of the University Ethics Committee, our survey was anonymized. Therefore, we were not able to account for non-response bias, i.e., to assess how respondents vary from non-respondents, which might potentially bias the results.
</p>
