<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A 69-year-old Chinese man with a 30-pack year smoking history presented with cough and decreased hemoglobin levels and platelet counts. The patient had a history of myelodysplastic syndrome and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Chest computed tomography (CT) performed in June 2019 showed right upper central lung cancer with right upper obstructive atelectasis, right hilar and mediastinal lymph node enlargement, and mild right-sided pleural effusion. No metastasis was observed on magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of the brain and emission computed tomography (ECT) of the bone. Serum levels of the tumor markers: carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA) and neuron-specific enolase (NSE) were within normal range. Fiberoptic bronchoscopy revealed a new biological blockage in the right main bronchus. The patient underwent neoplasm excision and stent implantation in the right main bronchus. Finally, the patient was diagnosed with stage IVa squamous cell carcinoma of the lung with a PD-L1 tumor proportion score (TPS) ≥50%. He received sintilimab, a PD-1 inhibitor, as the first-line treatment in July 2019 for PD-L1 overexpression. After two cycles of sintilimab therapy, CT showed a massive right-sided pleural effusion, which increased significantly in August 2019. However, the patient did not have any clinical symptoms such as fever or cough. Hence, two more cycles of sintilimab were administered. A follow-up CT was performed in September 2019; it showed that the patient had achieved partial response, and the right lung atelectasis and right-sided pleural effusion had regressed. However, the patient developed systemic edema, and experienced huge decrease in hemoglobin levels and platelet counts; CT showed that the right lung mass and obstructive atelectasis of the right lung had progressed at October 2019. Moreover, NSE levels were high (302.3 ng/ml, normal range 0.0–30.0 ng/ml). A bone marrow biopsy showed tumor cells that were positive for synaptophysin (Syn), chromogranin A (CgA), and CD45, suggestive of SCLC. The patient died of respiratory failure, severe anemia, and severe thrombocytopenia (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
  <bold>Figure 1</bold>
 </xref>).
</p>
