<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The ideal methodology for assessing this risk of hippocampal (or HAZ) metastases would be a close observation of patients with BM treated with HA-WBRT and followed with regular imaging. Considering the relatively low incidence of hippocampal metastases in general, a high number of patients treated by this complex RT technique would be needed to report data with sufficient power. Even more patients would be needed considering the aim of our study to describe the potential difference in laterality of hippocampal metastatic seeding (what means to divide enrolled patients into cohorts). Given the current absence of such a dataset in available literature before ongoing trials will be published, the retrospective review of large cohort of radiotherapy-naïve patients was chosen as the best possible approach currently to estimate the hippocampal and HAZ metastases incidence before eventual initiation of trials of unilateral hippocampal sparing. This approach of using treated patient data retrospectively for an analysis also seems to be ethically preferable comparing to the straightforward treatment of patients with unilateral hippocampal sparing WBRT and the evaluation of the development of BM in spared region in follow-up. With this retrospective description of the distribution of metastases, it can be at least estimated what is the risk of hippocampal (or HAZ) failure after HA-WBRT. Recently, in a pooled analysis of available data, we summarized the incidence of BM in 1557 patients from listed studies [
 <xref rid="B24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>–
 <xref rid="B30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>] and calculated that BM is present within hippocampi in 1.6% of patients and within HAZ in 9%, representing 0.6% and 2.8% of all BM, respectively [
 <xref rid="B31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>]. In comparison to this pooled analysis, we observed in the current study a much higher incidence of BM within hippocampus (in 7.7% patients representing 1.1% of all BM) as well as in HAZ (in 18.1% of patients representing 3.3% of all BM). This higher incidence observed in our unselected real-practice cohort may be explained by a relatively high mean number of BM (mean number of 10 BM compared to a mean of 4.5 BM in pooled analysis) with many patients presented initially with multiple BM disease. In another recent descriptive analysis of consecutive series of 2419 patients with BM treated at the Medical University of Vienna between 1990 and 2011, 48.7% of patients presented with a singular BM, 27.7% with 2–3, and 23.5% with &gt;3 BM [
 <xref rid="B32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>]. The corresponding percentages in our current study are as follows: 36%, 22%, and 42%, respectively. Some patients are referred to our radiotherapy department from relatively distant tertiary outpatient oncology practices, some with less availability and throughput of MRI devices, potentially explaining the lower number of limited brain disease in our cohort that contributed to relatively higher hippocampal involvement. Regardless of a possibly high incidence of BM observed in our study, progression in the HAZ area was very rare in patients from the prospective RTOG 0933 trial, which reported progression within HAZ in only 3 out of 67 progressed patients (4.5%) after a radiotherapy performed with sparing of both hippocampi [
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]. Altogether, despite these promising safety profile of RTOG 0933 and despite reported cases of advantageous usage of hippocampal sparing in real clinical practice, some controversy remains, especially regarding the safety of this method with concerns about undertreatment of HA regions [
 <xref rid="B33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]. The superiority of HA-WBRT in the management of patients with BM and the potential update in current standards of care will need to be confirmed within prospective randomized trials, most notably in the above-mentioned NRG CC001-NCT02360215 trial or NRG-CC003-NCT02635009 (A Randomized Phase II/III Trial of Prophylactic Cranial Irradiation with or without Hippocampal Avoidance for Small Cell Lung Cancer). In the meantime, this approach should be considered experimental and utilized only in individually selected cases with a required planning MRI for hippocampi contouring as well as for the exclusion of potential small BM within hippocampi or HAZ [
 <xref rid="B34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>].
</p>
