<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>We acknowledge several limitations of our study apart from its self-limiting retrospective nature, disallowing for example standardization of MRI, which should be ideally volumetric and standardized at baseline in order not to miss small lesion. The other limitations are mitigated by the analysis of location of centre of BM. With the generally spherical shape of BM, the centre of BM represents the site of initial focal growth of a micrometastasis. Whether this centre is placed within hippocampi or HAZ, in this particular patient, the focal point of metastatic settlement is inside the part of brain which would be spared in HA treatment approach (for example in previous HA prophylactic brain irradiation). On the other hand, the patient with a large metastasis within the left temporal lobe presented in the 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">Figure 1</xref> would be also classified as hippocampal since the border of BM touches the edge of the hippocampus. However, the spot where its centre is located is clearly outside the eventually undertreated HAZ and would receive a full dose of radiation (for example in previous HA prophylactic brain irradiation). Metastases in both outlined cases can be labelled as "hippocampal” but with different consequences behind, resolved by the analysis of the location of centres of metastases. Thus, discrimination between the centre of a mass and the border of a mass is necessary to comprehensively assess the risk of undertreating patients with HA-WBRT and would provide additional information in other ongoing trials as well. In our analysis of centres of BM, we observed interesting difference in patients with different number of centres of MTS in the right and left sides, where more patients presented with the centre of BM within left versus right HAZ (15 versus 6 patients; p = 0.07). These patients warrant further study including the analysis of potential changes in cerebral blood supply. Thus, the most reliable feature of our study is probably this analysis of the centre of BM mass.
</p>
