<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Following LC-MS/MS analyses, the raw data were inputted into the Progenesis QI 2.3 (Non-linear Dynamics, Waters, USA) for peak picking and alignment. Mass spectra of these metabolic characteristics were discerned through the accurate mass, MS/MS fragments spectra, and isotope ratio difference, by scanning in public available biochemical databases such as the Human Metabolome Database (HMDB) (
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.hmdb.ca/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">http://www.hmdb.ca/</ext-link>) and the Metlin database (
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://metlin.scripps.edu/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">https://metlin.scripps.edu/</ext-link>). A multivariate statistical analysis was conducted using "ropls” (Version 1.6.2, 
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://bioconductor.org/packages/release/bioc/html/ropls.html" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">http://bioconductor.org/packages/release/bioc/html/ropls.html</ext-link>) R package from Bioconductor on Majorbio Cloud Platform (
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://cloud.majorbio.com" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">https://cloud.majorbio.com</ext-link>). Principal component analysis (PCA) was applied to check outliers and present trends. Partial least squares discriminate analysis (PLS-DA) was used to identify the general metabolic changes in serum of sheep between high and low ADG. Variable importance in the projection (VIP) was computed by an orthogonal partial least squares discriminate analysis (OPLS-DA) model. Differential metabolites among ESI groups were summarized and annotated into their biochemical pathways through metabolic enrichment and pathway analysis based on database matching (KEGG, 
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.genome.jp/kegg/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">http://www.genome.jp/kegg/</ext-link>). Furthermore, Volcano plot was used to compare the size of the fold change to statistical significance.
</p>
