<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>It is well-documented that elite endurance athletes are characterized by having up to 40% higher levels of total hemoglobin mass (Hb
 <sub>mass</sub>) than untrained subjects (Kjellberg et al., 
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">1949</xref>). Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> strongly correlates with maximal oxygen uptake in endurance national team athletes (Schmidt and Prommer, 
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">2008</xref>), and there is a strong correlation between Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> and endurance performance, even in groups of highly-trained endurance athletes (Hauser et al., 
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>; Zelenkova et al., 
 <xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">2019b</xref>). Several studies (Wehrlin and Marti, 
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">2006</xref>; Wehrlin et al., 
 <xref rid="B17" ref-type="bibr">2006</xref>; Hauser et al., 
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>) have demonstrated that Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> in elite athletes increases temporarily with altitude training, but the variation of Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> over a training season is minimal (Garvican et al., 
 <xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">2010</xref>). In addition, long-term endurance training (without altitude training) in elite athletes does not increase Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> (Wehrlin et al., 
 <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>) and Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> in elite endurance athletes remains constant over many years (Wehrlin et al., 
 <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">2016</xref>). Therefore, the high Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> of elite athletes is more likely to originate from a specific genetic predisposition than from endurance training (Bouchard et al., 
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1999</xref>; Steiner et al., 
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>). We previously hypothesized that we could measure Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> in endurance athletes at age 16 to identify talent for endurance disciplines. In the first study (Steiner and Wehrlin, 
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">2011</xref>), we compared cross-sectional data of Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> in cross-country skiers and triathletes at age 16 with Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> in national team athletes at ages 19 and 28 elite national team athletes. While the Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> measurements at ages 19 and 28 were similarly high, at age 16, athletes had 30% lower values, which did not differ from their age-matched untrained controls (Steiner and Wehrlin, 
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">2011</xref>). Therefore, we hypothesized that Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> increases with endurance training in adolescents between ages 16 and 19 (Steiner and Wehrlin, 
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">2011</xref>). In a follow-up longitudinal study, we continued our Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> measurements at age 16 athletes and controls for an additional 3 years (Steiner et al., 
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>). Contrary to our hypothesis, there was no difference in the level of body weight related Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> between athletes and those in the control group at ages 16 and 19. Furthermore, Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> increased to the same extent in the endurance athlete group as in the untrained control group, and there was no correlation between the amount of endurance training and the increase in Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> (Steiner et al., 
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>). Interestingly, there was a wide range in the Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> level at ages 16 and 19, and the level of Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> at age 16 was an important predictor for Hb
 <sub>mass</sub> and performance at age 19 (Steiner et al., 
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>).
</p>
