<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Recently, treatment-free remission (TFR) has been proposed as a goal for CML treatment.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b5-1031835" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>–
  <xref rid="b7-1031835" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>
 </sup> Indeed, prospective trials have indicated that imatinib therapy can be successfully discontinued in CML patients who have maintained a DMR for at least 2 years.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b8-1031835" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>–
  <xref rid="b10-1031835" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>
 </sup> In these prospective trials, the TFR rate was 43% [95% confidence interval (CI): 33–52%] at 6 months
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b9-1031835" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>
 </sup> and 41% (95% CI: 29–52%) at 12 months in the STIM1 trial,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b8-1031835" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>
 </sup> while the TWISTER study revealed a TFR rate of 47.1% (95% CI: 31.5–62.7%) at 24 months.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b10-1031835" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>
 </sup> Moreover, the first TFR study of second-generation TKI, the DADI trial reported by Imagawa 
 <italic>et al.</italic>, showed that second-generation TKI therapy can be successfully discontinued.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b11-1031835" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>
 </sup> In this trial, all patients received dasatinib consolidation therapy for at least 1 year. The estimated TFR rate was 49% (95% CI: 36–61%) at 6 months.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b11-1031835" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>
 </sup> On the other hand, the ENESTfreedom study, which is a TFR study following frontline nilotinib treatment, required that all patients sustained DMR during the consolidation phase with nilotinib for 1 year. The TFR rate at 48 weeks was 51.6% (95% CI: 44.2–58.9%).
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b12-1031835" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>
 </sup> Although the DMR in the consolidation phase with a second-generation TKI was sustained in both the DADI trial and the ENESTfreedom study, the TFR rate was not superior to those in the previously reported imatinib TFR studies.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b8-1031835" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>–
  <xref rid="b10-1031835" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>
 </sup> Most relapses occurred within 6 months of discontinuing second-generation TKI or imatinib therapy, and there was no disease progression in patients with molecular relapse after discontinuation.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b8-1031835" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>–
  <xref rid="b12-1031835" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>
 </sup> All patients who relapsed remained sensitive to TKI re-treatment in these TFR studies.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b8-1031835" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>–
  <xref rid="b12-1031835" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
