<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par6">The study enrolled patients, 18 years of age or older, with newly diagnosed MM fulfilling the IMWG criteria for symptomatic MM and who have not received any prior therapy for myeloma. Patients were required to have measurable disease (serum M-protein ≥ 1 g/dL or urine M-protein ≥ 200 mg/24 h or involved free light chain level ≥ 10 mg/dL provided the serum free light chain ratio was abnormal), Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance status of 0–2, adequate hematologic (absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1000/mm
 <sup>3</sup>, platelets ≥ 75,000/mm
 <sup>3</sup>), hepatic (total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 × upper limit of normal [ULN], alanine/aspartate aminotransferase ≤ 3 × ULN), and renal (creatinine clearance ≥ 30 mL/min) function. Patients with grade ≥ 3 peripheral neuropathy or grade 2 with pain, grade &gt; 1 diarrhea, or who had major surgery or serious infection within 14 days prior to start of therapy were excluded. Patients receiving systemic treatment with strong CYP1A2 inhibitors or strong inhibitors/inducers of CYP3A within 14 days were excluded. Other factors that precluded participation in the trial included uncontrolled cardiovascular conditions (including uncontrolled hypertension, uncontrolled cardiac arrhythmias, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina, or myocardial infarction within the past 6 months), known human immunodeficiency virus infection, known hepatitis B surface antigen-positive status, or known or suspected active hepatitis C infection, and known allergy to any of the study medications, their analogs, or excipients in the various formulations. Other comorbidities or severe pre-existing illness that in the treating physician's opinion could interfere with oral absorption and/or tolerance of ixazomib citrate excluded patients from participation. Patients were characterized as having high-risk genetics if they had one of the following abnormalities on FISH testing: t(4;14), t(14;16), t(14;20) or del17p.
</p>
