,file,parsed,entities,labels,position_start,position_end
PMC6856665,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC6856665\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by Ethics Committee of Endocrinology and Metabolism Research Institute of Tehran University of Medical Sciences (Code: EC-00214).,"[Ethics Committee of Endocrinology, Metabolism Research Institute, Tehran University of Medical Sciences (Code]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 84, 117]","[79, 113, 160]"
PMC6877543,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC6877543\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the University of Ceara Hospital Research Ethics Board (Protocol no. 1886743). The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[the University of Ceara Hospital Research Ethics Board, 1886743]","['ORG', 'DATE']","[71, 140]","[125, 147]"
PMC6927906,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC6927906\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,We used an established protocol for cell isolation. When informed and written consent was given extracted third molars were used to prepare fibroblasts from the dental pulp. The protocol was approved by the Ethics committee of the Medical University of Vienna (631/2007).,"[third, Ethics, the Medical University of Vienna]","['ORDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[106, 207, 227]","[111, 213, 259]"
PMC7008714,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7008714\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Finnish National Supervisory Authority for Welfare (Dnro V/74832/2017, V/3235/2019) and Health and the ethics committees of Helsinki University Central Hospital (382/13/03/01/2014, HUS/114/2018) and Turku University Central Hospital (ETMK 78/2012). Samples and data from Spanish patients included in this study were provided by the IDIBGI Biobank (Biobanc IDIBGI, B.0000872), integrated in the Spanish National Biobanks Network, and they were processed following standard operating procedures with the appropriate approval of the ethics and scientific committees. Written informed consent from the participants' legal guardian/next of kin was not required to participate in this study in accordance with the national legislation and the institutional requirements.","[the Finnish National Supervisory Authority for Welfare, V/3235/2019, Health, Helsinki University Central Hospital, 382/13/03/01/2014, HUS/114/2018, Turku University Central Hospital, Spanish, the IDIBGI Biobank, Biobanc IDIBGI, B.0000872]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'NORP', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']","[71, 146, 163, 199, 237, 256, 274, 346, 403, 423, 439]","[125, 157, 169, 235, 254, 268, 307, 353, 421, 437, 448]"
PMC7040181,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7040181\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal experiments were performed in accordance with animal experimentation and ethics guidelines of the EU (2010/63/EU). Experimental protocols were approved by the Review Committee of Biological Research Centre and by the Joint Local Ethics and Animal Welfare Committee of Avidin Ltd., then by National Food Chain Safety Office Directorate of Animal Health and Animal Welfare (NÉBIH) in possession of an ethical clearance XXIX./128/2013.","[EU, 2010/63, EU, the Review Committee of Biological Research Centre, the Joint Local Ethics, Animal Welfare Committee, Avidin Ltd., National Food Chain Safety Office Directorate of Animal Health and Animal Welfare]","['ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[109, 113, 121, 166, 224, 251, 279, 300]","[111, 120, 123, 216, 246, 275, 290, 381]"
PMC7080866,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7080866\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by The ethics committee of Guangdong Provincial People’s Hospital.,[Guangdong Provincial People’s Hospital],['ORG'],[70],[108]
PMC7082878,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7082878\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Human Ethics Review Committee of the Israel Ministry of Health and the Tel-Aviv Medical Center. The ethics committee waived the requirement of written informed consent for participation.,"[Human Ethics Review Committee, the Israel Ministry of Health, the Tel-Aviv Medical Center]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 104, 138]","[100, 133, 165]"
PMC7096589,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7096589\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"Ethical approval was authorized through UCL Research Ethics Committee Office for the Vice Provost (0389/025: The internal representations of children and adolescents in care, 2017). Informed consent for participation was obtained from the children’s local authority social workers, Five Rivers supervising social workers and from the children’s foster carers/residential care team. The study was also covered by the UCL data protection registration.","[UCL Research Ethics Committee Office, 0389/025, 2017, Five, UCL]","['ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG']","[40, 99, 175, 282, 416]","[76, 107, 179, 286, 419]"
PMC7111464,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7111464\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by The Ethics Committee of the Peking University Health Science Center. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[The Ethics Committee of the Peking University Health Science Center],['ORG'],[71],[138]
PMC7142259,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7142259\sections\1_body\4_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by [Guangdong Women and Children Hospital Ethics committee]. The legal guardian of participants provided written informed consent to participate in this study.,[Guangdong Women and Children Hospital Ethics],['ORG'],[72],[116]
PMC7158757,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7158757\sections\1_body\4_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was done according to the Principle of Laboratory Animal Care (NIH Publication No. 85-23, revised 1985). The protocol was approved by the Animal Ethics Committee of Xinxiang Medical University.","[the Principle of Laboratory Animal Care, 85, 1985, the Animal Ethics Committee of Xinxiang Medical University]","['ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'ORG']","[39, 100, 115, 151]","[78, 102, 119, 209]"
PMC7174509,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7174509\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"Animal treatment protocols were approved by, and conducted in accordance with, animal welfare regulations of the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee of the Medical College of Georgia.","[the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee of the Medical College of, Georgia]","['ORG', 'GPE']","[109, 183]","[182, 190]"
PMC7193700,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7193700\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by The Institutional Review Board and Ethics Committee of Henan University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[The Institutional Review Board, Ethics Committee of Henan University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 106]","[101, 142]"
PMC7198785,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7198785\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethical committee of Northern and Central Switzerland (2015-00191). The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[Ethical, Central Switzerland, 2015-00191]","['ORG', 'LOC', 'DATE']","[71, 105, 126]","[78, 124, 136]"
PMC7201129,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7201129\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethics committee for Human Medical Research (KU Leuven). The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[Ethics, Human Medical Research]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 92]","[77, 114]"
PMC7203781,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7203781\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by Landesamt für Gesundheit und Soziales Berlin (LAGeSo) Turmstr. 21 10559 Berlin Germany.,"[Landesamt, Soziales Berlin, 21 10559, Berlin Germany]","['PERSON', 'GPE', 'DATE', 'GPE']","[46, 75, 109, 118]","[55, 90, 117, 132]"
PMC7206980,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7206980\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The Erasmus MC Medical Ethics Committee approved this availability without the need for informed consent, based on the use of fully anonymized remaining diagnostic material without the patient being subjected to additional risk or medical procedures. All animal experiments were approved by the Erasmus MCs Animal Ethics Committee.",[],[],[],[]
PMC7214627,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7214627\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethics Committees of Daping Hospital, Army Medical University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. The animal study was reviewed and approved by Ethics Committees of Daping Hospital, Army Medical University.","[Ethics Committees of Daping Hospital, Army Medical University, Ethics Committees of Daping Hospital, Army Medical University]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 109, 276, 314]","[107, 132, 312, 337]"
PMC7214803,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7214803\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,This study involve the use of human tissue collected from spontaneous miscarriages; tissue procurement was approved by the Ethical Commitee of Umbria’ Health Institutes (CEAS) and with written consent of mother.,[the Ethical Commitee of Umbria’ Health Institutes (CEAS],['ORG'],[119],[174]
PMC7220991,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7220991\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The study involving human participants was reviewed and approved by Cantonal Ethics Committee, Stampfenbachstrasse 121, 8090 Zurich, Switzerland (BASEC 2017-00128). The participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.","[Cantonal Ethics Committee, Stampfenbachstrasse, 121, 8090 Zurich, Switzerland, 2017-00128]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'CARDINAL', 'LOC', 'GPE', 'DATE']","[68, 95, 115, 120, 133, 152]","[93, 114, 118, 131, 144, 162]"
PMC7221066,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7221066\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"Our study involving human participants was reviewed and approved by the Human Research Ethics Committee affiliated to the Northern Sydney Local Health District, New South Wales government, Australia. The ethics committee reference number: RESP/15/314. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.","[the Human Research Ethics Committee, the Northern Sydney Local Health District, Australia]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']","[68, 118, 189]","[103, 159, 198]"
PMC7237746,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7237746\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee Jiangsu University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[the Ethics Committee Jiangsu University],['ORG'],[71],[110]
PMC7243121,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7243121\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Ethikkommission RUB. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[the Ethikkommission RUB],['ORG'],[71],[94]
PMC7261916,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7261916\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal studies were reviewed and approved by the University of Pennsylvania Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee and the University of Maryland Baltimore Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee.,"[the University of Pennsylvania Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee, the University of Maryland Baltimore Institutional Animal Care]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[49, 128]","[123, 190]"
PMC7263060,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7263060\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethical committee of Santa Chiara Hospital. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[Ethical, Santa Chiara Hospital]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 92]","[78, 113]"
PMC7272706,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7272706\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Ethical Commitee University of Rome Policlinico “Tor Vergata” number prot.0013157/2015. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[the Ethical Commitee University of Rome Policlinico],['ORG'],[71],[122]
PMC7273963,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7273963\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Danish National Committee on Health Research Ethics (H-15005137). The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[Danish National Committee on Health Research Ethics],['ORG'],[71],[122]
PMC7287171,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7287171\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The study involving human participants was approved by the Medical Ethics Committee at the Medical School, “G. d’Annunzio” University of Chieti-Pescara, Chieti, Italy (n°266 17 April 2014) and it is in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. All the subjects that were involved in the study gave their informed consent.","[the Medical Ethics Committee, the Medical School, Chieti, Italy, 17 April 2014, the Declaration of Helsinki]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'DATE', 'WORK_OF_ART']","[55, 87, 153, 161, 174, 218]","[83, 105, 159, 166, 187, 245]"
PMC7314920,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7314920\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Animal Care Committee of the Ottawa Hospital Research Institute. Written informed consent was obtained from the owners for the participation of their animals in this study. The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ottawa Health Science Network Research Ethics Board. Written informed consent to participate in this study was provided by the participants’ legal guardian/next of kin.,"[the Animal Care Committee of, the Ottawa Hospital Research Institute, Ottawa Health Science Network Research Ethics Board]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 75, 294]","[74, 113, 345]"
PMC7324629,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7324629\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by Temple University Animal Care and Use Committee.,[Temple University Animal Care and Use Committee],['ORG'],[46],[93]
PMC7326058,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7326058\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Subcommittee on Research and Animal Care (SRAC) of Central South University.,"[the Subcommittee on Research and Animal Care (SRAC, Central South University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 101]","[96, 125]"
PMC7327117,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7327117\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by The Ethics Committee of Vinmec International General Hospital Joint Stock Company. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[The Ethics Committee of Vinmec International General Hospital Joint Stock Company],['ORG'],[71],[152]
PMC7331483,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7331483\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Institutional Review Board of Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Institutional Review Board of Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology. Written informed consent was obtained from the individual(s) for the publication of any potentially identifiable images or data included in this article.","[the Institutional Review Board of Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, the Institutional Review Board of Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 129, 318, 376]","[127, 174, 374, 421]"
PMC7332757,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7332757\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"All experiments were conducted on commercially supplied cell lines. Therefore, ethics approval and written informed consent was not required for this study.",[],[],[],[]
PMC7333219,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7333219\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Animal Welfare and Research Ethics Committee at Jilin University in accordance with the animal welfare laws and the regulations of the Association for Assessment and Accreditation of Laboratory Animal Care (AAALAC).,"[the Animal Welfare and Research Ethics Committee, Jilin University, the Association for Assessment and Accreditation of Laboratory Animal Care]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 98, 181]","[94, 114, 255]"
PMC7338564,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7338564\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by ethical committee from the Fundeni Clinical Institute, Romania. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.","[the Fundeni Clinical Institute, Romania]","['ORG', 'GPE']","[94, 126]","[124, 133]"
PMC7348038,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7348038\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethics Committee of Ehime University School of Medicine. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. The animal study was reviewed and approved by University Committee for Animal Research, Ehime University.","[Ethics Committee of Ehime University School of Medicine, University Committee for Animal Research, Ehime University]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 270, 312]","[126, 310, 328]"
PMC7358551,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7358551\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,This study was approved by the Ethic committee of Tianjin Medical University General Hospital and Tianjin First Central Hospital. Patients and healthy controls gave their informed consent. The study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki.,"[Ethic, Tianjin Medical University General Hospital, Tianjin First Central Hospital, the Declaration of Helsinki]","['PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART']","[31, 50, 98, 232]","[36, 93, 128, 259]"
PMC7363762,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7363762\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by University of Ibadan, University College Hospital Ibadan Ethics Committee. Written informed consent to participate in this study was provided by the participants' legal guardian/next of kin.","[University of Ibadan, University College Hospital Ibadan Ethics Committee]",['ORG'],[71],[144]
PMC7372119,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7372119\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the First Hospital of Jilin University Ethics Committee (No. 2019–177). The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[the First Hospital of Jilin University Ethics Committee],['ORG'],[71],[126]
PMC7381156,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7381156\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of Nanjing Medical University. Written informed consent to participate in this study was provided by the participants’ legal guardian/next of kin. The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of Nanjing Medical University.,"[the Ethics Committee of Nanjing Medical University, the Ethics Committee of Nanjing Medical University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 285]","[121, 335]"
PMC7381338,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7381338\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Animal Experimental Ethics Committee of Zhejiang University.,[the Animal Experimental Ethics Committee of Zhejiang University],['ORG'],[46],[109]
PMC7381345,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7381345\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Internal Committee for the Care and Use of Laboratory Animals of the Faculty of Medicine, UNAM, with approved protocol number 027-CIC-2019.","[the Internal Committee for the Care and Use of Laboratory Animals, the Faculty of Medicine, UNAM, 027]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL']","[46, 115, 140, 176]","[111, 138, 144, 179]"
PMC7385414,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7385414\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Animal Ethics Committee of Fujian University of Traditional Chinese Medicine (SCXK#2016005).,[the Animal Ethics Committee of Fujian University of Traditional Chinese Medicine],['ORG'],[46],[126]
PMC7387574,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7387574\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal protocol was approved by the Standing Committee on Animals at Shanghai Ninth People's Hospital, Shanghai, P.R. China.","[the Standing Committee on Animals, Shanghai Ninth People's Hospital, Shanghai, P.R. China]","['ORG', 'FAC', 'GPE', 'ORG']","[36, 73, 107, 117]","[69, 105, 115, 127]"
PMC7390847,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7390847\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The study was approved by the Transplant Complications Working Party of the EBMT institutional review board and conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki and Good Clinical Practice guidelines. Since 1990, all patients provide informed consent authorizing the use of their personal information for research purposes.","[the Transplant Complications Working Party, EBMT, the Declaration of Helsinki and Good Clinical Practice, 1990]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'DATE']","[26, 76, 141, 214]","[68, 80, 195, 218]"
PMC7393983,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7393983\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the ethics committee of the Capital Region of Denmark (H-15006001). Written informed consent to participate in this study was provided by the participants' legal guardian/next of kin.,[the Capital Region of Denmark],['LOC'],[95],[124]
PMC7402373,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7402373\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by NRES Committee London, UK – Fulham Research Ethics Committee (fetal tissue) and Camden and Islington Community Local Research Ethics Committee (pediatric tissue). Written informed consent to participate in this study was provided by the participants’ legal guardian/next of kin.","[NRES Committee London, UK, Fulham Research Ethics Committee, Camden, Islington Community Local Research Ethics Committee]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG']","[71, 94, 99, 151, 162]","[92, 96, 131, 157, 213]"
PMC7403177,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7403177\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Institutional Review Boards at JSHCT and Tokyo Medical and Dental University. Written informed consent to participate in this study was provided by the participants' legal guardian/next of kin.,"[the Institutional Review Boards, JSHCT, Tokyo Medical and Dental University]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 106, 116]","[102, 111, 151]"
PMC7406658,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7406658\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by human ethics committee, the Guangzhou Medical University. The animal study was reviewed and approved by Animal Ethics Committee, University of Macau.","[the Guangzhou Medical University, Animal Ethics Committee, University of Macau]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[95, 175, 200]","[127, 198, 219]"
PMC7411138,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7411138\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by The Clinical Ethics Review Committee at Ningbo First Hospital. Written informed consent to participate in this study was provided by the participants' legal guardian/next of kin. Written informed consent was obtained from the individual(s), and minor(s)' legal guardian/next of kin, for the publication of any potentially identifiable images or data included in this article.","[The Clinical Ethics Review Committee, Ningbo First Hospital]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 111]","[107, 132]"
PMC7411472,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7411472\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Dutch National and Sanquin Internal Ethic Boards. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[Dutch National, Sanquin Internal Ethic Boards]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 90]","[85, 119]"
PMC7412717,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7412717\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by The Animal Care Committee at First Affiliated Hospital of Wenzhou Medical University.,"[The Animal Care Committee, First Affiliated Hospital of, Wenzhou Medical University]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 75, 104]","[71, 103, 130]"
PMC7413103,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7413103\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of Tongji Hospital.,[the Ethics Committee of Tongji Hospital],['ORG'],[46],[85]
PMC7424071,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7424071\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of Sun Yat-sen University Cancer Center. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[the Ethics Committee of Sun Yat-sen University Cancer Center],['ORG'],[71],[131]
PMC7426506,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7426506\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"This study was approved by the Ethics Committee of the cancer hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, and was registered with 
 ","[the Ethics Committee, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[27, 72]","[47, 107]"
PMC7434987,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7434987\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethics Committee of the National Cheng Kung University Hospital Institutional Review Board. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. The animal study was reviewed and approved by Animal and Ethics Review Committee of the Laboratory Animal Center at Taipei Medical University. Written informed consent was obtained from the owners for the participation of their animals in this study.,"[Ethics Committee, the National Cheng Kung University Hospital Institutional Review Board, Animal and Ethics Review Committee of the Laboratory Animal Center, Taipei Medical University]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 91, 305, 375]","[87, 161, 371, 400]"
PMC7438407,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7438407\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was reviewed and approved by Csongrád County Committee on the Food Chain and Animal Health, Government Office of Csongrád County, Rákóczi tér 1, Szeged 6722 Hungary. Written informed consent was obtained from the owners for the participation of their animals in this study.","[Csongrád County Committee, Animal Health, Government Office, Csongrád County, Rákóczi, 1, Szeged 6722 Hungary]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG']","[46, 94, 130, 147, 159, 162]","[71, 126, 145, 154, 160, 181]"
PMC7438587,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7438587\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by University Committee on Use and Care of Animals of Jiangsu University (2012258).,"[University Committee on Use and Care of Animals of Jiangsu University, 2012258]","['ORG', 'DATE']","[46, 117]","[115, 124]"
PMC7438598,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7438598\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee for Research (ECRA) of Lorestan University. Written informed consent was not required according to local and national guidelines.,"[the Ethics Committee for Research (ECRA, Lorestan University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 115]","[110, 134]"
PMC7456813,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7456813\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by CEP-Federal University of Bahia. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. The animal study was reviewed and approved by CEUA-Hospital São Rafael.,"[CEP-Federal University of Bahia, CEUA-Hospital São Rafael]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 246]","[102, 270]"
PMC7466444,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7466444\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal studies were performed according to the guidelines and regulations of the Institute of Laboratory Animal Science, Peking Union Medical College and Chinese Academy of Medical Science (Beijing, China). Efforts were made to minimize the number of animals in the studies. The use of rhesus macaque in research at the Institute of Laboratory Animal Science was approved by the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee (Protocol number #XC17001).","[the Institute of Laboratory Animal Science, Peking Union Medical College, Chinese Academy of Medical Science (Beijing, China, the Institute of Laboratory Animal Science, the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee, XC17001]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PRODUCT']","[81, 158, 203, 320, 379, 445]","[153, 201, 208, 362, 426, 452]"
PMC7468525,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7468525\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,All patients gave informed consent and the use of tumor samples was approved by the Hospital La Fe (Spain) Ethics Committee.,"[the Hospital La Fe, Ethics Committee]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[80, 107]","[98, 123]"
PMC7472694,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7472694\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Nanjing Medical University Institution Review Board (PJ2004-030-001). Written informed consent to participate in this study was provided by the participants’ legal guardian/next of kin.,[Nanjing Medical University Institution Review Board],['ORG'],[71],[122]
PMC7472722,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7472722\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of the Peking University Health Science Center.,[the Ethics Committee of the Peking University Health Science Center],['ORG'],[46],[113]
PMC7472958,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7472958\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,This study was approved by The West China Hospital research ethics committee. Written informed consent was waived per the committee approval because of the retrospective nature of the analysis.,[The West China Hospital],['ORG'],[27],[50]
PMC7473208,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7473208\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Research Ethics Committee of the First Affiliated Hospital, College of Medicine, Zhejiang University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.","[the Research Ethics Committee, the First Affiliated Hospital, College of Medicine, Zhejiang University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 104]","[100, 175]"
PMC7477045,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7477045\sections\1_body\7_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Commission for the Ethical Use and Care of Animals, Grisons, Switzerland.","[the Commission for the Ethical Use and Care of Animals, Grisons, Switzerland]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE']","[46, 102, 111]","[100, 109, 122]"
PMC7477074,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7477074\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was reviewed and approved by the ethics committee of the Landesuntersuchungsamt Rheinland-Pfalz, permission number 177-07/G 19-1-088.","[the Landesuntersuchungsamt Rheinland-Pfalz, 177-07, 19]","['FAC', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL']","[70, 132, 141]","[112, 138, 143]"
PMC7479063,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7479063\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee (IACUC) of Central South University.,"[the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee (IACUC, Central South University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 105]","[100, 129]"
PMC7479182,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7479182\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the institutional review board of Peking University Cancer Hospital. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[Peking University Cancer Hospital],['ORG'],[105],[138]
PMC7479240,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7479240\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the hospital Ethics Committee of The First Hospital of Jilin University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[the hospital Ethics Committee of The First Hospital of Jilin University],['ORG'],[71],[142]
PMC7480022,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7480022\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"For using non-human animals in the study, the project was reviewed and approved by the Research Ethics Review Committee of Kerman University of Medical Sciences, approval ID IR.KMU.REC.1398.084.","[the Research Ethics Review Committee of Kerman University of Medical Sciences, ID IR.KMU.REC.1398.084]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[83, 171]","[160, 193]"
PMC7484971,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7484971\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethics Committee of the First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[Ethics Committee, the First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 91]","[87, 144]"
PMC7494730,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7494730\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Institutional Review Board of the University of Tokyo Hospital (11044). The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[the Institutional Review Board, the University of Tokyo Hospital, 11044]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE']","[71, 105, 139]","[101, 137, 144]"
PMC7494731,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7494731\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Xinqiao Ethics Committee. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[Xinqiao Ethics Committee],['ORG'],[71],[95]
PMC7494742,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7494742\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of Xiangya Hospital of Central South University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Xiangya Hospital of Central South University Ethics Committee.,"[the Ethics Committee of Xiangya Hospital of Central South University, the Xiangya Hospital of Central South University Ethics Committee]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 283]","[139, 348]"
PMC7500210,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7500210\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,This study was reviewed and approved by Research Ethics Committee of Dr. Amaral Carvalho Hospital–Jahu-SP- Brazil (CEPHAC—2.917.389). The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[Research Ethics Committee, Brazil]","['ORG', 'GPE']","[40, 107]","[65, 113]"
PMC7500244,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7500244\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by Animal Ethics Committee of Shandong University of Technology.,"[Animal Ethics Committee, Shandong University of Technology]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 73]","[69, 106]"
PMC7505950,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7505950\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethics Committees of Zhengzhou University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. The animal study was reviewed and approved by Animal Welfare Committee of Zhengzhou University.,"[Ethics Committees, Zhengzhou University, Animal Welfare Committee, Zhengzhou University]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 92, 256, 284]","[88, 112, 280, 304]"
PMC7506071,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7506071\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethics Committee of the Affiliated Drum Tower Hospital of Nanjing University Medical school. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[Ethics Committee, Nanjing University Medical]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 129]","[87, 155]"
PMC7511512,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7511512\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Hospital Board of Vinmec International Hospital in Hanoi. Written informed consent to participate in this study was provided by the participants' legal guardian/next of kin. Written informed consent was obtained from the individual(s), and minor(s)' legal guardian/next of kin, for the publication of any potentially identifiable images or data included in this article.","[Hospital Board of Vinmec International Hospital, Hanoi]","['ORG', 'GPE']","[71, 122]","[118, 127]"
PMC7516035,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7516035\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by The Human Ethical Committee at fuwai hospital. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. The animal study was reviewed and approved by The Animal Ethical Committee at Fuwai Hospital.,"[The Human Ethical Committee, The Animal Ethical Committee, Fuwai Hospital]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'FAC']","[71, 260, 292]","[98, 288, 306]"
PMC7522314,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7522314\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal studies were reviewed and approved by University of New Mexico Health Sciences Center and University of Utah Health IACUCs.,[University of New Mexico Health Sciences Center and University of Utah Health],['ORG'],[49],[126]
PMC7525010,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7525010\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,This is a retrospective study and was approved by the Institutional Review Board (IRB) of SPHIC.,"[the Institutional Review Board, SPHIC]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[50, 90]","[80, 95]"
PMC7526461,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7526461\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by IFO ethics committee. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[IFO],['ORG'],[71],[74]
PMC7530283,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7530283\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Animal Ethics Committee of Yangzhou University.,"[the Animal Ethics Committee, Yangzhou University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 77]","[73, 96]"
PMC7530284,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7530284\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was reviewed and approved by the CHA University Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee on animal experiments (IACUC, approval no: 140013).","[the CHA University Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee, IACUC, 140013]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL']","[46, 132, 152]","[108, 137, 158]"
PMC7536350,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7536350\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of Zhengzhou University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of Zhengzhou University.,"[the Ethics Committee of Zhengzhou University, the Ethics Committee of Zhengzhou University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 259]","[115, 303]"
PMC7543453,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7543453\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethics Committee of the University of Tübingen (598/2011BO1). The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[Ethics Committee of the University of Tübingen, 598/2011BO1]","['ORG', 'CARDINAL']","[71, 119]","[117, 130]"
PMC7545038,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7545038\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by Zhejiang Sci-Tech University Animal Experimental Ethics Committee.,[Zhejiang Sci-Tech University Animal Experimental Ethics Committee],['ORG'],[46],[111]
PMC7546375,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7546375\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Institutional Review Board at Forsyth Institute. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[Institutional Review Board, Forsyth Institute]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 101]","[97, 118]"
PMC7546404,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7546404\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by The Institutional Review Board and Research Ethics Committee of The First Affiliated Hospital of Nanchang University and The National Healthcare Group Domain Specific Review Board of Singapore. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[The Institutional Review Board and Research Ethics Committee, The National Healthcare Group Domain Specific Review Board of Singapore]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 192]","[131, 263]"
PMC7546783,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7546783\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by ERES Converge, institutional review board, Lusaka, Zambia. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.","[ERES Converge, Lusaka, Zambia]","['PERSON', 'ORG', 'GPE']","[71, 114, 122]","[84, 120, 128]"
PMC7550528,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7550528\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"All experimental protocols were conducted in accordance with guidelines for care and use of laboratory animals approved by the Institutional Committee on the Care and Use of Animals of Third Institute of Oceanography, NMR (TIO-IACUC-03-2020-06-22).","[the Institutional Committee on the Care and Use of Animals of Third Institute of Oceanography, NMR]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[123, 218]","[216, 221]"
PMC7550539,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7550539\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The study protocol was approved by the Human Ethics Committee of Xiangya School of Medicine, Central South University. All subjects provided signed informed consent in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki.","[the Human Ethics Committee, Xiangya School of Medicine, Central South University, the Declaration of Helsinki]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART']","[35, 65, 184]","[61, 117, 211]"
PMC7550745,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7550745\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by Animal Care and Use Committee of Shanghai General Hospital of Nanjing Medical University.,"[Animal Care, Use Committee of Shanghai General Hospital, Nanjing Medical University]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 62, 108]","[57, 104, 134]"
PMC7551306,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7551306\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Tianjin First Center Hospital (Tianjin, China). The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.","[Tianjin First Center Hospital, Tianjin, China]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE']","[71, 102, 111]","[100, 109, 116]"
PMC7554317,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7554317\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The human HCC specimens were collected by the China-Japan Friendship Hospital, with informed consents from the patients or their guardians and approval from the Institutional Ethics Committee of the China-Japan Friendship Hospital. The animal studies were reviewed and approved by the Animal Ethics Committee of China-Japan Friendship Hospital.","[HCC, the China-Japan Friendship Hospital, the Institutional Ethics Committee, the China-Japan Friendship Hospital, the Animal Ethics Committee of China-Japan Friendship Hospital]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[10, 42, 157, 195, 281]","[13, 77, 191, 230, 343]"
PMC7559526,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7559526\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by Animal Ethics Monitoring Committee of Sichuan Agriculture University. Written informed consent was obtained from the owners for the participation of their animals in this study.,[Animal Ethics Monitoring Committee of Sichuan Agriculture University],['ORG'],[46],[114]
PMC7573160,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7573160\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by Animal Experimentation Committee of the University of Queensland.,[Animal Experimentation Committee of the University of Queensland],['ORG'],[46],[110]
PMC7574678,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7574678\sections\1_body\4_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was reviewed and approved by Institutional Animal Ethics Committe, Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore−560012, India.","[Institutional Animal Ethics Committe, Indian Institute of Science, India]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']","[46, 84, 131]","[82, 111, 136]"
PMC7574681,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7574681\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee (Houston Methodist Research Institute).,"[Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee, Houston Methodist Research Institute]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 91]","[89, 127]"
PMC7575714,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7575714\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Ethics Review Board and the Committee on Animal Research of the Catholic University of Louvain.,"[the Ethics Review Board, the Committee on Animal Research of the Catholic University of Louvain]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 74]","[69, 144]"
PMC7575909,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7575909\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of Dubai Health Authority (DHA) and Dubai Scientific Research Ethics Committee (DSREC-03/2019_10) United Arab Emirates. The participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[the Ethics Committee of Dubai Health Authority, Dubai Scientific Research Ethics Committee, United Arab Emirates]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']","[71, 128, 190]","[117, 170, 210]"
PMC7581790,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7581790\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University.,[The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University],['ORG'],[46],[99]
PMC7591468,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7591468\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Animal Ethics Committee of Kyushu University.,[the Animal Ethics Committee of Kyushu University],['ORG'],[46],[94]
PMC7591722,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7591722\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Biology and Medical Ethics Committee, Dalian University of Technology.","[the Biology and Medical Ethics Committee, Dalian University of Technology]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 88]","[86, 119]"
PMC7593406,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7593406\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The study involving human participants was reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of the center of the national principal investigator, called Comitato Unico Regionale Friuli-Venezia Giulia on 2017, 3 October (Protocol No. 26522) and by the Ethics Committees of all participating institutions. A written and informed consent was obtained from all patients according to the Declaration of Helsinki.","[the Ethics Committee, Comitato Unico, 2017, 3 October, 26522, the Ethics Committees, the Declaration of Helsinki]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART']","[68, 150, 200, 206, 230, 244, 376]","[88, 164, 204, 215, 235, 265, 403]"
PMC7593573,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7593573\sections\1_body\7_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,All research was conducted and parental consent obtained with the approval of the institutional review boards of the University of Pittsburgh (IRB-PRO11050036) and University of North Carolina (IRB-08-0237). Written informed consent to participate in this study was provided by the participants' legal guardian/next of kin. Written informed consent was obtained from the minor(s)' legal guardian/next of kin for the publication of any potentially identifiable images or data included in this article.,"[the University of Pittsburgh, IRB-PRO11050036, University of North Carolina]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[113, 143, 164]","[141, 158, 192]"
PMC7593785,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7593785\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of Xuzhou Medical University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[the Ethics Committee, Xuzhou Medical University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 95]","[91, 120]"
PMC7593792,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7593792\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of Helsinki and Uusimaa Hospital District. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[the Ethics Committee, Uusimaa Hospital District]","['ORG', 'LOC']","[71, 108]","[91, 133]"
PMC7604341,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7604341\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was reviewed and approved by The Animal Care and Use Committee of the South China Agricultural University, Guangzhou, China (approval number 2018B116).","[The Animal Care and Use Committee of the South China Agricultural University, Guangzhou, China, 2018B116]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'CARDINAL']","[46, 124, 135, 158]","[122, 133, 140, 166]"
PMC7604536,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7604536\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by SingHealth and National Health Care Group Research Ethics Committees Singapore. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. The animal study was reviewed and approved by International Animal Care and Use Committee (IACUC), A*STAR.","[SingHealth, National Health Care Group Research Ethics Committees Singapore, International Animal Care and Use Committee (IACUC, A*STAR]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 86, 293, 346]","[81, 149, 343, 352]"
PMC7606978,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7606978\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethics Committee of the canton of Zurich (project ID: BASEC 2018-02075). The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[Ethics Committee, Zurich, 2018-02075]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'DATE']","[71, 105, 131]","[87, 111, 141]"
PMC7642244,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7642244\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethics Committee of the Medical University of Vienna. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[Ethics Committee, the Medical University of Vienna]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 91]","[87, 123]"
PMC7642446,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7642446\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by IRB committee Auburn University. Written informed consent for participation was not required for this study in accordance with the national legislation and the institutional requirements.,"[IRB, Auburn University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 85]","[74, 102]"
PMC7642470,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7642470\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Animal experiments were performed at Children’s Hospital Los Angeles under the research protocols (31–08 and 3111) approved by the Animal Research Committee and in strict accordance with the recommendations in the Guide for the Care and Use of Laboratory Animals of the National Institutes of Health. The approval identification for Children’s Hospital Los Angeles is AAALAC A3276-01. Harvesting organs and tissues from wild type and mutant mice following euthanasia using pentobarbital was approved at Justus Liebig University Giessen by the federal authorities for animal research of the Regierungspräsidium Giessen, Hessen, Germany (Approved Protocol GI 20/10 Nr. G 84/2016). Written informed consent was obtained from the owners for the participation of their animals in this study.","[Animal, Children’s Hospital Los Angeles, 31–08, the Animal Research Committee, the National Institutes of Health, Children’s Hospital Los Angeles, Justus Liebig University Giessen, the Regierungspräsidium Giessen, Hessen, Germany]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE']","[50, 87, 149, 177, 316, 383, 553, 636, 669, 677]","[56, 118, 154, 206, 349, 414, 585, 667, 675, 684]"
PMC7642480,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7642480\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was reviewed and approved by all the animal experiment study was controlled and approved by the protocol Ethics Committee of the Second Affiliated Hospital, School of medicine, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.","[Ethics Committee, the Second Affiliated Hospital,, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE']","[122, 142, 194, 215, 225]","[138, 173, 213, 223, 230]"
PMC7644785,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7644785\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by Animal Care Committee of McGill University (AUP-7815).,"[Animal Care Committee of, McGill University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 71]","[70, 88]"
PMC7644804,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7644804\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the University of Pittsburgh Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee.,[the University of Pittsburgh Institutional Animal Care],['ORG'],[46],[100]
PMC7645114,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7645114\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee of Zhejiang University.,[the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee of Zhejiang University],['ORG'],[46],[116]
PMC7646258,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7646258\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Institutional review board of Nagoya University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[Nagoya University],['ORG'],[101],[118]
PMC7652754,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7652754\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,All animal experiments in this research were conducted according to protocols permitted by The Animal Care and Ethics Committee of Tianjin Medical University.,[The Animal Care and Ethics Committee of Tianjin Medical University],['ORG'],[91],[157]
PMC7654174,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7654174\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Institutional Review Board of Peking Union Medical College Hospital. Written informed consent for participation was not required for this study in accordance with the national legislation and the institutional requirements.,[Institutional Review Board of Peking Union Medical College Hospital],['ORG'],[71],[138]
PMC7655657,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7655657\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Public Institutional Review Board designated by the Ministry of Health and Welfare (P01-201802-31-001). The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[the Public Institutional Review Board, the Ministry of Health and Welfare]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 123]","[108, 157]"
PMC7655972,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7655972\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by Animal Ethics Committee of Xiamen University.,[Animal Ethics Committee of Xiamen University],['ORG'],[46],[90]
PMC7656008,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7656008\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"Our study was approved by the Ethics Committee of Shanghai Children’s Medical Center (SCMC), affiliated hospital of Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, department of hematology or pediatric intensive care unit and written informed consent was obtained from patients' parents or guardians.","[the Ethics Committee of Shanghai Children’s Medical Center, Shanghai, Jiao Tong University School of Medicine]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG']","[26, 116, 125]","[84, 124, 164]"
PMC7657266,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7657266\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by University of Iowa IACUC.,[University of Iowa],['ORG'],[46],[64]
PMC7658268,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7658268\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee of New York University.,[the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee of New York University],['ORG'],[46],[116]
PMC7658920,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7658920\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"This study, part of a protocol entitled “Translational research on soft tissue sarcomas”, was reviewed and approved by the Medical Ethics Committee of the Erasmus MC, Rotterdam, The Netherlands (MEC-2016-213). Written informed consent for participation was not required for this study in accordance with the national legislation and the institutional requirements.","[Translational, the Medical Ethics Committee, Rotterdam, The Netherlands]","['WORK_OF_ART', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'GPE']","[41, 119, 167, 178]","[54, 147, 176, 193]"
PMC7661436,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7661436\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethical Committee of Hunan Normal University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. The animal study was reviewed and approved by Laboratory Animal Ethics Committee of the Second Affiliated Hospital of Hunan Normal University.,"[Ethical Committee, Hunan Normal University, Laboratory Animal Ethics Committee, the Second Affiliated Hospital of Hunan Normal University]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 92, 259, 297]","[88, 115, 293, 354]"
PMC7661473,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7661473\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was reviewed and approved and all experimental procedures were conducted in accordance with the guidelines of the Canadian Council on Animal Care (CCAC) and approved by the Animal Care Committee at the Hospital for Sick Children, Canada and Southeast University, China.","[the Canadian Council on Animal Care, CCAC, the Animal Care Committee, the Hospital for Sick Children, Canada, Southeast University, China]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'GPE']","[127, 164, 186, 215, 247, 258, 280]","[162, 168, 211, 245, 253, 278, 285]"
PMC7662097,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7662097\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee (IACUC) of Shanghai Jiao Tong University.,"[the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee (IACUC, Shanghai]","['ORG', 'GPE']","[46, 105]","[100, 113]"
PMC7667288,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7667288\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethics Committees of all participating centers: Hospital Clínic, Hospital Germans Trias i Pujol, Hospital del Mar, Vall d’Hebron University Hospital, Fundació Althaia Manresa, and Hospital Universitari Doctor Josep Trueta. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.","[Ethics Committees, Hospital Clínic,, Pujol, Hospital del Mar,, Vall d’Hebron University Hospital, Fundació, Althaia Manresa, Josep Trueta]","['PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'PERSON', 'PERSON']","[71, 119, 161, 186, 221, 230, 280]","[88, 135, 185, 219, 229, 245, 292]"
PMC7670064,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7670064\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,Animals were bred and housed in the Association for Assessment and Accreditation of Laboratory Animal Care-accredited animal facility of Cincinnati Children’s Hospital Medical Center. All experiments conform to the regulatory standards of the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee (IACUC) and adhere to IACUC-approved protocols. The study was approved by the IACUC ethics committee at Cincinnati Children’s Hospital Medical Center.,"[the Association for Assessment and Accreditation of Laboratory Animal Care, Cincinnati Children’s Hospital Medical Center, the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee (IACUC, IACUC, Cincinnati Children’s Hospital Medical Center]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[32, 137, 239, 365, 391]","[106, 182, 293, 370, 436]"
PMC7674173,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7674173\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee for Animal Research at Zhejiang University (Ethics approval number: ZJU20200075).,"[the Ethics Committee for Animal Research at Zhejiang University (Ethics, ZJU20200075]","['ORG', 'PERSON']","[46, 135]","[117, 146]"
PMC7674620,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7674620\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,Ethical review and approval was not required for the study on human participants in accordance with the local legislation and institutional requirements. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. Written informed consent was obtained from the individual(s) for the publication of any potentially identifiable images or data included in this article.,[],[],[],[]
PMC7674674,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7674674\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethical Committee of Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Integrata Verona; N. 1828, May 12, 2010 “Institution of cell and tissue collection for biomedical research in Onco-Hematology”. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.","[Ethical Committee, N. 1828, May 12, 2010, Onco-Hematology]","['ORG', 'PERSON', 'DATE', 'ORG']","[71, 144, 153, 236]","[88, 151, 165, 251]"
PMC7674778,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7674778\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,All procedures involving live animals were approved by the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee at Colorado State University. Written informed consent was obtained from the owners for the participation of their animals in this study.,"[the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee, Colorado State University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[55, 106]","[102, 131]"
PMC7674920,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7674920\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethics Committee of São Rafael Hospital (approval number 19883113.0.0000.0048). The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[Ethics Committee of São Rafael Hospital],['ORG'],[71],[110]
PMC7674974,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7674974\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Comité Local d’Ethique pour la Recherche Clinique; reference: CLEA-2016-029, October 12, 2016. Written informed consent to participate in this study was provided by the participants' legal guardian/next of kin.","[Comité Local d’Ethique, Recherche Clinique, October 12, 2016]","['ORG', 'PERSON', 'DATE']","[71, 102, 148]","[93, 120, 164]"
PMC7676439,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7676439\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Achaia’s regional veterinary authority.,[],[],[],[]
PMC7677362,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7677362\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,All experiments were conducted in accordance with the Home Office Animals (Scientific Procedures) Act 1986 under the license number PPL80/2545 at the UEA.,"[the Home Office Animals (Scientific Procedures, 1986, PPL80/2545, UEA]","['ORG', 'DATE', 'PERSON', 'FAC']","[50, 102, 132, 150]","[96, 106, 142, 153]"
PMC7680803,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7680803\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by De Videnskabsetiske Komiteer i Region Hovedstaden. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[De Videnskabsetiske, i Region Hovedstaden]","['ORG', 'PERSON']","[71, 100]","[90, 120]"
PMC7680960,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7680960\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by Ethical Committee for Animal Experimentation of the University of Genoa (Prot. 319) and the Istituto di Ricerche Farmacologiche Mario Negri IRCCS.,"[Ethical Committee for Animal Experimentation of, the University of Genoa (Prot, 319, the Istituto di Ricerche Farmacologiche]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG']","[46, 94, 125, 134]","[93, 123, 128, 173]"
PMC7686784,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7686784\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by Animal Care and Use Committee of Yangzhou University.,"[Animal Care, Yangzhou University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 79]","[57, 98]"
PMC7688626,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7688626\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of Zhejiang Chinese Medical University (Resolution number ZSLL-2016-139).,[the Ethics Committee of Zhejiang Chinese Medical University (Resolution],['ORG'],[46],[117]
PMC7688779,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7688779\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by The Institutional Review Board at Tongji Hospital of Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology (TJ-IRB20190502). Written informed consent to participate in this study was provided by the participants' legal guardian/next of kin.","[The Institutional Review Board, Tongji Hospital of Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 105, 148]","[101, 146, 193]"
PMC7693549,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7693549\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by The Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[The Affiliated Hospital of Qingdao University],['ORG'],[71],[116]
PMC7701216,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7701216\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethics Committee of the Xiangya Hospital of Central South University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. Written informed consent was obtained from the individual(s) for the publication of any potentially identifiable images or data included in this article.,"[Ethics Committee, the Xiangya Hospital of Central South University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 91]","[87, 139]"
PMC7703438,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7703438\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethical Committee on Clinical Study of the First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[Ethical Committee],['ORG'],[71],[88]
PMC7708318,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7708318\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Nantes University Hospital Ethical Committee and the Committee for the Protection of Patients from Biologic Risks. the Nantes University Hospital Ethical Committee and the Committee for the Protection of Patients from Biologic Risks. All subjects provided written informed consent in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. Blood samples were collected from patients included in the EXPRESA cohort study (NCT00721097). The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee on Animal Experimentation of the Pays de la Loire (accreditation number: 9456).,"[the Nantes University Hospital Ethical Committee, the Committee for the Protection of Patients, Biologic Risks, the Nantes University Hospital Ethical Committee, the Committee for the Protection of Patients, Biologic Risks, the Declaration of Helsinki, EXPRESA, NCT00721097, the Ethics Committee on Animal Experimentation of the Pays de la Loire]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG']","[71, 124, 174, 190, 243, 293, 375, 463, 485, 641]","[119, 168, 188, 238, 287, 307, 402, 470, 496, 711]"
PMC7710518,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7710518\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was reviewed and approved by The Ethics Committee of the Shanghai General Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine.","[The Ethics Committee, the Shanghai General Hospital, Shanghai, Jiao Tong University School of Medicine]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG']","[46, 70, 101, 110]","[66, 99, 109, 149]"
PMC7710953,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7710953\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Research Ethics Committee of Guangzhou Medical University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. The animal study was reviewed and approved by Research Ethics Committee of Guangzhou Medical University.,"[Research Ethics Committee, Guangzhou Medical University, Research Ethics Committee, Guangzhou Medical University]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 100, 272, 301]","[96, 128, 297, 329]"
PMC7714830,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7714830\sections\1_body\7_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by Landesuntersuchungsamt Rheinland-Pfalz.,[Landesuntersuchungsamt Rheinland-Pfalz],['PERSON'],[46],[84]
PMC7718010,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7718010\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethics Committee of the Medical University of Vienna. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[Ethics Committee, the Medical University of Vienna]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 91]","[87, 123]"
PMC7719792,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7719792\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statements\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Health Research Ethics Board of Alberta. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. No animal studies are presented in this manuscript. No potentially identifiable human images or data is presented in this study.,"[Health Research Ethics Board, Alberta]","['ORG', 'GPE']","[71, 103]","[99, 110]"
PMC7719816,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7719816\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Animal Research Committee of the Sixth People's Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University.","[the Animal Research Committee, Sixth, People's Hospital, Shanghai, Tong University]","['ORG', 'ORDINAL', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG']","[46, 83, 89, 108, 122]","[75, 88, 106, 116, 137]"
PMC7721467,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7721467\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Zhengzhou University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. Written informed consent was obtained from the individual(s) for the publication of any potentially identifiable images or data included in this article.,[the Zhengzhou University],['ORG'],[71],[95]
PMC7724019,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7724019\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the ethics committee of the Sixth Medical Center, Chinese PLA General Hospital, China. Written informed consent to participate in this study was provided by the participants’ legal guardian/next of kin.","[Sixth, Chinese, PLA General Hospital, China]","['ORDINAL', 'NORP', 'ORG', 'GPE']","[99, 121, 129, 151]","[104, 128, 149, 156]"
PMC7726227,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7726227\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,All experimental animal procedures were approved by the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee of University of Murcia and Fundación Instituto de Investigacion Sanitaria Fundación Jiménez Diaz and performed according to the established guidelines (protocols numbers A13150201 and PROEX084/16).,"[the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee of University of Murcia, Fundación Instituto de Investigacion]","['ORG', 'PERSON']","[52, 128]","[123, 164]"
PMC7726356,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7726356\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Animal Research Committee of Hamamatsu University School of Medicine and those of Niigata University.,"[the Animal Research Committee of, Hamamatsu University School of Medicine, Niigata University]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 79, 132]","[78, 118, 150]"
PMC7726425,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7726425\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was reviewed and approved by Animal Ethics Committee of Shanghai Ninth People’s Hospital, China.","[Animal Ethics Committee, People’s Hospital, China]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']","[46, 88, 107]","[69, 105, 112]"
PMC7729088,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7729088\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Institutional Human Ethics Committee of Union Hospital, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee at Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology. Written informed consent was obtained from the owners for the participation of their animals in this study.","[the Institutional Human Ethics Committee of Union Hospital, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, the Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee at, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 131, 155, 344, 395, 419]","[129, 153, 200, 394, 417, 464]"
PMC7731732,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7731732\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Medical Ethics Committee of Zhujiang Hospital of Southern Medical University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[Medical Ethics Committee of Zhujiang Hospital of Southern Medical University],['ORG'],[71],[147]
PMC7732506,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7732506\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Osaka University Clinical Research Review Committee. Written informed consent to participate in this study was provided by the participants’ legal guardian/next of kin.,[Osaka University Clinical Research Review Committee],['ORG'],[71],[122]
PMC7732515,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7732515\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Animal Ethics Committee of the First Hospital of Jilin University.,"[the Animal Ethics Committee, the First Hospital of Jilin University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 77]","[73, 115]"
PMC7732624,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7732624\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ethics committee of the Medical University of Innsbruck. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[Ethics, the Medical University of Innsbruck]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 91]","[77, 126]"
PMC7732675,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7732675\sections\1_body\4_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Comité de Protection des Personnes IIe de France VII (hôpital de Bicêtre, Le Kremlin Bicêtre, FRANCE). The participants or legal guardian provided written informed consent to participate in this study.","[Comité de Protection des Personnes IIe de France, de Bicêtre, Le Kremlin Bicêtre, FRANCE]","['ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'GPE']","[71, 133, 145, 165]","[119, 143, 163, 171]"
PMC7744787,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7744787\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Laboratory Animal Control Committee of the Goldberg ED Research Institute of Pharmacology and Regenerative Medicine, Tomsk NRMC (IACUC Protocol No. 114062016).","[the Laboratory Animal Control Committee of the Goldberg ED Research Institute of Pharmacology and Regenerative Medicine, 114062016]","['ORG', 'DATE']","[46, 198]","[165, 207]"
PMC7746825,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7746825\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,All experimental procedures were performed in accordance with the European Community Council Directive (2010/63/UE) for the care and use of laboratory animals. Experimental protocols were approved by the local ethics committee “Comité d’éthique en expérimentation animal Charles Darwin No 5” under the number 02811.03 in compliance with European Union guidelines.,"[the European Community Council Directive, UE, Comité d’éthique, Charles Darwin, 02811.03, European Union]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'PERSON', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG']","[62, 112, 228, 271, 309, 337]","[102, 114, 244, 285, 317, 351]"
PMC7750436,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7750436\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by 
 ",[],[],[],[]
PMC7755609,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7755609\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was reviewed and approved by Animal experiments were approved by the Ethical committee of the University of Cadiz, as well as the Andalusian Committee of animal experimentation (registration number ES110120000210 and project number 07-04-2016-043).","[Animal, Ethical, the University of Cadiz, the Andalusian Committee, ES110120000210, 07-04-2016]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PRODUCT', 'CARDINAL']","[46, 86, 107, 143, 215, 249]","[52, 93, 130, 167, 229, 259]"
PMC7755610,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7755610\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"This study received ethics approval from St Vincent’s Hospital (Melbourne) Human Research Ethics Committee (HREC) (Ref: HREC-A 028/06), was endorsed by the CSIRO Health and Medical Research Ethics Committee (RR 5/2018) and was prospectively registered with the University of Melbourne HREC (ID: 1852006). All participants provided written informed consent to participate.","[St Vincent’s Hospital, Melbourne) Human Research Ethics Committee, HREC, the CSIRO Health and Medical Research Ethics Committee, the University of Melbourne HREC, 1852006]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE']","[41, 64, 108, 152, 257, 295]","[62, 106, 112, 206, 289, 302]"
PMC7755640,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7755640\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Animal Care Committee of the Leibniz Institute for Farm Animal Biology. Written informed consent was obtained from the owners for the participation of their animals in this study.,"[the Animal Care Committee of, the Leibniz Institute for Farm Animal Biology]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 75]","[74, 120]"
PMC7756004,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7756004\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by Tianjin Medical University.,[Tianjin Medical University],['ORG'],[46],[72]
PMC7756016,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7756016\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by National Institutes of Health Institutional Review Board. Written informed consent to participate in this study was provided by the participants’ legal guardian/next of kin.,[National Institutes of Health Institutional Review Board],['ORG'],[71],[127]
PMC7756119,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7756119\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,This study was approved by the Research Ethics Committee of the Taiwan National Health Research Institute and the Institutional Review Board of the China Medical University Hospital (ethics approval number: CMUH107-REC3-074 (CR1)). Written informed consent for participation was not required for this study in accordance with the national legislation and the institutional requirements.,"[the Research Ethics Committee, the Taiwan National Health Research Institute, the Institutional Review Board, the China Medical University Hospital]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[27, 60, 110, 144]","[56, 105, 140, 181]"
PMC7758322,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7758322\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the ethical guidelines of animal research at the University of Copenhagen and the University of Kentucky. Written informed consent was obtained from the owners for the participation of their animals in this study.,"[the University of Copenhagen, the University of Kentucky]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[91, 124]","[119, 150]"
PMC7758349,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7758349\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Institutional Review Board of Southwest Hospital. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. The animal study was reviewed and approved by Committee on the Ethics of Animal Experiments of the Shenyang Pharmaceutical University.,"[the Institutional Review Board of Southwest Hospital, Committee on the Ethics of Animal Experiments, the Shenyang Pharmaceutical University]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 267, 316]","[123, 312, 354]"
PMC7759627,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7759627\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The animal study was reviewed and approved by Animal Care and Use Committee of the Northeastern University Committee, China.","[Animal Care, the Northeastern University Committee, China]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']","[46, 79, 118]","[57, 116, 123]"
PMC7759629,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7759629\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Soochow University.,[the Soochow University],['ORG'],[46],[68]
PMC7759685,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7759685\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Ethics Committee of the First Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,"[the Ethics Committee, the First Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 95]","[91, 147]"
PMC7767887,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7767887\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The study design was reviewed and approved by the Local Ethics Committee of FSBI “RSMG” (Federal State Budgetary Institution “Research Centre for Medical Genetics”) to meet the requirements of the Helsinki Declaration of 1975 as revised in 2013. An informed consent for the use of the surgical material had been obtained from each patient, from whom an anonymous cell culture was derived.","[the Local Ethics Committee of FSBI, Federal State Budgetary Institution “Research Centre for Medical Genetics, the Helsinki Declaration of 1975, 2013]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'LAW', 'DATE']","[46, 89, 193, 240]","[80, 162, 225, 244]"
PMC7767994,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7767994\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The animal study was reviewed and approved by the Animal Ethics Committee of the Nanjing Agricultural University.,"[the Animal Ethics Committee, the Nanjing Agricultural University]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[46, 77]","[73, 112]"
PMC7767998,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7767998\sections\1_body\6_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"As our data were downloaded from the TCGA database, there is no requirement for ethics committee approval and consent to participate.",[TCGA],['ORG'],[37],[41]
PMC7769120,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7769120\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Academic Committee of Wuhan Union Hospital, Huazhong University of Science and technology. Written informed consent for participation was not required for this study in accordance with the national legislation and the institutional requirements.","[the Academic Committee of Wuhan Union Hospital, Huazhong University of Science]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[71, 119]","[117, 149]"
PMC7770105,C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\ethics_statement_frontiers_1000\PMC7770105\sections\1_body\7_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by Ruijin Hospital Research Ethics Committee. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.,[Ruijin Hospital Research Ethics Committee],['ORG'],[71],[112]
