,parsed,entities,labels,position_start,position_end,has_terms
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788872\sections\1_body\1_introduction\1_p.xml,"Lung transplant patients with treatment refractory moderate (grade 2) bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome (BOS) who do not qualify for a second transplant are at high risk of mortality or extreme disability. BOS is a subtype of chronic lung allograft dysfunction (CLAD) and is defined by progressive decline in forced expiratory volume in 1 second (FEV
 ","[2, BOS, second, BOS, 1 second]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORDINAL', 'ORG', 'TIME']","[67, 105, 135, 206, 337]","[68, 108, 141, 209, 345]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788872\sections\1_body\2_materials_and_methods\1_patient_population\1_p.xml,"Study patients were recruited from the clinical practice of the lung transplant program at Mayo Clinic in Jacksonville, Florida. Inclusion and exclusion criteria are listed in Table 
 ","[Mayo Clinic, Jacksonville, Florida]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE']","[91, 106, 120]","[102, 118, 127]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788872\sections\1_body\2_materials_and_methods\2_msc_manufacturing\1_p.xml,"MSC manufacturing was performed by Waisman Biomanufacturing at the University of Wisconsin‐Madison, Madison, Wisconsin. Clinical grade bone marrow was purchased from Lonza (Walkersville, MD, 
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788872\sections\1_body\2_materials_and_methods\3_transporting_msc\1_p.xml,"Shipping studies were performed to verify transporting cryopreserved MSCs between the manufacturing facility (Waisman Biomanufacturing at the University of Wisconsin‐Madison) and the clinical site (Mayo Clinic in Jacksonville, Florida) did not adversely impact MSC quality. It was discovered that some of the cell product bags were broken, prompting a change in thawing protocol. Because of the risk of MSC clumping and sedimentation during infusion, especially in the high‐dose group, a pilot experiment was performed, which led to adjustment and determination of the final cell concentration with least clumping and sedimentation. Similarly, dimethyl sulfoxide content was adjusted to a minimum while maintaining maximal post‐thaw viability. To ensure stability of the MSCs during infusion, pre‐ and postinfusion viability assessments were performed. Cells were thawed and diluted following an approved Standard Operating Procedure. The thawed, diluted cells were held at room temperature and samples were removed each hour over a 4‐hour period and assessed for recovery, clumping, and viability (Trypan Blue). MSC viability was >88% for all time points in all replicate studies. Studies were repeated with the thaw and viable cell count performed at the Mayo Clinic Cell Therapy Laboratory (Jacksonville, FL) with a viability >84%.","[Waisman Biomanufacturing, the University of Wisconsin‐Madison, Mayo Clinic, Jacksonville, Florida, MSC, MSC, each hour, Trypan Blue, 88%, the Mayo Clinic Cell Therapy Laboratory, Jacksonville, >84%]","['PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'TIME', 'ORG', 'PERCENT', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'PERCENT']","[110, 138, 198, 213, 227, 261, 403, 1016, 1099, 1132, 1253, 1294, 1329]","[134, 173, 209, 225, 234, 264, 406, 1025, 1110, 1135, 1292, 1306, 1333]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788872\sections\1_body\2_materials_and_methods\4_preparation_of_mscs_prior\1_p.xml,"On infusion day, the frozen MSCs underwent a standard protocol for thawing and infusion. Each bag was then diluted fivefold with Plasma‐Lyte (100 mL; Baxter Healthcare Corporation, Deerfield, IL, 
 ","[100 mL, Baxter Healthcare Corporation, Deerfield, IL]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[142, 150, 181]","[148, 179, 194]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788872\sections\1_body\2_materials_and_methods\5_msc_infusion_on_patients_\1_p.xml,"Infusion of MSCs was performed in the clinical apheresis unit. MSCs were infused at a rate of 2–3 mL/minute during the first 15 minutes, with the option to be adjusted up to 5 mL/minute if tolerated. Patients were monitored for any adverse reaction. Infusion toxicity was evaluated by continuously monitoring the patient's vital signs, electrocardiogram, and O
 ","[2–3 mL, the first 15 minutes]","['MONEY', 'TIME']","[94, 115]","[100, 135]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788872\sections\1_body\2_materials_and_methods\6_monitoring\1_p.xml,"Laboratory data (hemoglobin; white blood cell and platelet counts; and blood urea nitrogen, serum creatinine, and glucose levels) were collected for all patients prior to infusion (1–7 days) and on days 1, 7, and 30 after infusion. Arterial blood gases were obtained prior to infusion and on days 7 and 30 after infusion. Spirometric values were obtained within 7 days prior to infusion, just before infusion, and on days 1, 7, and 30 after infusion.","[1–7 days, days 1, 7, 30, 7 days, days 1, 7, 30]","['DATE', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL']","[181, 198, 206, 213, 362, 417, 425, 432]","[189, 204, 207, 215, 368, 423, 426, 434]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788872\sections\1_body\2_materials_and_methods\7_statistical_analysis\1_p.xml,"Individual variables were investigated across time using a one‐factor repeated measures analysis of variance. Significant differences among time points were investigated, adjusting for multiple comparisons using the Student‐Newman‐Kruels test. All statistical results were completed using SAS version 9.4 (SAS Institute Inc., Cary, NC, 
 ","[Student‐Newman‐Kruels, SAS, 9.4, SAS Institute Inc., Cary, NC]","['NORP', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE']","[216, 289, 301, 306, 326, 332]","[237, 292, 304, 324, 330, 334]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788872\sections\1_body\3_results\1_patient_population\1_p.xml,"Nine patients (seven men, two women) who were recipients of double lung transplant (
 ","[Nine, seven, two]","['CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL']","[0, 15, 26]","[4, 20, 29]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788872\sections\1_body\3_results\2_feasibility_of_msc_therap\1_p.xml,"The process of freezing, transporting, and thawing MSCs did not affect their viability: 92.4% ± 2.6% were viable prior to infusion and 93.0% ± 3.28% were found to be viable at the end of infusion (Table 
 ","[92.4%, ±, 2.6%, 93.0%, ±, 3.28%]","['PERCENT', 'NORP', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'NORP', 'PERCENT']","[88, 94, 96, 135, 141, 143]","[93, 95, 100, 140, 142, 148]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788872\sections\1_body\3_results\3_safety_and_tolerance_of_m\1_p.xml,"Patients were clinically evaluated for evidence of acute or delayed infusion‐related adverse events. Vital signs, pulmonary function test results, and Borg Dyspnea Index recorded before and after infusion of MSCs are summarized in Table 
 ",[Borg Dyspnea],['ORG'],[151],[163],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788872\sections\1_body\4_discussion\1_p.xml,"Immunomodulation induced by MSC therapy in solid organ transplant recipients has only recently been explored 
 ",[MSC],['ORG'],[28],[31],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788872\sections\1_body\5_conclusion\1_p.xml,"The results of our study suggest it is safe and feasible to provide cell therapy with intravenous infusion of bone marrow‐derived MSCs to lung transplant recipients with moderate obstructive CLAD, warranting future studies to assess the effectiveness of this therapy for management of acute or chronic graft dysfunction.",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788872\sections\1_body\6_author_contributions\1_p.xml,"C.A.K. and A.C.Z.: conception and design, financial support, administrative support, provision of study material or patients, collection and/or assembly of data, data analysis and interpretation, manuscript writing, final approval of manuscript; T.A.G.: conception and design, manuscript writing, final approval of manuscript; D.O.H.: collection and/or assembly of data, data analysis and interpretation, final approval of manuscript; D.H. and J.M.C.: conception and design, provision of study material or patients, manuscript writing, final approval of manuscript","[C.A.K., A.C.Z., D.H., J.M.C.]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'PERSON']","[0, 11, 435, 444]","[6, 17, 439, 450]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788872\sections\1_body\7_disclosure_of_potential_c\1_p.xml,D.J.H. is an employee of Cellular Dynamics International. J.M.C. is an employee of AxoGen Inc. The other authors indicated no potential conflicts of interest.,"[Cellular Dynamics International, J.M.C., AxoGen Inc.]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG']","[25, 58, 83]","[56, 64, 94]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788875\sections\1_body\1_introduction\1_p.xml,"Nonischemic dilated cardiomyopathy (DCM) is the most frequent cause of advanced heart failure 
 ",[Nonischemic],['NORP'],[0],[11],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788875\sections\1_body\2_materials_and_methods\1_patient_population\1_p.xml,"This study protocol represents a sub‐study of a parent prospective randomized study comparing the effects of repetitive and single‐dose cell therapy in patients with nonischemic DCM (
 ",[DCM],['ORG'],[178],[181],study protocol
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788875\sections\1_body\2_materials_and_methods\2_study_design\1_p.xml,"Patients were randomized in a 1:1 ratio to transendocardial cell therapy (SC Group) or no cell therapy (Controls). The allocation was done according to the covariate adaptive randomization strategy. At baseline, patients in the SC Group received granulocyte‐colony stimulating factor (G‐CSF); CD34
 ","[1:1, SC Group, Controls, the SC Group, granulocyte‐colony, CD34
 ]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PRODUCT']","[30, 74, 104, 224, 246, 293]","[33, 82, 112, 236, 264, 299]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788875\sections\1_body\2_materials_and_methods\3_echocardiography\1_p.xml,"Echocardiography was performed according to European Association of Cardiovascular Imaging recommendations 
 ",[European Association of Cardiovascular Imaging],['ORG'],[44],[90],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788875\sections\1_body\2_materials_and_methods\4_6‐minute_walk_test_and_nt\1_p.xml,"The 6‐minute walk test was performed by a blinded observer according to the standard protocol 
 ",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788875\sections\1_body\2_materials_and_methods\5_peripheral_blood_stem_cel\1_p.xml,"Stem cell mobilization and collection was performed as described previously 
 ",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788875\sections\1_body\2_materials_and_methods\6_electroanatomical_mapping\1_p.xml,"Electroanatomical mapping was performed using the Biosense NOGA system (Biosense‐Webster, Diamond Bar, California, 
 ","[Biosense, Diamond Bar, California]","['NORP', 'GPE', 'GPE']","[50, 90, 103]","[58, 101, 113]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788875\sections\1_body\2_materials_and_methods\7_follow‐up_and_endpoints\1_p.xml,"Patients were followed for 6 months. The primary endpoint was change in TAPSE. Secondary endpoints included changes in St, FAC, LVEF, NT‐proBNP, and 6‐minute walk test distance. In an exploratory analysis, we investigated a correlation of RV function and viability of the IVS.","[6 months, TAPSE, St, FAC, LVEF, RV, IVS]","['DATE', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[27, 72, 119, 123, 128, 239, 272]","[35, 77, 121, 126, 132, 241, 275]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788875\sections\1_body\2_materials_and_methods\8_statistical_methods_and_a\1_p.xml,"Based on our previous findings on CD34
 ","[CD34
 ]",['PRODUCT'],[34],[40],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788875\sections\1_body\3_results\1_patient_characteristics\1_p.xml,"Of 60 patients entering the study, 1 patient from the Control group died of sudden cardiac death (14 weeks after enrollment), and 1 patient from the SC Group underwent urgent heart transplantation (20 weeks from enrollment). During follow‐up, there were three hospitalizations for worsening of heart failure in the Control Group and one in the SC Group. At baseline, the SC Group and Controls did not differ in demographic and clinical parameters; all patients were treated with optimized medical management (Table 
 ","[60, 1, Control, 14 weeks, 1, the SC Group, 20 weeks, three, the Control Group, one, the SC Group, the SC Group, Controls, Table 
 ]","['CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'LAW']","[3, 35, 54, 98, 130, 145, 198, 254, 311, 333, 340, 367, 384, 509]","[5, 36, 61, 106, 131, 157, 206, 259, 328, 336, 352, 379, 392, 517]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788875\sections\1_body\3_results\2_changes_in_right_ventricu\1_p.xml,"At baseline, the two groups did not differ in parameters of right ventricular function. At 6 months, we found a significant improvement in TAPSE, St, and FAC in SC Group but not in Controls, which resulted in significantly higher values of all 3 parameters of RV function in the SC Group when compared with Controls (Fig. 
 ","[two, 6 months, TAPSE, St, FAC, SC Group, Controls, 3, RV, the SC Group, Controls, Fig]","['CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'PERSON']","[17, 91, 139, 146, 154, 161, 181, 244, 260, 275, 307, 317]","[20, 99, 144, 148, 157, 169, 189, 245, 262, 287, 315, 320]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788875\sections\1_body\4_discussion\1_p.xml,"This is the first clinical trial to date investigating the effects of cell therapy on RV function in DCM. In these patients, we found a significant improvement in parameters of RV function with transendocardial transplantation of cells in the left ventricle. Because the improvements in RV function correlated with increased viability of IVS, ventricular interdependence may represent a potential underlying mechanism for these findings.","[first, RV, DCM, RV, RV, IVS]","['ORDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[12, 86, 101, 177, 287, 338]","[17, 88, 104, 179, 289, 341]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788875\sections\1_body\4_discussion\6_study_limitations\1_p.xml,"The results of our study are subject to several limitations. The findings of the present study represent an extension of the parent study, with the primary aim to compare the effects of repetitive and single‐dose cell therapy on left ventricular function in patients with nonischemic DCM. The control arm did not receive any placebo procedures. Although, to minimize the bias, echocardiography data were analyzed at the end of the follow‐up period by an independent echosonographer, this does not fully overcome the limitations of an unblinded study. However, the echocardiography data were corroborated by the analysis of electroanatomical mapping, which is a fully automated procedure that generates data on myocardial viability using a computer algorithm performing in an operator‐independent manner. Although our sample size was small, both groups of patients were well matched at baseline. Our patient population included patients with DCM, but no biopsies were performed to exclude secondary cardiomyopathies. Finally, we recognize that patients with DCM are a heterogeneous patient population and dynamic changes in IVS viability and RV function may be multifactorial. In particular, parameters of RV function also may be affected by changes in loading conditions; however, we have found no changes in LV filling pressures or RV size in our study cohort.","[DCM, DCM, DCM, IVS, RV, RV, LV]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']","[284, 941, 1057, 1123, 1141, 1205, 1309]","[287, 944, 1060, 1126, 1143, 1207, 1311]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788875\sections\1_body\5_conclusion\1_p.xml,"In patients with DCM, CD34
 ","[DCM, CD34
 ]","['ORG', 'PRODUCT']","[17, 22]","[20, 28]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788875\sections\1_body\6_author_contributions\1_p.xml,"S.F. and B.V.: conception and design, provision of study material or patients, collection and/or assembly of data, data analysis and interpretation, manuscript writing; M.J., G.Z., A.C., and G.P.: conception and design, provision of study material or patients, collection and/or assembly of data, data analysis and interpretation.","[S.F., B.V., M.J., G.Z., A.C., G.P.]","['GPE', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'PERSON']","[0, 9, 169, 175, 181, 191]","[4, 13, 173, 179, 185, 195]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788875\sections\1_body\7_disclosures_of_potential_\1_p.xml,The authors indicated no potential conflicts of interest.,[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\0_background\1_p.xml,Hodgkin’s lymphoma (HL) and anaplastic large-cell lymphoma (ALCL) are the two most common tumors expressing CD30. The treatment of HL and ALCL has largely relied on cytotoxic chemotherapy.,"[two, CD30]","['CARDINAL', 'PRODUCT']","[74, 108]","[77, 112]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\0_background\9_p.xml,"Clinical studies involving adults with recurrent or refractory HL or ALCL in Japan and other countries demonstrated the efficacy and safety of SGN-35. Internationally, a clinical study that is being conducted involving adults with recurrent or refractory HL or ALCL suggests its efficacy. Pediatric patients should be given medicines that have been appropriately evaluated for their use. In the past, however, new approved drugs have been used for pediatric patients without the confirmation of safety and efficacy in pediatric patients. Therefore, it is significant to examine the safety and efficacy of SGN-35 in Japanese children.","[Japan, Japanese]","['GPE', 'NORP']","[77, 615]","[82, 623]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\10_pharmacokinetics\1_p.xml,"In a PK analysis set, pharmacokinetic parameters (Cmax, AUC, etc) for serum concentration of the drug will be estimated using non-compartmental analysis. Similarly, the serum concentration of all antibodies and plasma concentration of MMAE will be analyzed. Blood specimens used for evaluation of pharmacokinetics are collected at the time shown in Table 
 ","[MMAE, Table]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[235, 349]","[239, 354]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\1_protocol_digest_of_the_st\1_objectives\1_p.xml,Primary objective is to examine the safety and tolerance of SGN-35 in children with recurrent or refractory CD30-positive HL or sALCL. Accessory objective is to investigate the pharmacokinetics and efficacy of SGN-35 in children with recurrent or refractory CD30-positive HL or sALCL.,[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\1_protocol_digest_of_the_st\2_study_setting_and_protoco\1_p.xml,"This is a single-arm, open-label, multicenter phase I study involving four institutions: Hokkaido University Hospital, St. Marianna University School of Medicine Hospital, National Hospital Organization Nagoya Medical Center, and Kyushu University Hospital. The protocol has been reviewed and approved by institutional review boards of each institutions.","[four, Hokkaido University Hospital, St. Marianna University School of Medicine Hospital, National Hospital Organization Nagoya Medical Center, Kyushu University Hospital]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[70, 89, 119, 172, 230]","[74, 117, 170, 224, 256]",institutional review
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\1_protocol_digest_of_the_st\3_end_points\1_p.xml,Adverse events,[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\1_protocol_digest_of_the_st\4_eligibility_criteria\1_p.xml,Written informed consent regarding participation in this clinical study could be obtained from subjects and/or representatives,[],[],[],[],informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\1_protocol_digest_of_the_st\5_exclusion_criteria\1_p.xml,Those in whom the chief investigator/investigators considered it difficult to perform this clinical study.,[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\2_treatment_methods\1_p.xml,"SGN-35 is intravenously administered on Day 1 of each cycle (21 days/cycle). After Cycle 2, SGN-35 should be administered − 1 to + 3 days from the established day of administration, excluding cases in which a specific duration is required to achieve recovery from toxicity, appearing from the preceding cycle of SGN-35 therapy, of which the association with the investigational drug cannot be ruled out.","[Day 1, 21 days, Cycle 2, the established day]","['DATE', 'DATE', 'LAW', 'DATE']","[40, 61, 83, 143]","[45, 68, 90, 162]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\3_dose_limiting_toxicity__d\1_p.xml,"DLT should be evaluated from the initial administration of this drug until administration on the first day of administration in Cycle 2. In subjects in whom the appearance of toxicity made this-drug administration in Cycle 2 impossible, and treatment was discontinued, DLT must be evaluated until safety follow-up.","[DLT, the first day, Cycle 2, Cycle 2, DLT]","['ORG', 'DATE', 'LAW', 'LAW', 'ORG']","[0, 93, 128, 217, 269]","[3, 106, 135, 224, 272]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\4_follow_up\1_p.xml,"In subjects treated with this drug, the following assessments should be performed 28 days (7 days) after the final administration if it does not exceed the data cut-off day. These assessments should be conducted before the start of posttreatment. If examinations/observation/surveys are impossible for unavoidable reasons, such as complete withdrawal from this study, drop-out, death, and unfavorable conditions, the reasons must be recorded in original materials, and this study should be completed. In this case, deficits in examination/observation/survey items scheduled 28 days after the final administration are not regarded as deviations from the study protocol.","[28 days, 7 days, 28 days]","['DATE', 'DATE', 'DATE']","[82, 91, 574]","[89, 97, 581]",study protocol
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\5_efficacy_assessment_metho\1_p.xml,Positive findings on FDG-PET.,[FDG-PET],['ORG'],[21],[28],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\6_statistical_analysis\1_analysis_set\1_p.xml,"Those to whom an established dose of SGN-35 was administered in Cycle 1, and in whom observation for DLT assessment was completed.","[Cycle 1, DLT]","['DATE', 'ORG']","[64, 101]","[71, 104]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\7_safety_endpoints\1_p.xml,"The incidence of DLT will be calculated in DLT analysis set. The incidence of adverse events/reactions to the investigational drug will be calculated with respect to events, severity, and grade with safety analysis set.","[DLT, DLT]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[17, 43]","[20, 46]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\8_efficacy_endpoints\1_p.xml,"The ORR, CR rate, and their 95% confidence interval will be calculated in the FAS. To estimate the response duration, PFS, and EFS, the Kaplan-Meier method will be used. Their 95% confidence interval will be calculated with Greenwood’s formula.","[ORR, CR, 95%, FAS, PFS, EFS, Kaplan-Meier, 95%, Greenwood]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'PERCENT', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERCENT', 'PERSON']","[4, 9, 28, 78, 118, 127, 136, 176, 224]","[7, 11, 31, 81, 121, 130, 148, 179, 233]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\9_interim_analysis_and_moni\1_p.xml,"As it may be difficult to obtain sufficient information useful for efficacy assessment during this clinical study, interim analysis for efficacy assessment will not be conducted.",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\2_discussion\1_p.xml,"Pediatric patients should be administered medicines that have been appropriately evaluated for their use. In the past, however, new approved drugs have been used for pediatric patients without assessment of the efficacy and safety in those patients. Clinical studies involving adults with recurrent or refractory HL or ALCL in Japan and other countries demonstrated the efficacy and safety of SGN-35 [
 ",[Japan],['GPE'],[327],[332],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819207\sections\1_body\0_background\1_p.xml,"Despite great advances, relapsed and refractory B cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia (B-ALL) shows unfavorable prognosis, especially for adult patients [
 ",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819207\sections\1_body\1_methods\1_patient_enrollment_and_ch\1_p.xml,"The trial (
 ",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819207\sections\1_body\1_methods\2_clinical_protocols\1_p.xml,"Patients underwent an apheresis to obtain sufficient PBMCs for producing 1928zT2 T cells. The manufacture of 1928zT2 was completed in about 14 days. The cells were released for infusion after safety check. All patients received a lymphodepletion conditioning regimen which contained with fludarabine 25 mg/m
 ","[1928zT2, 1928zT2, about 14 days, 25]","['CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL']","[73, 109, 134, 300]","[80, 116, 147, 302]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819207\sections\1_body\1_methods\3_generation_and_expansion_\1_p.xml,"The 1928zT2 T cells were generated as previously described [
 ",[1928zT2],['CARDINAL'],[4],[11],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819207\sections\1_body\1_methods\4_flow_cytometry_of_cd19_ca\1_p.xml,"The percentages of transduced GFP-positive T cells, CD19 on leukemia cells, T cell phenotypes of the patient were determined by flow cytometry. The antibodies for CD3 (APC), CD4 (Percp-cy5.5), CD8 (PE), CD19 (APC), CD20 (PE), and CD22 (Percp-cy5.5) were used. The flow cytometry was performed with a FACSCalibur flow cytometer (BD Biosciences) and analyzed using FlowJo software.","[GFP, CD19, CD3, APC, Percp, CD19, APC, CD20 (PE), CD22, FACSCalibur, FlowJo]","['ORG', 'PERSON', 'LOC', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'PRODUCT', 'NORP', 'PRODUCT', 'ORG']","[30, 52, 163, 168, 179, 203, 209, 215, 230, 300, 363]","[33, 56, 166, 171, 184, 207, 212, 224, 234, 311, 369]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819207\sections\1_body\1_methods\5_killing_assays\1_p.xml,"The target cells K562, K562-CD19, and NALM6 were tagged both GFP and luciferase (GL), specifically incubated with GFP T, 1928z T or 1928zT2 T cells at the indicated ratios in triplicate wells in U-bottomed 96-well plates. Viability of target cells was monitored 18 h later by adding 100 dl/well substrate D-luciferin firefly (Life Sciences) resolved at 150 μg/ml. Background luminescence was negligible (< 1% than the signal from the wells with only target cells). The viability percentage was calculated as experimental signal/maximal signal × 100%, and killing percentage was equal to 100 − viability percentage.","[K562-CD19, NALM6, GFP, GFP, 1928z, 1928zT2, 96, 18, 100, Life Sciences, 150, Background, 1%, ×, 100%, 100]","['PRODUCT', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'PERSON', 'PERCENT', 'GPE', 'PERCENT', 'CARDINAL']","[23, 38, 61, 114, 121, 132, 206, 262, 283, 326, 353, 364, 406, 543, 545, 587]","[32, 43, 64, 117, 126, 139, 208, 264, 286, 339, 356, 374, 408, 544, 549, 590]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819207\sections\1_body\1_methods\6_xenograft_models_and_in_v\1_p.xml,"To develop the mouse subcutaneous tumor xenograft model of human extramedullary ALL leukemia [
 ",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819207\sections\1_body\1_methods\7_cytokine_measurements_and\1_p.xml,"IL-6 levels in plasma were assessed using enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA kit, eBioscience, USA) according to the manufacturer’s instructions. The immune-related cytokines were analyzed using Luminex MAGPIX system (Luminex Corp., Austin, TX) according to the manufacturers’ specifications. Samples were detected in triplicate relative to standards supplied by the manufacturer and analyzed for significant differences between different groups.","[IL-6, ELISA, eBioscience, USA, Luminex, Luminex Corp., Austin, TX]","['ORG', 'NORP', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG']","[0, 77, 88, 201, 224, 239, 247]","[4, 82, 104, 208, 237, 245, 249]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819207\sections\1_body\1_methods\8_quantitative_real_time_pc\1_p.xml,mRNA was extracted from cells with Trizol (Qiagen) and reverse transcribed into cDNA using the PrimeScript™ RT reagent Kit (Takara). All reactions were performed with TransStart Tip Green qPCR SuperMix (Transgene) on a Bio-Rad CFX96 real-time PCR machine. Delta CT calculations were relative to β-actin and were corrected for PCR efficiencies.,"[Trizol, Qiagen, the PrimeScript™ RT, Kit (Takara, SuperMix, PCR, Delta CT, PCR]","['GPE', 'ORG', 'LAW', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[35, 43, 91, 119, 193, 243, 256, 326]","[41, 49, 110, 130, 201, 246, 264, 329]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819207\sections\1_body\1_methods\9_statistics\1_p.xml,"Statistical analysis was performed with SPSS software version 19.0 (Inc., Chicago, IL, USA). Student’s 
 ","[19.0, Chicago, IL, USA, Student’s 
 ]","['CARDINAL', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'ORG']","[62, 74, 83, 87, 93]","[66, 81, 85, 90, 105]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819207\sections\1_body\2_results\1_1928zt2_t_cells_exhibited\1_p.xml,"We firstly evaluated the in vitro cytotoxic responses of 1928zT2 T cells exposed to NALM-6 cells (a CD19+ human B-ALL cell line), K562-GL cells with or without CD19 expression. As showed in the Fig. 
 ","[1928zT2, CD19, CD19, Fig]","['CARDINAL', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'PERSON']","[57, 100, 160, 194]","[64, 104, 164, 197]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819207\sections\1_body\2_results\2_tlr2_incorporation_promot\1_p.xml,"To further address the potential therapeutic application of 1928zT2 T cells in extramedullary leukemia, we next examined whether these cells harbored cytolytic activity against subcutaneous leukemia ex vivo
 ",[1928zT2],['CARDINAL'],[60],[67],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819207\sections\1_body\2_results\3_clinical_responses_to_inf\1_p.xml,"The infusion of 1928zT2 T cells was well tolerated without any immediate adverse effects in these three patients. Strikingly, the size and hypometabolism of the first patient’s breast lump was reduced obviously, detected by PET/CT scanning on day 30 after 1928zT2 T cells infusion (Fig. 
 ","[1928zT2, three, first, PET/CT, day 30, 1928zT2, Fig]","['CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORDINAL', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'PERSON']","[16, 98, 161, 224, 243, 256, 282]","[23, 103, 166, 230, 249, 263, 285]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819207\sections\1_body\2_results\4_in_vivo_expansion_of_1928\1_p.xml,"We used the flow-cytometry analysis to detect the GFP-positive 1928zT2 T cells in PBMCs in these three patients. In patient 1, the robust 1928zT2 T cells expansion occurred around day 12 and disappeared by day 92 (Fig. 
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819207\sections\1_body\2_results\5_toxicity_of_1928zt2_t_cel\1_p.xml,"The 1928zT2 T cells infusion was generally well tolerated in all these three patients. No immediate adverse side effects, episodes of tumor lysis syndrome, autoimmune disorder, and Graft-versus-host disease were observed. However, the patient 1 experienced grade 2 CRS on day 7 post infusion, with fever and left breast pain (Fig. 
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819207\sections\1_body\3_discussion\1_p.xml,"Extramedullary involvement in ALL remains a therapeutic challenge [
 ",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819207\sections\1_body\4_conclusions\1_p.xml,Our study demonstrated that the 1928zT2 T cells rapidly and reliably eradicated extramedullary and CNS leukemia and were well tolerated in these three ALL patients. Our results therefore suggested that adoptive transfer of 1928zT2 T cells has great potential to be used to treated ALL patients with extramedullary and CNS leukemia in the future.,"[1928zT2, CNS, three, 1928zT2, CNS]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG']","[32, 99, 145, 223, 318]","[39, 102, 150, 230, 321]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\0_background\1_p.xml,"Central venous catheter (CVC) placement is a frequently applied medical intervention that enables both monitoring and treatment of patients [
 ",[CVC],['ORG'],[25],[28],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\10_randomisation_and_blindin\1_p.xml,"Randomisation will be performed using a dedicated, password-protected, SSL-encrypted website with ALEA® software (TenALEA consortium, Amsterdam, The Netherlands). The researcher randomises the patient. Random block sizes are used. Block randomisation will be stratified per centre and per patient population (ICU vs. haematologic patients). Tunnelled lines are stratified per centre. Also, lines placed for dialysis/CVVH are stratified from central lines placed for other indications. This stratification takes place since dialysis/CVVH catheters are larger-bore catheters, made of stiffer materials and bear increased risk for bleeding [
 ","[ALEA, Amsterdam, The Netherlands, ICU]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'ORG']","[98, 134, 145, 309]","[102, 143, 160, 312]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\11_treatment_arms\1_p.xml,"Included patients will be randomised into one of two groups. One group of patients will be allocated to not receiving platelet transfusion prior to placement of the CVC, this is the experimental group. The other group of patients will be transfused with 1 unit of platelet concentrate prior to placement of the catheter, this is the comparison group. All platelet products will be manufactured, screened and stored according to local Dutch standards, (Sanquin Blood Bank). Platelet concentrates are prepared from pooled buffy coats from five donors, and re-suspended in plasma, after which pooled platelet concentrates are leukoreduced by filtration. All platelet products are stored, with gentle agitation at 20–24 °C, for up to 7 days in the Netherlands. All other care will be according to standard practice as indicated by the treating physician.","[one, two, One, CVC, 1, Dutch, Sanquin Blood Bank, five, 20–24, up to 7 days, Netherlands]","['CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'NORP', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'GPE']","[42, 49, 61, 165, 254, 434, 452, 537, 710, 724, 744]","[45, 52, 64, 168, 255, 439, 470, 541, 715, 736, 755]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\12_central_venous_catheter_p\1_p.xml,"All CVCs will be inserted percutaneously, under real-time US guidance, using the Seldinger technique. In the transfusion arm, catheters will be inserted as soon as possible after administration of 1 unit of platelet concentrate. The type of US device, catheters and (local) anaesthesia used is according to local hospital protocols. The puncture location will be determined by the puncturing physician. All procedures will be performed by experienced physicians, e.g. at least 50 previous line placements [
 ","[US, 1, US]","['GPE', 'CARDINAL', 'GPE']","[58, 197, 241]","[60, 198, 243]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\13_bleeding_complications\1_p.xml,"Bleeding complications will be scored using WHO grades of bleeding specified for CVC placement, which are defined in Additional file 
 ","[WHO, CVC]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[44, 81]","[47, 84]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\14_protocol_violation\1_p.xml,"If platelet concentrate is administered to patients assigned to not receiving platelet concentrate, patients will not be excluded. Reasons for additional transfusion are noted. Patients will be analysed according to intention-to-treat and per-protocol analyses. If line placement is unsuccessful due to technical reasons, data will also be analysed according to the intention-to-treat analysis. If blinding of the proceduralist is violated, this will be noted; however, patient data will not be excluded. If the 24-h time point is not completed, due to a CVC that is in situ for less than 24 h, or in the case that a patient deceases within this timeframe, obtained data will be analysed using missing data for the 24-h time point.","[24, CVC, less than 24, 24]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL']","[512, 555, 579, 715]","[514, 558, 591, 717]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\15_participant_timeline_and_\1_p.xml,"The participant timeline is presented in Fig. 
 ",[Fig],['PERSON'],[41],[44],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\16_data_collection\1_p.xml,"Inclusion is based on platelet count determined in the 24 h prior to randomisation. Baseline parameters, such as age, gender, height, weight and Body Mass Index (BMI), are collected. Recorded clinical parameters include date of admission, diagnosis, cause of thrombocytopenia, indication for CVC, use of defined confounding medication, hepatic- and kidney failure, diffuse intravascular coagulopathy and fever. For intensive care patients, also APACHE score, admission diagnosis and information about setting during admission are obtained. For haematologic patients, information about the haematologic condition and the phase of therapy is collected. In all patients, the most recent PT (INR), aPTT and haemoglobin levels, prior to randomisation are recorded. Information about the CVC, such as type, indication and diameter, is collected. Procedural details, such as insertion site, number of punctures, inadvertent arterial puncture, manual compression and the administration of ‘rescue platelets’, are recorded. According to standard care, blood is collected at 1 h and 24 h after CVC placement. In this way the effect of the platelet concentrate, if applicable, can be measured. A photographic image of the insertion site is taken prior to CVC placement, as well as directly post procedural and at 1 and 24 h after CVC placement. Clinical bleeding will be assessed at these same time points. All administered transfusion of blood products will be registered, as well as their clinical indication. All radiologic and surgical interventions will be documented.","[24, Baseline, CVC, APACHE, INR, CVC, 1, 24, CVC, CVC, CVC]","['CARDINAL', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[55, 84, 292, 445, 688, 782, 1065, 1073, 1084, 1244, 1319]","[57, 92, 295, 451, 691, 785, 1066, 1075, 1087, 1247, 1322]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\17_follow_up\1_p.xml,"The follow-up time for the primary outcome is 24 h. Patient information about both ICU and hospital discharge or death, whichever comes first, are collected.","[24, ICU, first]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORDINAL']","[46, 83, 136]","[48, 86, 141]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\18_data_management\1_p.xml,"An eCRF for the PACER trial in Open Clinica is developed. All participating centres have 24-h access to the eCRF. Data can be entered continuously for all participating patients. The principle investigator has access to the filled-out eCRFs. If data are entered incompletely or incorrectly, the principle investigator can contact the participating centres for clarification.","[PACER, 24]","['ORG', 'CARDINAL']","[16, 89]","[21, 91]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\19_statistical_consideration\1_p.xml,"We target to include 392 patients, with a potential limit of 462 patients to accommodate loss to follow-up and a possible dropout. The expected rate of severe peri-procedural bleeding incidents is around 0% [
 ","[392, 462, around 0%]","['CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'PERCENT']","[21, 61, 197]","[24, 64, 206]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\1_study_hypothesis\1_p.xml,"We hypothesise that the improved standards of CVC placement, e.g. the use of US, make the need for correction of thrombocytopenia prior to CVC placement obsolete.","[CVC, US, CVC]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG']","[46, 77, 139]","[49, 79, 142]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\20_statistical_analysis\1_p.xml,"Statistical analysis will be based both on an intention-to-treat principle and a per-protocol approach. Baseline assessments and outcome parameters will be summarised using simple descriptive statistics. The main analysis focusses on a comparison between the trial treatment groups of the primary outcome, the occurrence of relevant bleedings, expressed in a relative risk estimate and absolute risk increase, with the associated 95% upper confidence limit. Non-inferiority is demonstrated if this interval does not exceed the non-inferiority limit of 2.5% absolute difference in favour of transfusion.","[Baseline, 95%, 2.5%]","['PERSON', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT']","[104, 430, 552]","[112, 433, 556]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\21_withdrawal_and_replacemen\1_p.xml,"Subjects can leave the study at any time for any reason if they wish to do so without any consequences. The investigator can decide to withdraw a subject from the study for urgent medical reasons. When deferred consent is not obtained after randomisation and provisional inclusion of a patient, the randomised subject will be replaced. These cases will be recorded in the randomisation log without patient-specific data. The randomisation subject will be replaced in order to retain properly distributed randomisation groups and stratification.",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\22_study_organisation\1_p.xml,"The Steering Committee is composed of the principal investigators, the coordinating investigator and the local investigators in the participating ICUs and haematology departments. The coordinating investigator is responsible for administrative management and communication with the local investigators and provides assistance to the participating clinical sites in trial management, record keeping and data management. The coordinating investigator helps in setting up local training in the participating centres to ensure the study is conducted according to the ICH-GCP guidelines, to guaranty integrity of data collection and to ensure timely completion of the case report forms. The local investigators provide structural and scientific leadership. They guarantee the integrity of data collection and ensure timely completion of the case report forms.","[The Steering Committee, ICH]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[0, 563]","[22, 566]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\2_study_objective\1_p.xml,The primary objective is to demonstrate that the omission of prophylactic platelet transfusion in severely thrombocytopenic patients does not increase the amount of bleeding complications related to CVC placement.,[CVC],['ORG'],[199],[202],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\3_primary_endpoint\1_p.xml,"A procedure-related relevant bleeding, occurring within 24 h after the procedure. A WHO grade of 2–4 (Additional file 
 ","[24, WHO, 2–4]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL']","[56, 84, 97]","[58, 87, 100]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\4_secondary_endpoints\1_p.xml,• Platelet transfusion requirements within 24 h of CVC placement,"[24, CVC]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG']","[43, 51]","[45, 54]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\4_secondary_endpoints\9_p.xml,• Onset of acute lung injury within 48 h,[48],['CARDINAL'],[36],[38],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\5_design\1_p.xml,"The PACER trial is a randomised controlled, non-inferiority trial on prophylactic platelet transfusion prior to CVC placement in patients with severe thrombocytopenia. It is an investigator-initiated, multicentre, parallel, randomised controlled, two-arm trial in haematologic and/or intensive care patients with thrombocytopenia and an indication for CVC placement. The PACER trial will be conducted according to the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki as stated in the current version of Fortaleza, Brazil, 2013 [
 ","[PACER, CVC, two, CVC, PACER, the Declaration of Helsinki, Fortaleza, Brazil, 2013]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'DATE']","[4, 112, 247, 352, 371, 432, 496, 507, 515]","[9, 115, 250, 355, 376, 459, 505, 513, 519]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\6_consort_diagram\1_p.xml,"The Consolidated Standards of Reporting Trials (CONSORT) diagram of the PACER study is presented in Fig. 
 ","[The Consolidated Standards of Reporting Trials, PACER, Fig]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON']","[0, 72, 100]","[46, 77, 103]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\7_setting\1_p.xml,"The PACER trial is a multicentre study performed in six academic and five teaching hospitals in the Netherlands. We plan to include 392 patients in 36 months, with a potential limit of 462 patients to accommodate loss to follow-up and possible dropout.","[PACER, six, five, Netherlands, 392, 36 months, 462]","['ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'GPE', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL']","[4, 52, 69, 100, 132, 148, 185]","[9, 55, 73, 111, 135, 157, 188]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\8_study_population\1_p.xml,"Thrombocytopenic patients with a platelet count of 10–50 × 10
 ","[10–50, × 10
 ]","['CARDINAL', 'EVENT']","[51, 57]","[56, 63]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\9_consent\1_p.xml,"Informed consent will be obtained from all participants or a legal representative in case the former is impossible. As mentioned previously, this study involves two patient categories. In haematologic patients, lines are usually inserted electively for the administration of chemotherapy. Therefore, informed consent will be obtained before line placement. For the intensive care patient category, obtaining informed consent prior to CVC insertion is often not feasible. Therefore, for the intensive care setting patients may be included using the deferred consent procedure. We will randomise each patient at the ICU who meets the inclusion criteria directly before CVC placement. Informed consent from the legal representative will be requested as soon as possible. If informed consent is denied by a legal representative, the patient is excluded and data will no longer be used. Thenceforth, the patient is transfused according to the policy of the attending physician. If a patient dies before informed consent can be obtained, the data are used [
 ","[two, CVC, ICU, CVC]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[161, 434, 614, 667]","[164, 437, 617, 670]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\2_discussion\1_p.xml,"This is the first randomised trial that investigates the safety of a lower platelet concentrate transfusion threshold prior to CVC placement, in a non-inferiority design. If this trial concludes that omission of prophylactic platelets in patients with a platelet count of 10 × 10
 ","[first, CVC, 10]","['ORDINAL', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL']","[12, 127, 272]","[17, 130, 274]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\3_trial_status\1_p.xml,Currently recruiting,[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830087\sections\1_body\0_background\1_p.xml,"Approximately 85% of all lung cancers are classified as non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) and the majority of patients present with locally advanced or metastatic disease [
 ","[Approximately 85%, NSCLC]","['PERCENT', 'ORG']","[0, 84]","[17, 89]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830087\sections\1_body\1_methods\1_study_objectives\1_p.xml,"The primary objective was to evaluate the ORR (complete response [CR] + partial response [PR]) in each treatment arm. Secondary objectives included assessment of best response rate (CR, PR, or stable disease [SD] rates), disease control rate (DCR; CR + PR + SD), duration of objective tumor response (DOR), progression-free survival (PFS), and overall survival (OS) in each treatment arm. Safety within each arm and the PK profile of BTH1677 were also evaluated.","[ORR, DCR, CR]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']","[42, 243, 248]","[45, 246, 250]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830087\sections\1_body\1_methods\2_patient_eligibility\1_p.xml,"Patients, 18 to 75 years of age, provided written informed consent, and had histologically or cytologically confirmed non-squamous stage IIIB or IV NSCLC according to American Joint Committee on Cancer Staging v6 [
 ","[18, IIIB, IV NSCLC, American Joint Committee]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[10, 137, 145, 167]","[12, 141, 153, 191]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830087\sections\1_body\1_methods\3_study_design_and_treatmen\1_p.xml,"This randomized, open-label, multicenter, phase II study was performed at sites in Germany and the United States and was conducted in full accordance with the Good Clinical Practice: Consolidated Guideline approved by the International Conference on Harmonisation and all other applicable national and local laws/regulations. All study materials were approved by the governing ethics committee or institutional review board at each site.","[II, Germany, the United States, the Good Clinical Practice, Consolidated Guideline, the International Conference on Harmonisation]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[48, 83, 95, 155, 183, 218]","[50, 90, 112, 181, 205, 263]",ethics committee
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830087\sections\1_body\1_methods\4_study_assessments\1_p.xml,"Safety and tolerability were assessed by adverse events (AEs; National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events [CTCAE] v3.0), physical examinations, and laboratory tests.",[National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria],['ORG'],[62],[115],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830087\sections\1_body\1_methods\5_pharmacokinetics\1_p.xml,"Post-dosing blood samples were collected for PK assessments for BTH1677 on Day 1 of Cycles 1 and 3. Samples for BTH1677 trough level assessments were also obtained before weekly dosing on all other weeks of Cycles 1 and 2, as well as prior to dosing of Cycle 3, Day 1. Serum BTH1677 levels were measured by a beta-glucan specific enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) developed at Biothera Pharmaceuticals, Inc., which had a lower limit of detection of 1.2 ng/mL and a lower limit of quantitation of 4.7 ng/mL. Serum PK parameters were calculated using noncompartmental analysis (NCA) with NCA in WinNonlin® v5.2.","[PK, weekly, all other weeks, Cycle 3, Day 1, Serum BTH1677, ELISA, Biothera Pharmaceuticals, Inc., 1.2, 4.7, Serum, NCA, NCA, WinNonlin]","['ORG', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'LAW', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']","[45, 171, 188, 253, 269, 365, 385, 457, 504, 515, 584, 594, 601]","[47, 177, 203, 267, 282, 370, 415, 460, 507, 520, 587, 597, 610]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830087\sections\1_body\1_methods\6_statistical_analysis\1_p.xml,"The analysis populations for the blinded central radiology tumor assessments, safety and survival analyses, and PK analyses are shown by treatment arm in Fig. 
 ","[PK, Fig]","['GPE', 'PERSON']","[112, 154]","[114, 157]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830087\sections\1_body\2_results\1_patient_disposition\1_p.xml,"Between 29 September 2009 and 08 March 2013, a total of 92 patients with NSCLC were randomly assigned 2:1 to the BTH1677 or the Control arm. As shown in Fig. 
 ","[Between 29 September 2009, 08 March 2013, 92, NSCLC, 2:1, Fig]","['DATE', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'PERSON']","[0, 30, 56, 73, 102, 153]","[25, 43, 58, 78, 105, 156]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830087\sections\1_body\2_results\2_efficacy\1_tumor_associated_assessme\1_p.xml,"Tumor-associated assessments were based on the blinded central radiology review of the primary efficacy population. Although the between-group difference was not statistically significant, compared with the Control arm, patients in the BTH1677 arm had a higher ORR (60.4% vs 43.5%; 
 ","[ORR, 60.4%, 43.5%]","['ORG', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT']","[261, 266, 275]","[264, 271, 280]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830087\sections\1_body\2_results\2_efficacy\2_overall_survival\1_p.xml,"The OS Kaplan-Meier curves for the BTH1677 and Control arms are shown in Fig. 
 ",[Fig],['PERSON'],[73],[76],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830087\sections\1_body\2_results\3_safety\1_p.xml,"All patients receiving any treatment (BTH1677 
 ",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830087\sections\1_body\2_results\4_bth1677_pharmacokinetics\1_p.xml,"BTH1677 serum concentrations in both cycles were above the limit of quantitation (4.7 ng/mL) for all but 1 patient. Individual t
 ","[4.7, 1]","['CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL']","[82, 105]","[85, 106]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830087\sections\1_body\3_discussion\1_p.xml,"It has only been in recent years that harnessing the immune system in the fight against cancer has become well appreciated, especially with respect to therapy of NSCLC [
 ","[recent years, NSCLC]","['DATE', 'ORG']","[20, 162]","[32, 167]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830087\sections\1_body\4_conclusion\1_p.xml,"In conclusion, BTH1677 in combination with bevacizumab/carboplatin/paclitaxel as a first-line treatment of advanced NSCLC led to improvements in ORR, DOR, PFS, and OS compared with the Control arm. No major safety concerns were noted with the BTH1677 combination therapy. Ongoing studies are continuing to explore this novel PAMP immune modulator as an adjunct to antibody-based therapy, including checkpoint inhibitor therapies, for patients with NSCLC (NCT03003468) as well as other cancers (NCT02086175; NCT02981303).","[first, NSCLC, ORR, DOR, PFS, PAMP, NSCLC, NCT03003468, NCT02086175, NCT02981303]","['ORDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'PRODUCT', 'PERSON']","[83, 116, 145, 150, 155, 325, 448, 455, 494, 507]","[88, 121, 148, 153, 158, 329, 453, 466, 505, 518]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830392\sections\1_body\0_introduction\1_p.xml,"Allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (HSCT) is curative in advanced or aggressive hematologic malignancies despite associated toxicities. While a sibling matched at human leukocyte antigen (HLA)-A, -B, -C, and -DRB1 is optimal, only a minority of patients who may benefit from HSCT have such a donor available.
 ",[HSCT],['ORG'],[291],[295],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830392\sections\1_body\1_methods\1_p.xml,This prospective clinical trial was approved by the institutional review board of the Dana-Farber Cancer Institute/Harvard Cancer Center. Written informed consent was obtained prior to patient enrollment.,[Dana-Farber Cancer Institute/Harvard Cancer Center],['ORG'],[86],[136],informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830392\sections\1_body\1_methods\2_study_design\1_p.xml,"The study was a one-stage randomized phase II trial with the primary objective of comparing the incidence of aGvHD in two bort-based GvHD prophylaxis regimens to conventional tac/mtx. The study was designed for the primary comparisons of the grade II-IV aGvHD rates in Arm A 
 ","[one, two, GvHD, II-IV]","['CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'PERSON', 'PERSON']","[16, 118, 133, 248]","[19, 121, 137, 253]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830392\sections\1_body\1_methods\3_patients\1_p.xml,"Adult hematologic malignancy patients lacking an available HLA-matched sibling with an available 8/8 (
 ",[8/8],['CARDINAL'],[97],[100],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830392\sections\1_body\1_methods\4_transplantation\1_p.xml,"Conditioning comprised busulfan (0.8 mg/kg twice daily IV) and fludarabine (30 mg/m
 ","[0.8, daily, 30]","['CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL']","[33, 49, 76]","[36, 54, 78]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830392\sections\1_body\1_methods\5_immunophenotyping\1_p.xml,"CD4
 ",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830392\sections\1_body\1_methods\6_statistical_consideration\1_p.xml,"The primary endpoint was a grade II-IV aGvHD rate by day 180 after stem cell infusion. Secondary endpoints included cumulative incidence of aGvHD, NRM, relapse, chronic (c)GvHD, and PFS, OS and GvHD-free/relapse-free survival (GRFS). The study was designed for the primary comparisons of the grade II-IV aGvHD rates in arm A 
 ","[II-IV, day 180, NRM, PFS, GvHD, II-IV]","['PERSON', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'PERSON']","[33, 53, 147, 182, 194, 298]","[38, 60, 150, 185, 198, 303]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830392\sections\1_body\2_results\1_p.xml,"
 ",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830392\sections\1_body\3_discussion\1_p.xml,"Most adult hematologic malignancy patients who may benefit from allogeneic HSCT lack an available sibling donor and are considered for a MUD or 1-locus MMD, with umbilical cord blood (UCB) and haploidentical (haplo) donors being additional alternative options. Regarding 8/8 MUD, as a result of improvements in DNA-based typing and supportive care, survival outcomes are considered similar to those of MRD HSCT,
 ","[MUD, 1, MRD HSCT]","['ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG']","[137, 144, 402]","[140, 145, 410]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830392\sections\1_body\3_discussion\9_p.xml,"These data highlight the inadequacy of non-randomized comparators for evaluating early phase single arm interventional studies, and document, as an updated standard, the improved MMD and MUD RIC HSCT outcomes achievable with conventional tac/mtx in this study (2-year OS of 58% and 62%, respectively). In the future, prospective trials of alternative donors (e.g., UCB, haplo) and novel GvHD prophylaxis regimens (e.g., maraviroc, PTCy) may need to benchmark these outcomes. In contrast, the bar for the novel GRFS endpoint appears far lower, ranging from 8% to 12% in our study, with no significant difference between treatment arms (
 ","[MMD, MUD, 2-year OS, 58%, 62%, UCB, GvHD, GRFS, 8% to 12%]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'PERCENT']","[179, 187, 261, 274, 282, 365, 387, 510, 556]","[182, 190, 270, 277, 285, 368, 391, 514, 565]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5833907\sections\1_body\0_key_points\1_p.xml, ,[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5833907\sections\1_body\1_introduction\1_p.xml,"Hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (HSCT) allows the treatment of numerous diseases in both children and adults, such as hematologic malignancies, non-malignant hemopathies, and severe immunodeficiencies [
 ",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5833907\sections\1_body\2_patients_and_methods\1_p.xml,The National Committee of Informatics and Liberty approved the current study.,"[The National Committee of Informatics, Liberty]","['ORG', 'PERSON']","[0, 42]","[37, 49]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5833907\sections\1_body\2_patients_and_methods\9_p.xml,"To explore the modalities of use of the online model, we performed an analysis of sensitivity to our findings to assess the network ability, as a result of shared information, to compensate for missing variables such as cyclosporine residual concentration, mean dose, mean hemoglobin, mean creatinine, CRP, interacting drugs, cholestasis, documented infection, and weight (Netica software version 5.23).","[CRP, Netica, 5.23]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL']","[302, 373, 397]","[305, 379, 401]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5833907\sections\1_body\3_results\1_p.xml,"Of the 155 patients in total, six were excluded as they were given cyclosporine for several weeks before HSCT or they took cyclosporine orally. Forty-four patients were also excluded from the generation of synthetic data due to one or several missing data at the time of blood sampling for the initial determination of the cyclosporine residual blood concentration following HSCT. A final total of 105 patients without missing data at this time were retained (see Fig. 
 ","[155, six, several weeks, HSCT, Forty-four, one, HSCT, 105, Fig]","['CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'PERSON']","[7, 30, 84, 105, 144, 228, 375, 398, 464]","[10, 33, 97, 109, 154, 231, 379, 401, 467]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5833907\sections\1_body\3_results\3_modelling_procedure\1_p.xml,"We assessed that the synthetic dataset was representative for our database by a visual check of the probability densities distribution, and by comparing the variables of interest (Table 
 ",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5833907\sections\1_body\3_results\4_validation_of_the_predict\1_p.xml,"The final predictive model for the ability of the initial cyclosporine trough blood concentration after HSCT to be in the therapeutic range, after a tenfold cross-validation, presented good validation characteristics with an AUC-ROC of 0.89 ± 0.02 (see Fig. 
 ","[AUC-ROC, 0.89, Fig]","['ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'PERSON']","[225, 236, 253]","[232, 240, 256]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5833907\sections\1_body\3_results\5_sensitivity_to_missing_da\1_p.xml,"The results of the analysis of sensitivity to findings that was performed on the synthetic population are shown in Fig. 
 ",[Fig],['PERSON'],[115],[118],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5833907\sections\1_body\4_discussion\1_p.xml,"In our pediatric population undergoing HSCT who were receiving cyclosporine to prevent GVHD, TAN Bayesian network was the best method to predict whether the initial cyclosporine concentration after HSCT will be in the therapeutic range. The therapeutic range of the cyclosporine blood concentration rather than cyclosporine blood concentration itself was chosen as the endpoint because it seemed the most clinically relevant and simplest to handle for clinicians while using an online Bayesian network. This tool will allow them to find the best cyclosporine dosing regimen to reach the therapeutic interval right after transplantation, using a simple method, provided that further external validation is satisfactory.","[HSCT, GVHD, TAN Bayesian, HSCT, Bayesian]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']","[39, 87, 93, 198, 485]","[43, 91, 105, 202, 493]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5833907\sections\1_body\4_discussion\9_p.xml,Our approach testing the sensitivity of our method with regards to missing data seems very important as data in clinical practice are often incomplete because of real-life conditions.,[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5833907\sections\1_body\4_discussion\16_limitations\1_p.xml,"It should be noted that some other variables may influence cyclosporine trough blood concentrations, but these are not available nor considered in clinical practice, and thus this model does not include them.",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5833907\sections\1_body\5_conclusion\1_p.xml,"In this study we have developed and validated an online Bayesian network to assess the ability of the initial cyclosporine blood concentration to be in the therapeutic interval after pediatric HSCT. This model allows the simulation of different dosing regimens, finding the best to enable the right cyclosporine residual concentration to be reached immediately after transplantation, minimizing the risk of adverse effects and GVHD occurrence. The characteristics of this model are satisfactory but external multicentric validation is needed before its use in clinical practice.",[Bayesian],['GPE'],[56],[64],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5834144\sections\1_body\0_introduction\1_p.xml,"Advances in our understanding of the pathophysiology of CINV, identification of patient risk factors [
 ",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5834144\sections\1_body\1_patients_and_methods\1_study_design\1_p.xml,"This was a phase III, multicenter, randomized, double-blind/double-dummy, single initial cycle, parallel group international study. Patients were randomized at 46 enrolling sites in 4 countries (30 in China, 5 Taiwan, 3 Thailand, and 8 Korea) between February 2014 and August 2015.","[III, 46, 4, 30, China, 5, Taiwan, 3, Thailand, 8 Korea, between February 2014, August 2015]","['ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'GPE', 'CARDINAL', 'GPE', 'CARDINAL', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'DATE', 'DATE']","[17, 160, 182, 195, 201, 208, 210, 218, 220, 234, 243, 269]","[20, 162, 183, 197, 206, 209, 216, 219, 228, 241, 264, 280]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5834144\sections\1_body\1_patients_and_methods\2_patients\1_p.xml,"Inclusion/exclusion criteria were similar to those in the original oral NEPA pivotal trials [
 ",[NEPA],['ORG'],[72],[76],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5834144\sections\1_body\1_patients_and_methods\3_treatment\1_p.xml,"Patients were stratified by gender and randomly assigned (1 : 1) to receive either NEPA or APR/GRAN treatment (
 ","[1, NEPA, APR/GRAN]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[58, 83, 91]","[59, 87, 99]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5834144\sections\1_body\1_patients_and_methods\4_assessments\1_p.xml,"During days 1–5 (0–120 h), each patient completed a diary, capturing emetic episodes, severity of nausea and rescue medications intake. An emetic episode was defined as any episode of vomiting or retching or combined vomiting/retching. Severity of nausea was evaluated using a 100-mm horizontal visual analog scale (VAS) ranging from ‘no nausea’ (0 mm) to ‘nausea as bad as it could be’ (100 mm). The Functional Living Index-Emesis (FLIE) questionnaire [nine nausea-specific (nausea domain) and nine vomiting-specific (vomiting domain) items] was used to assess the impact of CINV on patient’s daily life. Responses were marked on a 100-mm VAS with anchors of 1 and 7. Patients completed this questionnaire on days 2 and 6 [
 ","[days, 100-mm, 100, The Functional Living Index-Emesis (, FLIE, nine, nine, 100-mm, 1, days 2]","['DATE', 'QUANTITY', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'QUANTITY', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE']","[7, 277, 388, 397, 433, 454, 495, 633, 660, 710]","[11, 283, 391, 433, 437, 458, 499, 639, 661, 716]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5834144\sections\1_body\1_patients_and_methods\5_statistical_analysis\1_p.xml,"For the primary endpoint, non-inferiority of NEPA and APR/GRAN was demonstrated if the lower limit of the confidence interval (CI; two-sided 95% CI significance level) for the difference between NEPA and APR/GRAN in proportion of patients with overall CR was greater than −10%. The risk difference and associated 95% CI were analyzed using the Cochran–Mantel–Haenszel (CMH) test stratified by gender. For secondary endpoints of acute/delayed and daily CR as well as no emesis, NSN, no nausea, no rescue use, and NIDL as assessed by the FLIE, statistical analyses utilized the same methods as the primary endpoint, without testing for non-inferiority.","[NEPA, APR/GRAN, CI, two, 95%, CI, NEPA, APR/GRAN, CR, 95%, CMH, NSN, NIDL, FLIE]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'PERCENT', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'PERCENT', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[45, 54, 127, 131, 141, 145, 195, 204, 252, 313, 369, 477, 512, 536]","[49, 62, 129, 134, 144, 147, 199, 212, 254, 316, 372, 480, 516, 540]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5834144\sections\1_body\2_results\1_analyzed_patient_populati\1_p.xml,"A total of 834 patients were randomized into the study (
 ",[834],['CARDINAL'],[11],[14],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5834144\sections\1_body\2_results\2_efficacy\1_p.xml,"For the primary efficacy endpoint, NEPA demonstrated non-inferiority to APR/GRAN with overall CR rates of 73.8% and 72.4%, respectively (95% CI: −4.5%, 7.5%) (Figure 
 ","[NEPA, CR, 73.8%, 72.4%, 95%, −4.5%, 7.5%]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT']","[35, 94, 106, 116, 137, 145, 152]","[39, 96, 111, 121, 140, 150, 156]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5834144\sections\1_body\2_results\3_safety\1_p.xml,"The incidence of AEs was comparable between the two treatment groups (NEPA 58.1%, APR/GRAN 57.5%). The most common TRAEs were constipation (NEPA 8.0%, APR/GRAN 6.3%) and hiccups (NEPA 2.7%, APR/GRAN 1.4%). Among the patients reporting AEs, the majority (90%) reported events of mild/moderate intensity, with more severe AEs in the APR/GRAN group (10.8% versus NEPA 8.7%). There were two patients with serious TRAEs in each group (NEPA: i) atrial fibrillation and (ii) chest pain/hypotension/decreased heart rate/non-responsiveness (concomitant medication included amifostine); APR/GRAN: (i) increased alanine aminotransferase and (ii) pancreatitis. While the patient experiencing the chest pain/hypotension event recovered within an hour of NEPA treatment, this was the only AE leading to discontinuation from study. There were no deaths in the NEPA group, while four patients treated with APR/GRAN died due to unrelated AEs. Changes from baseline in 12-lead ECGs were rare and similar.","[two, NEPA, 58.1%, APR, GRAN, 57.5%, NEPA 8.0%, APR, GRAN, 6.3%, NEPA, 2.7%, 1.4%, 90%, APR, GRAN, 10.8%, NEPA, 8.7%, two, NEPA, an hour, NEPA, AE, NEPA, four, 12]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'PERCENT', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERCENT', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERCENT', 'ORG', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERCENT', 'ORG', 'PERCENT', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'TIME', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL']","[48, 70, 75, 82, 86, 91, 140, 151, 155, 160, 179, 184, 199, 254, 331, 335, 347, 360, 365, 383, 430, 730, 741, 775, 845, 863, 951]","[51, 74, 80, 85, 90, 96, 149, 154, 159, 164, 183, 188, 203, 257, 334, 339, 352, 364, 369, 386, 434, 737, 745, 777, 849, 867, 953]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5834144\sections\1_body\3_discussion\1_p.xml,"While the current antiemetic armamentarium offers the potential to prevent CINV in the majority of patients, events including hospitalization do occur. Simplifying the multi-drug regimens may be appealing to clinicians and patients and may enhance compliance with antiemetic guideline recommendations. The standard aprepitant regimen requires co-administration of a 5-HT
 ",[5],['CARDINAL'],[366],[367],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5834144\sections\1_body\3_discussion\9_p.xml,"In conclusion, our study indicated that as a combination antiemetic targeting two antiemetic pathways with a single dose administered only once per cycle, NEPA offers a convenient and simplified prophylactic antiemetic that is at least as effective as a 3-day aprepitant regimen with granisetron.","[two, NEPA, 3-day]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'DATE']","[78, 155, 254]","[81, 159, 259]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5834772\sections\1_body\5_conflict_of_interest\1_p.xml,"K.A. has received honoraria and research funding from Eisai Co., Ltd. M.O. has received research funding from Eisai Co., Ltd., Kyowa Hakko Kirin Co., Ltd., Zenyaku Kogyo Co., Ltd., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Pfizer Japan Inc., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., GlaxoSmithKline K.K., MSD K.K., AstraZeneca K.K., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, Symbio Pharmaceuticals Limited, Solasia Pharma K.K., Mundipharma K.K., Celgene K.K., and Sumitomo Dainippon Pharma Co., Ltd. T.U. has received research funding from Eisai Co., Ltd. K.T. has received research funding from Eisai Co., Ltd., Mundipharma K.K., Celgene K.K., Solasia Pharma K.K., Kyowa Hakko Kirin Co., Ltd., and HUYA Bioscience International. D.M. has received honoraria from Eisai Co., Ltd and Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. M.N. and T.N. are employees of Eisai Co., Ltd. K.O. has no conflict of interest.","[K.A., Eisai Co., Ltd., M.O., Eisai Co., Ltd., Kyowa Hakko Kirin Co., Ltd., Zenyaku Kogyo Co., Ltd., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Pfizer Japan Inc., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., GlaxoSmithKline K.K., MSD K.K., AstraZeneca K.K., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, Symbio Pharmaceuticals Limited, Solasia, Sumitomo Dainippon Pharma Co.,, Eisai Co., Ltd., K.T., Eisai Co., Ltd., Mundipharma K.K., K.K., Solasia, Kyowa Hakko Kirin Co., Ltd., HUYA Bioscience International, D.M., Eisai Co., Ltd and Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., M.N., T.N., Eisai Co., Ltd., K.O.]","['GPE', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE']","[0, 54, 70, 110, 127, 156, 181, 214, 233, 262, 284, 294, 312, 351, 383, 440, 516, 532, 572, 589, 615, 621, 642, 675, 706, 739, 790, 799, 821, 837]","[4, 69, 74, 125, 154, 179, 212, 231, 260, 282, 292, 310, 349, 381, 390, 470, 531, 536, 587, 605, 619, 628, 669, 704, 710, 783, 794, 803, 836, 841]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5835032\sections\1_body\0_introduction\1_p.xml,"After allogeneic stem cell transplantation (alloSCT), severe graft-versus-host disease (GVHD) can be induced by donor T-cells recognizing normal tissues of the recipient. T-cell depletion (TCD) of the stem cell graft is an effective strategy to prevent GVHD, and alloSCT regimens using the CD52 antibody alemtuzumab for TCD or using infusion of purified CD34 cells demonstrate efficient engraftment and reduced acute GVHD (
 ","[TCD, GVHD, TCD, CD34, GVHD]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PRODUCT', 'PERSON']","[189, 253, 320, 354, 417]","[192, 257, 323, 358, 421]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5835032\sections\1_body\1_materials_and_methods\1_patients\1_p.xml,"After approval by the LUMC Institutional Review Board and written informed consent from the patient according to the Declaration of Helsinki, a 4-mm punch biopsy from normal skin over the posterior iliac crest was taken from patients at the day of alloSCT or at 3, 6, 12, or 24 weeks after alloSCT in the absence of GVHD. In case of the presence of GVHD after alloSCT, a skin biopsy was taken from affected skin. Diagnosis of skin GVHD was confirmed by an experienced pathologist.","[the LUMC Institutional Review Board, the Declaration of Helsinki, 3, 6, 12, 24 weeks, GVHD]","['ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'PERSON']","[18, 113, 262, 265, 268, 275, 349]","[53, 140, 263, 266, 270, 283, 353]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5835032\sections\1_body\1_materials_and_methods\2_immunofluorescence_labeli\1_p.xml,"To investigate the pro-inflammatory environment in the skin at various time points after transplantation, 4-µm cryopreserved sections were cut, dried for 1 h at 60°C followed by 30 min at room temperature, and fixated in acetone for 10 min. Immunohistochemical staining was performed overnight at room temperature using monoclonal antibodies (MoAbs) against CD3 (IgG2a, Ps1-ab699, Abcam, Cambridge, MA, USA) and CD8 (IgG2b, 4B11, Leica Microsystems, Rijswijk, Netherlands) as markers for T-cell infiltration in the skin and against HLA class II (IgG1, p104630, Dako, Heverlee, Belgium), HLA-DR (IgG2b, B8.11.2), and CD54 (IgG1, ab20, Abcam) as markers for activated cells. To investigate whether HLA class II-positive cells in skin biopsies were resident dermal dendritic cells (DCs), inflammatory dermal DC, or dermal macrophages, staining with MoAb against CD1c (IgG1, MCA694, Bio-Rad Laboratories, Veenendaal, Netherlands), CD11c (IgG1, B-Ly6, BD, Breda, Netherlands), CD40 (IgG1, 5C3, BD), CD54 (IgG1, ab20, Abcam), CD86 (IgG1, ab23556, Abcam), CD206 (IgG1, 19.2, BD), and CD209 (IgG1, AZM D1, BD) was performed. Afterward, slides were incubated for 1 h at room temperature with secondary fluorescently labeled goat-anti-mouse IgG2a ALEXA 546 (red), IgG2b ALEXA 647 (blue), and IgG1 ALEXA 488 (green) (Alexa, Invitrogen, Breda, Netherlands) diluted in phosphate-buffered saline with 1% bovine serum albumin. After washing, slides were covered with Mowiol 4-88 (Sigma Aldrich), and images were captured by confocal laser scanning microscope LSM510 (Zeiss, Sliedrecht, Netherlands).","[4-µm, 1, 60, 30, 10, overnight, MoAbs, CD3 (IgG2a, Abcam, Cambridge, MA, USA, Leica Microsystems, Rijswijk, Netherlands, II, Dako, Belgium, CD54, ab20, Abcam, II, DC, MoAb, MCA694, Bio-Rad Laboratories, Veenendaal, Netherlands, CD11c, BD, Breda, Netherlands, CD40, BD, CD54, ab20, Abcam, CD86, Abcam, CD206, 19.2, BD, CD209, 1, 546, 647, Alexa, Breda, Netherlands, 1%, Mowiol 4-88, Sigma Aldrich, LSM510 (Zeiss, Sliedrecht, Netherlands]","['CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'TIME', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'PERSON', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'NORP', 'PERSON', 'CARDINAL', 'GPE', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'NORP', 'PERSON', 'PRODUCT', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'PERCENT', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'GPE', 'GPE']","[106, 154, 161, 178, 233, 284, 343, 358, 381, 388, 399, 403, 430, 450, 460, 542, 561, 577, 616, 628, 634, 706, 805, 846, 871, 879, 901, 913, 927, 947, 951, 958, 972, 989, 994, 1006, 1012, 1020, 1041, 1049, 1062, 1068, 1077, 1154, 1243, 1266, 1306, 1325, 1332, 1387, 1452, 1465, 1544, 1559, 1571]","[110, 155, 163, 180, 235, 293, 348, 368, 386, 397, 401, 406, 448, 458, 471, 544, 565, 584, 620, 632, 639, 708, 807, 850, 877, 899, 911, 924, 932, 949, 956, 969, 976, 991, 998, 1010, 1017, 1024, 1046, 1054, 1066, 1070, 1082, 1155, 1246, 1269, 1311, 1330, 1343, 1389, 1463, 1478, 1557, 1569, 1582]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5835032\sections\1_body\1_materials_and_methods\3_statistical_analysis\1_p.xml,"Quantification of labeled cells in the dermis was done using Image J (National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD, USA) by measuring the dermal area count, which is a calculation of the percentage of the area taken by the labeled cells as a part of the total dermal area in the biopsy as described before (
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5835032\sections\1_body\2_results\1_no_overt_inflammatory_env\1_p.xml,"To investigate whether conditioning before alloSCT results in an inflammatory environment in the skin coinciding with increased expression of HLA class II molecules and attraction of T-cells, the quantitative presence of HLA class II- or CD3-expressing cells in the dermal layer was substantiated by dermal area count calculation in skin biopsies taken from patients at the time of the transplantation following NMA or MA conditioning and compared to normal skin biopsies. As shown in a representative example in Figure 
 ","[II, NMA, MA]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[152, 412, 419]","[154, 415, 421]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5835032\sections\1_body\2_results\2_increase_of_hla_class_ii_\1_p.xml,"To analyze the activation status of dermal cells early after alloSCT and after hematopoietic reconstitution in the absence of an allogeneic immune response, we substantiated the amount of HLA class II-expressing cells and T-cells in skin biopsies taken during hematopoietic recovery (3 and 6 weeks after transplantation) and during the period of immune reconstitution (12 and 24 weeks after transplantation) by dermal area count calculation. Patients were selected not to have GVHD of the skin. Biopsies taken at various time points after transplantation were compared to biopsies taken at the day of transplantation (
 ","[II, 3, 12, 24 weeks, the day]","['CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'DATE']","[198, 284, 369, 376, 590]","[200, 285, 371, 384, 597]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5835032\sections\1_body\2_results\3_massive_inflammation_in_b\1_p.xml,"To investigate whether the skin biopsies that showed significant increase in HLA class II-positive cells 24 weeks after MA alloSCT were immunohistochemically different from biopsies with overt inflammation, skin biopsies taken from patients suffering from acute skin GVHD within 24 weeks after alloSCT were analyzed.","[II, 24 weeks, MA, 24 weeks]","['CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'DATE']","[87, 105, 120, 279]","[89, 113, 122, 287]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5835032\sections\1_body\2_results\4_recruitment_of_macrophage\1_p.xml,"To determine the nature of the increased numbers of HLA class II-positive cells observed in the dermal region of the skin during immune reconstitution following MA transplantation, expression of CD1c, CD11c, CD40, CD54, CD86, and CD206 (mannose receptor) was measured, since these markers allow distinction of different subsets of dermal APC (Table 
 ","[II, MA, CD11c, CD40, CD54, CD86, CD206, APC]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'PERSON']","[62, 161, 201, 208, 214, 220, 230, 338]","[64, 163, 206, 212, 218, 224, 235, 341]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5835032\sections\1_body\2_results\5_gradual_replacement_of_re\1_p.xml,"To investigate whether the observed dermal macrophages with non-professional APC phenotype after alloSCT were of patient or donor origin, XY-FISH combined with staining of HLA class II was performed after alloSCT from patients with a gender-mismatched donor. Skin biopsies taken from patients after auto-SCT were used as negative controls. After alloSCT, a gradual decline of the percentages of patient-derived HLA class II-positive cells was observed, and HLA class II-positive cells of patient origin were replaced by cells of donor origin. However, even 24 weeks after alloSCT, HLA class II-positive cells of patient origin could be detected in the skin (Figures 
 ","[APC, II, 24 weeks, II]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL']","[77, 182, 557, 591]","[80, 184, 565, 593]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5835032\sections\1_body\3_discussion\1_p.xml,"Our data illustrate that the conditioning regimen before alloSCT did not directly cause an inflammatory environment in the skin at the day of infusion of the stem cell graft. In the absence of GVHD, after hematologic recovery following TBI containing MA alloSCT, HLA class II-positive macrophages, but not cells with a phenotype of professional APC were recruited to the dermal region of the skin. These HLA class II-positive macrophages are most probably involved in repairing tissue damage. T-cells were also recruited to the dermal area, but did not show activation or interaction with the HLA class II-positive cells. In contrast, after conditioning regimens lacking TBI, no increase in dermal macrophages or T-cells was observed during the phase of hematologic and immunologic recovery. In the absence of GVHD, patient chimerism of dermal HLA class II-positive cells gradually changed over time to a median of 23% at 6 months after alloSCT, but patient-derived HLA class II-positive cells remained detectable. Skin affected by GVHD also contained high number of T-cells and HLA class II-expressing cells, but with an activated APC phenotype. In these biopsies, strong interactions between APC and T-cells were seen, coincided by the activation of T-cells and local inflammation resulting in upregulation of HLA class II molecules also on epidermal cells. Probably due to destruction of recipient-derived APC by donor T-cells during GVHD, these biopsies only contained APC of donor origin.","[the day, TBI, MA, APC, II, TBI, II, 23%, 6 months, GVHD, II, APC, APC, II, APC, APC]","['DATE', 'ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'PERCENT', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[131, 236, 251, 345, 603, 671, 854, 915, 922, 1032, 1089, 1132, 1194, 1322, 1409, 1473]","[138, 239, 253, 348, 605, 674, 856, 918, 930, 1036, 1091, 1135, 1197, 1324, 1412, 1476]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5835032\sections\1_body\4_author_contributions\1_p.xml,"PB and BZ contributed equally as first authors. PB, BZ, AK, and ME performed research experiments and analyzed the data. PB, BZ, KS, EJ, JF, and IJ interpreted the data and wrote the manuscript.","[BZ, first, BZ, KS, EJ, JF, IJ]","['ORG', 'ORDINAL', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[7, 33, 125, 129, 133, 137, 145]","[9, 38, 127, 131, 135, 139, 147]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5835032\sections\2_back\0_supplementary_material\1_p.xml,"The Supplementary Material for this article can be found online at 
 ",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5841331\sections\1_body\0_introduction\1_p.xml,"Momelotinib (MMB; GS-0387; CYT387) is a JAK1 and JAK2 inhibitor, with therapeutic activity in myelofibrosis (MF), in humans as well as in mice
 ","[MMB, GS-0387, CYT387]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[13, 18, 27]","[16, 25, 33]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5841331\sections\1_body\1_methods\1_p.xml,"The current study was approved by the Mayo Clinic institutional review board and all patients provided informed written consent for clinical trial participation, study sample collection as well as permission for its use in research. Patient eligibility criteria, study design, treatment plan, study test schedule, and other protocol details have previously been reported
 ",[Mayo Clinic],['ORG'],[38],[49],informed written consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5841331\sections\1_body\2_results\1_patient_characteristics_a\1_p.xml,"The current study involves 100 MMB-treated patients (median age 66 years; 58% males) from the Mayo Clinic who were enrolled between 20 November 2009 and 10 November 2010; 64 patients had primary, 22 post-polycythemia vera, and 14 post-essential thrombocythemia MF; 73 (73%) harbored 
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5841331\sections\1_body\2_results\2_adverse_events\1_p.xml,"As of July 2017, MMB treatment has been discontinued in 91 (91%) patients, after a median treatment duration of 1.4 years (range 0.02–6.2); median duration of treatment in the nine (9%) patients still receiving the drug was 6.7 years (range 6.3–7.2). The most frequent reason for treatment discontinuation was suboptimal response or progressive disease (59%), including on-study leukemic transformation (3 patients); other reasons included side effects (15%) including peripheral neuropathy (7 patients), on-study deaths (15 patients), and development of secondary malignancies (3 patients). “MMB-related” grade 3 or 4 AEs included thrombocytopenia (34%), neutropenia (9%), anemia (5%), increased serum lipase (7%), alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (4%), aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (2%), alkaline phosphatase (2%) levels, and headaches (2%). In addition, noteworthy grade 1 or 2 AEs included peripheral neuropathy 47%, increased serum lipase (14%), amylase (17%), bilirubin (13%), AST (21%), ALT (19%) levels, increased activated partial thromboplastin time (APTT) (17%), headaches (13%), dizziness (22%), nausea (23%), and diarrhea (20%). Most of the AEs, except peripheral neuropathy, were reversible.","[July 2017, MMB, 91 (91%, 1.4 years, 0.02–6.2, 9%, 6.7 years, 6.3–7.2, 59%, 3, 15%, 7, 15, 3, 3, 34%, 9%, 5%, 7%, 4%, 2%, 2%, 2%, 1, 2, 47%, 14%, 17%, 13%, AST, 21%, 19%, 17%, 13%, 22%, 23%, 20%]","['DATE', 'ORG', 'PERCENT', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'PERCENT', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'PERCENT', 'CARDINAL', 'PERCENT', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERSON', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT', 'PERCENT']","[6, 17, 56, 112, 129, 182, 224, 241, 354, 404, 454, 492, 522, 579, 612, 650, 669, 682, 711, 748, 787, 814, 841, 876, 881, 918, 947, 962, 979, 985, 990, 1001, 1070, 1087, 1104, 1118, 1138]","[15, 20, 63, 121, 137, 184, 233, 248, 357, 405, 457, 493, 524, 580, 613, 653, 671, 684, 713, 750, 789, 816, 843, 877, 882, 921, 950, 965, 982, 988, 993, 1004, 1073, 1090, 1107, 1121, 1141]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5841331\sections\1_body\2_results\3_treatment_efficacy_and_pr\1_p.xml,"Clinical improvement (CI) was achieved by 57 (57%) patients and included anemia response in 44%, and spleen response in 43% of informative cases. Response in both anemia and spleen was recorded in 12 patients while 27 and 18 patients experienced “spleen only” or “anemia only” response. Fifty-one percent of transfusion-dependent patients became transfusion independent. The majority of patients also had marked improvement in their symptoms. Forty-nine (86%) of the 57 patients with CI have since discontinued treatment, after a median treatment duration of 2.3 years. CI was more likely to occur in 
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5841331\sections\1_body\2_results\4_overall_and_leukemia_free\1_p.xml,"To date, 73 (73%) deaths, occurring at a median of 2.5 years (range 0.06–6.9), and 15 (15%) leukemic transformations, occurring at a median of 3.6 years (range 0.12–7.2), have been recorded. Twenty-seven (27%) patients are currently alive and followed for a median of 6.6 years (range 5.5–7.2) from the time of study entry; among them, eight have received allogeneic stem cell transplant (ASCT) and were censored at the time of the procedure for survival analysis. Median survival from the time of study entry was 3.2 years with 5-year survival of 30%.","[73, 73%, 2.5 years, 15, 15%, 3.6 years, 0.12–7.2, Twenty-seven, 27%, 6.6 years, 5.5–7.2, eight, ASCT, Median, 3.2 years, 5-year, 30%]","['CARDINAL', 'PERCENT', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'PERCENT', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'PERCENT', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'NORP', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'PERCENT']","[9, 13, 51, 83, 87, 143, 160, 191, 205, 268, 285, 336, 389, 465, 514, 529, 548]","[11, 16, 60, 85, 90, 152, 168, 203, 208, 277, 292, 341, 393, 471, 523, 535, 551]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5841331\sections\1_body\3_discussion\1_p.xml,"It is now well-established that momelotinib treatment in MF provides relief from symptomatic splenomegaly and constitutional symptoms, and unlike most other JAK2 inhibitors, also improves anemia in a substantial fraction of patients
 ",[],[],[],[],False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5842589\sections\1_body\0_background\1_multiple_myeloma\1_p.xml,"Multiple myeloma (MM) is a plasma cell tumour and has an annual incidence in the UK of approximately 4500 new cases [
 ","[MM, annual, UK, approximately 4500]","['PERSON', 'DATE', 'GPE', 'CARDINAL']","[18, 57, 81, 87]","[20, 63, 83, 105]",False
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5842589\sections\1_body\0_background\2_tackling_the_unmet_needs_\1_p.xml,"Two clear areas of unmet need arose from the Myeloma X study. Firstly, although superior to non-ASCT consolidation, both the DoR and DuR post-salvage ASCT were inferior to those reported in first-line treatment. This has been reported in phase III collaborative studies and national/international transplant registries. Hence, the question remains of how to utilise novel agents to augment this effect, aiming to achieve similar DoR and DuR to those seen in first-line treatment. Furthermore, in the Myeloma X study, for patients with evidence of molecular high-risk disease (
 ","[Two, Myeloma, Firstly, DoR, DuR, ASCT, first, DoR, DuR, first, Myeloma]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORDINAL', 'FAC', 'PERSON', 'PRODUCT', 'ORDINAL', 'FAC', 'PRODUCT', 'ORDINAL', 'ORG']","[0, 45, 62, 125, 133, 150, 190, 429, 437, 458, 500]","[3, 52, 69, 128, 136, 154, 195, 432, 440, 463, 507]",False
