,parsed,entities,labels,position_start,position_end,has_terms
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5788875\sections\1_body\2_materials_and_methods\1_patient_population\1_p.xml,"This study protocol represents a sub‐study of a parent prospective randomized study comparing the effects of repetitive and single‐dose cell therapy in patients with nonischemic DCM (
 ",[DCM],['ORG'],[178],[181],study protocol
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\1_protocol_digest_of_the_st\2_study_setting_and_protoco\1_p.xml,"This is a single-arm, open-label, multicenter phase I study involving four institutions: Hokkaido University Hospital, St. Marianna University School of Medicine Hospital, National Hospital Organization Nagoya Medical Center, and Kyushu University Hospital. The protocol has been reviewed and approved by institutional review boards of each institutions.","[four, Hokkaido University Hospital, St. Marianna University School of Medicine Hospital, National Hospital Organization Nagoya Medical Center, Kyushu University Hospital]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[70, 89, 119, 172, 230]","[74, 117, 170, 224, 256]",institutional review
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\1_protocol_digest_of_the_st\4_eligibility_criteria\1_p.xml,Written informed consent regarding participation in this clinical study could be obtained from subjects and/or representatives,[],[],[],[],informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5796474\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\4_follow_up\1_p.xml,"In subjects treated with this drug, the following assessments should be performed 28 days (7 days) after the final administration if it does not exceed the data cut-off day. These assessments should be conducted before the start of posttreatment. If examinations/observation/surveys are impossible for unavoidable reasons, such as complete withdrawal from this study, drop-out, death, and unfavorable conditions, the reasons must be recorded in original materials, and this study should be completed. In this case, deficits in examination/observation/survey items scheduled 28 days after the final administration are not regarded as deviations from the study protocol.","[28 days, 7 days, 28 days]","['DATE', 'DATE', 'DATE']","[82, 91, 574]","[89, 97, 581]",study protocol
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5819660\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\9_consent\1_p.xml,"Informed consent will be obtained from all participants or a legal representative in case the former is impossible. As mentioned previously, this study involves two patient categories. In haematologic patients, lines are usually inserted electively for the administration of chemotherapy. Therefore, informed consent will be obtained before line placement. For the intensive care patient category, obtaining informed consent prior to CVC insertion is often not feasible. Therefore, for the intensive care setting patients may be included using the deferred consent procedure. We will randomise each patient at the ICU who meets the inclusion criteria directly before CVC placement. Informed consent from the legal representative will be requested as soon as possible. If informed consent is denied by a legal representative, the patient is excluded and data will no longer be used. Thenceforth, the patient is transfused according to the policy of the attending physician. If a patient dies before informed consent can be obtained, the data are used [
 ","[two, CVC, ICU, CVC]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[161, 434, 614, 667]","[164, 437, 617, 670]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830087\sections\1_body\1_methods\2_patient_eligibility\1_p.xml,"Patients, 18 to 75 years of age, provided written informed consent, and had histologically or cytologically confirmed non-squamous stage IIIB or IV NSCLC according to American Joint Committee on Cancer Staging v6 [
 ","[18, IIIB, IV NSCLC, American Joint Committee]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[10, 137, 145, 167]","[12, 141, 153, 191]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830087\sections\1_body\1_methods\3_study_design_and_treatmen\1_p.xml,"This randomized, open-label, multicenter, phase II study was performed at sites in Germany and the United States and was conducted in full accordance with the Good Clinical Practice: Consolidated Guideline approved by the International Conference on Harmonisation and all other applicable national and local laws/regulations. All study materials were approved by the governing ethics committee or institutional review board at each site.","[II, Germany, the United States, the Good Clinical Practice, Consolidated Guideline, the International Conference on Harmonisation]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[48, 83, 95, 155, 183, 218]","[50, 90, 112, 181, 205, 263]",ethics committee
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5830392\sections\1_body\1_methods\1_p.xml,This prospective clinical trial was approved by the institutional review board of the Dana-Farber Cancer Institute/Harvard Cancer Center. Written informed consent was obtained prior to patient enrollment.,[Dana-Farber Cancer Institute/Harvard Cancer Center],['ORG'],[86],[136],informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5835032\sections\1_body\1_materials_and_methods\1_patients\1_p.xml,"After approval by the LUMC Institutional Review Board and written informed consent from the patient according to the Declaration of Helsinki, a 4-mm punch biopsy from normal skin over the posterior iliac crest was taken from patients at the day of alloSCT or at 3, 6, 12, or 24 weeks after alloSCT in the absence of GVHD. In case of the presence of GVHD after alloSCT, a skin biopsy was taken from affected skin. Diagnosis of skin GVHD was confirmed by an experienced pathologist.","[the LUMC Institutional Review Board, the Declaration of Helsinki, 3, 6, 12, 24 weeks, GVHD]","['ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'PERSON']","[18, 113, 262, 265, 268, 275, 349]","[53, 140, 263, 266, 270, 283, 353]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5841331\sections\1_body\1_methods\1_p.xml,"The current study was approved by the Mayo Clinic institutional review board and all patients provided informed written consent for clinical trial participation, study sample collection as well as permission for its use in research. Patient eligibility criteria, study design, treatment plan, study test schedule, and other protocol details have previously been reported
 ",[Mayo Clinic],['ORG'],[38],[49],informed written consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5842589\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\14_data_collection\1_p.xml,"Data will be collected using paper CRFs and entered into a validated trial database by the CTRU. A validation check program will be incorporated into the trial database to verify the data, and discrepancy reports will be generated for resolution by the investigator. Priority validations will be incorporated into the validation program to ensure that any discrepancies related to participant rights or safety are expedited to sites for resolution. Data will be monitored for quality and completeness by the CTRU. Missing data will be chased until received, and confirmed as not available, or the trial is at analysis. The CTRU/Sponsor will reserve the right to intermittently conduct source data verification exercises on a sample of participants, which will be carried out by staff from the CTRU/Sponsor. Source data verification will involve direct access to participant notes at the participating hospital sites and the central collection of copies of consent forms and other relevant investigation reports. Data will be held on a secure server at the University of Leeds and paper CRFs stored in a locked unit, both of which are accessible only to authorised trial staff.","[CTRU, CTRU, The CTRU/Sponsor, the University of Leeds]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[91, 508, 619, 1052]","[95, 512, 635, 1075]",consent form
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5842589\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\5_trial_population\1_p.xml,"The ACCoRd study aims to investigate the aforementioned treatment strategy within a population of participants with measurable, by IMWG criteria, relapsed MM requiring therapy who had undergone ASCT in first-line treatment and progressed for the first time at least 12 months after undergoing ASCT. The study will be conducted within an adult population (18 years or older), capable of giving written informed consent, with Eastern Cooperative Oncology (ECOG) Performance Status (ECOG PS) 0–2 and adequate full blood count (FBC), as well as satisfactory renal, hepatobiliary, pulmonary and cardiac function.","[ACCoRd, IMWG, MM, ASCT, first, first, at least 12 months, ASCT, 18 years, Eastern Cooperative Oncology]","['ORG', 'GPE', 'PERSON', 'PRODUCT', 'ORDINAL', 'ORDINAL', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'ORG']","[4, 131, 155, 194, 202, 246, 257, 293, 355, 424]","[10, 135, 157, 198, 207, 251, 275, 297, 363, 452]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5842589\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\8_registration_and_randomis\1_p.xml,"Following confirmation of written informed consent and eligibility, an authorised member of staff at the trial research site will register participants immediately into the study. Registration will be performed centrally using the Leeds Clinical Trials Research Unit (CTRU) automated 24-h telephone and web registration and randomisation system (Gen24). Following successful registration, participants will undergo four to six cycles of ITD re-induction and will subsequently be assessed for response.","[Registration, the Leeds Clinical Trials Research Unit, CTRU, 24, four to six, ITD]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG']","[180, 227, 268, 284, 415, 437]","[192, 266, 272, 286, 426, 440]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5845260\sections\1_body\2_results\1_p.xml,"Twenty subjects with MS provided informed consent and were enrolled into this feasibility study from October 10, 2014 to February 18, 2015. Mean age of enrollees was 41.15 (SD = 9.29) years; 60% (12/20) were female (Table 
 ","[October 10, 2014 to February 18, 2015, 41.15, 60%, 12/20]","['DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'PERCENT', 'CARDINAL']","[101, 166, 191, 196]","[138, 171, 194, 201]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5864898\sections\1_body\4_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"The ethics committee of Hannover Medical School approved this study (Study number: 2148-2014 and 2604-2014), and all patients provided written confirmed consent before enrollment.","[Hannover Medical School, 2148-2014, 2604-2014]","['ORG', 'DATE', 'DATE']","[24, 83, 97]","[47, 92, 106]",ethics committee
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5891950\sections\1_body\1_methods\4_mesenchymal_stem_cells__m\1_p.xml,"ASCs (passage (P)2–P4) were used for injections into healthy and neurologically diseased horses. These cells were obtained from the UC Davis VMTH Regenerative Medicine Laboratory (RML). These samples were originally submitted for MSC expansion for autologous patient treatment. Excess cells not used for treatment were donated for research purposes with written consent of the owner. Cryopreserved MSCs were thawed, washed, and expanded in culture exactly as previously described [
 ","[the UC Davis VMTH Regenerative Medicine Laboratory, RML]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[128, 180]","[178, 183]",written consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5916588\sections\1_body\2_discussion\1_p.xml,This study protocol is designed to focus on investigating the neuromodulation role of transcranial LED therapy (TCLT) for patients who are victims of severe traumatic brain injury (TBI) with diffuse axonal injury. The objective of the study is to verify the hypothesis that this therapy presents pro-cognitive effects for rehabilitation.,[TBI],['ORG'],[181],[184],study protocol
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5932813\sections\1_body\1_methods\4_selection_of_cases_and_re\1_p.xml,"Patients admitted in the haematology wards of the two participating centres receiving myeloablative chemotherapy and who are expected to develop prolonged neutropenia (> 7 days) will be followed up daily by the attending physicians and by a research nurse specifically commissioned to carry out this study. Screening swabs from the catheter hubs and the catheter insertion site will be collected previous to randomisation by the usual nursing personnel; then, the catheter samples will be sent to the microbiology laboratory in order to identify patients with positive cultures (exclusion criteria). Patients with negative screening cultures will be followed up daily by the research nurse in charge and/or the investigators of the study, to assess whether they meet all the inclusion criteria and none of the exclusion criteria. A blood test will be performed every 2–3 days according to the protocols of each centre to document the development of neutropenia. Patients with neutropenia who met the inclusion criteria will be asked to sign the informed consent. The research nurse in charge and/or the investigators of the study will explain the study to the potential participants and ask them to sign the informed consent.","[two, daily, daily, 2–3]","['CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL']","[50, 198, 662, 867]","[53, 203, 667, 870]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5934787\sections\1_body\1_methods\4_study_design_and_treatmen\1_p.xml,"Once subjects signed the informed consent, and were found eligible, there was a 1 month “wash in” period, during which subjects adjusted their exercise level in order to achieve 150 min of moderate-intensity physical activity per week. Diet counseling was also provided. At visit 1, baseline values of the following measures were gathered: blood biochemistries, vitals, biophysical parameters, resting energy expenditure (REE), arterial stiffness measures, and endothelial progenitor cells analysis. Subjects were then randomized to one of two arms: saxagliptin 5 mg/day or placebo, in a blinded manner. Subjects took either saxagliptin (n = 21) or placebo (n = 21) for 12 weeks, while engaging in 150 min of moderate intensity physical activity per week. Visits were conducted every 6 weeks, ending at week 12 (visit 3).","[150, 1, one, two, 5, 21, 21, 12 weeks, 150, 6 weeks, week 12, 3]","['CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL']","[178, 280, 533, 540, 562, 642, 662, 670, 698, 784, 803, 818]","[181, 281, 536, 543, 563, 644, 664, 678, 701, 791, 810, 819]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5943466\sections\1_body\1_materials_and_methods\1_patient_population\1_p.xml,"This was a randomized, open‐label, multicenter, dose‐ranging, active‐controlled study of Rolontis versus pegfilgrastim in patients aged ≥18 years with breast cancer who were candidates for adjuvant or neoadjuvant treatment with TC chemotherapy (NCT01724866). Other key inclusion criteria included the willingness and ability to provide written informed consent; Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status ≤2; adequate bone marrow function before the start of chemotherapy (ANC ≥1.5 × 10
 ","[Rolontis, ≥18 years, NCT01724866, Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group, ANC]","['ORG', 'DATE', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[89, 136, 245, 362, 491]","[97, 145, 256, 396, 494]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5951114\sections\1_body\1_materials_and_methods\3_mechanism_of_action_of_cy\1_p.xml,"PBMCs were isolated from venous blood of healthy adult participants following informed consent per approved institutional protocol (McGill University). CD4 memory T cells were obtained by magnetic activated cell sorting with negative selection, which depletes CD45RA, CD8, CD14, CD16, CD19, CD56, CD36, CD123, anti-TCRγδ, and CD235a (glycophorin A) according to manufacturer’s instructions (Miltenyi Biotec, Auburn, CA, USA). The resulting phenotype was CD3
 ","[McGill University, CD14, CD16, CD19, CD56, CD36, CD123, anti-TCRγδ, Miltenyi Biotec, USA]","['ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PRODUCT', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'GPE']","[132, 273, 279, 285, 291, 297, 303, 310, 391, 420]","[149, 277, 283, 289, 295, 301, 308, 320, 406, 423]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5951114\sections\1_body\5_ethics_statement\1_p.xml,"Samples were collected, as specified in the immune monitoring sub study, from patients enrolled in the trial “Autologous Stem Cell Transplant for Multiple Sclerosis (MS/BMT)” (NCT01099930) following informed consent as approved by the institutional review boards. PBMCs were isolated from healthy donors following informed consent per approved institutional protocol (McGill University).","[Autologous Stem Cell Transplant for Multiple Sclerosis (MS/BMT, McGill University]","['WORK_OF_ART', 'ORG']","[110, 368]","[172, 385]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5983708\sections\1_body\3_4__materials_and_methods\1_4_1__patients\1_p.xml,"The study was designed as a prospective, open-label, nonrandomized clinical trial in a single center for subjects with ALS. The trial (international number: NCT02193893) was approved (approval code: KB-0012/06/10; 25 January 2010) by the Ethics Committee of the Pomeranian Medical University in Szczecin (Poland) and performed in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki; all patients provided written informed consent. A total of 12 patients, four females and eight males, between 21 and 65 years old (49.7 ± 13.08), with sporadic ALS according to the El Escorial Revised Criteria [
 ","[ALS, NCT02193893, KB-0012/06/10, 25 January 2010, the Ethics Committee of, the Pomeranian Medical University in Szczecin (, Poland, the Declaration of Helsinki, 12, four, eight, between 21 and 65 years old, 49.7, 13.08, ALS, the El Escorial Revised Criteria]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[119, 157, 199, 214, 234, 258, 305, 346, 434, 447, 464, 477, 506, 513, 535, 552]","[122, 168, 212, 229, 257, 305, 311, 373, 436, 451, 469, 504, 510, 518, 538, 584]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC5983708\sections\1_body\3_4__materials_and_methods\3_4_3__cells\1_p.xml,"BM from the patients was obtained after informed consent was given. BM samples (40–50 mL) were aspirated in local anesthesia, from the posterior iliac crest of recruited patients and subsequently resuspended in a collecting medium (phosphate-buffered saline (PBS), pH 7.2) and heparin (20 U/mL; Gibco, Waltham, MA, USA). BM samples were lysed in BD PharmLyse Lysing Solution (BD Biosciences, San Jose, CA, USA) for 15 min at room temperature in the dark and washed twice in phosphate-buffered saline. The obtained suspension of BM nucleated cells (NCs) was subjected to immunomagnetic separation procedures (MiniMACS, Miltenyi Biotec, Auburn, AL, USA). Lineage-negative SPCs (7.89 ± 5.77 × 10
 ","[40–50 mL, PBS, 7.2, 20, U/mL, Gibco, Waltham, MA, USA, BD PharmLyse Lysing Solution, San Jose, USA, 15, Miltenyi Biotec, USA, 7.89, 10]","['MONEY', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'CARDINAL', 'PERSON', 'GPE', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL']","[80, 259, 268, 286, 289, 295, 302, 311, 315, 346, 392, 406, 415, 618, 647, 676, 690]","[88, 262, 271, 288, 293, 300, 309, 313, 318, 374, 400, 409, 417, 633, 650, 680, 692]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6042450\sections\1_body\1_methods\1_study_enrollment_and_incl\1_p.xml,"These findings are the mid-term results of a prospective, experimental, non-controlled, phase I clinical trial supported by investigator-driven funding. The inclusion criteria included secondary infertility or embryo transfer failure caused by recurrent IUA, a desire to be pregnant, an age of less than 45 years, and agreeing to participate in the study. Patients were excluded from recruitment if they had any of the following issues: having hysteroscopy contraindications, chromosome karyotype abnormalities, congenital uterine malformations, severe adenomyosis, contraindications to pregnancy, contraindications to estradiol treatment, medical history of pelvic malignant tumors, previous experience with pelvic radiotherapy. For patients who met the indications for stem cell therapy, written informed consent was obtained. Patients with recurrent IUA were diagnosed according to their history profiles, and three experienced gynecologists at the Drum Tower Hospital performed hysteroscopy examinations for severity classification using the American Fertility Society scoring method (The American Fertility Society, 1988) during the screening process.","[IUA, IUA, three, the Drum Tower Hospital, the American Fertility Society, The American Fertility Society, 1988]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'FAC', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE']","[254, 853, 913, 948, 1042, 1089, 1121]","[257, 856, 918, 971, 1072, 1119, 1125]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6042555\sections\1_body\3_ethics_and_dissemination\1_p.xml,"A waiver of informed consent by prescribers and patients was granted under the condition to provide an information leaflet to patients in the participating wards. Several publications in peer-reviewed journals are planned from this trial: these will include the description of the development of the intervention and main findings of the trial. Furthermore, the findings will be presented at national and international conferences.",[],[],[],[],informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6048892\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\3_inclusion_criteria\1_p.xml,Written informed consent (must be available before enrolment in the trial),[],[],[],[],informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6048892\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\5_assessment_of_the_primary\9_p.xml,"For the last patient in, the final study visit will be 12 months after baseline. This is considered the final study visit (last patient out). All other patients will be followed regularly as described in detail until death or until 12 months after baseline. Beyond that, all patients can be followed within routine clinical visits according to national guidelines and survival and progression data will be documented until ‘last patient out’. If death occurs at less than 12 months or patients leave the study prior to 12 months, they will be still included into the intention-to-treat population.","[12 months, 12 months, 12 months]","['DATE', 'DATE', 'DATE']","[55, 232, 519]","[64, 241, 528]",national guidelines
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6048892\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\9_ethical_issues__informati\1_p.xml,"The study protocol, Patient Information sheet, and Declaration of Informed Consent was approved by the Heidelberg University Ethics Committee (S-470/2017). The procedures described in the submitted study protocol regarding the performance, evaluation, and documentation of this study has been selected in such a way that the principles of the Good Clinical Practice (GCP) guidelines are observed. The regulations regarding medical confidentiality and data protection are fulfilled. Informed consent will be obtained from all participants in the study.","[Patient Information, the Heidelberg University Ethics Committee, the Good Clinical Practice]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[20, 99, 339]","[39, 141, 365]",study protocol
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6048892\sections\1_body\2_discussion\1_p.xml,"The primary aim of this trial is to exploratively investigate the effect of SRS compared to WBRT in patients with BM from SCLC. Currently, according to national guidelines, the recommendation for patients with BM from SCLC, regardless of the number of BM, is WBRT [
 ","[SRS, WBRT, SCLC, SCLC]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'DATE']","[76, 92, 122, 218]","[79, 96, 126, 222]",national guidelines
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6050722\sections\1_body\1_methods\1_study_design_and_patient_\1_p.xml,"In this study, a total of 726 patients were enrolled at Xiangya Hospital, Central South University between May 2009 and Feb 2017. This study was approved by the Ethics Committee of Institute of Clinical Pharmacology of Central South University (No. CTXY-120025-2) and conducted in compliance with the provisions of the Declaration of Helsinki (Chinese Clinical Trial Register: ChiCTR-PPC-14005297). All patients provided written informed consent that explicitly included genetic information sharing with qualified investigators before enrollment.","[726, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, May 2009, Feb 2017, the Ethics Committee of Institute of Clinical Pharmacology of Central South University, the Declaration of Helsinki]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART']","[26, 56, 74, 107, 120, 157, 315]","[29, 72, 98, 115, 128, 243, 342]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6055619\sections\1_body\5_conflict‐of‐interest_disc\1_p.xml,"P.G.R. reports advisory board participation for Celgene, Novartis and Takeda. C.C.H. reports research funding from Takeda, Celgene, ARNO Therapeutics, Janssen Pharmaceuticals, Karyopharm and Merck, and advisory board participation for Thrassos and InCyte. C.A.R. reports independent review committee membership for Millennium/Takeda clinical trial NCT01564537, advisory committee membership for Millennium, and consultancy fees from Celgene and Bristol Myers Squibb. D.H.V. reports stock ownership in Amgen, and honoraria from Celgene, Takeda, Janssen and Amgen. J.G.B. reports research funding from AbbVie, Acetylon, Amgen, Bluebird, Bristol Myers Squibb, Calithera, Celgene, Constellation, Curis, Epizyme, Janssen, Karyopharm, Kesios, Novartis, Onyx, Takeda and Tragara. M.L. reports research funding from Celgene and Takeda, and advisory board participation for Takeda. A.C. reports research funding from and advisory board participation for Millennium/Takeda, Celgene, Array Bio Pharma, Novartis Pharmaceuticals and Onyx, research funding from Janssen Pharmaceuticals and Bristol Myers Squibb, and consultancy fees from Janssen Pharmaceuticals and Bristol Myers Squibb. S.D.S. reports research funding from Seattle Genetics, Merck Sharp and Dohme Corp, Janssen Research and Development, LLC, Acerta Pharma BV, Pharmacyclics, Genentech and Portola Pharmaceuticals. N.R. reports consultancy for Onyx, Amgen, Millennium and Celgene. C.B., N.G. and D.B. report employment by Millennium Pharmaceuticals Inc., a wholly owned subsidiary of Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited. E.L. reports previous employment by Millennium Pharmaceuticals Inc., a wholly owned subsidiary of Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited. A.D.B. and J.E. report stock ownership in and employment by Millennium Pharmaceuticals Inc., a wholly owned subsidiary of Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited. R.B. reports honoraria from Celgene and research funding (to his institution) from Celgene, Takeda, Karyopharm, Merck, Bristol Myers Squibb, Novartis and Signal Genetics. M.H. and D.L. declare no competing financial interests.","[Takeda, C.C.H., Janssen Pharmaceuticals, Karyopharm, Merck, Thrassos, InCyte, C.A.R., Millennium/Takeda, NCT01564537, Millennium, Bristol Myers Squibb, Amgen, Janssen, Amgen, AbbVie, Acetylon, Amgen, Bluebird, Bristol Myers Squibb, Calithera, Karyopharm, Kesios, Takeda, Tragara, M.L., Takeda, Takeda, A.C., Millennium/Takeda, Celgene, Janssen Pharmaceuticals, Bristol Myers Squibb, Janssen Pharmaceuticals, Bristol Myers Squibb, S.D.S., Seattle Genetics, Merck Sharp, Dohme Corp, Janssen Research and Development, LLC, Acerta Pharma BV, Pharmacyclics, Genentech, Portola Pharmaceuticals, N.R., Onyx, C.B., N.G., D.B., Millennium Pharmaceuticals Inc., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, E.L., Millennium Pharmaceuticals Inc., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, J.E., Millennium Pharmaceuticals Inc., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, R.B., Takeda, Karyopharm, Merck, Bristol Myers Squibb, Novartis, Signal Genetics, M.H., D.L.]","['PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PRODUCT', 'EVENT', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'PERSON', 'GPE', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'PERSON', 'PERSON', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'GPE']","[70, 78, 151, 176, 191, 235, 248, 256, 315, 348, 395, 445, 501, 544, 556, 600, 608, 618, 625, 635, 657, 717, 729, 753, 764, 773, 820, 865, 873, 945, 1048, 1076, 1124, 1152, 1174, 1211, 1229, 1245, 1257, 1291, 1296, 1314, 1329, 1343, 1368, 1397, 1434, 1440, 1449, 1475, 1537, 1576, 1612, 1674, 1724, 1773, 1835, 1874, 1966, 1974, 1986, 1993, 2015, 2028, 2045, 2054]","[76, 84, 174, 186, 196, 243, 254, 262, 332, 359, 405, 465, 506, 551, 561, 606, 616, 623, 633, 655, 666, 727, 735, 759, 771, 777, 826, 871, 877, 971, 1071, 1096, 1147, 1172, 1180, 1227, 1240, 1255, 1289, 1294, 1312, 1327, 1338, 1366, 1372, 1401, 1438, 1444, 1453, 1506, 1574, 1580, 1643, 1711, 1728, 1804, 1872, 1878, 1972, 1984, 1991, 2013, 2023, 2043, 2049, 2058]",review committee
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6057940\sections\1_body\3_methods\17_patients\1_p.xml,"Patients in this study were enrolled in the GEICAM/2012-12 (EDALINE) clinical trial (ClinicalTrials.gov Identifier: NCT02027376); a single-arm, open-label, phase I, 3 + 3 dose escalation study in which patients with TNBC were treated with the SMOi Sonidegib (LDE-225) in combination with docetaxel to determine the MTD and the Recommended Phase II Dose (RP2D), as the primary objective. Written informed consent was obtained from all patients and documented before performing any protocol-specific procedure. The study was conducted in accordance with the International Conference on Harmonization Good Clinical Practice Guidelines (ICH GCP), the Declaration of Helsinki and applicable local regulatory requirements and laws. The protocol was approved by the Institutional Review Board and the Ethics Committee of all the participating sites (Hospital General Universitario Gregorio Marañón, Hospital Universitario Clínico San Carlos, Complejo Hospitalario Universitario A Coruña, Hospital Universitario Virgen del Rocío, Hospital Universitario Virgen de la Victoria), according to the requirements of the Spanish regulations (GEICAM/2012-12; clinicaltrials.gov identifier: NCT02027376). Eligible patients, with no more than three previous lines of chemotherapy for metastatic disease were treated with 21-day cycles of intravenous docetaxel 75 mg/m
 ","[3, TNBC, MTD, the International Conference on Harmonization Good Clinical Practice Guidelines, the Declaration of Helsinki, the Institutional Review Board, the Ethics Committee, Hospital, Marañón,, Complejo Hospitalario Universitario, Virgen del Rocío, Hospital Universitario Virgen de la Victoria, Spanish, GEICAM/2012-12, no more than three, 21-day, 75]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'NORP', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL']","[165, 216, 315, 552, 643, 755, 790, 843, 883, 935, 1004, 1106, 1127, 1212, 1303, 1342]","[166, 220, 318, 631, 670, 785, 810, 851, 891, 970, 1066, 1113, 1141, 1230, 1309, 1344]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6057940\sections\1_body\3_methods\5_animals_and_surgery\1_p.xml,"All animal procedures were carried out in accordance with relevant national and international guidelines and according to the animal protocol approved by the Garvan/St Vincent’s Animal Ethics Committee (Animal ethics number 11/46). M6-Ctrl or M6-Hh (0.75×10
 ","[Garvan, St Vincent’s, 11/46, M6-Ctrl]","['ORG', 'PERSON', 'CARDINAL', 'PERSON']","[158, 165, 224, 232]","[164, 177, 229, 239]",national guidelines
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6064619\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\9_timelines\1_p.xml,Ethics approval was obtained from the Human Research Ethics Committee of the University of Melbourne in October 2016. Ethics approval was obtained from the North Sydney Local Health Districts ethics committee in March 2017 and governance approval from the Northern Sydney Local Health Districts Governance office in July 2017. Recruitment commenced in August 2017 and is anticipated to be completed in December 2019. The trial is due for completion in December 2020 when all participants will have completed 12-month follow-up.,"[the Human Research Ethics Committee, the University of Melbourne, October 2016, the North Sydney Local Health Districts, March 2017, the Northern Sydney Local Health Districts Governance, July 2017, August 2017, December 2019, December 2020, 12-month]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'DATE']","[34, 73, 104, 152, 212, 252, 316, 352, 402, 452, 508]","[69, 100, 116, 191, 222, 305, 325, 363, 415, 465, 516]",ethics committee
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6066484\sections\1_body\1_patients_and_methods\6_statistical_analyses\1_p.xml,"The primary end point of the phase 1 portion of this trial was to assess the maximum tolerated dose (MTD). The phase 1 portion of the study was expected to require a minimum of 6 and a maximum of 12 evaluable patients. For the phase 2 portion of this trial, the primary end point was the rate of complete or very good partial response. A success was defined as a CR or VGPR noted as the objective status on two consecutive evaluations. All patients meeting the eligibility criteria who signed a consent form and received at least one dose of the drug were evaluable for response, with the exception of patients who were determined to be a major treatment violation. The sample size for the phase 2 portion of the study was calculated using a one-stage binomial design. The 6 patients treated at the MTD in the phase 1 portion were also included in the phase 2 portion for overall sample size estimation. A maximum of 35 additional evaluable patients were planned to be accrued at the MTD dose level for a maximum of 41 evaluable patients in the phase 2 portion of this study. An additional 4 patients were accrued to account for ineligibility, cancellation, major treatment violation, or other reasons. With 41 evaluable patients, the study provided 90% power to test the null hypothesis that the ≥ VGPR rate is at most 40% vs. the alternative hypothesis that the ≥ VGPR rate is at least 60%, with a 1-sided significance level of 
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6070095\sections\1_body\3_methods\1_patients_and_clinical_pro\1_p.xml,"We reviewed 53 consecutive adults with relapsed or refractory B-ALL who received 19-28z CAR T cells at MSKCC in a phase I clinical trial (NCT01044069) from May 2010 until August 2016 when the study was completed. This historical cohort study was reviewed and approved by the institutional review board at MSKCC. Details regarding the study design were described elsewhere [
 ","[53, 19-28z, NCT01044069, May 2010, August 2016, MSKCC]","['CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'PERSON']","[12, 81, 138, 156, 171, 305]","[14, 87, 149, 164, 182, 310]",institutional review
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6078186\sections\1_body\1_patients_and_methods\1_study_design\1_p.xml,"This study was conducted in accordance with the ethical principles of Good Clinical Practice and to the latest Declaration of Helsinki amendment. It was reviewed and approved by Severance Hospital Institutional Review Board, and the study information was registered on 
 ","[Good Clinical Practice, Severance Hospital Institutional Review Board]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[70, 178]","[92, 223]",ethical principles
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6078186\sections\1_body\1_patients_and_methods\3_procedures\1_p.xml,"After providing written informed consent, the subjects attended an initial screening visit to undergo screening procedures between 2 and 28 days prior to the first dosing. On Day −1, eligible subjects were admitted to the clinical trials center at Severance Hospital and randomized. After an overnight fast, subjects were administered a single dose of filgrastim on the early morning of Day 1. Either the test or reference drug was administered by the pre-assigned sequence. Blood was drawn for PK and PD evaluation at prespecified time points. On Day 3, the subjects had 48-hour PK/PD samples drawn, underwent a repeated safety assessment, and were discharged from the site. PD sampling after discharge was performed via subsequent visits according to a predetermined time schedule. After a 28-day washout period, period 2 was conducted in a crossover manner. On Day 14±2 of period 2, subjects underwent a follow-up visit for final safety assessments. During the hospital stay and at follow-up, adverse event (AE) monitoring, concomitant medication recording, laboratory analyses (hematology, blood chemistry, coagulation, urinalysis), physical examination, vital signs (blood pressure, pulse rate, and body temperature), and 12-lead ECG were also performed. To examine drug immunogenicity, anti-filgrastim antibodies test was performed at each admission and follow-up.","[2 and 28 days, first, Day −1, Severance Hospital, the early morning of Day 1, Day 3, 48-hour, 28-day, 2, Day 14±2, 2, AE, 12, ECG]","['DATE', 'ORDINAL', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'TIME', 'DATE', 'TIME', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG']","[131, 158, 175, 248, 366, 548, 572, 792, 822, 864, 883, 1011, 1227, 1235]","[144, 163, 181, 266, 392, 553, 579, 798, 823, 872, 884, 1013, 1229, 1238]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6104757\sections\1_body\3_ethics_and_dissemination\1_p.xml,"The study will be conducted according to the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki (Adopted by the 18th World Medical Association (WMA) General Assembly, Helsinki, Finland, June 1964 and amended by the 64th WMA General Assembly, Fortaleza, Brazil, October 2013) and in accordance with the Dutch Medical Research Involving Human Subjects Act (WMO). The study has been approved by the Dutch Central Committee on Research Concerning Human Subjects (protocol number NL51705.000.15).","[the Declaration of Helsinki (Adopted, 18th, World Medical Association, WMA, General Assembly, Helsinki, Finland, June 1964, 64th, WMA General Assembly, Fortaleza, Brazil, October 2013, the Dutch Medical Research Involving Human Subjects Act, the Dutch Central Committee on Research Concerning Human Subjects, NL51705.000.15]","['WORK_OF_ART', 'ORDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'DATE', 'ORDINAL', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[59, 103, 108, 135, 140, 158, 168, 177, 206, 211, 233, 244, 252, 289, 383, 466]","[95, 107, 133, 138, 156, 166, 175, 186, 210, 231, 242, 250, 264, 344, 448, 480]",protocol number
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6137884\sections\1_body\2_results\1_patient_characteristics\1_p.xml,"Between December 2013 and November 2016, 10 consecutive patients were enrolled and followed up for a period of 12 months according to the study protocol. Baseline characteristics are presented in Table 
 ","[Between December 2013 and November 2016, 10, 12 months, Baseline, Table]","['DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'PERSON', 'ORG']","[0, 41, 111, 154, 196]","[39, 43, 120, 162, 201]",study protocol
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6138767\sections\1_body\5_materials_and_methods\2_study_design\1_p.xml,This randomized phase II trial compared ICT/CCRT with CCRT. The PUL regimen was administered biweekly during ICT and CCRT. Eligible patients were stratified into 4 groups on the basis of 2 factors: tumor resectability (resectable vs unresectable) and disease stage (III vs IV). A consensus on resectability was provided by a multidisciplinary team. Randomization codes were generated independently for each stratum. A permuted block randomization scheme was used to generate the randomization codes so that the number of patients assigned to the 2 treatment arms was approximately equal. The institutional review board of our institution approved this study. Written informed consent was obtained from all patients before therapy.,"[II, ICT, PUL, ICT, CCRT, 4, 2, 2]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL']","[22, 40, 64, 109, 117, 162, 187, 546]","[24, 43, 67, 112, 121, 163, 188, 547]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6141688\sections\1_body\1_materials_and_methods\1_ethical_statement\1_p.xml,"Ethical approval (register number 09-210M, project number CFU-12/09) for the study was obtained from the Regional Ethical Review Board, Umeå, Sweden. All parts of the study were performed according to the Declaration of Helsinki. The patients were included after informed written consent.","[09, the Regional Ethical Review Board, Umeå, Sweden, the Declaration of Helsinki]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'WORK_OF_ART']","[34, 101, 136, 142, 201]","[36, 134, 140, 148, 228]",informed written consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6142101\sections\1_body\1_methods\3_design\1_p.xml,"Patients were enrolled by signing a consent form prior to transplantation. Three months following transplantation, upon consent, patients were allocated to the SYT group. Patients who were not interested in taking SYT were allocated to the control group. Both groups continued to receive standard biomedical care from their oncologist. Patients allocated to the treatment group were to receive a batch of SYT once each month for a duration of 6 months. Peripheral blood samples were collected and analyzed on a monthly basis.","[Three months, SYT, SYT, SYT, each month, 6 months, monthly]","['DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'DATE']","[75, 160, 214, 405, 414, 443, 511]","[87, 163, 217, 408, 424, 451, 518]",consent form
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6142101\sections\1_body\2_preliminary_results\1_patients\1_p.xml,"Patients from the Division of Hematology and Oncology of the China Medical University Hospital were consecutively enrolled in the trial from September 1, 2015, onwards. The study protocol was approved by the Institutional Review Board of the China Medical University Hospital (DMR-105-005), and all participants provided informed consent. The trial protocol was made public on 
 ","[the Division of Hematology, the China Medical University Hospital, September 1, 2015, the Institutional Review Board, the China Medical University Hospital]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[14, 57, 141, 204, 238]","[40, 94, 158, 234, 275]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6153548\sections\1_body\1_patients_and_methods\1_study_design_and_particip\1_p.xml,"In this first-in-human, dose-escalation phase I trial, adult patients with relapsed or refractory NHL for whom standard measures did not exist or were no longer effective were enrolled from one European (Switzerland) and five US cancer center sites. To be eligible, patients had to be aged 18 years or older with a histologically confirmed diagnosis of lymphoma limited to DLBCL, FL, MCL, or MZL. Patients were also required to have received at least one prior anti-CD20 based therapeutic regimen, have a life expectancy of greater than 3 months, an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance status of 2 or lower, and adequate hematological, renal, and hepatic function. Prior therapies resulting in exclusion included chemotherapy or radiation within 3 weeks of study entry, radioimmunotherapy within 2 months of starting study drug, major surgery within 30 days, prior treatment with a CD37-directed agent, and allogenic stem cell transplantation. The trial was conducted in accordance with US Food and Drug Administration regulations, the International Conference on Harmonisation Guidelines for Good Clinical Practice, and the Declaration of Helsinki. The study was compliant with all relevant Institutional Review Board and Independent Ethics Committee requirements and all patients provided written informed consent for participation. The trial is registered at 
 ","[first, NHL, one, European, Switzerland, five, US, 18 years, MCL, MZL, at least one, greater than, Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance, 2, 3 weeks, 2 months, 30 days, US Food and Drug Administration, the International Conference on Harmonisation Guidelines for Good Clinical Practice, the Declaration of Helsinki, Institutional Review Board, Independent Ethics Committee]","['ORDINAL', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'NORP', 'GPE', 'CARDINAL', 'GPE', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[8, 98, 190, 194, 204, 221, 226, 290, 384, 392, 442, 524, 550, 607, 757, 807, 861, 998, 1043, 1132, 1203, 1234]","[13, 101, 193, 202, 215, 225, 228, 298, 387, 395, 454, 536, 596, 608, 764, 815, 868, 1029, 1126, 1159, 1229, 1262]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6160169\sections\1_body\1_materials_and_methods\2_treatment\1_p.xml,"Patients were treated according to national guidelines, which generally included chemotherapy with or without radiotherapy (
 ",[],[],[],[],national guidelines
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6160169\sections\1_body\1_materials_and_methods\8_ethics\1_p.xml,"Ethical approval was obtained by the regional ethics committee in Uppsala, Sweden according to the declaration of Helsinki (2014/020, 2014/020/1, and 2014/233). Informed consent from participants was not required according to the ethics committee. All data were fully anonymized before accessed.","[Uppsala, Sweden, 2014/020/1, 2014/233]","['GPE', 'GPE', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL']","[66, 75, 134, 150]","[73, 81, 144, 158]",ethics committee
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6160434\sections\1_body\1_materials_and_methods\1_study_design__subjects__t\1_p.xml,"This was a single arm Phase II open label, single agent, multicenter clinical trial for subjects with HRNB who had completed standard therapy or therapy for refractory/relapsed disease. Subjects were enrolled onto the Beat Childhood Cancer Trial NMTRC003/003B from June 2012 to February 2016. This trial was approved by the Western Institutional Review Board as well as by local Institutional Review Boards at 22 enrolling hospitals across the United States (Saint Louis University Institutional Review Board, University of California San Diego Human Research Protections Program, Orlando Health/Orlando Regional Healthcare System Institutional Review Board, Medical University of South Carolina Institutional Review Board for Human Research, Chesapeake Research Review, Inc., Spectrum Health Institutional Review Board, Connecticut Children’s Medical Center Institutional Review Board, Children’s Mercy Hospital Pediatric Institutional Review Board, Institutional Review Board for Human Subjects for Baylor College of Medicine and Affiliated Hospitals, Vanderbilt University Human Research Protection Program, Phoenix Children’s Hospital Institutional Review Board, Seton Healthcare Institutional Review Board, Tufts University Health Sciences Institutional Review Board, University of Utah Institutional Review Board, Institutional Review Board of Children’s Hospitals and Clinics of Minnesota, Penn State Milton S. Hershey Medical Center – Penn State College of Medicine – Human Subjects Protection Office - Institutional Review Board, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center Institutional Review Board, Johns Hopkins Medicine All Children’s Hospital Institutional Review Board, Albert Einstein College of Medicine Institutional Review Board and The Research Institute at Nationwide Children’s Hospital). Prior to study entry, written informed consent from the subject (if 18 or over), or from a parent and/or legal guardian (if under 18 y.o.) for study participation was obtained on all subjects. All methods were performed in accordance with relevant guidelines and regulations. ClinicalTrials.gov Identifiers: NCT01586260 Unique ID: NMTRC 003 Released 4/24/2012 as well as NCT02395666 Unique ID: NMTRC003B Released 3/5/2015.","[the Beat Childhood Cancer Trial NMTRC003/003B, June 2012 to February 2016, the Western Institutional Review Board, Institutional Review Boards, 22, the United States, Saint Louis University Institutional Review Board, University of California San Diego Human Research Protections Program, Orlando Health/Orlando Regional Healthcare System Institutional Review Board, Medical University of South Carolina Institutional Review Board for Human Research, Chesapeake Research Review, Inc., Spectrum Health Institutional Review Board, Connecticut Children’s Medical Center Institutional Review Board, Children’s Mercy Hospital Pediatric Institutional Review Board, Institutional Review Board for Human Subjects for Baylor College of Medicine and Affiliated Hospitals, Vanderbilt University Human Research Protection Program, Phoenix Children’s Hospital Institutional Review Board, Seton Healthcare Institutional Review Board, Tufts University Health Sciences Institutional Review Board, University of Utah Institutional Review Board, Institutional Review Board of Children’s Hospitals, Clinics of Minnesota, Penn State, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center Institutional Review Board, Johns Hopkins Medicine All Children’s Hospital Institutional Review Board, Albert Einstein College, Medicine Institutional Review Board, The Research Institute, Nationwide Children’s Hospital, 18, under 18 y.o, 003, 4/24/2012, NCT02395666 Unique, 3/5/2015]","['ORG', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'PERSON', 'CARDINAL']","[214, 265, 320, 379, 410, 440, 459, 510, 581, 659, 743, 777, 821, 887, 951, 1054, 1111, 1167, 1212, 1273, 1320, 1375, 1397, 1539, 1615, 1690, 1717, 1757, 1783, 1884, 1940, 2153, 2166, 2187, 2229]","[259, 291, 358, 406, 412, 457, 508, 579, 657, 741, 775, 819, 885, 949, 1052, 1109, 1165, 1210, 1271, 1318, 1370, 1395, 1407, 1613, 1688, 1713, 1752, 1779, 1813, 1886, 1952, 2156, 2175, 2205, 2237]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6175065\sections\1_body\2_methods\1_mrc_myeloma_ix\1_p.xml,"Myeloma IX recruited patients with newly‐diagnosed MM aged ≥18 years from 120 centres in the United Kingdom between 2003 and 2007 and was registered with the appropriate organisation (ISRCTN68454111). All 120 centres reviewed the protocol and all recruited participants gave written informed consent in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki, with an opt‐in component for the QoL sub‐study. The study was an open‐label randomised, phase III trial with a factorial design in which there were two randomisations. The first included randomised allocation of patients to receive a bisphosphonate (sodium clodronate or zoledronic acid) and induction treatment, either intensive or non‐intensive, determined by the treating clinicians’ assessments in combination with patient performance status and preferences following informed discussion. In the intensive pathway, patients were randomised to receive cyclophosphamide, vincristine, doxorubicin and dexamethasone (CVAD) or oral cyclophosphamide, thalidomide and dexamethasone (CTD) followed by high dose melphalan plus autologous stem cell transplant (ASCT). In the non‐intensive pathway, the randomisation was to attenuated CTD (CTDa) or melphalan and prednisolone (MP). A further randomisation allocated patients to either thalidomide maintenance therapy or observation only. Details of the trial, including the randomisation methods and sample size calculation, have been published elsewhere together with results of primary and secondary endpoints related to treatment effectiveness and safety (Morgan 
 ","[Myeloma, MM, ≥18 years, 120, the United Kingdom, between 2003 and 2007, 120, the Declaration of Helsinki, opt‐in, two, first, zoledronic, CTD, ASCT, CTD, Morgan 
 ]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'GPE', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'NORP', 'CARDINAL', 'ORDINAL', 'NORP', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[0, 51, 59, 74, 89, 108, 205, 319, 356, 496, 520, 619, 1028, 1103, 1176, 1550]","[7, 53, 68, 77, 107, 129, 208, 346, 362, 499, 525, 629, 1031, 1107, 1179, 1559]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6195794\sections\1_body\3_methods\1_trial_design\1_p.xml,"We performed a phase 1/2 open-label multicenter dose-escalation trial in 12 adult participants to evaluate the safety and tolerability of subretinal transplantation of hESC-derived RPE cells. The intervention was unmasked. The study received the approval of the Medicines and Health Products Regulatory Authority, the United Kingdom Gene Therapy Advisory Committee, and the Moorfields Eye Hospital Research Governance Committee. We provided potential candidates with detailed information, including an explanation of the aims of the trial and the possible consequences of participation. Participants provided their written informed consent before enrolment. We performed the study in accordance with the tenets of the Declaration of Helsinki and registered the trial at 
 ","[1/2, 12, RPE, the Medicines and Health Products Regulatory Authority, the United Kingdom Gene Therapy Advisory Committee, the Moorfields Eye Hospital Research Governance Committee, the Declaration of Helsinki]","['CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART']","[21, 73, 181, 258, 314, 370, 714]","[24, 75, 184, 312, 364, 427, 741]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6208687\sections\1_body\1_patients_and_methods\1_data_source\1_p.xml,"The TLN is an open, longitudinal, multicentre, observational, prospective cohort study, which started in 2009. The study was reviewed by the responsible ethics committee and registered at 
 ","[TLN, 2009]","['ORG', 'DATE']","[4, 105]","[7, 109]",ethics committee
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6216432\sections\1_body\2_materials_and_methods\1_study_design_and_overview\1_p.xml,"This study was a phase I, single‐center, and open‐label trial of a single intravenous infusion of autologous umbilical cord blood in 25 children with ASD. All children were initially enrolled in a screening protocol to obtain medical records and information about their banked cord blood unit. All participants' caregivers completed a pre‐study screening interview by phone and provided medical records and videos for review by the study team to determine eligibility for the trial. Children with a confirmed diagnosis of ASD and a qualified banked autologous umbilical cord blood unit were eligible to participate. Written informed consent was obtained for both the screening and the treatment phases of the trial. The trial was approved by the Duke University Health System Institutional Review Board and conducted under IND #15949. Participants and their caregivers traveled to Duke University three times as part of their participation in the study. At their baseline visit, they were evaluated and received a single intravenous autologous cord blood infusion. At 6 and 12 months post‐infusion, participants returned for follow‐up clinical assessments. Additional caregiver interviews and questionnaires were collected at 3 and 9 months post‐infusion.","[25, ASD, ASD, the Duke University Health System Institutional Review Board, IND, Duke University, three, 6 and 12 months, 3 and 9 months]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'DATE']","[133, 150, 522, 742, 823, 881, 897, 1068, 1226]","[135, 153, 525, 802, 826, 896, 902, 1083, 1240]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6224728\sections\1_body\2_methods__participants__in\8_recruitment\1_p.xml,"All patients with myeloma or lymphoma at Karolinska University Hospital and Uppsala University Hospital, and patients with myeloma at the University Hospitals in Linköping and Örebro who are to undergo ASCT will be asked to participate in the study. Information will be given at the time of stem cell apheresis and in material sent to the patient in connection with the invitation letter, with information about admission to the ward for ASCT. Inclusion in the study will take place after written consent on arrival at the ward to be admitted for ASCT. For underage patients (16–17 years), parents will also be informed and asked if they consent to their children’s participation. Estimated time for inclusion is approximately 1.5 years starting from 12
 ","[Karolinska University Hospital, Uppsala University Hospital, the University Hospitals, Linköping, Örebro, ASCT, ASCT, ASCT, (16–17 years, approximately 1.5 years, 12]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL']","[41, 76, 134, 162, 176, 202, 438, 547, 575, 713, 751]","[71, 103, 158, 171, 182, 206, 442, 551, 587, 736, 753]",written consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6224728\sections\1_body\2_methods__participants__in\9_patient_and_public_involv\1_p.xml,Comparison of the balance between efficacy and safety for Cooral and ice in the prevention of OM is in the best interest of patients. Patients were not involved in the design of this study or in the recruitment or conduct of the study. The study results will be disseminated to study participants orally and in writing. The burden of the interventions will be assessed by the patients themselves. No patient advisers were involved in the design or conduct of the study.,"[Comparison, Cooral]","['ORG', 'ORG']","[0, 58]","[10, 64]",study participants
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6224728\sections\1_body\5_methods__monitoring\4_auditing\1_p.xml,"The study will be monitored by KTA to ensure that it is carried out in accordance with the established study protocol, Helsinki declaration, ISO14155:2011 and other applicable guidelines and regulations. A monitoring plan has been established.","[KTA, Helsinki, ISO14155:2011]","['ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG']","[31, 119, 141]","[34, 127, 154]",study protocol
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6224728\sections\1_body\6_ethics_and_dissemination\1_protocol_amendments\1_p.xml,"Important protocol modifications will be communicated by KTA to investigators, trial participants, trial registries, review board, journals and regulators.",[KTA],['ORG'],[57],[60],review board
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6224728\sections\1_body\6_ethics_and_dissemination\2_consent_or_assent\1_p.xml,"Written informed consent (online 
 ",[],[],[],[],informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6278957\sections\1_body\1_methods\3_ethics\1_p.xml,Forty-six institutions participated in this study. The study was conducted in accordance with the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. Written informed consent was obtained from each par ticipant before enrollment. The study was approved by the Ethics Committee of Akita University (N. 786) and by all institutional ethic committees that participated in this study. The study was registered with UMIN-CTR (UMIN000005904).,"[Forty-six, the Declaration of Helsinki, the Ethics Committee of Akita University]","['CARDINAL', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'ORG']","[0, 112, 247]","[9, 139, 287]",ethic committe
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6303849\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\8_consent\1_p.xml,"The investigator will explain the details of this clinical trial to potential study subjects, and provide sufficient time for them to consider whether they will participate in the study. Voluntary informed consent will be obtained from the study subjects in a written form. Consent will be documented as being signed and dated by the study subject on the informed consent form. Consent will be obtained in a written form from a parent or a legal guardian or a legally acceptable representative when a study subject is legally incompetent.","[Voluntary, Consent, Consent]","['PERSON', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[187, 274, 378]","[196, 281, 385]",consent form
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6303849\sections\1_body\1_methods_design\9_randomization_and_blindin\1_p.xml,"The study participants will be given a unique identification number, and they will be assigned to either the study-drug group or the control-placebo group. Randomization will be conducted using a web-based randomization program constructed by means of the blocked randomization method. The web-based randomization will be managed by the Medical Research Collaborating Center of Seoul National University Hospital (
 ",[the Medical Research Collaborating Center of Seoul National University Hospital],['ORG'],[333],[412],study participants
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6311293\sections\1_body\1_2__material_and_methods\1_2_1__patients_and_image_s\1_p.xml,"Consecutive patients with newly diagnosed BM referred between 1.1.2011 and 31.12.2014 to radiotherapy at Masaryk Memorial Cancer Institute in Brno, Czech Republic, were included in this retrospective study. Patients with available MRI scan that revealed first BM were eligible for further analysis. This MRI was used to describe spatial distribution of BM in order to avoid bias of previous local treatment of BM in estimation of incidence of hippocampal BM. Basic clinical data was obtained from electronic medical records. All patients signed the informed consent allowing usage of their clinical and imaging data for research purposes in an anonymous form.","[between 1.1.2011 and 31.12.2014, Masaryk Memorial Cancer Institute, Brno, Czech Republic, first]","['CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'ORDINAL']","[54, 105, 142, 148, 254]","[85, 138, 146, 162, 259]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6312024\sections\1_body\1_methods\1_study_population_and_chro\1_p.xml,"Research was conducted with informed consent, Institutional Review Board approval and in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. The clinical data used were from 339 patients with incident chronic GvHD enrolled in the Chronic GvHD Consortium study, a pre-existing multicenter prospective observational clinical database.
 ","[Institutional Review Board, the Declaration of Helsinki, 339, GvHD]","['ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'CARDINAL', 'PERSON']","[46, 105, 167, 202]","[72, 132, 170, 206]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6312036\sections\1_body\1_methods\1_study_design_and_patients\1_p.xml,"The RiBVD multicenter phase II trial enrolled newly diagnosed MCL patients ≥65 years or <65 years if ineligible or unwilling to undergo autologous stem cell transplantation. The study was conducted in 37 centers of the Lymphoma Study Association (LYSA) (NCT 01457144) and was approved by institutional review boards and ethics committees at all sites, and conducted according to the Declaration of Helsinki. The diagnosis of MCL was established according to the World Health Organization (WHO) 2008 criteria. Ki67 staining and scoring were performed centrally, according to European MCL Network recommendations.
 ","[II, MCL, ≥65 years or <65 years, 37, the Lymphoma Study Association, the Declaration of Helsinki, MCL, the World Health Organization (WHO, European MCL Network]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[28, 62, 75, 201, 215, 379, 425, 458, 574]","[30, 65, 97, 203, 245, 406, 428, 492, 594]",ethics committee
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6334730\sections\1_body\1_patients_and_methods\1_study_design\1_p.xml,"This multicenter, open-label study was conducted at 21 sites in Japan from January 2013 to February 2017. The study consisted of two parts: a phase 1 component designed to confirm the safety and tolerability of forodesine 300 mg twice-daily for 28 days in patients with relapsed/refractory PTCL and a phase 2 component designed to evaluate the efficacy and safety of this forodesine regimen in relapsed PTCL. The study was conducted in accordance with ethical principles of the Declaration of Helsinki and in compliance with International Council for Harmonization guidelines for Good Clinical Practice. The Institutional Review Boards of all participating institutions approved the study protocol, and all patients provided written informed consent. The study was registered at 
 ","[21, Japan, January 2013, February 2017, two, 1, 300, 28 days, PTCL, 2, the Declaration of Helsinki, International Council for Harmonization, Good Clinical Practice, The Institutional Review Boards]","['CARDINAL', 'GPE', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'CARDINAL', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[52, 64, 75, 91, 129, 148, 222, 245, 290, 307, 474, 525, 580, 604]","[54, 69, 87, 104, 132, 149, 225, 252, 294, 308, 501, 564, 602, 635]",ethical principles
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6342895\sections\1_body\2_methods\9_ethics_committee_analysis\1_p.xml,"This study has been evaluated and approved by our ethics committee, the Ethics Committee for Health of Centro Hospitalar de São João/Faculty of Medicine of Oporto University.",[the Ethics Committee for Health of Centro Hospitalar de São João/Faculty of Medicine of Oporto University],['ORG'],[68],[173],ethics committee
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6365372\sections\1_body\1_subjects_and_methods\1_study_design\1_p.xml,"This was a prospective, phase IV, multicenter, randomized, open-label study conducted at seven sites in four countries: Taiwan, Republic of Korea, United States, and Canada (ClinicalTrials.gov Identifier: NCT01164475). The study was conducted in compliance with the Declaration of Helsinki, Good Clinical Practice guidelines, and the laws, regulations, and applicable guidelines of the relevant countries, and was approved by each institutional review board. All patients provided written informed consent.","[seven, four, Taiwan, Republic of Korea, United States, Canada, NCT01164475, the Declaration of Helsinki]","['CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'GPE', 'PERSON', 'WORK_OF_ART']","[89, 104, 120, 128, 147, 166, 205, 262]","[94, 108, 126, 145, 160, 172, 216, 289]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6391590\sections\1_body\3_materials_and_methods\1_study_design\1_p.xml,"We conducted a multicenter, open-label, randomized clinical trial to assess the safety, pharmacokinetics, and exploratory efficacy of intravenously administered JR-141 (NCT 03128593). The study was conducted in eight hospitals and specialized MPS centers in Japan and was in compliance with the Declaration of Helsinki. The protocol and patient informed consent were reviewed and approved by the Institutional Review Board at each participating institution.","[NCT 03128593, eight, MPS, Japan, the Declaration of Helsinki, the Institutional Review Board]","['DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'ORG']","[169, 211, 243, 258, 291, 392]","[181, 216, 246, 263, 318, 422]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6391590\sections\1_body\3_materials_and_methods\2_participants_and_procedur\1_p.xml,"A total of 14 male patients were enrolled in the study. Two patients (aged 33 and 63) who had no intellectual disability and were able to recognize and verbally report their subjective symptoms were selected for the dose-escalation study (part 1) and were given 0.01, 0.1, 1.0, and 2.0 mg/kg/week of JR-141 intravenously. In part 2 of the study, the other 12 patients (average age, 12.9 years; range, 6 to 25 years; SD, 5.3), seven of whom had intellectual disability, were randomly assigned to a 1.0 or 2.0 mg/kg/week of JR-141 dosing group. Key inclusion criteria were as follows: age 6 years or older (16 years or older in the initial dose-escalation study) at the time of informed consent; a diagnosis of MPS II based on the measurement of overall IDS activity in leukocytes, plasma, and cultured skin fibroblasts along with a genetic analysis; under pharmacotherapy with idursulfase (0.5 mg/kg/week) for at least 12 weeks before the initial administration of JR-141. Key exclusion criteria included a history of hematopoietic stem cell transplantation, practical inability to undergo lumbar puncture, serious drug allergy or hypersensitivity making them unsuitable for participation in the study, a history of receiving other investigational products within 4 months before the beginning of this study. All patients or legally acceptable representatives provided signed informed consent prior to enrolment. Full inclusion and exclusion criteria are listed in the appendix, and the study protocol is available online.","[14, Two, 33 and 63, 1, 0.01, 0.1, 1.0, 2.0, 2, 12, 12.9 years, 6 to 25 years, 5.3, seven, 1.0, 2.0, age 6 years or older, 16 years, 0.5, at least, 4 months]","['CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'CARDINAL', 'CARDINAL', 'DATE']","[11, 56, 75, 244, 262, 268, 273, 282, 330, 356, 382, 401, 420, 426, 497, 504, 583, 605, 889, 909, 1263]","[13, 59, 84, 245, 266, 271, 276, 285, 331, 358, 392, 414, 423, 431, 500, 507, 603, 613, 892, 917, 1271]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6418329\sections\1_body\1_materials_and_methods\5_ethics\1_p.xml,"The study protocol was approved by the Ethics Committee of The Islamic Azad University of Mashhad with this code (IR.IAU.MSHD.REC.1396.115). The patients filled in a written informed consent prior to study entry. The questionnaires were anonymous, and all collected data were regarded as confidential.",[the Ethics Committee of The Islamic Azad University],['ORG'],[35],[86],informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6418329\sections\1_body\5_acknowledgment\1_p.xml,"The authors would like to thank the study participants and coordinators, the medical and paramedical staff at the participating institutions.",[],[],[],[],study participants
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6425108\sections\1_body\5_ethical_considerations\1_p.xml,"All procedures described herein were performed in compliance with the scientific and ethics committees of the Hospital Angeles Pedregal, the Declaration of Helsinki, and approved by the Comisión Federal para la Protección de Riesgos Sanitarios (COFEPRIS, CMN2012-027). Fetal tissue was obtained in 1998 at Good Samaritan Hospital (Los Angeles, CA) with institutional approval #97-11-01, within their neuro-transplantation program. Human fetal brain tissue donor informed consent forms were obtained in accordance with NIH guidelines for use of fetal tissue (available from: 
 ","[the Hospital Angeles Pedregal, the Declaration of Helsinki, Comisión, la Protección de Riesgos Sanitarios, COFEPRIS, CMN2012-027, 1998, Good Samaritan Hospital, Los Angeles, #97-11-01, NIH]","['ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART', 'ORG', 'PERSON', 'ORG', 'PRODUCT', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'MONEY', 'ORG']","[106, 137, 186, 208, 245, 255, 298, 306, 331, 376, 518]","[135, 164, 194, 243, 253, 266, 302, 329, 342, 385, 521]",consent form
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6442956\sections\1_body\1_methods\1_patients_and_donors\1_p.xml,"This retrospective study included all consecutive adult patients who received a first alternative donor HCT for any underlying diagnosis at Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center/Seattle Cancer Care Alliance between 2006 and 2015 and subsequently developed chronic GvHD that required systemic treatment. The alternative grafts included unrelated 4–6/6-HLA-matched single or double umbilical cord blood units (UCB), related HLA-haploidentical bone marrow or mobilized peripheral blood stem cells plus post-transplant cyclophosphamide (Haplo/PTCY), and mobilized peripheral blood stem cells from unrelated donors with a single HLA allele mismatched at an A, B, C or DRB1 locus by high resolution typing (1-mMUD), regardless of whether the mismatch resulted in antigen disparity at the locus. Patients had given written consent allowing the use of medical records for research in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki, and the institutional review board approved the study.","[first, HCT, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center/, between 2006 and 2015, GvHD, 4–6/6, UCB, Haplo/PTCY, the Declaration of Helsinki]","['ORDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'PERSON', 'CARDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART']","[80, 104, 140, 208, 265, 346, 409, 534, 893]","[85, 107, 179, 229, 269, 351, 412, 544, 920]",institutional review
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6442960\sections\1_body\1_methods\1_p.xml,"This was a retrospective observational study. All patients diagnosed with CLL according to the World Health Organization criteria from 2007 to 2013 were identified from the National Cancer Registry. A representative physician from each of Sweden’s six health-care regions reviewed all the patient files in the region to identify patients who had received first-line CLL treatment due to progressive, symptomatic CLL. Patients who had started therapy before the end of 2013 were included in order to obtain sufficient follow up. Their files were analyzed in detail from the date of diagnosis until death or until the end of the study period (2017), whichever came first. Patients who had only received treatment for autoimmune hemolysis or idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura (ITP) not related to progressive CLL were excluded. As this was a retrospective observational study, ethics committee approval (2013/952–31/3) was obtained; in Sweden no informed patient consent was required. The study was performed in accordance with the ethical principles of the Declaration of Helsinki
 ","[CLL, the World Health Organization, 2007, 2013, the National Cancer Registry, Sweden, six, first, CLL, CLL, 2017, first, ITP, CLL, Sweden, the Declaration of Helsinki
 ]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'DATE', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'CARDINAL', 'ORDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'ORDINAL', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'GPE', 'WORK_OF_ART']","[74, 91, 135, 143, 169, 239, 248, 355, 366, 412, 641, 663, 776, 808, 935, 1053]","[77, 120, 139, 147, 197, 245, 251, 360, 369, 415, 645, 668, 779, 811, 941, 1082]",ethical principles
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6714858\sections\1_body\1_patients_and_methods\1_p.xml,"All the participating children and parents were informed about the study, and informed consent was received. The study was approved by the Ethics Committee of Erciyes University Medical Faculty with no: TTU2016-6579 and was also supported by the Erciyes University Research Project Management Unit under the project designated as TTU2016-6579.","[the Ethics Committee of Erciyes University Medical Faculty, the Erciyes University Research Project Management Unit, TTU2016-6579]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'ORG']","[135, 242, 330]","[193, 297, 342]",informed consent
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC6760546\sections\1_body\1_patients_and_methods\1_patients’_eligibility\1_p.xml,"Total 32 eligible patients were enrolled into the clinical trial with ages from 20- to 62-year-old with hematologic malignancies including acute myeloid leukemia (AML), acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL), high-risk myelodysplasia (MDS), chronic myelomonocytic leukemia (CMML) from June 2017 to January 2018 in our center. ECOG performance status was ≤2 in all patients. All patients had adequate baseline laboratory values for eligibility. This study had ethical approval from the local ethical committees and conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. All patient data originate from clinical trials with mandatory written informed consent.","[62-year-old, AML, CMML, June 2017 to January 2018, the Declaration of Helsinki]","['DATE', 'ORG', 'ORG', 'DATE', 'WORK_OF_ART']","[87, 163, 270, 281, 539]","[98, 166, 274, 306, 566]",ethical approval
C:\Users\shweata\dictionary\ethics_statement_project\stem_cell_2018\PMC8059405\sections\1_body\1_methods\1_study_design\1_p.xml,"This multicenter, open-label study was conducted in accordance with Good Clinical Practice, per the International Conference on Harmonization Guideline E6, and with ethical principles outlined in the Declaration of Helsinki. The protocol was approved by the institutional review boards of all participating centers. All patients provided written informed consent. This study is registered at 
 ","[Good Clinical Practice, the International Conference on Harmonization Guideline E6, the Declaration of Helsinki]","['ORG', 'ORG', 'WORK_OF_ART']","[68, 96, 196]","[90, 154, 223]",ethical principles
