<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par46">
 <italic>The secondary endpoints are as follow:</italic>
 <list list-type="bullet">
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par47">PFS at 2 and 3 years defined as the time from randomization until the date of the first objective progression or death</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par48">Bone progression free-survival (BPFS) at 1 year defined as the time from the date of randomization to the date of documented bone progression at the level at the entire skeleton.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par49">Local control (LC) at 1 year defined as the time from the date of randomization to the date of a documented local event at the level of bone oligometastases presents at randomization.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par50">Cancer-specific survival (CSS) at 1, 2 and 3 years defined as the time from the date of randomization to the date of documented death from cancer or complication from the treatment.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par51">Overall survival (OS) at 1, 2 and 3 years defined as the time from the date of randomization to the date of documented death from any cause.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par52">Acute and late Toxicity at 1, 2 and 3 years assessed by the National Cancer Institute Common Toxicity Criteria (NCI CTC) version 4.0.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par53">Quality of Life assessed using self-administered questionnaires (EORTC-QLQ-C30, EORTC-QLQ-BM22, and EQ-5D-3L) [
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>–
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par54">Pain score evaluated accordingly to Numeric Scale.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par55">The Cost- Utility /Cost-Effectiveness / Budget Impact analysis performed on QALYs (Quality-Adjusted Life Years) and ICERs (Incremental Cost-Effectiveness Ratios) calculation based on EQ-5D-3L questionnaire.</p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
