<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A female patient (from a G1P1 mother) of 3.5 years of age was admitted to the Pediatric Hematology Department of Xianyang Caihong Hospital in June 2019. Body temperature was 36.7°C, and body weight was 15 kg. The patient had severe anemia, acupoint-size bleeding spots, and a few ecchymoses all over her body, as well as astigmatism and hyperopia. Hearing was normal. There were no palpable superficial lymph nodes. Heart and lung auscultation showed no abnormalities. No abnormalities were observed in the limbs. Growth and development appeared normal for age. Both parents were in good health. It was a non-consanguineous marriage. There was no familial history of diabetes and hereditary anemia. Laboratory routine blood test showed white blood cells (WBC) at 5.48 × 10
 <sup>9</sup>/L, neutrophils (N) at 26.64%, absolute neutrophil count (ANC) at 1.46 × 10
 <sup>9</sup>/L, lymphocytes (L) at 61.5%, red blood cells (RBC) at 1.66 × 10
 <sup>12</sup>/L, hemoglobin (Hb) at 51 g/L, mean corpuscular volume (MCV) at 98 fl, platelets (PLT) at 8 × 10
 <sup>9</sup>/L, and Ret at 0.022. Biochemical examination showed fasting blood glucose at 13.0 mmol/L (3.9–6.1 mmol/L), fasting insulin at 1.02 mol/L (3–25 mol/L), and HbA1c at 7.8% (4.0–6.5%), indicating diabetes. Serum ferritin, folic acid, and vitamin B12 levels were normal. Bone marrow examination revealed hyperplasia, with high erythrocyte proliferation, accounting for 48.5%, with 24.5% of megaloblasts (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1A</xref>). There were vacuoles in the cytoplasm of some primitive erythrocytes. No pathological hematopoiesis was observed in granulocytes and megakaryocytes. Erythrocytic examination showed iron particles in the extracellular area, as well as ringed sideroblasts (13%) (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1B</xref>). Bone marrow biopsy suggested myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS). The karyotype analysis showed 46, XX. The chromosome mutagenicity testing showed that the patient had DNA damage in peripheral lymphocytes. The comet assay showed that the comet cell percentage was 21% and that there was no apoptosis. The mitochondrial gene testing was not consistent with the patient's phenotype or suspected pathogenic mutation. Peripheral blood samples of the patient and her parents were collected for genomic DNA analysis. The patient had a c.515G&gt;A (p.G 172D) homozygous mutation in 
 <italic>SLC19A2</italic> (NM_006996), indicating TRMA. Exon 2 of 
 <italic>SLC19A2</italic> was amplified and sequenced (
 <italic>SLC19A2</italic>-2F: CGG GAG GCT CCT CCA TAT TT; 
 <italic>SLC19A2</italic>-2R: TTG CCA CAG ACT ACC TCC GT), and the results showed that the mother was a carrier of the c.515G&gt;A (p.G 172D) heterozygous mutation and that the father was wild type (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1C</xref>). There was a homozygosis zone of 248.31 Mb in the region of homozygosity [ROH (1p36.33q44)] [i.e., region arr (hg19) 1p36.33q44 (888,658–249,198,16)hmz], while chromosome 1 was of the normal copy number (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1D</xref>). No database-recorded and disease-related CNV changes were observed in her father and mother according to the gene chip detection results, indicating that the patient's homozygosis region was inherited from her mother alone and induced by maternal UPD. The patient was treated with thiamine (10 mg/time, 3 times/day, Linfen Baozhu Pharmaceutical) and subcutaneous injection of insulin of 6 U (i.h, 3 times/day before each meal). Blood glucose levels were maintained at 4.1–10 mmol/L. After 10 days of treatment, blood routine showed that Hb had increased from 54 to 112 g/L, reticulocytes from 2.2 to 14%, and PLT from 8 × 10
 <sup>9</sup>/L to 217 × 10
 <sup>9</sup>/L. The insulin dose was adjusted to 3 U (i.h, 3 times per day, before each meal). Thiamine was continued (10 mg/ day, 3 times per day). Fasting glucose levels were maintained at 3.5–7.2 mmol/L.
</p>
