<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Publishing DTD v1.1 20151215//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName JATS-journalpublishing1.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 1.1?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName jp2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Medicine (Baltimore)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Medicine (Baltimore)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">MEDI</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Medicine</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">0025-7974</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1536-5964</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Lippincott Williams &#x00026; Wilkins</publisher-name><publisher-loc>Hagerstown, MD</publisher-loc></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">7982173</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">33725995</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">MD-D-21-01431</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000025138</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="art-access-id">25138</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>3800</subject></subj-group><subj-group><subject>Research Article</subject><subject>Study Protocol Clinical Trial</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Effects of probiotics on gastrointestinal complications and nutritional status of postoperative patients with esophageal cancer</article-title><subtitle>A protocol of randomized controlled trial</subtitle></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">http://orcid.org/0000-0003-1358-1572</contrib-id><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Chao</given-names></name><degrees>MB</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>a</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Jing</given-names></name><degrees>MM</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>a</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>Weiwei</given-names></name><degrees>MB</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>a</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Yuan</surname><given-names>Jinyan</given-names></name><degrees>MB</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2"><sup>b</sup></xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp"><sup>&#x02217;</sup></xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff1"><label>a</label>The NO.2 Hospital of Baoding Department of Gastroenterology</aff><aff id="aff2"><label>b</label>Shanxi Provincial People's Hospital Thoracic Surgery.</aff><author-notes id="cor1"><corresp><label>&#x02217;</label>Correspondence: Jinyan Yuan, No.256, Youyi West Road, Xian, Shanxi Province, Shanxi Provincial People's Hospital shanxixian 610075, China (e-mail: <email>13700279532@163.com</email>).</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><day>19</day><month>3</month><year>2021</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>19</day><month>3</month><year>2021</year></pub-date><volume>100</volume><issue>11</issue><elocation-id>e25138</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>20</day><month>2</month><year>2021</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>22</day><month>2</month><year>2021</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2021 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2021</copyright-year><license license-type="open-access" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0" specific-use="CC-BY"><license-p>This is an open access article distributed under the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0 (CCBY), which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited. <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</ext-link></license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xlink:href="medi-100-e25138.pdf"/><abstract><title>Abstract</title><sec sec-type="background"><title>Background:</title><p>Gastrointestinal complications and malnutrition are common problems that affect postoperative rehabilitation and survival of patients with esophageal cancer. Evidence has shown that probiotics have a positive effect on improving gastrointestinal complications and nutritional status of patients with esophageal cancer after surgery, but there is a lack of prospective studies on this topic. We designed this prospective randomized controlled trial to evaluate the effects of probiotics on gastrointestinal complications and nutritional status in patients with postoperative esophageal cancer.</p></sec><sec sec-type="methods"><title>Methods:</title><p>This is a prospective, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. It was approved by the Clinical Research Ethics Committee of our hospital. 192 patients will be randomly divided into probiotics group and the placebo group in a 1:1 ratio. After operation, probiotics and placebo will be given orally for 8&#x0200a;weeks. The indexes of nutritional status and incidence of digestive tract complications will be recorded and the data will be analyzed by SPSS 18.0 software.</p></sec><sec sec-type="discussion"><title>Discussion:</title><p>This study will evaluate the effect of probiotics on gastrointestinal complications and nutritional status of postoperative patients with esophageal cancer. The results of this study will provide clinical basis for the use of probiotics in postoperative treatment of esophageal cancer.</p></sec><sec><title>Trial registration:</title><p>OSF Registration number: D DOI 10.17605/OSF.IO/QHW86</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group><title>Keywords</title><kwd>complications</kwd><kwd>esophageal cancer</kwd><kwd>nutritional status</kwd><kwd>probiotics</kwd><kwd>protocol</kwd><kwd>Randomized controlled trial</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group id="award1" award-type="Fundref"><funding-source>the Baoding science and technology research and development project</funding-source><award-id>No. 1951ZF021</award-id><principal-award-recipient>Not Applicable</principal-award-recipient></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>OPEN-ACCESS</meta-name><meta-value>TRUE</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec><label>1</label><title>Introduction</title><p>As many as 80% of esophageal cancer patients are malnourished.<sup>[<xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]</sup> Due to the particularity of tumor location, insufficient nutrition intake and malignant consumption of tumor, negative effects of patients&#x02019; bad psychological state (such as depression, anxiety, fear, etc.) can lead to negative nutritional balance in patients with esophageal cancer.<sup>[<xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,<xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]</sup> At present, the treatment of esophageal cancer is still based on surgery combined with radiotherapy and chemotherapy. Postoperative changes in the anatomical pathway of the upper digestive tract, perioperative fasting (usually 5&#x02013;7&#x0200a;days), surgical trauma stress, absorption of endotoxin and destruction of mucosal barrier lead to the disorder of digestive tract flora, resulting in a series of gastrointestinal complications and aggravating the poor nutritional status of postoperative patients with esophageal cancer.<sup>[<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]</sup> It is not conducive to postoperative rehabilitation of patients,<sup>[<xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]</sup> and limits further anti-tumor therapy such as radiotherapy and chemotherapy at the same time, which has a serious impact on the prognosis and survival of patients.<sup>[<xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,<xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]</sup> Therefore, gastrointestinal complications are the most important perioperative complications of esophageal cancer. It is particularly important to reduce the incidence and improve the nutritional status after operation.</p><p>There are many kinds of colonizing bacteria in the human digestive tract, and these colonizing bacteria cluster together to form a colony.<sup>[<xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]</sup> Existing studies have confirmed that changes in the composition of digestive tract flora are closely related to esophageal cancer and digestive tract carcinogenesis.<sup>[<xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</sup> Normal alimentary tract flora plays an important role in host nutrient metabolism, drug metabolism, maintenance of intestinal mucosal barrier structural integrity, immune regulation, etc. It has been shown that the supplementation of probiotics can adjust the composition of the maladjusted flora in the body, maintain the microecological balance, and promote the recovery and health of the body.<sup>[<xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]</sup> At present, probiotics have been widely used in the postoperative adjuvant therapy of digestive system tumors such as colorectal cancer and gastric cancer, and have been proven to reduce complications, improve the integrity of the intestinal mucosal barrier, and improve the nutritional status.<sup>[<xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]</sup> Although retrospective studies have confirmed that probiotics are beneficial for patients with esophageal cancer,<sup>[<xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]</sup> no rigorous clinical studies have evaluated the effects of probiotics on nutrition and gastrointestinal complications in patients with postoperative esophageal cancer.</p><p>Therefore, we will conduct a prospective randomized controlled study to analyze whether postoperative intake of probiotics in patients with esophageal cancer can reduce gastrointestinal complications and improve the nutritional status of patients.</p></sec><sec><label>2</label><title>Materials and methods</title><sec><label>2.1</label><title>Study design</title><p>This is a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled prospective trial to study the effects of probiotics on gastrointestinal complications and nutritional status in postoperative patients with esophageal cancer. This scheme will be written according to the Consolidated Standards of Reporting Trials,<sup>[<xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]</sup> and the Consolidated Standards of Reporting Trials flow chart is shown in Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">1</xref>.</p><fig id="F1" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>Flow diagram.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="medi-100-e25138-g001"/></fig></sec><sec><label>2.2</label><title>Ethics and registration</title><p>This protocol conforms to the Helsinki Declaration and has been approved by the Clinical Research Ethics Committee of our hospital. This experiment has already been registered (OSF)(registration number: DOI 10.17605/OSF.IO/QHW86). We will fully inform patients and their families about the potential risks of this study. Patients or their families are required to sign a written informed consent form. Patients are free to choose whether to continue the trial at any time during the study.</p></sec><sec><label>2.3</label><title>Patients</title><sec><label>2.3.1</label><title>Inclusion criteria</title><list list-type="simple"><list-item><label>(1)</label><p>All patients underwent radical resection of esophageal cancer and were confirmed by postoperative pathology.</p></list-item><list-item><label>(2)</label><p>The patient has no cognitive impairment and can communicate normally.</p></list-item><list-item><label>(3)</label><p>Patients and their families voluntarily participated in the study and signed the informed consent form.</p></list-item></list></sec><sec><label>2.3.2</label><title>Exclusion criteria</title><list list-type="simple"><list-item><label>(1)</label><p>Previous history of gastrointestinal surgery, history of inflammatory enteritis and recurrence of esophageal cancer.</p></list-item><list-item><label>(2)</label><p>Those who suffer from severe metabolic diseases or who have developed severe cachexia.</p></list-item><list-item><label>(3)</label><p>Patients with severe liver, kidney, lung function diseases and immune system diseases.</p></list-item><list-item><label>(4)</label><p>Had a long history of hormone use before operation.</p></list-item><list-item><label>(5)</label><p>Patients who took probiotics by themselves before operation.</p></list-item></list></sec></sec><sec><label>2.4</label><title>Sample size</title><p>The sample size was calculated based on the score of serum albumin six weeks after surgery. According to the results of the pilot study, the score of the probiotics group was 37.94&#x0200a;&#x000b1;&#x0200a;7.15 and that of the placebo group was 34.53&#x0200a;&#x000b1;&#x0200a;5.29. Set &#x003b1;&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0.025, one-tailed, and <italic>&#x003b2;</italic>&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;0.10. According to the calculation of PASS15.0 software, each group needs 86 participants, and the estimated withdrawal rate is 10%, and 96 participants will be included in each group.</p></sec><sec><label>2.5</label><title>Program implementation</title><p>We will screen patients who meet the criteria through pre-hospital recruitment and in-hospital inpatients. 192 patients will be included in this study. Patients will randomly select any number from 001 to 192 from a sealed envelope and are assigned to the probiotic group (group A) and placebo group (group B) according to the parity of the number. Probiotics and placebo are marked &#x0201c;A&#x0201d; and &#x0201c;B&#x0201d; respectively. The probiotics are Live Combined Bifidobacterium, Lactobacillus and Enterococcus Powder (Shanghai Xinyi Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd. National drug license S10970105, 1&#x0200a;g/bag), made up of Bifidobacterium, Lactobacillus acidophilus, Enterococcus faecalis. The number of living bacteria per gram is not less than 1.0&#x0200a;&#x000d7;&#x0200a;107CFU. The placebo is made of starch, and there is no difference in appearance and smell between them.</p><p>All the patients will be operated by the same operation team. There is no obvious anastomotic fistula which is confirmed by upper gastrointestinal radiography after the operation. They can start eating. On the advice of the dietitian, the patients in the two groups will be given a liquid diet and gradually transferred to a semi-fluid diet to a normal diet. To ensure that antibiotics given after surgery do not interfere with the results of the study, patients will start taking probiotics or a placebo two weeks after surgery. The dose is 2 bags per time, 3 times a day, and infused with warm water for 8&#x0200a;weeks.</p></sec><sec><label>2.6</label><title>Observation index</title><list list-type="simple"><list-item><label>(1)</label><p>Nutritional status index: fasting venous blood will be taken from the two groups at 2 week, 6&#x0200a;weeks after operation and at the end of treatment to detect hemoglobin (Hb), serum albumin, prealbumin and total lymphocyte count, and to measure the height and weight of the two groups at two time points. Calculate body mass index, body mass index normal value&#x0200a;&#x0003e;&#x0200a;20.0&#x02013;25.0&#x0200a;kg/m<sup>2</sup>, 18.5&#x0223c;20.0&#x0200a;kg/m<sup>2</sup> is potential malnutrition &#x0003c; 18.5&#x0200a;kg/m<sup>2</sup> is malnutrition.</p></list-item><list-item><label>(2)</label><p>Complication index: anorexia, acid regurgitation, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea (&#x02265;3 times/d), pulmonary infection, incision infection and anastomotic leakage will be recorded during the study period.</p></list-item></list></sec><sec><label>2.7</label><title>Data collection and management</title><p>The patients are followed up by telephone for 30&#x0200a;days after treatment by two assistants, and the data will be collected and recorded. The relevant information and data of this study will be collected, shared and stored in a separate storeroom to protect the confidentiality before, during and after the test. People outside this research group do not have access to relevant data.</p></sec><sec><label>2.8</label><title>Statistical analysis</title><p>The collected data are statistically analyzed by SPSS 18.0 software. The counting data use the chi-square test; measurement data use the mean &#x000b1; standard deviation (<inline-formula id="FI1"><mml:math id="M1"><mml:mrow><mml:mover accent="true"><mml:mi>x</mml:mi><mml:mo stretchy="true">&#x000af;</mml:mo></mml:mover><mml:mo>&#x000b1;</mml:mo><mml:mi>s</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:math></inline-formula>), the normal distribution uses the independent sample t-test, and the skewed distribution uses the Mann-Whitney <italic>U</italic> test. When <italic>P</italic>&#x0200a;<italic>&#x0003c;0.05</italic>, the difference is considered to be statistically significant.</p></sec></sec><sec><label>3</label><title>Discussion</title><p>After operation, the gastrointestinal tract of patients with esophageal cancer is mostly in a state of hypodynamic, and up to 50% of patients will have disturbance of gastric emptying, gastric dumping syndrome, dysphagia and other phenomena, which can lead to enteral nutritional intolerance, adverse reactions such as reflux, vomiting, abdominal distension, constipation, diarrhea, and even serious complications such as aspiration pneumonia and severe malnutrition.<sup>[<xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]</sup> Due to perioperative fasting, gastrointestinal mucosal cells lack of food stimulation for a long time, ischemia and hypoxia lead to the decrease of mucosal cell proliferation and repair ability, the weakening of barrier function, and the weakening of immune defense.<sup>[<xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]</sup> Intestinal bacterial translocation<sup>[<xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]</sup> and increased endotoxin secretion<sup>[<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]</sup> are more likely to occur, and the probability of enterogenous infection increases. The high metabolism caused by surgical destruction of the mucosal barrier and stress is prone to acid-base imbalance, electrolyte disturbance, early postoperative gastrointestinal intolerance and so on to further aggravate the imbalance of gastrointestinal flora.</p><p>Some studies have pointed out that probiotics can maintain the balance of intestinal flora, reduce ectopic flora and endotoxin into the blood,<sup>[<xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]</sup> and regulate intestinal motility in both ways, which can alleviate the severity of diarrhea in patients with irritable bowel syndrome with hyperkinetic bowel syndrome. It can also reduce the degree of abdominal distension caused by gastrointestinal motility deficiency, increase the frequency of intestinal peristalsis, maintain intestinal peristaltic continuity,<sup>[<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</sup> and effectively improve the nutritional status of postoperative patients with digestive system tumors. It is beneficial to the recovery after operation.<sup>[<xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]</sup> Supplementation of probiotics can reduce the incidence of gastrointestinal complications and improve the nutritional status of patients after surgery by regulating gastrointestinal flora, improving microecological balance and restoring the physiological function of gastrointestinal tract in tumor patients.<sup>[<xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</sup> At present, there are few clinical studies on the application of probiotics for postoperative patients with esophageal cancer, and it is still controversial whether probiotics is beneficial to postoperative patients with esophageal cancer. Therefore, we intend to use this randomized controlled study to explore the effects of probiotics on gastrointestinal complications and nutritional status in postoperative patients with esophageal cancer.</p><p>The regionalization of the study population and short follow-up time are the shortcomings of this study program. Therefore, more multi-center and long-term follow-up studies are needed to determine the effects of probiotics on postoperative patients with esophageal cancer.</p></sec><sec><title>Author contributions</title><p><bold>Conceptualization</bold>: Chao Liu and Jing Yang.</p><p><bold>Data curation</bold>: Chao Liu and Jing Yang.</p><p><bold>Formal analysis</bold>: Weiwei Dong.</p><p><bold>Funding acquisition</bold>: Jinyan Yuan.</p><p><bold>Software</bold>: Jing Yang and Weiwei Dong.</p><p><bold>Supervision</bold>: Jinyan Yuan, Weiwei Dong.</p><p><bold>Writing &#x02013; original draft:</bold> Chao Liu and Jing Yang.</p><p><bold>Writing &#x02013; review &#x00026; editing</bold>: Chao Liu and Jinyan Yuan.</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn fn-type="abbr"><p>Abbreviations: ALB = serum albumin, BMI = body mass index, CONSORT = Consolidated Standards of Reporting Trials, Hb = hemoglobin, RCT = Randomized controlled trial, TLC = prealbumin and total lymphocyte count.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>How to cite this article: Liu C, Yang J, Dong W, Yuan J. Effects of probiotics on gastrointestinal complications and nutritional status of postoperative patients with esophageal cancer: a protocol of randomized controlled trial. <italic>Medicine</italic>. 2021;100:11(e25138).</p></fn><fn fn-type="supported-by"><p>This work was supported by the Baoding science and technology research and development project (No. 1951ZF021).</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>Informed consent has been obtained from the patient and approval has been obtained from the ethics committee.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>This study has been approved by the Ethics committee.</p></fn><fn fn-type="COI-statement"><p>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>Data sharing not applicable to this article as no datasets were generated or analyzed during the current study.</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="R1"><label>[1]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bozzetti</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Mariani</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name><surname>Lo Vullo</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>The nutritional risk in oncology: a study of 1,453 cancer outpatients</article-title>. <source>Supportive care in cancer: official journal of the Multinational Association of Supportive Care in Cancer</source>
<year>2012</year>;<volume>20</volume>:<fpage>1919</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>28</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22314972</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R2"><label>[2]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Momoki</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Okada</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Preoperative Depressive Mood of Patients With Esophageal Cancer Might Delay Recovery From Operation-Related Malnutrition</article-title>. <source>Journal of clinical medicine research</source>
<year>2019</year>;<volume>11</volume>:<fpage>188</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>95</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30834041</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R3"><label>[3]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Na</surname><given-names>BG</given-names></name><name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>SS</given-names></name><name><surname>Cho</surname><given-names>YA</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Nutritional Status of Patients with Cancer: A Prospective Cohort Study of 1,588 Hospitalized Patients</article-title>. <source>Nutrition and cancer</source>
<year>2018</year>;<volume>70</volume>:<fpage>1228</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>36</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30900926</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R4"><label>[4]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Heller</surname><given-names>AR</given-names></name><name><surname>R&#x000f6;ssler</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Litz</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Omega-3 fatty acids improve the diagnosis-related clinical outcome</article-title>. <source>Crit Care Med</source>
<year>2006</year>;<volume>34</volume>:<fpage>972</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>9</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16484909</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R5"><label>[5]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Effect of early enteral nutrition on postoperative nutritional status and immune function in elderly patients with esophageal cancer or cardiac cancer</article-title>. <source>Chin J Cancer Res</source>
<year>2013</year>;<volume>25</volume>:<fpage>299</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>305</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23825906</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R6"><label>[6]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Shang</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>The predictive value of a preoperative systemic immune-inflammation index and prognostic nutritional index in patients with esophageal squamous cell carcinoma</article-title>. <source>J Cell Physiol</source>
<year>2019</year>;<volume>234</volume>:<fpage>1794</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>802</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30070689</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R7"><label>[7]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Schwegler</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name><surname>von Holzen</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Gutzwiller</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Nutritional risk is a clinical predictor of postoperative mortality and morbidity in surgery for colorectal cancer</article-title>. <source>Br J Surg</source>
<year>2010</year>;<volume>97</volume>:<fpage>92</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>7</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20013933</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R8"><label>[8]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Gail</surname><given-names>MH</given-names></name><name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Association between upper digestive tract microbiota and cancer-predisposing states in the esophagus and stomach</article-title>. <source>Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev</source>
<year>2014</year>;<volume>23</volume>:<fpage>735</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>41</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24700175</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R9"><label>[9]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name><surname>Winckler</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Oral Microbiota and Risk for Esophageal Squamous Cell Carcinoma in a High-Risk Area of China</article-title>. <source>PloS One</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>10</volume>:<fpage>e0143603</fpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26641451</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R10"><label>[10]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Blaser</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Disappearing microbiota: Helicobacter pylori protection against esophageal adenocarcinoma</article-title>. <source>Cancer prevention research (Philadelphia, Pa)</source>
<year>2008</year>;<volume>1</volume>:<fpage>308</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>11</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R11"><label>[11]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Raymond</surname><given-names>DP</given-names></name><name><surname>Seder</surname><given-names>CW</given-names></name><name><surname>Wright</surname><given-names>CD</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Predictors of major morbidity or mortality after resection for esophageal cancer: a society of thoracic surgeons general thoracic surgery database risk adjustment model</article-title>. <source>Ann Thorac Surg</source>
<year>2016</year>;<volume>102</volume>:<fpage>207</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>14</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27240449</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R12"><label>[12]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Randomised clinical trial: the effects of perioperative probiotic treatment on barrier function and post-operative infectious complications in colorectal cancer surgery - a double-blind study</article-title>. <source>Aliment Pharmacol Ther</source>
<year>2011</year>;<volume>33</volume>:<fpage>50</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>63</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21083585</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R13"><label>[13]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Dong</given-names></name><name><surname>Xiaoran</surname><given-names>Shen</given-names></name><name><surname>Yini</surname><given-names>Dang</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Advances in the study of gastrointestinal microecology and esophageal cancer [J]</article-title>. <source>Chinese Journal of Gastroenterology and Hepatology</source>
<year>2018</year>;<volume>27</volume>:<fpage>569</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>72</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R14"><label>[14]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Schulz</surname><given-names>KF</given-names></name><name><surname>Altman</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name><surname>Moher</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>CONSORT 2010 statement: Updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomised trials</article-title>. <source>Journal of pharmacology &#x00026; pharmacotherapeutics</source>
<year>2010</year>;<volume>1</volume>:<fpage>100</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>7</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21350618</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R15"><label>[15]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Reintam Blaser</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Malbrain</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Starkopf</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Gastrointestinal function in intensive care patients: terminology, definitions and management</article-title>. <source>Recommendations of the ESICM Working Group on Abdominal Problems</source>
<year>2012</year>;<volume>38</volume>:<fpage>384</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>94</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R16"><label>[16]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gangadharan</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>SE</given-names></name><name><surname>Hassan</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Protein calorie malnutrition, nutritional intervention and personalized cancer care</article-title>. <source>Oncotarget</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>8</volume>:<fpage>24009</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>30</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28177923</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R17"><label>[17]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Okada</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Momoki</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Habu</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Effect of Postoperative Oral Intake on Prognosis for Esophageal Cancer</article-title>. <source>Nutrients</source>
<year>2019</year>;<volume>11</volume><issue>(6.)</issue>:</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R18"><label>[18]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yi</surname><given-names>Zhang</given-names></name><name><surname>Lijie</surname><given-names>Tan</given-names></name><name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>Qian</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Effect of early postoperative enteral nutrition in patients with esophageal cancer [J]</article-title>. <source>Parenteral &#x00026; Enteral Nntrition</source>
<year>2007</year>;<volume>14</volume>:<fpage>282</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>5</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R19"><label>[19]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jianwei</surname><given-names>Cao</given-names></name><name><surname>Mingfei</surname><given-names>Geng</given-names></name><name><surname>Dongshan</surname><given-names>Zhu</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Effects of alanyl -glutamine and microecological preparations on humoral immune function of patients with esophageal carcinoma</article-title>. <source>Henan Medical Research</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>24</volume>:<fpage>31</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R20"><label>[20]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hungin</surname><given-names>AP</given-names></name><name><surname>Mulligan</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Pot</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Systematic review: probiotics in the management of lower gastrointestinal symptoms in clinical practice -- an evidence-based international guide</article-title>. <source>Aliment Pharmacol Ther</source>
<year>2013</year>;<volume>38</volume>:<fpage>864</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>86</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23981066</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R21"><label>[21]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tingting</surname><given-names>Yu</given-names></name><name><surname>Xiaoliang</surname><given-names>Shu</given-names></name><name><surname>Tao</surname><given-names>Lei</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>The effects of probiotics on patients with gastrointestinal tumor after operation: a systematic review</article-title>. <source>Parenteral &#x00026; Enteral Nutrition</source>
<year>2016</year>;<volume>23</volume>:<fpage>136</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>42</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R22"><label>[22]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lina</surname><given-names>Zhu</given-names></name><name><surname>Yufang</surname><given-names>Zhan</given-names></name><name><surname>Jiuchao</surname><given-names>Zhang</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Effects of probiotics combined with enteral nutrition on gastrointestinal function of postoperative patients with esophageal cancer</article-title>. <source>Chinese Journal of Microecology</source>
<year>2018</year>;<volume>30</volume>:<fpage>924</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>7</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>