<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A 59-year-old man experienced a surgery of lung cancer in 2016. He was diagnosed with primary rectosigmoid-junction SCC (pT4aN2M0 IIIc, tumor size: 10 cm×9 cm) and underwent radical resection in September, 2019. After surgery, he was treated with the chemotherapy (Docetaxel+Cisplatin). In March 2020, liver metastasis was found and he was treated with the chemotherapy (Nab-Paclitaxel + Nedaplatin). During the chemotherapy, the patient showed a progressive disease. A genetic testing was used to the surgery tissue and a 
 <italic>BRCA2 p.V220fs</italic> mutation was found. According to the mutation of 
 <italic>BRAC2</italic>, the treatment was changed to Niraparib. But the tumor continued to progress. In April 2020, this patient was admitted to our hospital. The computed tomography (CT) revealed metastasis in the liver and abdominal &amp; pelvic cavity (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
  <bold>Figure 1</bold>
 </xref>). Biopsy was performed, and the pathology of the specimen revealed SCC (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
  <bold>Figure 2A</bold>
 </xref>). Immunohistochemistry (IHC) showed a strong positive expression of PD-L1 in tumor cells (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
  <bold>Figure 2B</bold>
 </xref>). Next generation sequencing (NGS) of biopsy tissue was performed on Illumina HiSeq sequencer (Illumina, San Diego, CA) with a median unique exon coverage depth of 800× in a College of American Pathologists (CAP) and Clinical Laboratory Improvement Amendments (CLIA) certified laboratory (3D Medicine Inc., Shanghai, China) (
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>). The NGS results showed that the 
 <italic>KRAS</italic>/
 <italic>NRAS</italic>/
 <italic>BRAF</italic> genes were wild-type. And this patient harbored one germline mutation in 
 <italic>BRCA2</italic>, 
 <italic>p.V220Ifs*4</italic>. The TMB-H (18.99 Muts/Mb) and MSS were identified. No SNVs were detected in 
 <italic>MLH1</italic>, 
 <italic>MSH2</italic>, 
 <italic>MSH6</italic> and 
 <italic>PMS2</italic>. The IHC method was used to confirm that the patient had pMMR rectosigmoid-junction SCC cancer (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f3">
  <bold>Figures 3A–D</bold>
 </xref>). In April 28, 2020, the patient was received Sintilimab, a PD-1 antibody (200 mg on D1, every 3 weeks) (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
  <bold>Figure 4A</bold>
 </xref>). And on May 12, 2020, the chemotherapy was added (Capecitabine 1.5 g, twice a day on D1-D14, every 3 weeks). About three months later, a partial response was confirmed in the CT scan (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
  <bold>Figures 4B–E</bold>
 </xref>) and lasted until January 6, 2021. In January 2021, lymph node enlargement was found and he was treated with the Sintilimab plus Capecitabine and Bevacizumab (200 mg on D1). Currently, at the end of Mar. 2021, the patient was continuing the immunotherapy combined with chemotherapy and a stable response was confirmed.
</p>
