<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The probabilities of DFS, aGvHD-free survival, and OS were calculated using the Kaplan-Meier estimator. The probabilities of neutrophil and platelet engraftment, TRM, disease progression/relapse, and aGvHD and cGvHD were calculated using the cumulative incidence estimator. GvHD was calculated using disease progression/relapse or death as competing risks. Matching criteria for controls consisted of age within 5 years; performance score (≥90 
 <italic>vs</italic>. &lt;90); Bu-based regimen (Flu/Bu reduced intensity, Bu/Cy MA, or Flu/Bu MA); disease, and donor type (human leukocyte antigen [HLA]-matched sibling vs. HLA-matched unrelated donor). Up to four matches per case were selected whenever possible; when more controls were available preference was given to identical stem cell source (bone marrow, peripheral blood) and closest age. With respect to stem cell source, 124 of the 135 CIBMTR control patients were also matched for this variable. The follow up of the control patients was administratively censored at 22 months, which corresponded to the longest follow up of the trial patients. With 35 patients enrolled in the trial and 140 controls, there was an 80% power to detect an improvement of 20% on day 180 aGvHD-free survival. The outcomes were compared between groups using a stratified log-rank test or Gray’s test for survival and competing risk outcomes, respectively, with matched sets defining strata. Stratified Cox or Fine-Gray regression was used to obtain hazard ratios with 95% confidence intervals. Each cytokine was analyzed separately in the combined sample, and by conditioning regimen (ablative 
 <italic>vs</italic>. RIC). Cytokine values were shifted by half of the smallest nonzero value and then log-transformed to improve normality of the residuals. First, a separate analysis was conducted for each treatment group (Toc and Control) followed by a joint analysis. A repeated measures analysis was performed using a mixed effects model with a random subject-specific intercept to incorporate within-subject dependence. All time-points were compared to the baseline value with Dunnett-Hsu adjustment for multiple testing. The estimates were back-transformed to the original scale for reporting.
</p>
