<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fn-group>
 <fn id="d31e333">
  <p id="ntpara0010">
   <italic>Supplemental material available at</italic>
   <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.aaojournal.org" id="intref0010" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    <italic>www.aaojournal.org</italic>
   </ext-link>
   <italic>.</italic>
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn id="d31e342">
  <p id="ntpara0015">Financial Disclosure(s): The author(s) have made the following disclosure(s): A.N.R.: Consultant - Abcodia, Myriad Genetics.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn id="d31e345">
  <p id="ntpara0020">R.G.W.: Scientific Advisory Board - Foundation Fighting Blindness, AGTC; Patent - Visual Field Modelling and Analysis software.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn id="d31e348">
  <p id="ntpara0025">D.H.W.S.: Consultant - Alcon, Bayer.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn id="d31e351">
  <p id="ntpara0030">E.A.: Employee - Astellas Institute for Regenerative Medicine.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn id="d31e354">
  <p id="ntpara0035">R.P.L.: Patents relevant to the generation and use of RPE cells derived from pluripotent stem cells.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn id="d31e357">
  <p id="ntpara0040">J.W.B.B.: Consultant - Astellas Institute for Regenerative Medicine.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn id="d31e360">
  <p id="ntpara0045">Supported by Advanced Cell Technology; Ocata Therapeutics; Astellas Institute for Regenerative Medicine; NIHR Biomedical Research Centre for Ophthalmology at Moorfields and University College London, London, United Kingdom; The Wellcome Trust (grant no.: 099173/Z/12/Z); Moorfields Eye Charity, London, United Kingdom; Moorfilelds Eye Hospital Special Trustees, London, United Kingdom; and RP Fighting Blindness. James Bainbridge is an NIHR Research Professor. The sponsor participated in the design of the study and approval of the manuscript.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn id="d31e363">
  <p id="ntpara0050">HUMAN SUBJECTS: This study included human subjects or tissues. Study protocol was approved by the Medicines and Health Products Regulatory Authority, the UK Gene Therapy Advisory Committee, and the Moorfields Eye Hospital Research Governance Committee. Informed consent was obtained from all human subjects. This adhered to the tenets of the Declaration of Helsinki.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn id="d31e366">
  <p id="ntpara0055rr">No animals were used in this study.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn id="d31e369">
  <p id="ntpara0055">Author Contributions:</p>
 </fn>
 <fn id="d31e373">
  <p id="ntpara0060">Conception and design: Mehat, Sundaram, Ripamonti, Weleber, Lee, Rubin, Dhillon, Steel, Anglade, Lanza, Michaelides, Bainbridge</p>
 </fn>
 <fn id="d31e376">
  <p id="ntpara0065">Analysis and interpretation: Mehat, Sundaram, Ripamonti, Robson, Smith, Borooah, Robinson, Innes, Weleber, Lee, Crossland, Rubin, Dhillon, Steel, Anglade, Lanza, Ali, Michaelides, Bainbridge</p>
 </fn>
 <fn id="d31e379">
  <p id="ntpara0070">Data collection: Mehat, Sundaram, Ripamonti, Robson, Borooah, Rosenthal, Innes, Crossland, Rubin, Dhillon, Steel, Michaelides, Bainbridge</p>
 </fn>
 <fn id="d31e382">
  <p id="ntpara0075">Obtained funding: N/A</p>
 </fn>
 <fn id="d31e385">
  <p id="ntpara0080">Overall responsibility: Mehat, Sundaram, Ripamonti, Robson, Smith, Borooah, Robinson, Rosenthal, Weleber, Lee, Crossland, Rubin, Dhillon, Steel, Anglade, Lanza, Ali, Michaelides, Bainbridge</p>
 </fn>
</fn-group>
