<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Controlling abundance of wildlife species that are simultaneously protected, abundant, competitive for resources, and in conflict with some stakeholders is a formidable challenge for resource managers. We demonstrated that the GnRH vaccine, GonaCon-Equine, could be an effective immunocontraceptive for free-ranging feral horses, particularly when the primary vaccination is followed by reimmunization four years later. This vaccine was shown to be safe for pregnant females and neonates and did not result in deleterious behavioral side effects during the foaling/breeding season. The only adverse reactions to vaccination were non-debilitating inflammatory responses at injection sites. One noteworthy implication has emerged regarding long-term management of free-ranging horse populations using GonaCon-Equine vaccine: effective management and development of population models will need to incorporate repeat immunizations of this vaccine to optimize management strategies aimed at stabilizing the growth rate of feral horse populations. Our research suggests that practical application of this vaccine in feral horses will require an initial inoculation that may provide only modest suppression of fertility followed by reimmunization over time that together could result in greater reduction in population growth rates. Future research will begin to define the most effective revaccination schedule with GonaCon-Equine for suppressing reproductive rates in free-ranging horses, the duration of effectiveness, and the return to fertility following treatment. Moreover, applying GonaCon-Equine to control the growth of feral horse populations will require that resource managers choose specific tactics for treating animals. Choices must be made on the number and age to treat and the frequency of treatment needed to maintain the desired population age structure and genetic diversity. Decisions on the most beneficial tactics will depend on overarching management goals and long-term objectives for the population.</p>
