<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par107">Assessments to be performed prior to participant registration to the ACCoRd study and starting treatment are a physical examination (including systolic and diastolic blood pressure, height, weight, BSA, vital signs, assessment for peripheral neuropathy, for example, using the Neurotoxicity Assessment Tool); ECOG PS and Revised International Staging System (R-ISS) classification; medical history (including details of concomitant disease and medication, prior chemotherapy and ASCT and previous trial participation); Haematopoietic Cell Transplantation (HCT) Comorbidity Index score; FBC; serology of hepatitis B and C; urea and electrolytes, liver function tests, albumin, lactate dehydrogenase, C-reactive protein, calcium, creatinine and β
 <sub>2</sub>-microglobulin; estimated creatinine clearance; paraprotein, serum free light chains, serum total (class-specific) immunoglobulins and urinary light chain detection (quantification where available); bone marrow aspirate and trephine (if available) within 4 weeks prior to registration; a pregnancy test; cardiac function (LVEF) within 12 weeks prior to registration; pulmonary function (
 <italic>K</italic>
 <sub>CO</sub>/
 <italic>D</italic>
 <sub>LCO</sub>) and an axial skeletal survey (performed as part of the restaging process in accordance with IMWG recommendations and local policy, and can be supplemented by computed tomography (CT), magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) or other investigation when appropriate in accordance with local practice). Additionally, for the central investigation, a set of compulsory samples must be provided to the appropriate lab, to include peripheral clotted blood (10 ml) and random urine sample (10 ml); bone marrow aspirate (2 ml) in ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid (EDTA) and bone marrow trephine (where available) in formalin, embedded in paraffin/wax block or on slides (See Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref> for assessment schedule details).
</p>
