<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>While FA was recognized as an early candidate disorder for gene therapy, several obstacles have been identified that have delayed clinical success.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b3-1031806" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>
 </sup> Initial clinical trials demonstrated a dramatic approximately 50-fold reduction in the number of true HSPCs in FA patients relative to other gene therapy patients, such as those treated for primary immune deficiencies.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b7-1031806" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>
 </sup> Moreover, FA HSPCs were exceptionally fragile when manipulated 
 <italic>ex vivo</italic> for gene transfer. No treated patient has demonstrated stable improvements in blood cell counts with long-term persistence of gene-corrected blood cells. These studies highlighted two needs for innovation in 
 <italic>FA</italic> gene therapy: 1) to increase the number of available HSPCs for gene transfer and infusion; and 2) to increase the engraftment potential of these cells after gene transfer and infusion. Following the recommendations of the International FA Gene Therapy Working Group,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b8-1031806" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>
 </sup> we launched a phase I clinical trial of gene therapy for FA complementation group A (FA-A) patients in 2011 (
 <italic>
  <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://clinicaltrials.gov" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">clinicaltrials.gov</ext-link> identifier: 01331018
 </italic>). This trial design incorporates several features aiming to improve HSPC numbers and fitness. These include: i) a self-inactivating (SIN) lentiviral vector (LV) for transfer of the 
 <italic>FANCA</italic> cDNA regulated by a human phosphoglycerate kinase (hPGK) promoter; ii) a short, overnight transduction to minimize 
 <italic>ex vivo</italic> manipulation, as well as addition of the antioxidant N-acetylcysteine (NAC) throughout manipulation; and iii) culture under reduced oxygen (5%) to limit oxidative DNA damage.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b9-1031806" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
