<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The target HSPC population for gene transfer expresses the CD34 cell surface protein (CD34
 <sup>+</sup>). When stained with fluorophore-conjugated antibody against CD34 and analyzed by flow cytometry, a small proportion of BM cells are CD34
 <sup>+</sup>, representing both primitive stem cells and more committed progenitors.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b10-1031806" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>
 </sup> The standard clinical procedure for isolating these cells first involves either BM collection or mobilization of the cells into circulation through cytokine stimulation with granulocyte colony stimulating factor (G-CSF) or, in certain clinical scenarios, a combination of G-CSF and the chemokine receptor CXCR4 antagonist plerixafor, followed by peripheral blood leukapheresis (mAPH). Initial isolation technologies relied on CD34 antigen expression on the cell surface and utilized biotinavidin affinity, panning, or immununomagnetic bead-based approaches. Expected yields were 50% of available CD34
 <sup>+</sup> cells with highly variable purities, ranging from 20–90% across techniques.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b11-1031806" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>
 </sup> Of these, immunomagnetic bead-based positive selection is the most widely-applied today, with the first US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approval of a clinical device for human use in 2014. Advances in this technology to include automation have improved reliability in recovery to a mean yield of 70% with purities regularly over 90%.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b12-1031806" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
  <xref rid="b13-1031806" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>
 </sup> However, these values are based on BM and mAPH products wherein 1–3% of total cells express CD34 antigen, and the majority of these cells display high levels of CD34. For FA patients, the frequency of CD34
 <sup>+</sup> cells is much lower: 0.1–1.5% in BM.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b14-1031806" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
  <xref rid="b15-1031806" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>
 </sup> This implies that non-standard processes may be required to preserve the limited numbers of HSPCs for gene transfer in FA.
</p>
