<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The most likely reason why our DCS regimen failed to achieve the primary endpoint was that the total dose was insufficient. DCS regimens with higher and lower doses have been reported for unresectable advanced gastric cancer, with the higher-dose regimen being more effective but more toxic and the lower-dose regimen being less toxic (
 <xref rid="ref8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
 <xref rid="ref9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>). In Japan, several phase II trials have been conducted to identify the optimal dosage of DCS for preoperative chemotherapy (
 <xref rid="ref18" ref-type="bibr">18–21</xref>). Each study had different eligibility criteria and primary endpoints. Among the studies of preoperative low-dose DCS therapy, we first set the pRR as the primary endpoint. This was not a common approach at the time, as we did not have sufficient evidence regarding the pathological response, but a recent study showed that the pRR was an excellent surrogate endpoint for the overall survival in studies of preoperative chemotherapy (
 <xref rid="ref22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>). The doses of each drug in this study were as follows: docetaxel, 10 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup>/week; cisplatin, 15 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup>/week and S-1, 280 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup>/week. On the other hand, a representative high-dose regimen reported by Hirakawa et al. (
 <xref rid="ref18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>) was composed of docetaxel 20 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup>/week, cisplatin 20 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup>/week and S-1 373 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup>/week. Recently, the pRR of other studies of preoperative DCS therapy was reported to be 50–57% in the lower-dose regimen (
 <xref rid="ref19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,
 <xref rid="ref20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>) and 65.9% in the higher-dose regimen (
 <xref rid="ref18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>). The pRR in this study was 54.8%. Similar pRRs were observed in other studies with low-dose DCS regimens. We speculate that this supports the hypothesis that the pRR is associated with the dose of chemotherapy.
</p>
