<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Clinical courses vary widely, and death or requirement for shunt placement does not always occur even in preterm infants with severe IVH 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0007" ref-type="ref">7</xref>. Therefore, identifying additional biomarkers for the early identification of neuronal injury, in addition to cranial ultrasonography, is crucial for improving therapeutic outcomes 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0027" ref-type="ref">27</xref>. Various CSF biomarkers, including TGFß‐1 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0028" ref-type="ref">28</xref>, VEGF 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0029" ref-type="ref">29</xref>, BDNF 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0020" ref-type="ref">20</xref>, GDNF 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0030" ref-type="ref">30</xref>, and proinflammatory cytokines, such as IL‐1α 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0031" ref-type="ref">31</xref>, IL‐1ß 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0032" ref-type="ref">32</xref>, CCL‐3, and CCL‐19 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0031" ref-type="ref">31</xref> have been used to diagnose brain injury and predict neurodevelopmental outcomes. In a previous study of brain‐specific proteins in the CSF, glial fibrillary acidic protein level was found to be substantially higher in infants with IVH and PHH than in normal infants. It was also correlated with disability and parenchymal lesions 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0033" ref-type="ref">33</xref>. Concentrations of amyloid precursor proteins (APP), soluble APPα, and L1 cell adhesion molecule have also been shown to be selectively increased in PHH infants 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0034" ref-type="ref">34</xref>. In this study, the baseline level of IL‐6 in the initial CSF obtained before MSC transplantation was correlated with initial ventricular dilatation measured as VI and AHW, and was higher in infants who received shunt operations. However, our small sample size and lack of an appropriate control group urge caution for inferences from our results relating to biomarkers. Further research is necessary to understand whether any biomarkers in the CSF 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0035" ref-type="ref">35</xref> can be used, in addition to cranial ultrasonography, to predict neuronal injury, progress of PHH, and poor neurodevelopmental outcomes. Such biomarkers will help identify preterm infants with severe IVH who are most likely to benefit from stem cell therapy. Another limitation of our study stems from the small sample volumes of CSF obtained from extremely tiny premature infants. Assessment of technical variation was consequently impractical, though laboratory has verification of interassay and intraassay reliability for the cytokine profiles in previous other samples.
</p>
