<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract id="abs0010">
 <sec>
  <title>Background</title>
  <p>To clarify the effect of induction chemotherapy (ICT) in patients with advanced pharyngeal and laryngeal squamous cell carcinoma (PLSCC) treated with concurrent chemoradiotherapy (CCRT).</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Methods</title>
  <p>Patients with treatment-naïve nonmetastatic advanced PLSCC were stratified according to disease stage (III or IV) and resectability before being randomized to either a ICT/CCRT or CCRT arm. A cisplatin/tegafur-uracil/leucovorin regimen was administered during ICT and CCRT. The primary end point was overall survival (OS).</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Results</title>
  <p>We enrolled 151 patients during December 2006 to February 2011. The median follow-up of surviving patients was 54.5 months. The ICT/CCRT arm included more patients with hypopharynx cancer (57.1% vs 40.5%, 
   <italic>p</italic> = 0.09) and N2 or N3 diseases (85.7% vs 74.4%, 
   <italic>p</italic> = 0.02). In the ICT/CCRT and CCRT arms, the 5-year OS was 48.1% and 53.2% (
   <italic>p</italic> = 0.45); progression-free survival (PFS) was 31.8% and 55.6% (
   <italic>p</italic> = 0.015); and locoregional control (LRC) was 37.7% and 56.2% (
   <italic>p</italic> = 0.026), respectively. The adverse events and compliance to radiotherapy were similar. However, the proportion of patients receiving a total dose of cisplatin during CCRT &lt;150 mg/m
   <sup>2</sup> was higher in the ICT/CCRT arm (46.8% vs 16.2%; 
   <italic>p</italic> = 0.000) and independently predicted poorer PFS and LRC in multivariate analysis.
  </p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Conclusion</title>
  <p>OS did not vary between the ICT/CCRT and CCRT arms. However, poorer compliance to CCRT and inferior LRC and PFS were observed in the ICT/CCRT arm. Optimizing the therapeutic ratio in both ICT and CCRT settings are necessary for developing a sequential strategy for patients with advanced-stage PLSCC.</p>
 </sec>
</abstract>
