<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>COG AALL1131 (NCT02883049), a phase III trial for patients aged 1-30 years with newly diagnosed high-risk B-ALL opened to enrollment on February 27, 2012 and the VHR randomization closed on February 15, 2017. Eligibility criteria included: 1-9 years of age inclusive with a presenting white blood cell count ≥50×10
 <sup>9</sup>/L; ≥10 to &lt;31 years of age with any white blood cell count; &gt;1 to &lt;31 years of age with testicular leukemia, central nervous system leukemia (CNS3; ≥5/μL white blood cells and cytospin positive for blasts in the cerebral spinal fluid and/or clinical signs of CNS leukemia), or steroid pre-treatment in patients &lt;10 years of age for whom no pre-steroid white blood cell count was obtained.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b7-1040986" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>
 </sup> At the end of induction therapy, patients were fur ther classified as VHR if they had any of the following criteria: ≥13 years of age; CNS3 leukemia at diagnosis; day 29 bone marrow minimal residual disease ≥0.01% determined by flow cytometry;
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b7-1040986" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
  <xref rid="b8-1040986" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>
 </sup> induction failure [&gt;25% bone marrow blasts (M3) on induction day 29], severe hypodiploidy (DNA index &lt;0.81 and/or &lt;44 chromosomes); intrachromosomal amplification of chromosome 21, or lysine methyltransferase 2A (
 <italic>KMT2A</italic>, formerly mixed lineage leukemia, 
 <italic>MLL</italic>) rearrangement. In addition, patients with National Cancer Institute standard-risk B-ALL, enrolled on the COG study AALL0932 (NCT01190930) for standard-risk B-ALL (≥1 to &lt;10 years of age with a white blood cell count &lt;50x10
 <sup>9</sup>/L), were classified as VHR following induction if they met any of the above VHR criteria or if they had day 29 bone marrow minimal residual disease ≥0.01% in the absence of favorable cytogenetics (no trisomies of chromosomes 4 and 10 and no 
 <italic>ETV6/RUNX1</italic> fusion). Patients with Down syndrome were not eligible for the VHR stratum given the concern of increased toxicity of the regimen. Toxicities were graded using the National Cancer Institute’s Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events version 4.0. The study was approved by the National Cancer Institute, the Pediatric Central Institutional Review Board, and institutional review boards at each participating COG institution.
</p>
