<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fn-group>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>
   <bold>Authors' Note:</bold> If any reader is interested in individual participant data that underlie the results reported in this article, the authors have no objection to share these, after de-identification, and requests will be considered on request.
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>
   <bold>Trial Registration:</bold>
   <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://Clincaltrials.gov" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Clincaltrials.gov</ext-link> identifier NCT02580071.
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>
   <bold>Author Contributions:</bold> Drafting of manuscript: TF. Study design: TF, TTC, and HRY. Data collection and analysis: TF. Statistical analyses: JHC. Critical revision of the manuscript for intellectual content: TF, TTC, and HRY.
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="COI-statement">
  <p>
   <bold>Declaration of Conflicting Interests:</bold> The author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="financial-disclosure">
  <p>
   <bold>Funding:</bold> The author(s) disclosed receipt of the following financial support for the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article: This study was supported by China Medical University under the Aim for Top University Plan of the Ministry of Education, Taiwan. This study was also supported in part by China Medical University Hospital, Taiwan (DMR-105-005) and the Taiwan Ministry of Health and Welfare Clinical Trial and Research Center of Excellence (MOHW106-TDU-B-212-113004). The funders had no role in study design, data collection and analysis, decision to publish, or preparation of the article.
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>
   <bold>ORCID iD:</bold> Hung-Rong Yen 
   <inline-graphic xlink:href="10.1177_1534735418756736-img1.jpg" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/> 
   <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-0131-1658" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-0131-1658</ext-link>
  </p>
 </fn>
</fn-group>
