<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>To carry out this study we selected 80 patients (table of patients (
 <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="supplementary-material-1">available here</xref>)) referred to our attention for different reasons. The inclusion criteria were that the patients had at least 3 episodes of aphthae within the year, their age was over 18 years, and they were not affected by other diseases of the oral cavity and the gastrointestinal tract. The study lasted 12 months from the June 1, 2015, to June 1, 2016. This research was conducted in private practice; thus it did not require approval by the local ethics committee. The investigators were trained about study-specific methods, and university researchers have made a contribution only to data entries and to evaluation of the clinical progress. All investigations reported have been carried out in accordance with the 1975 Helsinki Declaration, as revised in 2013 for ethical approval. All participants provided written informed consent after receiving explanations on study objectives and procedures. We asked the patients to begin the treatment with medicines we proposed at the first moment the aphthae symptoms appeared. The last day of treatment was when the patient felt no more need to follow the therapy. Four parameters were considered:
 <list list-type="roman-lower">
  <list-item>
   <p>Pain was graded according to an analytical scale of 0 to 5 where 0 represents normality and 5 is the value given to the highest pain possible.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Difficulty in eating (intended as the difficulty in keeping food or liquids in the oral cavity as well as the difficulty in chewing) was graded according to an analytical scale where 0 represents normality and 5 represents the impossibility of eating.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Difficulty in swallowing (intended as normal swallowing up to impossibility to swallow at all) was graded according to an analytical scale where 0 represents normal swallowing and 5 represents the top level of swallowing difficulty.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>Difficulty in producing sounds or speech again is represented in analytical scale with 0 representing the normal ability to produce sounds and 5 representing the impossibility to talk at all.</p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
