<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>We formed the following groups:
 <list list-type="roman-lower">
  <list-item>
   <p>
    <italic>Placebo group (P)</italic>: this group was given vaseline oil.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>
    <italic>Anaesthetic group (A)</italic>: the active ingredient that we gave and that reacted on contact with the aphthae was Ropivacaine 100 mgs in 10 mls: the patient was told to put the anaesthetic on the lesions with a cotton pad and hold it there for 10 seconds.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>
    <italic>Pharmaceutical drugs group (M)</italic>: this group was given a medicinal compound already present in the market based on Sorbitol Aqua, Propanediol (Zemea), Aqua, Propylene Glycol, Polycarbophil (Noveon AA-1USP), Mucosave FG (Maltodextrin, Opuntia Ficus-Indica stem extract, Olea Europaea leaf extract), Sodium Hydroxide, Taurine, PVP (Luviskol K90), Geogard Ultra (Gluconolactone, Sodium Benzoate, Calcium Gluconate), Xylitol, Sodium Hyaluronate, SymRelief (Bisabolol, Zingiber Officinale root extract), Sucralose, Aroma, and Stevia Rebaudiana extract. This medicinal compound is an alcohol-free gel which was applied 2 to 3 times a day or more if needed after the meals during one week up to complete removal of the symptoms.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>
    <italic>Vitamin group (V)</italic>: this group was given a pharmaceutical compound already in the market based on vitamin A, D, E, B1, B2, B6, B12, C, E, folic acid, pantothenic acid, biotin, niacin, calcium, magnesium, iron, copper, iodine, zinc, manganese, and molybdenum. The administration of these vitamins was the giving of 1 pill a day from the moment that the disease became evident taken up to 7 days after the end of the disease [
    <xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>, 
    <xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>, 
    <xref rid="B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>
    <italic>Vitamin + local anaesthetic + pharmaceutical drugs (VAM)</italic>: this group was given the three medications described in the other preceding groups in the same way as they were introduced to the other groups, except that they were given in a combined way. First the anaesthetic was given, then medicine was given, and, after the anaesthetic took effect, the vitamin pill was administered.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>
    <italic>Vitamin + pharmaceutical drugs (VM)</italic>: this group was given the two medications described in the previous groups and they were given in the order already described: first the pharmaceutical medicine was given and later the vitamin.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>
    <italic>Anaesthetic + pharmaceutical drugs (AM)</italic>: these medications were given in the same way as they were given in the other groups with the anaesthetic given first and then the other medicine given after the anaesthetic took effect.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p>
    <italic>Anaesthetic vitamin group (AV)</italic>: this group was given the two medications. As in the other groups, the anaesthetic was administered first, and then the vitamin pill was given after the anaesthetic took effect.
   </p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
