<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Transformation to small-cell carcinoma is a known mechanism of resistance to EGFR-TKIs in adenocarcinoma. One possible explanation is the low sensitivity to treatment for a small number of tumor cells, and the higher proportion of the small-cell carcinoma component in the initial tumor due to selective pressure. Recently, studies revealed that transformation to SCLC was associated with inactivation of Retinoblastoma 1 and p53, which promote small-cell cloning from adenocarcinoma at an early stage due to divergent evolutionary processes (
 <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>). Transformation to small-cell carcinoma may also be a mechanism of resistance to PD-1 inhibitors in NSCLC (
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>). In our patients, rapid tumor progression was observed after only four cycles of ICIs, despite PD-L1 expression in the tumor tissue. We should take into consideration that the original tumors in our two patients were probably a combination of small-cell carcinoma and squamous cell carcinoma, which were not detected in the initial biopsy specimen, explained by the low SCLC component that was not detectable in the initial transbronchial lung biopsy sample. The other possibility is that the NSCLC cells underwent histological transformation to SCLC cells due to the PD-1 inhibitor. However, while the mechanism is unclear, this possibility is supported by previous studies. In previous reports of transformation to SCLC in EGFR-mutant adenocarcinoma, the EGFR mutation was identical in all the transformed SCLC tissue (
 <xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>). The SCLC-transformation cases described in our series may be isolated examples of a general phenomenon of resistance to ICIs due to a loss of mutations associated with neoantigens or other tumor cell-dependent elements of the immune response. From the clinical trials performed so far, the efficacy of ICIs may be lower in SCLC than in NSCLC, which is possibly supportive of transformation to SCLC as a mechanism of escape from immunotherapy (
 <xref rid="B21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>). Furthermore, pathology and immunohistochemistry are the gold standard for SCLC diagnosis. Next-generation sequencing (NGS) is a technology used by many laboratories to test for inherited disorders and tumor mutations. However, given that the rate of gene mutation in SCLC is relatively low, we did not consider NGS as an option for our patients. Nonetheless, in the best-case scenario, NGS and molecular fingerprinting would be the next best step and would help in determining the origin of SCLC and may also help elucidate the mechanism of resistance.
</p>
