<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>To reduce patients flow to the hospital and prevent human infections, AATD home therapy was activated for 16 patients using a specific patient support program, a home care project, already activated independently throughout Italy. The program allows patients to infuse intravenous augmentation therapy at home by qualified nurses in continuous contact with the referring physician. Fourteen patients in treatment for over one year and two patients with recent treatment initiation were placed in patient support program. The procedures involved in administering home-based intravenous therapy with AATD were the same as in the hospital. An experienced nurse wearing adequate personal protective equipment measured the vital signs, then proceeded to prepare the therapy to be administered. The therapy was administered intravenously according to the schedule. The operator remained at the patient's home throughout the administration. In the end, the vital parameters were checked again and, finally, the venous access removed. The Saint George Respiratory Questionnaire (SGRQ) was not used in all its length. We used a modified Quality of Life (QoL) score for our questionnaire, consisting of six questions (
 <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>), to analyze the general state of health, subjective symptoms of the patient and impact of therapy on the patient's and family life. To date, no validated questionnaires are available to assess QoL in patients with AATD. All the individual values were defined based on a 5-point scale: 1) many times a day/very much; 2) every day/much; 3) two or three times a week/not much; 4) once a week/few times; and 5) rarely or never/not at all. There was also a blank space where the patient could leave a comment about their experience of home therapy. The QoL score was calculated as the sum of the points obtained from questions. The minimum possible score was 6, the maximum 30. We compared QoL score for each patient at time zero (during the last hospital administration session) and after 3 months of home therapy.
</p>
