<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Measurements of FMD, NMD, cIMT, and pulse-wave analysis were performed in the morning between 7:00 a.m. and 9:00 a.m. after overnight fasting in a temperature-controlled (22–24°C) and quiet room by one trained technician. At the beginning of the FMD measurement, a blood pressure cuff was placed on the right forearm below the antecubital fossa and the baseline diameter of the right brachial artery was examined in a longitudinal plane between 2 and 7 centimeters proximal to the antecubital fossa in the patient. Three end-diastolic diameters between two intimal layers were measured ECG-gated during image acquisition in a one-centimeter-long segment of the brachial artery. Subsequently, the cuff was inflated &gt;50 mmHg above the resting systolic pressure for 5 min, then deflated and 60 s after cuff release, the post-ischemic diameter of the brachial artery was measured. During a rest of 15 min, pulse-wave analysis including measurement of the aortic PWV and augmentation index was performed on the left arm and calculated 
 <italic>via</italic> the oscillometric device Mobil-O-Graph® (I.E.M. Mobil-O-Graph, I.E.M., Cockerillstr., Stolberg, Germany) by an automated analysis. A size-adjusted cuff was placed on the patient's left upper arm about 2-4 centimeters above the antecubital fossa in supine position and subsequent pulse-wave analysis was performed, while the patient did not to speak or move over the whole pulse-wave analysis. Also, during the same rest of 15 min, the patient underwent measurement of the cIMT of both common carotid artery in supine position using a high-resolution linear array probe with 8–13 MHz (Siemens ACUSON S2000™, Siemens Healthcare Corp., Henkelstr., Erlangen, Germany). The thickness of the intimal and medial layers of the common carotid wall was measured on frozen longitudinal images in at least one-centimeter-long segment of the artery. After that rest of 15 min, the diameter of the right brachial artery was recorded similar to the technique described for FMD before and 5 min after sublingual administration of 0.4 mg glyceryl trinitrate spray. FMD and NMD measurements were performed with an 8–13 MHz linear array transducer using a conventional ultrasound scanner (Siemens ACUSON S2000™, Siemens Healthcare Corp., Henkelstr., Erlangen, Germany). Most recommendations for the measurement of FMD and NMD were fulfilled according to recent guidelines (
 <xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>). The measurements revealed a reduced FMD of 0.0% and a reduced NMD of 15.5% according to proposed reference values (
 <xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>). Pulse-wave analysis revealed a PWV of 5.9 m/s and an augmentation index of 27% while ultrasonography revealed a cIMT of 0.4 mm of both common carotid arteries.
</p>
