<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A 71-year-old man presented with productive cough. A CT scan confirmed the presence of an irregular mass in the left upper lobe. Positron emission tomography confirmed the presence of mediastinal lymph nodes. Serum CEA and NSE levels were normal. Fiberoptic bronchoscopy revealed a neoplasm at the opening of the upper branch of the left bronchus. A diagnosis of stage IIIa squamous cell carcinoma of the lung (cT1cN2M0) was made in December 2018 based on bronchoscopy-guided biopsy results (P63 positive). Two cycles of neoadjuvant chemotherapy with cisplatin-gemcitabine were administered. A CT scan performed in January 2019 showed that the mass in the left upper lobe had reduced significantly. Therefore, the patient underwent radical surgery of the left upper lung. Pathological biopsy of the surgical specimen revealed medium-poorly differentiated squamous cell carcinoma with par-bronchogenic lymph node metastases (pT1cN1M0, IIb); the tumor was P63-positive and Syn-negative. Postoperatively, the patient received four cycles of adjuvant chemotherapy with cisplatin-gemcitabine until May 2019. Five months after adjuvant chemotherapy, the patient developed tumor recurrence in the left lung with left pleural metastases. A combination of PD-1 inhibitors and docetaxel was prescribed based on the PD-L1 TPS expression of 1% (22C3 test). However, he refused docetaxel therapy. After two additional months of nivolumab monotherapy (four cycles), the CT scan showed tumor progression and metastases in the left lung and left pleura, compared to the CT findings of October 2019. Further, NSE levels were high (92.3 ng/ml). A CT-guided biopsy of the left pleural mass revealed that the tumor cells were positive for Syn and negative for P63; these findings were consistent with SCLC. From December 2019, he received two cycles of cisplatin and etoposide chemotherapy. The size of metastases in the left lung and left pleura decreased significantly, and the NSE levels decreased to 14.9 ng/ml. However, bone ECT showed metastases in the seventh, ninth, and twelfth thoracic vertebrae. The patient was thus diagnosed with disease progression. A combination of chemotherapy and internal radiotherapy with Strontium-89 was recommended to the patient, but he declined any further treatment. Finally, he died of the primary disease during the fourth month of follow-up (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
  <bold>Figure 2</bold>
 </xref>).
</p>
