<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract>
 <p>
  <bold>Background:</bold> In clinical practice, cardiac computed tomography (CCT) has a limited role in acute coronary syndromes (ACS). Several trials evaluated CCT in low and intermediate risk patients presenting to the emergency room (ER) and noted that it was both safe and feasible. During the COVID19 pandemic, it is imperative to adopt a pathway for the evaluation of ACS that permits early discharge, reduces invasive coronary angiography and limits exposure of healthcare workers. Here, we present a single center experience by which CCT was incorporated in the clinical pathway of patients presenting to the ER with chest pain and ACS.
 </p>
 <p>
  <bold>Methods:</bold> This is a snapshot study of the first 27 patients who underwent CCT immediately after the lockdown in the city of Jeddah. ST elevation myocardial infarctions and hemodynamically unstable patients were excluded. Those with unstable angina or a Non-ST elevation myocardial infarction were screened for COVID19. The patients' COVID19 status and the results of the CCT were then used to determine the treatment strategy. Patient predisposition, hospital stay and exposure of staff are collected and reported.
 </p>
 <p>
  <bold>Results:</bold> All CCT images were interpretable with no limitations or significant artifact. CCT identified critical disease in 7 patients (26%), normal epicardial coronary arteries in 11 (41%) and mild to moderate disease in 9 (33%). All patients with normal or mild to moderate disease were assigned to a conservative strategy and discharged within 24 h. Those with a NSTEMI and critical anatomy were assigned to an additional invasive evaluation with subsequent revascularization. During the course of this study, no transmission to healthcare workers occurred.
 </p>
 <p>
  <bold>Conclusion:</bold> CCT enabled 80% of patients to be discharged within the first 24 h, the majority of whom were discharged from the emergency room. It was able to identify critical anatomy facilitating appropriate revascularization. This snapshot study warrants exploration of the role of CCT in ACS further particularly since the latest European Society of Cardiology's Non-STEACS guidelines suggest a role for CCT in the evaluation of low risk ACS.
 </p>
</abstract>
