<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0015">Stargardt disease (STGD1) is the most common cause of macular degeneration in children and young adults. The condition originates in disease-causing sequence variants in the 
 <italic>ABCA4</italic> gene
 <xref rid="bib1" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>1</sup>
 </xref> and results in progressively severe impairment of sight. The 
 <italic>ABCA4</italic> gene encodes a rim protein located on the intracellular disc membranes of light-sensitive photoreceptor cells that play an essential role in the retinoid cycle.
 <xref rid="bib2" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>2</sup>
 </xref> Gene defects result in accelerated accumulation of a putative toxic metabolite, Di-retinoid-pyridinium-ethanolamine, within the underlying phagocytic retinal pigment epithelial (RPE) cells, leading to cell dysfunction and eventual cell death
 <xref rid="bib3" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>3</sup>
 </xref> with progressive atrophy expanding from the central macula.
 <xref rid="bib4" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>4</sup>
 </xref> Retinal pigment epithelial cells support the function and survival of overlying photoreceptor cells by multiple mechanisms, including recycling of visual pigment and phagocytosis of outer segments.
 <xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>5</sup>
 </xref> Degeneration of RPE cells leads to secondary dysfunction and degeneration of overlying photoreceptor cells, and consequently progressively severe impairment of sight. Stargardt disease currently is untreatable, but replenishment of degenerating RPE cells with healthy cells offers the possibility of benefit by better supporting the function and survival of overlying photoreceptor cells, and consequently improving or protecting sight for a period limited by the consequences of the underlying photoreceptor disorder. A similar approach may benefit atrophic age-related macular degeneration, which shares key features with STGD1, including progressive atrophy of RPE and overlying photoreceptor cells. However, differences in their cause and progression are likely to influence the potential benefit of subretinal administration of human embryonic stem cell (hESC)-derived RPE cell suspensions. For example, age-related changes in Bruch’s (basement) membrane and chronic inflammation in age-related macular degeneration may influence the adhesion and survival of donor cells.
</p>
