<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0020">In experimental models of retinal degeneration, subretinal injection of hESC-derived RPE cell suspensions can protect photoreceptor cells and retinal function.
 <xref rid="bib6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref> In human participants with STGD1, subretinal injection of up to 150 000 hESC-derived RPE cells resulted in no serious adverse events related to the transplanted cells.
 <xref rid="bib8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref> However, assessment of visual function has been limited. Herein we present the results of a dose-escalation trial of up to 200 000 hESC-derived RPE cells in 12 participants. To mitigate the risk of harm, we chose to investigate the safety of hESC-derived RPE transplantation in the poorer-seeing eye of individuals with advanced disease, acknowledging that any potential for benefit would be limited in this context by established degeneration of photoreceptor cells. Retinal degeneration in STGD1 typically advances progressively by expansion from the macula. We chose to administer cells to a target area, predefined for each study eye, extending from relatively well-preserved functional retina across a transitional zone of progressive degeneration to an area of atrophic nonfunctional retina. This afforded us the opportunity both to determine the safety of the transplanted cells in relatively healthy retina and to explore the potential benefit to function and survival of overlying photoreceptor cells in the degenerating and atrophic areas. By defining the target zone in the retina of each study eye before intervention, according to the distribution of disease severity and preferred locus of fixation, we were able to evaluate in detail the structure and function of this region before intervention using OCT, autofluorescence imaging, full-field perimetry, and microperimetry. For assessment of visual function, we established each participants’ test–retest variability for each test by means of multiple testing at baseline and controlled for the natural history of the condition, learning effects, and performance variability by comparison with the contralateral uninjected eye, on the basis that disease progression in an individual is symmetrical
 <xref rid="bib11" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>11</sup>
 </xref> and that monocular performance of the contralateral uninjected eye is not influenced by the intervention. We considered that for each participant, changes in performance of both eyes symmetrically would indicate disease progression, learning effects, or both and that differences between the eyes may indicate a consequence of the intervention.
</p>
