<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par114">Swallowing motion over the course of early glottic radiotherapy has been reported to be rare and unlikely to impact on dose delivery [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR50">50</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR53">53</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR55">55</xref>]. However, respiratory motion, laryngeal shift in relation to the vertebral structures over the course of RT, as well as the occasional occurrence of swallowing motion at the time of simulation could introduce substantial treatment delivery inaccuracies [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR50">50</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR57">57</xref>]. The safety of VC-RT may therefore be highly dependent on adequate precautions including the addition of an ITV margin accounting for breathing motion, use of volumetric IGRT with daily match on the larynx as well as verification of larynx resting position at time of planning CT scan acquisition. Following these principles, the group from Erasmus MC Cancer Institute reported excellent outcomes from VC-RT in a retrospective cohort 30 patients with T1a glottic cancer, with no local failures at 2 years [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>]. More recently, Sher et al. reported outcomes from a phase I dose-escalation trial (50 Gy in 15 escalated to 42.5 Gy in 5 fractions) of VC-RT for Tis-T2N0 of the glottis, using an ITV derived from a 4D-CT [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR65">65</xref>]. While the study reported acceptable early tolerability of the ultra-hypofractionated regimen with 7% rate of dose limiting grade 3–4 toxicity, as high as 17% of patients (5 of 29) developed a local recurrence. A closer look at these 5 recurrences reveals that 3 were among 7 patients with T2 tumors (leading to a 43% local recurrence rate in T2N0), 1 occurred in a patient with a T1b lesion that was inaccurately delineated and resulted in a marginal miss, and 1 was in a previously understaged tumor which, in retrospect, was a T4 lesion. While these results are somewhat reassuring in regard to the safety of VC-RT for T1N0 glottic larynx, these recurrences certainly highlight the importance of careful staging and accurate clinical assessment of tumor extension when considering VC-RT, and certainly question the safety of this approach for T2 tumors. Total laryngectomy frequently constituting the salvage treatment option in the context of local recurrence after irradiation, the consequences of treatment failures can have severe impacts on patients’ quality of life and survival. Taken together, these considerations justify the current equipoise as to whether VC-RT can lead to similar efficacy as CL-RT in early glottic cancer.
</p>
