<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par115">The current phase II multicenter Bayesian trial will accrue 155 patients with T1N0 glottic cancer, randomized to VC-RT versus CL-RT. The study is limited by the fact that it does not constitute a true randomized non-inferiority trial, but the feasibility of such a design is rendered impossible by the unrealistic necessary sample size of &gt; 2000 patients. Therefore, this trial would likely provide the best possible comparison between the 2 treatment arms. Local control at 2 years has been selected as the primary endpoint as the majority of local recurrences occur within the first 2 years after radiotherapy [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR66">66</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR67">67</xref>], however, LC will continue to be monitored in the context of this trial up to 5 years after radiotherapy. LC in the literature for T1N0 of the glottic larynx varies between 85 and 95% [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>].; this variation is at least partly dependent on the distribution of T1a versus T1b in the cohorts. With a target LC of 92% and a margin of 8%, any LC below 84% - therefore below the expected range- would be deemed unacceptable. In the context of this pragmatic trial, each center will use their own standard of care dose and fractionation regimen; as a general principle, radiotherapy will consist in mild hypofractionation regimen of 5 fractions per week, over 4 to 6 weeks. Institutions will not be allowed to change their dose/fractionation once accrual has started. As the study is stratified by participating institution, there will be a balanced number of patients with each dose/fractionation in each arm. In addition, as intensity modulated proton beam therapy is the standard of care for early glottic larynx cancer in some centers, the trial allows the use of proton beam therapy, as long as the same treatment technique is used in each arm.
</p>
