<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>At present, surgery is the main treatment option for early-stage lung cancer, as it can prolong survival and improve the quality of life of patients. In recent years, the progress in the pathophysiology of the perioperative period has shown that a variety of factors such as pain, response to stress, organ dysfunction, nausea, vomiting, intestinal obstruction, hypoxemia symptoms, and immobilization can lead to increased postoperative morbidity and prolongation of the hospital stay and recovery period.
 <xref rid="cit0001" ref-type="bibr">1</xref> One lung ventilation (OLV) is often required during thoracoscopic radical resection of lung cancer, eventually leading to an imbalance in the ventilation/blood flow and an increase in the intrapulmonary shunt rate. OLV over 2 h can cause acute lung injury.
 <xref rid="cit0002" ref-type="bibr">2</xref> Studies have shown that the intravenous use of lidocaine in outpatient surgery
 <xref rid="cit0003" ref-type="bibr">3</xref> and laparoscopic bariatric surgery
 <xref rid="cit0004" ref-type="bibr">4</xref> can significantly improve the quality of postoperative recovery and reduce the consumption of opioids in the perioperative period. Lidocaine is a common clinical amide local anesthetic, with a wide range of anti-inflammatory and analgesic effects. Animal experiments have shown that lidocaine can reduce the inflammatory response during surgery, increase lung compliance, and relax airway smooth muscle, thereby playing a role in lung protection.
 <xref rid="cit0005" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
 <xref rid="cit0006" ref-type="bibr">6</xref> However, the role of lidocaine in improving the quality of recovery and lung protection effects in patients undergoing thoracoscopic radical resection of lung cancer is still unclear. This study intends to explore the effect of intravenous use of lidocaine during thoracoscopic radical resection of lung cancer on the patients' postoperative quality recovery and lung protection.
</p>
