<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The 5-year event-free survival rate for patients with high-risk B-ALL enrolled in the COG AALL0232 trial (2004 – 2011) randomized to high-dose methotrexate during interim maintenance-1 was 79.6% compared to 75.2% for the patients in the control arm (Capizzi methotrexate) (
 <italic>P</italic>=0.008) of that study.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b3-1040986" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>
 </sup> Patients identified as having VHR B-ALL are predicted to fare worse than high-risk patients overall and, depending on the specific VHR risk factors, their 4-year DFS rates can range anywhere from 40 to 80%.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b8-1040986" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
  <xref rid="b13-1040986" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>–
  <xref rid="b22-1040986" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>
 </sup> Based on the relatively poor outcomes for these VHR patients, they are candidates for investigation of novel, more intensive, yet potentially more toxic, therapeutic strategies designed to improve DFS. Based on this hypothesis, and without mature data from the AALL0232 study available at the time of study development, the COG high-risk B-ALL study AALL1131 was designed to further intensify cytotoxic chemotherapy during the consolidation and delayed intensification phases of therapy to improve the DFS in the VHR subgroup. Two intensification strategies were tested in AALL1131 and compared to the control arm. The first intensification strategy included the combination of clofarabine with cyclophosphamide/etoposide, a promising combination in relapsed ALL
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b23-1040986" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,
  <xref rid="b24-1040986" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>
 </sup> (experimental arm 2) and cyclophosphamide/etoposide without clofarabine (experimental arm 1). This began as a 1:2:2 randomization between the control arm and experimental arms 1 and 2, respectively. Experimental arm 2, testing clofarabine, was found to be too toxic and not feasible when given in this combination to newly diagnosed patients with VHR B-ALL, and this arm of AALL1131 was, therefore, closed to further accrual in September 2014.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b7-1040986" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>
 </sup> AALL1131 thus continued as a two-arm study comparing the control arm with experimental arm 1 in a 1:2 randomized fashion. This randomization was later stopped for futility when the interim monitoring boundary was crossed, identifying non-superiority of DFS when consolidation and delayed intensification included cyclophosphamide/etoposide compared to standard VHR therapy (modified augmented Berlin-Frankfurt-Münster regimen). With additional follow-up after closure of the randomization, there was even stronger evidence that experimental arm 1 would never be superior to the control arm with the reported DFS being 85.5±6.8% for the control arm compared to 72.3±6.3% for experimental arm 1 (
 <italic>P</italic>=0.76). The 4-year DFS of 85.5±6.8% reported for the control arm of this study was higher than the 70% we originally predicted based on data available for patients with VHR features treated in the preceding B-ALL studies for standard-risk (AALL0331) and high-risk (AALL0232) patients. Many patients in these earlier studies did not receive high-dose methotrexate during interim maintenance-1 which may have resulted in the differences in the DFS rates we report. Additionally, the definitions of VHR were expanded in AALL1131 to include groups of patients at least 13 years of age as well as lower minimal residual disease thresholds which may also have contributed to differences in the DFS we observed.
</p>
