<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The outcome of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) appears to be influenced by the interaction among genetic, hormonal and environmental factors. In this context, low levels of circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D [25(OH)D], the biomarker of vitamin D status, represent a risk factor for COVID-19 and 1,25(OH)2 vitamin D(3) (the active metabolite of vitamin D) seems to play a protective role in this disease by controlling the cytokine storm, enhancing the production of antimicrobial peptides and maintaining the integrity of the epithelium (
 <xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">Pagano et al., 2020</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">Hutchings et al., 2021</xref>). Moreover, 1,25(OH)2 vitamin D(3), by increasing the expression of angiotensin-converting enzyme (ACE)2, the functional receptor for SARS-CoV-2, induces ACE2/Ang‐(1-7)/MasR axis activity and inhibits renin and the ACE/Ang II/AT1R axis. This process leads to the protection against acute lung injury/acute respiratory distress syndrome (
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">Xu et al., 2017</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">Gagliardi et al., 2020</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">Kumar et al., 2020</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">Malek Mahdavi, 2020</xref>). In the same vein, 17β-estradiol increases the expression of ACE2 also playing a protective role in COVID-19 (
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">Seeland et al., 2020</xref>). Although epidemiological data indicate that COVID-19 produces more severe symptoms and higher mortality in elderly in comparison to young patients and in men in comparison to women (
 <xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">Pagano et al., 2020</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">Chen et al., 2021</xref>), to date, sex, and age differences in vitamin D status in infected patients have not been evaluated yet. Hence aim of this study was to analyze the levels of circulating 25(OH)D in patients hospitalized for COVID-19 divided accordingly to their sex and age. We also correlated 25(OH)D levels with patient's respiratory status and with sex hormones plasma levels to analyze the potential relationship of these parameters.
</p>
