<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1">
 <media xlink:href="40880_2018_330_MOESM1_ESM.docx" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <caption>
   <p>
    <bold>Additional file 1: Table S1.</bold> Incidence of late toxicities in the combination group during follow up. 
    <bold>Table S2.</bold> Actual delivered treatments for all enrolled patients. 
    <bold>Table S3.</bold> Percentage changes from baseline of D-CEUS functional parameters stratified by progression after three years of follow up. 
    <bold>Figure S1.</bold> Biomarker expression in NPC tumour tissue and normal nasopharyngeal epithelial cells. 
    <bold>A</bold> VEGFR2; 
    <bold>B</bold> PDGFR; 
    <bold>C</bold> C-kit. VEGFR2, vascular endothelial growth factor receptor; PDGFR, platelet-derived growth factor receptor. 
    <bold>Figure S2.</bold> Serum VEGF (
    <bold>A</bold>), PDGF (
    <bold>B</bold>) and SCF (
    <bold>C</bold>) concentration at baseline, two weeks after taking famitinib, and 12 weeks post-treatment (by ELISA), respectively. VEGF, vascular endothelial growth factor; PDGF, platelet-derived growth factor; SCF, stem cell factor. 
    <bold>Figure S3.</bold>
    <bold>A</bold> and 
    <bold>B</bold> show the results of longitudinal monitoring of the change in plasma EBV DNA concentrations of 14 patients in continuous remission and 6 patients who exhibited relapse, respectively. 
    <bold>Figure S4.</bold> Progression-free survival (
    <bold>A</bold>) and distant metastasis-free survival (
    <bold>B</bold>) in patients with nasopharyngeal cancer treated with intensity-modulated radiotherapy, chemotherapy, and famitinib. Kaplan-Meier survival distributions according to the percentage variation in functional parameters (PI, AUC, PW, and PIWI) at day 8 for famitinib treatment alone. The curves show an association between an early decrease in functional parameters of PI, AUC, PW, and PIWI (after seven days of treatment, D8) and the disease progression. Patients were divided into two groups: those with a percentage decrease in PI (
    <bold>C</bold>), AUC (
    <bold>D</bold>), PW (
    <bold>E</bold>), and PIWI (
    <bold>F</bold>) greater than or equal to 30% (blue curve) and those with an increase or a percentage decrease lower than 30% (green curve). PI, peak intensity; AUC, area under the time-intensity curve; PW, slope coefficient of wash-in; WIPI, wash-in perfusion index.
   </p>
  </caption>
 </media>
</supplementary-material>
