<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par67">
 <list list-type="order">
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par68">Male or female, 
    <underline>&gt;</underline> 18 years of age.
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par69">Patients with histologically proven ER-positive, HER2-negative advanced breast cancer receiving an AI in combination with a CDK 4/6 inhibitor. Biopsy of metastatic disease if technically feasible but not mandatory.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par70">Patients must have evidence of extracranial metastatic disease with or without intracranial metastases.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par71">Radiological evidence of stable or responding disease to an AI in combination with a CDK 4/6 inhibitor for a period of at least 6 months prior to study entry. (Patient must have ongoing stability/response in at least one lesion at the time of registration).</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par72">Evidence of new or existing OPD in 1–5 lesions. With reference to RECIST 1.1 [
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>] and or PERCIST 1.0 [
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>], OPD is defined as follow: 
    <list list-type="alpha-lower">
     <list-item>
      <p id="Par73">Using CT for intracranial or extracranial OPD: 
       <list list-type="simple">
        <list-item>
         <label>i.</label>
         <p id="Par74">&gt; 5 mm increase in the diameter of an existing lesion OR</p>
        </list-item>
        <list-item>
         <label>ii.</label>
         <p id="Par75">&gt; 20% increase in the diameter of an existing lesion on 2 consecutive imaging studies at least 2 months apart OR</p>
        </list-item>
        <list-item>
         <label>iii.</label>
         <p id="Par76">The appearance of one or more new soft tissue lesions, measuring &gt; 5 mm.</p>
        </list-item>
       </list>
      </p>
     </list-item>
     <list-item>
      <p id="Par77">Using Positron Emission Tomography for extracranial OPD: 
       <list list-type="simple">
        <list-item>
         <label>i.</label>
         <p id="Par78">&gt; 30% increase in 18F-FDG SUV peak, with &gt; 0.8 SUV units increase in tumour SUV from the baseline scan in pattern typical of tumour and not of infection/treatment effect OR</p>
        </list-item>
        <list-item>
         <label>ii.</label>
         <p id="Par79">New 18F-FDG avid lesions typical of cancer (including new bone lesion) and unrelated to treatment effect and/or infection.</p>
        </list-item>
       </list>
      </p>
     </list-item>
    </list>
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par80">For patients with liver or lung metastases, maximum of 3 oligoprogressive lesions in single organ.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par81">All OPD must be amenable to SRT. 
    <list list-type="alpha-lower">
     <list-item>
      <p id="Par82">Patients with risk of bone fracture are not candidate for SRT</p>
     </list-item>
    </list>
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par83">For patients with intracranial metastases, SRT is the preferred treatment option, however, if clinical assessment indicated that upfront surgery is better, then post-operative SRT to the surgical cavity is recommended.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par84">ECOG performance status 0–2.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par85">Life expectancy ≥6 months.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par86">Provision of written informed consent.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par87">Clinician and participant are willing to continue current line of therapy.</p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
