<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par40">Wavelengths within the far-red to the near-infrared range (630–1000 nm) along with a minimal energy density of 4 J/cm
 <sup>2</sup> are the optimal therapeutic intervention [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>]. Stimulating biological processes proved to be effective with these wavelengths and energy density. It is believed that they act by four main actions:
 <list list-type="order">
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par41">Stimulating mitochondria to increase adenosine triphosphate (ATP) production [
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>, 
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>] through increased cytochrome c oxidase (CCO) effect. CCO acts by absorbing light photon and avoiding nitric oxide (NO) inhibitory effect on itself. Thus, there is an increase in mitochondrial membrane potential, providing more oxygen consumption, as soon as more glucose is metabolized, and more ATP is produced [
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par42">Inhibition of microglial activation and also acting as a strong antioxidant promoting an anti-inflammatory effect (increase in mitochondrial superoxide dismutase) [
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>, 
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par43">Increasing regional cerebral blood flow [
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>, 
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par44">Changing protein expression through signaling mediators and activation of transcription factors. These changes last for some considerable time and explain the long-lasting effect [
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par45">Promoting 
    <italic>neurogenesis</italic> and 
    <italic>synaptogenesis</italic>. However, this was only seen in studies with small animals treated with NIR in the acute stage post-TBI [
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>, 
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>, 
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>].
   </p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
