<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>More recently, Chambers et al. 
 <xref rid="sct312264-bib-0018" ref-type="ref">18</xref> reported results of a phase I trial in which bone marrow‐derived MSCs from 5 donors were infused into 10 patients with either BOS grade 1 and added risk factors or BOS grade 2 or 3 showing rapid decline in FEV
 <sub>1</sub> despite medical therapy. Their protocol infused 2 million MSCs per kg twice a week for 2 weeks for a total of 8 million MSCs per kg. They reported only minor and transient fall in mean arterial pressure and O
 <sub>2</sub> saturation during infusion of MSCs, with rapid recovery and no other clinically significant adverse events. Two of their patients died from progressive BOS at 152 and 270 days after the final infusion of MSCs, but the investigators did not believe these deaths were related to MSC infusion. They observed a reduction in the rate of decline in FEV
 <sub>1</sub> following MSC infusion, concluding that infusion of MSCs was feasible and safe in patients with advanced CLAD 
 <xref rid="sct312264-bib-0018" ref-type="ref">18</xref>. Our study also used bone marrow‐derived MSCs with the primary purpose to improve lung function, or at least arrest the rate of decline in lung function, in patients with progressive BOS refractory to medical therapy. Our group was less diverse than those in the study from Chambers et al., as only patients with moderate BOS (grade 2) were included and our patients received only a single infusion of MSCs from a single, healthy donor. Our patients were of advanced age, likely from excluding younger patients who could qualify for retransplant, and they were long‐term survivors after transplant, who had developed moderate BOS a median of 5 years after transplant (range, 1.4–9 years). Our study shows that it is feasible to manufacture bone marrow‐derived MSCs, cryopreserve them, and transport them long distances for clinical administration, and these cells remain viable and sterile prior to infusion. Our study indicates that the intravenous infusion of bone marrow‐derived MSCs is safe, well tolerated, and produces no alteration in vital signs, gas exchange, pulmonary function test variables, or changes in routine blood work values. The long‐term effects in lung function and gas exchange resulting from this cell therapy intervention are reported elsewhere 
 <xref rid="sct312264-bib-0019" ref-type="ref">19</xref>.
</p>
