<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="other"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Publishing DTD v1.1 20151215//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName JATS-journalpublishing1.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 1.1?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName jp2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">BMJ Open</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">BMJ Open</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="hwp">bmjopen</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">bmjopen</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>BMJ Open</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2044-6055</issn><publisher><publisher-name>BMJ Publishing Group</publisher-name><publisher-loc>BMA House, Tavistock Square, London, WC1H 9JR</publisher-loc></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">7845673</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">bmjopen-2020-044190</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2020-044190</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Surgery</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="hwp-journal-coll"><subject>1506</subject><subject>1737</subject></subj-group><series-title>Protocol</series-title></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Postneoadjuvant surveillance and surgery as needed compared with postneoadjuvant surgery on principle in multimodal treatment for oesophageal cancer: a scoping review protocol</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib id="author-20406157" contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">http://orcid.org/0000-0002-1188-3158</contrib-id><name><surname>Schmucker</surname><given-names>Christine</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib id="author-81738647" contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Nagavci</surname><given-names>Blin</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib id="author-81738707" contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">http://orcid.org/0000-0001-9291-9695</contrib-id><name><surname>Hipp</surname><given-names>Julian</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib id="author-50422473" contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">http://orcid.org/0000-0001-5610-9425</contrib-id><name><surname>Schmoor</surname><given-names>Claudia</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib id="author-81738759" contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Meerpohl</surname><given-names>Joerg</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff4">4</xref></contrib><contrib id="author-58158435" contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">http://orcid.org/0000-0002-3485-7446</contrib-id><name><surname>Hoeppner</surname><given-names>Jens</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">2</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff5">5</xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff1"><label>1</label><institution content-type="department">Institute for Evidence in Medicine (for Cochrane Germany Foundation)</institution>, <institution>Medical Center - University of Freiburg, Faculty of Medicine, University of Freiburg</institution>, <addr-line content-type="city">Freiburg</addr-line>, <addr-line content-type="state">Baden-W&#x000fc;rttemberg</addr-line>, <country>Germany</country></aff><aff id="aff2"><label>2</label><institution content-type="department">Center for Surgery, Department of General and Visceral Surgery</institution>, <institution>Medical Center - University of Freiburg, Faculty of Medicine, University of Freiburg</institution>, <addr-line content-type="city">Freiburg</addr-line>, <addr-line content-type="state">Baden-W&#x000fc;rttemberg</addr-line>, <country>Germany</country></aff><aff id="aff3"><label>3</label><institution content-type="department">Clinical Trials Unit</institution>, <institution>Medical Center - University of Freiburg, Faculty of Medicine, University of Freiburg</institution>, <addr-line content-type="city">Freiburg im Breisgau</addr-line>, <addr-line content-type="state">Baden-W&#x000fc;rttemberg</addr-line>, <country>Germany</country></aff><aff id="aff4"><label>4</label><institution content-type="department">Cochrane Germany</institution>, <institution>Cochrane Germany Foundation</institution>, <addr-line content-type="city">Freiburg</addr-line>, <country>Germany</country></aff><aff id="aff5"><label>5</label><institution content-type="department">Department of Surgery</institution>, <institution>University Medical Center Schleswig-Holstein, Campus Luebeck</institution>, <addr-line content-type="city">Luebeck</addr-line>, <country>Germany</country></aff><author-notes><corresp><label>Correspondence to</label> Prof Dr Jens Hoeppner; <email>jens.hoeppner@uksh.de</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2021</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>28</day><month>1</month><year>2021</year></pub-date><volume>11</volume><issue>1</issue><elocation-id>e044190</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>28</day><month>8</month><year>2020</year></date><date date-type="rev-recd"><day>21</day><month>12</month><year>2020</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>08</day><month>1</month><year>2021</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; Author(s) (or their employer(s)) 2021. Re-use permitted under CC BY-NC. No commercial re-use. See rights and permissions. Published by BMJ.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2021</copyright-year><license license-type="open-access" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/"><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" start_date="2021-01-27">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open access article distributed in accordance with the Creative Commons Attribution Non Commercial (CC BY-NC 4.0) license, which permits others to distribute, remix, adapt, build upon this work non-commercially, and license their derivative works on different terms, provided the original work is properly cited, appropriate credit is given, any changes made indicated, and the use is non-commercial. See:&#x000a0;<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xlink:title="pdf" xlink:href="bmjopen-2020-044190.pdf"/><self-uri content-type="reviewers-comments-pdf" xlink:href="bmjopen-2020-044190.reviewer_comments.pdf"/><self-uri content-type="draft-revisions-pdf" xlink:href="bmjopen-2020-044190.draft_revisions.pdf"/><abstract><sec><title>Introduction</title><p>In current medical practice of curative treatment for non-metastatic oesophageal cancer, surgery on principle is carried out by oesophagectomy after neoadjuvant treatment. However, oesophagectomy is often associated with postoperative morbidity and mortality. Taking into account that modern neoadjuvant therapy is effective and many of patients show no vital tumour cells in the operative specimens, we aim to perform a scoping review as part of the development phase for a prospectively planned multicentre randomised controlled trial investigating &#x02018;surgery as needed vs surgery on principle in patients with postneoadjuvant complete response of oesophageal cancer&#x02019; (Prospective trial registration number DRKS00022801). This scoping approach will allow us to finally define and/or adapt the research question including the design and methodology of the randomised controlled trial taking into account the findings for example, research gaps and/or pitfalls in the currently available study pool addressing this or very similar questions.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods and analysis</title><p>To identify relevant research, we will conduct searches in the electronic databases Medline, Web of Science Core Collection, Cochrane Library and Science Direct. We will also check references of relevant studies and perform a cited reference research (forward citation tracking). Titles and abstracts of the records identified by the searches will be screened and full texts of all potentially relevant articles will be obtained. We will consider randomised trials and non-randomised controlled studies. Data extraction tables will be set up, including study and patients&#x02019; characteristics, aim of study and reported outcomes. We will summarise the data using tables and figures (eg, bubble plots) to present the research landscape and to describe potential clusters and/or gaps to support the planning of a randomised trial in this patient population.</p></sec><sec><title>Ethics and dissemination</title><p>Ethical approval is not required for this scoping review. Study findings will be shared by publication in a peer-reviewed journal and by presentation to key stakeholders on scientific meetings.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group><kwd>oesophageal disease</kwd><kwd>radiation oncology</kwd><kwd>gastrointestinal tumours</kwd><kwd>thoracic surgery</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group id="funding-1"><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="FundRef">http://dx.doi.org/10.13039/501100002347</institution-id><institution>Bundesministerium f&#x000fc;r Bildung und Forschung</institution></institution-wrap></funding-source><award-id>01KD1908</award-id></award-group><award-group id="funding-2"><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution>Baden-Wuerttemberg Ministry of Science, Research and Art</institution></institution-wrap></funding-source><award-id>Funding programme Open Access (w/o spec. number)</award-id></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>special-feature</meta-name><meta-value>unlocked</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><boxed-text id="BX1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><title>Strengths and limitations of this study</title></caption><list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p>The scoping review is part of the development phase for a prospectively planned multicentre randomised trial, addressing &#x02018;Surgery as needed versus surgery on principle in patients with post-neoadjuvant complete response of oesophageal cancer&#x02019; (Prospective trial registration number DRKS00022801).</p></list-item><list-item><p>The scoping review will allow us to finally define and/or adapt the research question, the design and methodology of the following randomised trial.</p></list-item><list-item><p>The scoping review protocol is guided by validated methodological frameworks and the scoping review will be reported according to the preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis statement for scoping reviews, and therefore, will be conducted in line with &#x02018;the state-of-the-art&#x02019; criteria.</p></list-item><list-item><p>We will conduct comprehensive literature searches and map the current ongoing and published studies by extracting and cluster key data such as neoadjuvant treatment protocols, diagnostic methods of response evaluation and surveillance, and therapeutic outcomes.</p></list-item><list-item><p>The final scoping review will be limited to English and German language studies.</p></list-item></list></boxed-text><sec sec-type="intro" id="s1"><title>Introduction</title><p>Neoadjuvant chemoradiation (nCRT) and neoadjuvant chemotherapy (nCTX) improve patients&#x02019; survival in curative treatment of non-metastatic oesophageal cancer and have become the standard of care in Western Europe.<xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref> In these multimodal oncological protocols, curative surgery is carried out after neoadjuvant treatment by oesophagectomy. However, oesophagectomy implicates postoperative mortality rates between 6% and 11% and postoperative morbidity rates range from 60% to 80%.<xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2&#x02013;4</xref> In recent years, neoadjuvant therapy has become increasingly effective, with 16%&#x02013;49% of patients showing no tumour cells in the operative specimens.<xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5&#x02013;7</xref> This high locoregional histopathological complete response rate imposes a need to identify complete responder and avoid potentially unnecessary and harmful surgery in this population. Considering that neoadjuvant treatment without surgery is effective for a large proportion of patients, more individual/personalised treatment options based on surveillance and surgery only if needed are highly relevant for patients with non-metastatic oesophageal cancer.</p></sec><sec id="s2"><title>Objectives</title><p>We aim to perform a scoping review as part of the development phase for a prospectively planned multicentre randomised controlled trial, addressing &#x02018;Surgery as needed vs surgery on principle in patients with post-neoadjuvant complete response of oesophageal cancer&#x02019; (Prospective registration identifier of the clinical trial will be DRKS00022801. Registration is currently in process and will be completed after we have incoperated the results of the scoping review). The scoping review will allow us to finally define and adapt the research question and methodology of the following randomised trial taking into account the findings (such as research gaps and/or methodological pitfalls) in the currently available pool of primary studies addressing this or very similar questions.</p><p>The objectives of the scoping review are as follows:</p><list list-type="order"><list-item><p>What specific neoadjuvant protocols of nCRT and nCTX have been studied for surveillance and surgery as needed?</p></list-item><list-item><p>In what populations or settings have these protocols been studied?</p></list-item><list-item><p>Which diagnostic methods have been used for postneoadjuvant tumour staging and surveillance of tumour response?</p></list-item><list-item><p>Which outcomes have been addressed in the clinical studies on surveillance and surgery as needed in oesophageal cancer?</p></list-item><list-item><p>What results were observed with respect to survival rates?</p></list-item></list></sec><sec sec-type="methods" id="s3"><title>Methods and analysis</title><p>This protocol is written with reference to the preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols statement<xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref> and &#x02018;a priori&#x02019; defines the methodology on which the scoping review will be based on:</p><sec id="s3-1"><title>Eligibility criteria</title><sec id="s3-1-1"><title>Participants/population</title><p>We will focus on studies including adults with non-metastatic oesophageal cancer (after receiving neoadjuvant treatment). Studies including patients with distant metastases of oesophageal cancer, presence of gastric cancer; and/or participants younger than 18 years of age will be excluded.</p></sec><sec id="s3-1-2"><title>Intervention and comparator treatment</title><p>We will consider surveillance after neoadjuvant therapy as eligible intervention. Surgery on principle after neoadjuvant therapy will be the comparator treatment.</p></sec><sec id="s3-1-3"><title>Context</title><p>We will consider all nCTX and nCRT interventions implemented and evaluated in the context of non-metastatic oesophageal cancer.</p></sec><sec id="s3-1-4"><title>Relevant outcomes</title><p>We will capture any outcomes reported in the eligible study pool. Highly important outcomes are displayed in <xref ref-type="boxed-text" rid="B1">box 1</xref>. This table is non-exhaustive and will be completed depending on the outcomes reported in the identified study pool.</p><boxed-text id="B1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Box 1</label><caption><title>Outcome variables.</title></caption><p>Outcomes (list will be completed depending on outcomes reported in the available study pool)</p><list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p>Overall survival.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Progression-free survival.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Proportion of radical resection margin.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Postoperative complications. (frequency and severity).</p></list-item><list-item><p>Rate and timing of distant dissemination.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Disease recurrence rate.</p></list-item></list></boxed-text></sec><sec id="s3-1-5"><title>Study types</title><p>Randomised controlled trials; non-randomised controlled studies (using strategies of non-random allocation for assigning interventions) and observational studies (with control group) will be eligible for the scoping review. We will not consider single arm studies. Due to a missing control group within this study design. The reason for this exclusion is that studies without a control group provide no reliable data to estimate comparative effectiveness and will, therefore, not be useful for the planned randomised trial. Furthermore, review articles, clinical guidelines and work that has not been peer-reviewed (eg, thesis, editorials, letters, comments) will be excluded.</p><p>We will not apply any exclusion criteria regarding study duration and/or the study setting.</p></sec></sec><sec id="s3-2"><title>Information sources</title><p>The searches for this scoping review will be performed and conducted by following the recommendation of PRESS (Peer Review of Electronic Search Strategies)<xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>; that is, a medical sciences librarian will develop the search strategies; in addition, search strategies will be validated by checking whether they identified studies already known. We will not use any date restrictions in the electronic searches. For each database, the date of the search, the search strategy and the number of search results will be documented.</p><p>Systematic searches for relevant published trials will be conducted in the following electronic data sources</p><list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p>Medline, Medline Daily Update, Medline In Process &#x00026; Other Non-Indexed Citations, Medline Epub Ahead of Print (via Ovid) (a preliminary search strategy is displayed in <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">table 1</xref>).</p></list-item><list-item><p>Web of Science Core Collection: Science Citation Index-EXPANDED (SCI-EXPANDED) (via Clarivate Analytics).</p></list-item><list-item><p>Cochrane Library (via Wiley).</p></list-item><list-item><p>Science Direct (via Elsevier).</p></list-item></list><table-wrap id="T1" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Preliminary search strategy for Medline (Ovid).</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>#</bold></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Searches</bold></td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">((esophag* or oesophag*) adj5 (cancer* or neoplas* or carcino* or tumor* or tumour* or malign* or adenocarcin* or adeno-carcin*)).ti, ab, kf.</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">esophageal neoplasms/ or esophageal squamous cell carcinoma/</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1 or 2</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">(chemoradi* or radiochemo* or chemo-radi* or radio-chemo* or chemotherap* or Radiation or radiotherap*).ti, ab, kf.</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">exp Chemoradiotherapy/ or (Chemotherapy, Adjuvant/ and Radiotherapy, Adjuvant/)</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4 or 5</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">(((watch* or see) adj3 wait*) or (active* adj3 surveil*) or ((selective* or needed or necessar* or unnecessar* or declin* or avoid* or on-demand) adj6 (resect* or surg* or esophagectom* or oesophagectom*)) or (chemoradiation alone or chemoradiation only or chemo-radiation alone or chemo-radiation only)).ti, ab, kf.</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Watchful Waiting/</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7 or 8</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">(surg* or standard treatment or standard therapy or standard surgical resection or tri-modal* or trimodal* or esophagectom* or oesophagectom*).ti, ab, kf.</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">11</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">exp Esophagectomy/</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10 or 11</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">13</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 and 6 and 9 and 12</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">14</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">exp animals/ not exp humans/</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">15</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">editorial/ or letter/ or Congress/</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">16</td><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">13 not 14</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">17</td><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">16 not 15</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">18</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">limit 17 to (english or german)</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">19</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">randomized controlled trial.pt.</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">controlled clinical trial.pt.</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">21</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">randomized.ab.</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">22</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">placebo.ab.</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">23</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">drug therapy.fs.</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">randomly.ab.</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">25</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">trial.ab.</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">26</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">groups.ab.</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">27</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">19 or 20 or 21 or 22 or 23 or 24 or 25 or 26</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">28</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 and 9 and 27</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">29</td><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">28 not 14</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">30</td><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">28 not 15</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">31</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">limit 30 to (english or german)</td></tr><tr><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">32</td><td align="char" char="." valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">18 or 31</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>Searches for unpublished and ongoing studies will be performed in ClinicalTrials.gov (<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="www.clinicaltrials.gov">www.clinicaltrials.gov</ext-link>), WHO International Clinical Trials Registry Platform (<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.who.int/ictrp/search/en">http://www.who.int/ictrp/search/en</ext-link>) and the German study register (<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="www.drks.de">www.drks.de</ext-link>).</p><p>We will use relevant studies and/or systematic reviews to search for additional references via the PubMed similar articles function (<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.nlm.nih.gov/bsd/disted/pubmedtutorial/020_190.html">https://www.nlm.nih.gov/bsd/disted/pubmedtutorial/020_190.html</ext-link>), and forward citation tracking. Reference lists of relevant studies and systematic reviews will also be reviewed manually.</p></sec><sec id="s3-3"><title>Identification of relevant Studies</title><p>Titles and abstracts of the records identified by the searches will be screened and full texts of all potentially relevant articles will be obtained. Full texts will be checked for eligibility, by two reviewers and reasons for exclusions will be documented (full-text screening). The complete screening process will be conducted in Covidence (<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.covidence.org">https://www.covidence.org</ext-link>).</p></sec><sec id="s3-4"><title>Extraction of study data/data items</title><p>The following study data will be extracted and relevant information tabulated and/or described descriptively:</p><list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p>Study characteristics, that is, author, year of publication, study type (randomised trial, non-randomised study) and design (superiority, non-inferiority trial), study status (eg, planned, ongoing, completed, prematurely discontinued), start and end of study.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Details regarding sample size calculation.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Details on sample size (number of participants screened and randomised/finally included; reasons for screening failures and number and reasons for drop-offs and compliance).</p></list-item><list-item><p>Aim of the study.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Setting, that is, geographical and organisational setting.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Characteristics and definition of participants (age, gender, tumour histology and tumour stage).</p></list-item><list-item><p>Details on neoadjuvant therapy (drug names, dose).</p></list-item><list-item><p>Details on the diagnostic methods used for post-neoadjuvant tumour staging and surveillance of tumour response.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Definition of complete responders.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Characteristics of intervention/surveillance group (definition of surveillance).</p></list-item><list-item><p>Characteristics of comparator/surgery group (type of surgery and time between neoadjuvant therapy and surgery).</p></list-item><list-item><p>Pathohistological complete response rate after neoadjuvant therapy (surgery group).</p></list-item><list-item><p>On-demand surgery rate (surveillance group).</p></list-item><list-item><p>All reported outcomes and their exact definitions, that is, how and when the outcome measures were assessed.</p></list-item><list-item><p>Recruitment and follow-up time (planned and actual time).</p></list-item></list><p>Data from each included study will be extracted by one reviewer and checked by a second. Disagreements will be resolved through discussion until consensus will be reached.</p></sec><sec id="s3-5"><title>Risk of bias</title><p>Risk of bias assessment is not part of a scoping review and will not be assessed accordingly.<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10 11</xref></p><p>The methodology of the scoping review may be adapted minimally during the review process itself in terms of eligibility criteria, data extraction and outcome variables.<xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12 13</xref></p></sec><sec id="s3-6"><title>Data analyses/summary</title><p>We will summarise the collected study data using tables and figures (eg, bubble plots) to present the research landscape and to describe potential clusters and/or gaps to support the planning of the proposed randomised trial in this patient population.</p></sec><sec id="s3-7"><title>Perspective/discussion</title><p>Currently in Western Europe the majority of patients with non-metastatic resectable oesophageal cancer are treated with nCTX or nCRT plus consecutive surgery. Despite postneoadjuvant pathological complete response rates between 16% and 49%, surgery is carried out in all patients and independent of the results of post-neoadjuvant response evaluation.<xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5&#x02013;7</xref> The &#x02018;Nationale Dekade gegen Krebs&#x02019; programme of the german national government (<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.dekade-gegen-krebs.de/de/praxisveraendernde-studien-fuer-eine-bessere-patientenversorgung-2018.html">https://www.dekade-gegen-krebs.de/de/praxisveraendernde-studien-fuer-eine-bessere-patientenversorgung-2018.html</ext-link>) is supporting a multicentre randomised trial (which will be conducted by our study group) challenging this &#x02018;sometimes potentially harmful&#x02019; algorithm by comparing postneoadjuvant surgery on principle versus surveillance (with surgery only if needed in the event of a persisting or recurring local tumour). Using a randomised study design, we aim to optimise therapeutic outcomes by personalisation of the therapeutic sequence. According to the current evidence and also supported by our clinical experience, it is likely that a subgroup of pathological complete responders (with consecutive omission of potentially harmful surgery) will be identified.<xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref> A survival disadvantage of delayed surgery in case of local tumour relapse is likely to be excluded in a protocol of close surveillance in complete responder.<xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></p><p>Although the scoping review may not provide effect estimates including an evaluation of the certainty of evidence, it will be of great value to crystallise research questions, and the extent of available evidence by highlighting areas where evidence is lacking. The scoping review will support us to map the existing primary research for potential duplications. Furthermore, it will provide an overview of the (1) characteristics and definitions of patient populations (included in available studies) and settings, (2) details on the interventions (including type of neoadjuvant therapy, time between neoadjuvant therapy and surgery, definition of surveillance), (3) details on the diagnostic methods used for postneoadjuvant tumour staging, (4) definition of complete responders, (5) outcome measures and (6) follow-up times. Hence the scoping process will allow us to systematically develop the concept of the randomised trial based on current knowledge (including pitfalls) in this newly emerging treatment area.</p><p>By searching the searching the literature in different databases (ie, behind Medline) and also study registers (eg, ClinicalTrials.gov), all relevant completed but also ongoing studies comparing surveillance with surgery on demand in esophaegeal cancer will be identified. Finally the results of the scoping review will reveal (1) whether the diagnostic methods used and the definition for complete responders were appropriate and homogeneous, (2) whether the included sample sizes were sufficient to draw conclusions on benefits and harms, (3) what interventions were considered (eg, nCRT and/or chemotherapeutic protocols), (4) what outcomes of interest were covered, (5) whether follow-up times were sufficient and (6) whether clinical results across studies are homogeneous. We believe that the planned randomised trial will benefit from this state-of-the art research approach, and therefore, will provide patients, clinicians and other stakeholders with high evidence considering various patient-relevant outcomes when comparing these two treatment approaches.</p><p>Furthermore, parallel to the scoping review patient&#x02019;s values and perspectives towards choice of treatment will be analysed (DRKS00022050) prior to the start of the randomised trial and patient oriented information material for the trial will be developed and provided.</p><p>Overall, the final goal will be the development and verification of a protocol to identify patients with pathological complete response (based on reliable diagnostic methods and definitions for complete responders) who would not need to undergo high-risk surgery in the increasing subgroup of postneoadjuvant complete responders. This treatment procedure is expected to reduce morbidity and mortality rates, and increase quality of life. Regarding the socioeconomic impact, omission of oesophagectomy reduces treatment duration, complication rates and time of hospital stay. This results in reduced treatment costs and a faster return to normal life for this patient population.</p></sec></sec><sec id="s4"><title>Ethics and dissemination</title><p>Formal ethical approval is not required, as primary patient data will not be collected in this scoping review. We plan to publish the full scoping review in a peer-reviewed journal and to present the results at national and international scientific conferences.</p></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Material</title><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="d39e241"><caption><title>Reviewer comments</title></caption><media mimetype="application" mime-subtype="pdf" xlink:href="bmjopen-2020-044190.reviewer_comments.pdf"/></supplementary-material><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="d39e242"><caption><title>Author's manuscript</title></caption><media mimetype="application" mime-subtype="pdf" xlink:href="bmjopen-2020-044190.draft_revisions.pdf"/></supplementary-material></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Contributors:</bold> All authors of the manuscript meet the ICMJE criteria for authorship: ChS, BN and JM designed the scoping review protocol. ChS and BN designed the preliminary search strategy. JeH and JuH contributed as experts for surgical and multimodal treatment of oesophageal cancer and provided scientific knowledge. ChS and JH wrote the scoping review protocol. JuH and CS are guarantors of the manuscript.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Funding:</bold> This work was supported by a research grant (grand number 01KD1908) 'Nationale Dekade gegen Krebs' provided to JeH by the federal ministry of education and research (BMBF).</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Disclaimer:</bold> The funder was not involved in the development of the protocol. The article processing charge was funded by the Baden-Wuerttemberg Ministry of Science, Research and Art and the University of Freiburg in the funding programme Open Access Publishing.</p></fn><fn fn-type="COI-statement"><p><bold>Competing interests:</bold> None declared.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Patient and public involvement:</bold> Patients and/or the public were involved in the design, or conduct, or reporting, or dissemination plans of this research. Refer to the Methods section for further details.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Patient consent for publication:</bold> Not required.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Provenance and peer review:</bold> Not commissioned; externally peer reviewed.</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="R1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hoeppner</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Zirlik</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Brunner</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>Multimodal treatment of locally advanced esophageal adenocarcinoma: which regimen should we choose? Outcome analysis of perioperative chemotherapy versus neoadjuvant chemoradiation in 105 patients</article-title>. <source>J Surg Oncol</source>
<year>2014</year>;<volume>109</volume>:<fpage>287</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>93</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/jso.23498</pub-id><?supplied-pmid http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24277235?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24277235</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Nimptsch</surname><given-names>U</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Mansky</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Hospital volume and mortality for 25 types of inpatient treatment in German hospitals: observational study using complete national data from 2009 to 2014</article-title>. <source>BMJ Open</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>7</volume>:<elocation-id>e016184</elocation-id>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2017-016184</pub-id><?supplied-pmid http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28882913?></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Taioli</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Schwartz</surname><given-names>RM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Lieberman-Cribbin</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>Quality of life after open or minimally invasive esophagectomy in patients with esophageal cancer-a systematic review</article-title>. <source>Semin Thorac Cardiovasc Surg</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>29</volume>:<fpage>377</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>90</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1053/j.semtcvs.2017.08.013</pub-id><?supplied-pmid http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28939239?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28939239</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>van der Sluis</surname><given-names>PC</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>van der Horst</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>May</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>Robot-Assisted minimally invasive Thoracolaparoscopic esophagectomy versus open transthoracic esophagectomy for resectable esophageal cancer: a randomized controlled trial</article-title>. <source>Ann Surg</source>
<year>2019</year>;<volume>269</volume>:<fpage>621</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>30</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/SLA.0000000000003031</pub-id><?supplied-pmid http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/30308612?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30308612</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Al-Batran</surname><given-names>S-E</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Hofheinz</surname><given-names>RD</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Pauligk</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>Histopathological regression after neoadjuvant docetaxel, oxaliplatin, fluorouracil, and leucovorin versus epirubicin, cisplatin, and fluorouracil or capecitabine in patients with resectable gastric or gastro-oesophageal junction adenocarcinoma (FLOT4-AIO): results from the phase 2 part of a multicentre, open-label, randomised phase 2/3 trial</article-title>. <source>Lancet Oncol</source>
<year>2016</year>;<volume>17</volume>:<fpage>1697</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>708</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(16)30531-9</pub-id><?supplied-pmid http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27776843?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27776843</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Homann</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Pauligk</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Luley</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>Pathological complete remission in patients with oesophagogastric cancer receiving preoperative 5-fluorouracil, oxaliplatin and docetaxel</article-title>. <source>Int J Cancer</source>
<year>2012</year>;<volume>130</volume>:<fpage>1706</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>13</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/ijc.26180</pub-id><?supplied-pmid http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21618509?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21618509</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>van Hagen</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Hulshof</surname><given-names>MCCM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>van Lanschot</surname><given-names>JJB</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>Preoperative chemoradiotherapy for esophageal or junctional cancer</article-title>. <source>N Engl J Med</source>
<year>2012</year>;<volume>366</volume>:<fpage>2074</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>84</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1112088</pub-id><?supplied-pmid http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22646630?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22646630</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Moher</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Shamseer</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Clarke</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015 statement</article-title>. <source>Syst Rev</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>4</volume>:<elocation-id>1</elocation-id>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/2046-4053-4-1</pub-id><?supplied-pmid http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25554246?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25554246</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>McGowan</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Sampson</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Salzwedel</surname><given-names>DM</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>PRESS Peer Review of Electronic Search Strategies: 2015 Guideline Statement</article-title>. <source>J Clin Epidemiol</source>
<year>2016</year>;<volume>75</volume>:<fpage>40</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>6</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2016.01.021</pub-id><?supplied-pmid http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27005575?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27005575</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Grant</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Booth</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>A typology of reviews: an analysis of 14 review types and associated methodologies</article-title>. <source>Health Info Libr J</source>
<year>2009</year>;<volume>26</volume>:<fpage>91</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>108</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1471-1842.2009.00848.x</pub-id><?supplied-pmid http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19490148?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19490148</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Higgins</surname><given-names>JPT</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Altman</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Sterne</surname><given-names>JAC</given-names></name></person-group>
<chapter-title>Chapter 8: Assessing risk of bias in included studies</chapter-title> : <person-group person-group-type="editor"><name name-style="western"><surname>Higgins</surname><given-names>JPT</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Churchill</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Chandler</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>, <source>Cochrane Handbook for systematic reviews of Interventionsversion 5.2.0</source>. <publisher-name>(updated June2017), Cochrane</publisher-name>, <year>2017</year>
<uri xlink:href="www.training.cochrane.org/handbook">www.training.cochrane.org/handbook</uri></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Levac</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Colquhoun</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>O'Brien</surname><given-names>KK</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Scoping studies: advancing the methodology</article-title>. <source>Implement Sci</source>
<year>2010</year>;<volume>5</volume>:<fpage>69</fpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-5-69</pub-id><?supplied-pmid http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20854677?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20854677</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R13"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Arksey</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>O'Malley</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Scoping studies: towards a methodological framework</article-title>. <source>Int J Soc Res Methodol</source>
<year>2005</year>;<volume>8</volume>:<fpage>19</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>32</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/1364557032000119616</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R14"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Noordman</surname><given-names>BJ</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Spaander</surname><given-names>MCW</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Valkema</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>Detection of residual disease after neoadjuvant chemoradiotherapy for oesophageal cancer (preSANO): a prospective multicentre, diagnostic cohort study</article-title>. <source>Lancet Oncol</source>
<year>2018</year>;<volume>19</volume>:<fpage>965</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>74</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(18)30201-8</pub-id><?supplied-pmid http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/29861116?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29861116</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R15"><label>15</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Taketa</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Sudo</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal></person-group>
<article-title>Propensity-based matching between esophagogastric cancer patients who had surgery and who declined surgery after preoperative chemoradiation</article-title>. <source>Oncology</source>
<year>2013</year>;<volume>85</volume>:<fpage>95</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>9</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1159/000351999</pub-id><?supplied-pmid http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23860252?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23860252</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>