<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The functional role of different γδ T cell populations in HCV persistence and associated liver malignancies remains to be understood. 
 <italic>Per se</italic>, γδ T cells are enriched not only in liver tissues of healthy persons but also in patients with hepatitis infections (
 <xref rid="B22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>). Hepatic γδ T cell populations express the NK-cell marker CD56, the liver-homing marker CD161, produce INF-γ, and demonstrate an effector/memory phenotype (
 <xref rid="B23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>–
 <xref rid="B25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>). Especially, chronic HCV patients with liver cirrhosis display elevated γδ T cell numbers and their cytokine production and cytotoxicity was suggested to play a role in inflammatory necrotic processes (
 <xref rid="B26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>–
 <xref rid="B29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>). Studies analyzing matched blood and liver specimens from patients with chronic liver diseases indicated that Vδ2
 <sup>+</sup> and/or Vδ1
 <sup>+</sup> can infiltrate the liver (
 <xref rid="B25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>). Increased Vδ1
 <sup>+</sup> cell frequencies in liver transplant recipient were associated with high viral loads (HCV, CMV) (
 <xref rid="B30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>). Likewise, patients infected with only HCV, or co-infected with HIV undergoing active antiretroviral therapy (HAART), had elevated Vδ1
 <sup>+</sup> γδ T cells in the blood and liver, which was linked to liver inflammation (
 <xref rid="B28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>). Of note, HAART therapy did not restore intrahepatic Vδ1
 <sup>+</sup> T cells to normal levels within HCV/HIV co-infected patients (
 <xref rid="B31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>). Especially, Vγ9JP
 <sup>+</sup>Vδ2
 <sup>+</sup> cells have been revealed to inhibit viral replication (
 <xref rid="B32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>). Other studies connect HCV persistence to low Vγ9JP
 <sup>+</sup>Vδ2
 <sup>+</sup> frequencies, impaired IFN-γ production, and γδ T cell exhaustion (
 <xref rid="B24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>), while the cytotoxicity and continuous activation of Vγ9JP
 <sup>+</sup>Vδ2
 <sup>+</sup> during chronic HCV infection contributes to liver inflammation and cirrhosis (
 <xref rid="B24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>). The therapeutic application of zoledronate to activate Vγ9JP
 <sup>+</sup>Vδ2
 <sup>+</sup> γδ T cells through cellular accumulation of IPP was suggested as a strategy to apply γδ T cells to inhibit viral replication during interferon-based therapies (
 <xref rid="B32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>).
</p>
