<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par53">The human UGT1A subfamily enzymes are encoded by the 
 <italic>UGT1A</italic> gene locus on Chromosome 2q37.1 by alternative splicing. Nine functional proteins (UGT1A1, 1A3, 1A4, 1A5, 1A6, 1A7, 1A8, 1A9, and 1A10) were translated by the locus. All the isoforms share 4 common exons from exon 2 to exon 5, but have unique exon 1 and individual promoter pairs in turn of 1A8, 1A10, 1A9, 1A7, 1A6, 1A5, 1A4, 1A3, 1A1 in the 
 <italic>UGT1</italic>A pre-mRNA [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>]. The 
 <italic>UGT1A1</italic> exon 1/promoter is the nearest one to the common exon 2. UGT1A1 plays important roles in the clearance and metabolism of many endogenous or exogenous compounds such as irinotecan [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>]. Two functional single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in 
 <italic>UGT1A1</italic>, i.e. 
 <italic>UGT1A1*28</italic> (rs8175347) and 
 <italic>UGT1A1*6</italic> (rs4148323) are reported. The 
 <italic>UGT1A1*28</italic> polymorphism that results in TA repeating number alteration in the TATA box in the promoter can decrease the 
 <italic>UGT1A1</italic> expression and accounts for increased risk for irinotecan-induced neutropenia [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>] and myelosuppression [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>]. In 2005, the USA Food and Drug Administration (FDA) warned that patients with 
 <italic>UGT1A1*28/*28</italic> genotype are at increased risk for neutropenia when irinotecan is used, and a lower starting dose of irinotecan was recommended for 
 <italic>UGT1A1*28/*28</italic> homozygotes [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>]. 
 <italic>UGT1A1*6</italic> is a missense variants (Gly71Arg) in 
 <italic>UGT1A1</italic> exon 1 that leads to decreased UGT1A1 enzyme function [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>] and is also a risk factor for irinotecan toxicity. 
 <italic>UGT1A1*6</italic> variant is mainly observed in the Asians with allele frequency ranges in 15–30%. In 2008, the Ministry of Health, Labour, and Welfare of Japan also warned increased risk of severe irinotecan-related neutropenia in Japanese patients carrying the 
 <italic>UGT1A1*6</italic> or 
 <italic>*28</italic> allele, and approved diagnostic test for 
 <italic>UGT1A1</italic> genotypes [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>]. As UGT1A is involved in Ara-C detoxification, we hypothesized that the functional polymorphisms in 
 <italic>UGT1A1</italic> may affect chemosensitivity to Ara-C based therapies in AML patients through influence Ara-C metabolism, which could eventually improve responses to Ara-C and AML prognosis.
</p>
