<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The importance of IL-6 in human GvHD is supported by studies which have shown that patients with elevated plasma levels of IL-6,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b9-1030717" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,
  <xref rid="b10-1030717" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>
 </sup> as well as those with a recipient or donor IL-6 genotype which results in increased IL-6 production,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b11-1030717" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>–
  <xref rid="b14-1030717" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>
 </sup> have an increased incidence and severity of this disease. The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approval of tocilizumab (Toc; Actemra™), which is a humanized anti-IL-6 receptor antibody that blocks both the membrane and soluble forms of the receptor for the treatment of severe active rheumatoid arthritis,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b15-1030717" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,
  <xref rid="b16-1030717" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>
 </sup> has allowed off-label use of this agent to determine whether blockade of IL-6 signaling attenuates GvHD. To that end, it was demonstrated that Toc induced clinical responses in patients with steroid refractory acute (a)GvHD that primarily involved the lower GI tract.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b17-1030717" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>
 </sup> Furthermore, the addition of Toc to standard immune suppression resulted in a low incidence of aGvHD in a patient population which was comprised primarily of myeloid maligananices,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b18-1030717" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>
 </sup> providing evidence that inhibition of IL-6 might also be an effective approach for the prevention of GvHD. Notably, however, in the latter study myeloablative (MA) conditioning was carried out exclusively with total body irradiation (TBI) and cyclophosphamide (Cy), which is not a widely employed regimen for the treatment of myeloid malignancies. Since the intensity of the conditioning regimen is known to affect the magnitude of inflammatory cytokine production,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b19-1030717" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>
 </sup> the relevance of these results to patients treated with alternative, more commonly utilized conditioning regimens is not clear. Furthermore, there was no corresponding demographically-matched control population against which to assess these results.
</p>
