<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In general, second‐ or third‐line chemotherapy treatment for EPNEC has a response rate of 0%‐18.8% and a PFS of 2.1‐3.8 months.
 <xref rid="cas14811-bib-0009" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>9</sup>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="cas14811-bib-0014" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>14</sup>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="cas14811-bib-0016" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>16</sup>
 </xref>, 
 <xref rid="cas14811-bib-0023" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>23</sup>
 </xref> In this study, we estimated the response rate to be 15.4% and the PFS as 1.8 months. Here, TMZ monotherapy was undertaken in six cases as a second‐line treatment, but in the other seven cases, it was undertaken as the third‐ or salvage‐line treatment. Patients in this study undergoing TMZ monotherapy showed more advanced disease than patients from the other TMZ studies reported so far. According to recently published real‐world data, the median PFS for poorly differentiated NEC was 2.8 months in the TMZ monotherapy group and 2.9 months in the capecitabine combination group (
 <italic>P</italic> = .982). Median OS for poorly differentiated NEC was 6.2 months in the TMZ monotherapy group and 12.7 months in the capecitabine combination group (
 <italic>P</italic> = .613). Capecitabine addition did not have a significant impact on EPNEC, compared with NET. The addition of other agents to TMZ might be necessary for EPNEC. Temozolomide monotherapy is mildly toxic, and incidents of severe toxic events have been rare in previously reported studies. In this study, there were no grade 3 or 4 hematological and few nonhematological toxicities. Patients received chemotherapy for a long duration (approximately 6 months; detailed data not shown), and their general condition was no better than that reported in previous studies. No severe toxicity was observed in these advanced patients. Recently, many studies for unresectable NEN were undertaken using TMZ and capecitabine combination therapy that showed the rate of severe adverse events was very low (grade 3 or 4 hematological toxicities, 3.4%; nonhematological toxicities, less than 1%) and confirmed the mild toxicity of this therapy.
 <xref rid="cas14811-bib-0025" ref-type="ref">
  <sup>25</sup>
 </xref>
</p>
