<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>IRIS describes a series of symptoms and clinical characteristics that may be observed in previously immunocompromised patients during rapid restoration of immunity function in the presence of a pathogen or foreign antigen (
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>). However, there is no universally agreed-upon definition for IRIS. Immune deficiency is most frequently linked to HIV, a reversal of immunosuppressant states, and withdrawal of immunosuppressive drugs. IRIS can involve multiple organs, including the CNS, liver, lung, stomach, and intestine (
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>). The incidence of CNS-IRIS ranges widely according to CNS infection including TB, cryptococcus, and JC virus. An underlying mechanism of CNS-IRIS involves exposing large amounts of a foreign antigen to an immune system with improving ability which then responds and causes inflammation. Immune overactivation is caused by the hyper-responsiveness of the innate immune system as T lymphocyte function recovers (
 <xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>). On brain biopsy or postmortem examinations, T lymphocytes and macrophages are found predominantly in the parenchyma and perivascular spaces (
 <xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>). Brain MRI abnormalities, including new swelling with perilesional and perivascular edema, are often found in CNS-IRIS patients (
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>). The lesions might show contrast enhancement on MRI, due to local inflammation and breakdown of the blood–brain barrier (
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>). Corticosteroids treatment is usually given to reduce the overactivation inflammatory response. In CNS-IRIS caused by TB and cryptococcus, corticosteroids treatment is recommended (
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>). However, use of corticosteroids in progressive multifocal leukoencephalopathy IRIS remains controversial (
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>). Furthermore, the dose and course of corticosteroids are still uncertain.
</p>
