<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Pulmonary nocardiosis is the most common primary infection, through the inhalation of airborne spores or mycelial fragments from the environment, and is more common in immunosuppression individuals (
 <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>). Pulmonary nocardiosis can present as cough, fever, chest pain, and is similar with other pulmonary infection (
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>). Chest radiographic manifestations are variable, showing as large irregular nodules, nodules, pleural effusions (
 <xref rid="B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>), etc., in which pleural effusions account for one-third of all the manifestations (
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>). Other common 
 <italic>Nocardia</italic> infections have also been reported as central nervous system (CNS) nocardiosis (
 <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>) and cutaneous nocardiosis (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>) and may be the secondary infection of pulmonary nocardiosis through hematogenous dissemination in immunosuppression patients (
 <xref rid="B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>). Primary cutaneous infections tends more common in immunocompetent patient due to the open injury (
 <xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>). This patient firstly presented respiratory symptoms 10 days prior the admission and then developed skin swelling and pain, when was 7 days before the admission. This patient had taken corticosteroid drugs and tacrolimus for 5 months and he had not suffered open injury. Thus, we considered pulmonary nocardiosis as primary infection for this patient. It would be perfect if the intermuscular abscesses specimen was performed with mNGS. However, the cost of mNGS was a burden to this patient. Moreover, we considered the intermuscular abscesses were the result of primary pulmonary nocardiosis through hematogenous dissemination. Therefore, the necessity of intermuscular abscesses for mNGS could be limited.
</p>
