<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par48">We target to include 392 patients, with a potential limit of 462 patients to accommodate loss to follow-up and a possible dropout. The expected rate of severe peri-procedural bleeding incidents is around 0% [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref>]. Major bleeding is defined as WHO grade 3: gross blood loss requiring transfusion, or grade 4: debilitating blood loss (Additional file 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>: Table S1). Considering the low complication occurrence, sample sizes that are by far unrealistic within the proposed study are required to demonstrate non-inferiority with an acceptable non-inferiority limit of (&lt; 1%). We therefore also include WHO grade-2 bleedings in the definition of the primary outcome. As the observed bleeding events will concern predominantly grade-2 bleedings, and probably no or only incidental bleedings with more severe grades 3 or 4, an upper limit reflecting an absolute risk increase of 2.5% more bleeding events as the criterion to statistically demonstrate non-inferiority is considered both statistical and clinical acceptable. The sample size is increased by 2% to correct for loss to follow-up and by 15% to correct for dropouts, e.g. refusal of consent. Using a non-inferiority design, a sample size of 196 patients (per arm) and a percentage bleeding events of 1% in the control group and an expected percentage bleeding events of 1% in the experimental group will result in a power of 80% to exclude that there is a significant bleeding rate in the experimental arm (&gt; 3.5% bleedings, absolute risk increase 2.5%, two group 
 <italic>t</italic> test with a 0.05 two-sided significance level). As we do not anticipate any loss to follow-up – considering the short time-span of the study – we therefore intend to enrol 392 patients in total.
</p>
