<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The hUCB‐MSCs were isolated and maintained as previously described 
 <xref rid="sct312331-bib-0022" ref-type="ref">22</xref>. Briefly, hUCB samples were obtained from the umbilical vein immediately after delivery and were mixed with Hetasep solution (StemCell Technologies, Vancouver, Canada) at a ratio of 5:1, and then incubated at room temperature. The supernatant was collected, and mononuclear cells were obtained using Ficoll (GE healthcare life sciences, Pittsburgh, PA) density‐gradient centrifugation, according to the manufacturer's protocol 
 <xref rid="sct312331-bib-0023" ref-type="ref">23</xref>. The cells were washed twice in phosphate buffered solution. Next, the cells were seeded at a density of 2 × 10
 <sup>5</sup> to 2 × 10
 <sup>6</sup> cells/cm
 <sup>2</sup> on plates in growth media that consisted of D‐media (formula 78‐5470EF; Gibco BRL, Grand Island, NY) containing EGM‐2 SingleQuot and 10% fetal bovine serum (Gibco BRL). After 3 days, nonadherent cells were removed 
 <xref rid="sct312331-bib-0024" ref-type="ref">24</xref>. The stem cell characteristics of hUCB‐MSCs were verified by determining their differentiation, proliferation, and immunological phenotypes as previously described 
 <xref rid="sct312331-bib-0025" ref-type="ref">25</xref>. The subjects were given a single intravenous infusion of 2.5 × 10
 <sup>7</sup>, 5 × 10
 <sup>7</sup>, or 1 × 10
 <sup>8</sup> cells of hUCB‐MSCs for 30 minutes. Three patients were allocated to each cluster. The first cluster received the lowest cell number and then moved (increased hUCB‐MSC numbers) to the next cluster if there was no dose‐limited adverse event. Clinical and safety parameters were monitored after 24 hours, 72 hours, 1 week, and 4 weeks following the infusion (Fig. 
 <xref rid="sct312331-fig-0001" ref-type="fig">1</xref>). Hematological and biochemical tests, urine analysis, chest radiography, and a 12‐lead electrocardiogram (ECG) were performed. For the disease status assessment, values from a 66/68‐swollen/tender joint count, DAS28, a pain visual analog scale (VAS), and a health assessment questionnaire (HAQ) were obtained. Serum cytokines, including IL‐1β, IL‐6, IL‐8, IL‐10, and TNF‐α, at baseline and 24 hours after the infusion of hUCB‐MSC were analyzed with a Human High Sensitivity T Cell Magnetic Bead Panel (Merck KGaA, Darmstadt, Germany).
</p>
