<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par72">We will summarize the demographic and other baseline characteristics of the study participants. Continuous variables will be presented as mean ± standard deviations or median (interquartile range). The two-sample 
 <italic>t</italic> test or Wilcoxon's rank sum test will be used to compare the groups according to the normal distribution. Categorical variables will be presented as frequency and the percentage. Pearson's chi-square test or Fisher's exact test will be used to compare the groups. Changes in the percentage of CD34-positive cells in peripheral blood and liver tissues at 1 month of treatment will be compared between the groups using the two-sample 
 <italic>t</italic>-test or Wilcoxon's rank sum test. In the PR group, the changes in CTP score, MELD score, and CLIF-SOFA score at 1 week and 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6 months will be compared between the groups (steroid + placebo versus steroid + G-CSF) using the two-sample 
 <italic>t</italic> test or Wilcoxon's rank sum test. In the NR group, the changes in CTP score, MELD score, and CLIF-SOFA score at 1 week, 1 month, and 2 months will be compared between the groups (placebo vs. G-CSF) using two-sample 
 <italic>t</italic> test or Wilcoxon's rank sum test. In addition, repeated measures analysis of variance (ANOVA) will be performed to analyze the difference in repeated measures between the groups. OS of the subgroups according to the alcoholic hepatitis histologic score (AHHS) will be calculated by the Kaplan–Meier method and will be compared by log-rank test. Multivariate Cox regression analysis will be used to evaluate the independent variables (
 <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.05) in the whole study sample, the PR group, and the NR group. To determine the mortality prediction model, the cutoff value using area under the receiver operating characteristic curve (AUROC) will be calculated, and sensitivity and specificity will be calculated. The discrimination function of the model will be evaluated by the Kaplan–Meier method according to the estimated cut-off value. All analyses will be performed using SPSS Statistics software version 20.0 (IBM Corp., Armonk, NY, USA) and SAS version 9.2 software (SAS Institute, Cary, NC, USA).
</p>
