<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Vital signs on arrival showed a blood pressure of 82/46 mmHg. Notably, erythematous rash was found throughout the chest, abdomen and limbs of the patient (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1</xref>). The patient was first diagnosed with a systemic allergic reaction. We administered intravenous fluids and norepinephrine to maintain a blood pressure &gt;90/60 mmHg. Dexamethasone (10 mg) and promethazine (25 mg) were administered to treat his allergic reaction. An initial twelve-lead electrocardiogram (ECG) immediately after admission showed ST-segment elevation in leads II, III and aVF (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">Figure 2</xref>). Acute inferior myocardial infarction due to RCA occlusion was also considered. Emergency coronary angiography was performed (the right coronary angiography results after stent implantation 2 months earlier was shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">Figure 3A</xref>), and the results revealed severe stenosis in the distal RCA (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">Figure 3B</xref>). Intravascular ultrasound showed plaque rupture and thrombosis (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">Figure 3B</xref>). The minimum lumen area at the stenosis was 3.0 mm
 <sup>2</sup>, and the plaque burden was 80.7%. Percutaneous coronary intervention was performed in the distal RCA with a 3.5 mm × 38 mm stent. Coronary angiography after stent implantation showed an acceptable angiographic result with a thrombolysis in myocardial infarction (TIMI) flow grade of 3 (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">Figure 3C</xref>). The procedure was successful, and the patient's symptoms were relieved completely. Postoperative ECG indicated ST-segment elevation in leads II, III and aVF disappeared (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F4">Figure 4</xref>). Laboratory evaluation revealed a troponin I level of 0.448 ng/ml (normal range &lt;0.03), an eosinophil count of 0.51 × 10
 <sup>9</sup>/L (0.05–0.5), and an immunoglobulin E level of 405 IU/ml (0–100). Echocardiography revealed no obvious abnormality. The diagnosis of type II Kounis syndrome induced by phloroglucinol was made, and the condition manifested as acute ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction caused by allergic plaque rupture and thrombosis.
</p>
