<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par27">A 55-year-old male patient presented with enlarged inguinal, para-iliac, and bronchopulmonary lymph nodes, sweating and weight loss in November 2006. In December 2006, an inguinal lymph node biopsy was performed, and histological and immunohistochemical findings showed diffuse large B-cell lymphoma (DLBCL), stage IIIB. By June 2007, the patient had achieved a partial response (PR) after six cycles of CHOP as first-line treatment. In December 2007, the patient presented with enlarged inguinal and para-iliac lymph nodes, indicating disease progression. The patient then received second-line therapy with etoposide and corticosteroids. There was further disease progression in January 2008. In February 2008, the patient signed an informed consent to participate in PIX301. Computed tomography (CT) assessment revealed Ann Arbor stage III with enlarged bronchopulmonary and para-iliac lymph nodes. The diagnosis was confirmed by blinded central histological review, as per protocol. The bone marrow biopsy revealed no bone marrow involvement; the patient had an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance status of 1 and an International Prognostic Index of 1, and no history of previous or concomitant diseases. He was randomly allocated to pixantrone in March 2008 and started therapy with 85 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup> pixantrone dimaleate (which corresponds to 50 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup> in pixantrone's base form), given on days 1, 8 and 15 of each 28-day cycle for six cycles. Treatment was completed in August 2008 without any missed or reduced doses. Response to therapy was monitored using CT every 8 weeks, as well as 28 days after the end of treatment. The patient achieved a PR at the end of treatment. Electrocardiographic measurements, troponin T, multigated acquisition scan and echocardiogram were used to assess possible cardiotoxicity; all were within normal limits. No adverse events were observed during treatment, except for relatively long-lasting skin discoloration (over 6 months after the end of the therapy). After the end of treatment (August 2008), CT monitoring was performed regularly (4, 6, 8, 10, 12, 14 and 18 months) until June 2010 and annually thereafter. No disease progression was observed. The patient's last visit was in January 2017; he was asymptomatic, with no evidence of recurrent disease.
</p>
