<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<author-notes>
 <title>Article Information</title>
 <p>
  <bold>Accepted for Publication:</bold> November 16, 2020.
 </p>
 <p content-type="published-online">
  <bold>Published:</bold> January 15, 2021. 
  <?xpp bx;1?>doi:
  <uri content-type="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2020.34045</uri>
 </p>
 <p content-type="open-access-note">
  <bold>Open Access:</bold> This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the 
  <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://jamanetwork.com/pages/cc-by-license-permissions" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">CC-BY License</ext-link>. © 2021 Sutton EJ et al. 
  <italic>JAMA Network Open</italic>.
 </p>
 <corresp id="zoi201035cor1">
  <bold>Corresponding Author:</bold> Elizabeth J. Sutton, MD, Department of Radiology, Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center, 300 E 66th St, Suite 727, New York, NY 10065 (
  <email xlink:href="suttone@mskcc.org" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">suttone@mskcc.org</email>).
 </corresp>
 <p content-type="author-contributions">
  <bold>Author Contributions:</bold> Dr Sutton had full access to all of the data in the study and takes responsibility for the integrity of the data and the accuracy of the data analysis.
 </p>
 <p>
  <italic>Concept and design:</italic> Sutton, Braunstein, El-Tamer, Powell, Norton, Sacchini, Morris.
 </p>
 <p>
  <italic>Acquisition, analysis, or interpretation of data:</italic> Sutton, Braunstein, El-Tamer, Brogi, Hughes, Bryce, Gluskin, Woosley, Tadros, Sevilimedu, Martinez, Toni, Smelianskaia, Nyman, Razavi, Fung, Sedorovich, Sacchini, Morris.
 </p>
 <p>
  <italic>Drafting of the manuscript:</italic> Sutton, Braunstein, Woosley, Sevilimedu, Martinez, Smelianskaia, Sedorovich, Sacchini.
 </p>
 <p>
  <italic>Critical revision of the manuscript for important intellectual content:</italic> Sutton, Braunstein, El-Tamer, Brogi, Hughes, Bryce, Gluskin, Powell, Tadros, Toni, Nyman, Razavi, Norton, Fung, Sacchini, Morris.
 </p>
 <p>
  <italic>Statistical analysis:</italic> Braunstein, Sevilimedu.
 </p>
 <p>
  <italic>Obtained funding:</italic> Sutton, Norton, Morris.
 </p>
 <p>
  <italic>Administrative, technical, or material support:</italic> Sutton, Braunstein, Bryce, Gluskin, Woosley, Martinez, Norton, Fung, Sedorovich, Morris.
 </p>
 <p>
  <italic>Supervision:</italic> Sutton, Braunstein, El-Tamer, Gluskin, Powell, Tadros, Smelianskaia, Norton, Sacchini.
 </p>
 <p content-type="COI-statement">
  <bold>Conflict of Interest Disclosures:</bold> Dr Morris reported receiving funding from the Susan G. Komen Foundation and Grail Inc for breast cancer research not related to the present work. No other disclosures were reported.
 </p>
 <p content-type="funding-statement">
  <bold>Funding/Support:</bold> This work was partially supported by grant P30 CA008748 from the National Institutes of Health/National Cancer Institute and by grant RSCH1622 from the Guerbet/Radiological Society of North America (Dr Sutton).
 </p>
 <p>
  <bold>Role of the Funder/Sponsor:</bold> The funders had no role in the design and conduct of the study; collection, management, analysis, and interpretation of the data; preparation, review, or approval of the manuscript; and decision to submit the manuscript for publication.
 </p>
 <p content-type="data-sharing-statement">
  <bold>Data Sharing Statement:</bold> See 
  <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="note-ZOI201035-1-s">Supplement 3</xref>.
 </p>
 <p>
  <bold>Additional Contributions:</bold> We thank Joanne Chin, MFA, ELS, who provided editorial assistance as part of her employment as a full-time senior editor at Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center. Ms Chin was financially compensated for her contribution.
 </p>
 <p>
  <bold>Additional Information:</bold> Coauthor James D. Sedorovich, BS, died July 18, 2019.
 </p>
</author-notes>
