<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>With increasing recognition of the importance of transparency and objectivity in the selection process (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>), as well as a wish to attract diverse applicants from across Canada, in 2016 the Head of the Division of Child &amp; Youth Mental Health (DCYMH) tasked the resident selection committee with modernizing their selection process by applying emerging best practices in selection, including: independent sampling, competency definition, multiple interviews, and relative ranking of candidates (
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>–
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>). The first step was to undertake a process of identifying the key applicant attributes to be considered in CAP trainee selection. The goals of this attribute identification quality-improvement (QI) exercise were 4-fold; (1) identification of an explicit set of attributes for use in the new selection protocol, (2) explicit descriptions of desired UT CAP applicant profiles, (3) mitigating sources of potential bias in the admissions process, and (4) distinguishing our program from others across the country, thus, distinctly positioning the UT CAP training program within the competitive national CAP training landscape (which we refer to as 
 <italic>branding</italic>). Shappell and colleagues (
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>) define brand identity for postgraduate training programs as a "set of associations that defines a program, differentiates it from others in the specialty, and makes it relevant to specific target groups.” Although branding is often seen as a marketing goal, we also view it as a quality goal in order to develop overarching educational consistency across the many UT CAP teaching sites. Renewal of the CAP subspecialty selection process was seen to be an integral component of defining and establishing the UT CAP brand identity, thus, differentiating the UT CAP training program from others across the country (
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>) and fostering applicant's self-selection of the program. By defining key attributes and then incorporating them into the admissions process, we also sought to mitigate some sources of bias in the admissions process (
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>). Further, the identified priority attributes for resident selection would guide future CAP residency curriculum renewal to bring alignment across UT CAP selection and curriculum practices and ultimately the vision and mission for the DCYMH.
</p>
