<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Neutrophils are the most common leukocytes in blood and constitute 50–70% of the white blood cells corresponding to an absolute neutrophil count of 1.8-7.7 × 10
 <sup>9</sup>/l blood (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>). As part of the first line of defense they immediately migrate to the site of an infection following gradients of chemoattractants released by tissue-dwelling, pathogen sensing cells (
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>). Like macrophages, neutrophils are professional phagocytes. However, unlike macrophages, they are loaded with preformed granules containing antimicrobial effector molecules (
 <xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>). This allows neutrophils to kill invading microbes very efficiently. During phagocytosis, neutrophils engulf microbes into the phagosome that subsequently fuses with granules to form an antimicrobial environment that toxifies microorganisms by reactive oxygen species (ROS), antimicrobial peptides and proteins (
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>). To eradicate microbes in the extracellular milieu neutrophils either degranulate antimicrobial effectors into the extracellular milieu (
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>) or deliver their effectors embedded into a web-like structure, known as neutrophil extracellular traps (
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>). Clinically relevant neutropenia and severe neutropenia are defined by neutrophil counts below 1.5–2 × 10
 <sup>9</sup>/l or 0.5 × 10
 <sup>9</sup>/l, respectively (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>). Neutropenia occurs transiently or chronically in a variety of diseases and disorders and renders individuals more susceptible to infections (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>–
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>). A major group at risk for neutropenia are patients treated for hematological malignancies: Chemo- and radiation therapy often affect hematopoiesis, thereby reducing neutrophil production (
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>). Furthermore, immunosuppressive drugs such as azathioprine or mycophenolate can depress neutrophil counts (
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>). Accordingly, persistent neutropenia is a known risk factor for invasive bacterial and fungal infections after receiving a hematopoietic stem cell (HSC) transplant (
 <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>). Today, the granulocyte colony-stimulating factor (G-CSF) is widely used as a prophylactic treatment to counteract neutropenia and to prevent infections, for instance, in patients undergoing systemic chemotherapy (
 <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>). However, studies on lymphoma patients revealed that G-CSF given as primary prophylaxis could not increase overall survival or reduce infection-related mortality (
 <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>). Another study on patients undergoing HSC transplantation while receiving G-CSF treatment showed a slightly decreased infection rate but no difference in treatment-related mortality (
 <xref rid="B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>). HSCs are transplanted either by autologous or allogeneic routes into patients suffering from different malignant and non-malignant hematopoetic disorders, for instance, acute myeloid leukemia, myeloma, or thalassemia major (
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>). To increase the number of pluripotent cells in peripheral blood, the donors receive G-CSF prior to the process of harvesting HSCs from peripheral blood (
 <xref rid="B21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>). Concomitantly, the numbers of circulating neutrophils increase. Naturally, the cytokine G-CSF is a major factor controlling the development and function of neutrophils (
 <xref rid="B22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>). G-CSF regulates proliferation, maturation, survival, and functional activation of these cells (
 <xref rid="B24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>). During the course of an infection, serum levels of G-CSF increase which in turn enhances proliferation of granulocytic precursor cells and an increased level of circulating neutrophils (
 <xref rid="B23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>). In our study we aimed to analyze the quality of neutrophils resulting from G-CSF-treatment. We investigated key neutrophil functions in cells isolated from blood of healthy individuals recruited as HSC donors before and after G-CSF treatment as well as from allogeneic HSC recipients at different time points after receiving the HSC graft from G-CSF-treated donors. While oxidative burst and phagocytosis were unaffected in all these samples, chemotaxis was significantly reduced upon treatment with G-CSF. Strikingly, impaired chemotaxis was detectable in neutrophils from HSC recipients up to 4 weeks post engraftment.
</p>
