<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par71">All statistical analyses were performed using GraphPad Prism 6.0c software (GraphPad Software). For all in vitro experiments, three or six technical replicates were analyzed for each experiment, and results are presented as the mean ± s.e.m. of three biological replicates. Quantitative analyses were carried out using unpaired two-tailed Student's 
 <italic>t</italic> test with equal standard deviation after confirming that the data met appropriate assumptions (normality, homogenous variance, and independent sampling). Seven to ten mice per treatment group were used for all in vivo experiments with SMOi treatment. Five mice per treatment group were utilized for RNA-Seq. For all RT-qPCR experiments, three technical replicates were analyzed for each experiment, and results are presented as the mean ± s.e.m. of three biological replicates. Subsequent statistical analyses of in vivo experiments were performed with either unpaired two-sided Student's 
 <italic>t</italic> tests or the Fisher's exact test. Survival analysis was performed using the Log-rank (Mantel−Cox) test. A 
 <italic>P</italic> value &lt; 0.05 was considered statistically significant. *
 <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.05, **
 <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.01, ***
 <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.001, ****
 <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.0001. Estimation of variation within each group was determined by s.e.m. Sample size estimation was initially chosen by using power calculations for guidance (
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://biomath.info/power/ttest.htm" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">http://biomath.info/power/ttest.htm</ext-link>). Effect sizes were estimated at 30% for single agent arms, based on earlier data with single agent docetaxel and SMO inhibitors. With alpha = 0.05 and power = 0.9 and allowing for attrition of ~1 mouse/group, ≥7 mice per group were needed for all preclinical studies. For the Phase I clinical trial EDALINE, descriptive analysis on demographic and clinicopathological characteristics (age, visceral disease, number of involved sites, prior treatment, histologic tumor grade and Ki67), Hh biomarkers expression (HH and GLI1) and efficacy data to the combined therapy sonidegib with docetaxel were performed. The Chi-square test of Independence was assessed to examine the association between epithelial HH and stromal GLI1 expression and efficacy endpoints: best tumor response (complete or partial response, stable disease, progression disease, and Time to Progression (TTP)). TTP was defined as the time from treatment commencement until objective tumor progression (does not include deaths). Progression-free survival (PFS) was explored using Kaplan−Meier survival analysis. PFS was defined as the time from treatment commencement until disease progression or death. For mouse and clinical studies, specialists were blinded to the experiment treatment groups.
</p>
