<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Radiotherapy which is the most commonly used method for the treatment of HNC, uses high-energy radiation to shrink tumors and kill cancer cells, thus preventing the cells from growing, dividing, and spreading. However, when using radiotherapy, irradiation of normal tissue, in particular tissue close to the tumor, is unavoidable. Thus, this therapy often complex and frequently associated with significant short-and long-term complications including mucositis, dysgeusia, dysphagia, weight loss, malnutrition, hypo-salivation, increased risk of dental caries, increased risk of progression of periodontal disease, dental hypersensitivity, infections, mucosal atrophy, trismus, neuropathic pain and osteoradionecrosis (ORN).
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]
 </sup> A reduction in salivary function is a common side-effect of radiotherapy to the head and neck region.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]
 </sup> When major salivary glands are subject to high radiotherapy doses, hypo-salivation becomes a problem and the resulting dry mouth environment makes retention of intact dentition a significant challenge.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
  <xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]
 </sup> Limited and often poor dietary choices compound the risk of dental breakdown in these patients.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
  <xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
  <xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]
 </sup> Dental extractions as a result of dental caries place post-radiotherapy patients at risk of ORN with potentially serious consequences.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
  <xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]
 </sup> These side effects may delay and interfere with cancer treatment and may result in increased treatment costs and reduced quality of life (QoL).
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]
 </sup> Preservation of intact dentition is, therefore, paramount in safeguarding the HNC patient's life quality.
</p>
