<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par21">Patient 3 was a 20-year-old male with a third recurrence of ALL with CNS-3 status [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>] and extramedullary involvement. He received a diagnosis of ALL (CD19
 <sup>+</sup>, BCR/ABL-) in 2000 when he was 3 years old (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5a</xref>). During the following 13 years, he had received more than 20 courses of intensive systemic chemotherapy (SC) and IT and remained being in CR. However, he had a relapse in BM and CNS in 2013. Then, he underwent allo-HSCT from a 10/10 HLA allele-matched unrelated female donor in 2014 and the second CR was achieved. Despite he received IT for more than six courses, the patient suffered from second recurrence with CNS-ALL. He had a good response to IT and irradiation and achieved CR for a third time. However, the cancer recurred again 10 months later with CNS and extramedullary involvement in June, 2017. The bone marrow examination still showed signs of complete remission. The whole-body PET/CT showed that extensive extramedullary relapse involving almost the entire pleura, peritoneum, pelvic fascia, pancreas, and multiple lymph nodes (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5b</xref>). A biopsy was performed on right-sided supraclavicular node mass, and characteristic megakaryocytes, erythroblasts and myeloid cells were observed microscopically. The markers were identified as CD3−, CD20−, CD19+, TdT+++, CD10+++, CD34−, and Ki67+ (90%), revealing the leukemic involvement (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5c</xref>). A palpable mass below xiphoid was identified by B-mode ultrasound, and inhomogeneous hypo-echoic mass about 3.0 × 1.9 cm in diameter was seen (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5d</xref>). In addition, aberrant blast cells were detected histologically (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5e</xref>) and examined CD19
 <sup>+</sup>CD10
 <sup>+</sup> phenotype (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5f</xref>) in the CSF obtained by lumbar puncture. X/Y fluorescent in situ hybridization (FISH) showed that XY-type recipient cells accounted for 50% of the cerebrospinal cells, further indicating a relapse in the CSF (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5g</xref>).
</p>
