<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par42">This is the first study proposed to evaluate the chemopreventive effect of aspirin and metformin combination therapy in patients with rectal ACF. Given its role as an analgesic, antipyretic and agent for cardiovascular prophylaxis, aspirin has become one of the most commonly used drugs. Many studies have provided considerable evidence demonstrating its potential for the prevention of CRC. Aspirin exerts its anticancer effects through several interconnected mechanisms, including prostaglandin synthesis and catabolism in epithelial cells [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>]; inhibition of WNT β-catenin signalling [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>]; inactivation of platelets [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>] and the host immune response [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>]. Aspirin may also act through several other unknown mechanisms. Furthermore, aspirin may has been hypothesized to act synergistically with other agents [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>]. Further study is needed to clear the chemopreventive effect of aspirin. Metformin (1,1-dimethylbiguanide hydrochloride) is a biguanide derivative that is widely used for the treatment of diabetes mellitus [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>]. Metformin activates AMPK, which inhibits the mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) pathway [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>]. The mTOR pathway plays an important role in the regulation of cellular protein translational machinery and cell proliferation [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>]. The best-characterized downstream effector of mTOR is S6 kinase, which regulates the initiation and elongation phases of translation [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>]. Activation of the mTOR pathway has been shown to accelerate cell cycle progression from G1 to S in CRC DLD-1 cells [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>]. Therefore, AMPK activation may inhibit cell growth and proliferation by suppressing protein synthesis, thereby having a potent antiproliferative effect. Recent evidence indicates that metformin has a suppressive effect on tumorigenesis and cancer cell growth [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>]. In one study, metformin was demonstrated to activate AMPK and consequently decrease cellular proliferative activity, to produce a general decrease in protein synthesis in vitro in human breast carcinoma cells [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref>]. Metformin was also shown to inhibit the proliferation of human prostate cancer cells [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>]. In addition, we performed a RCT and we showed that metformin reduced the incidence of new polyps in patients after polypectomy of the colon [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]. However, similar to aspirin, the chemopreventive effective was limited. In this study, we aim to evaluate the chemopreventive effect of aspirin and metformin combination therapy in patients with rectal ACF and determine whether the combined use of aspirin and metformin produces a stronger chemopreventive effect than each drug alone. Because we hypothesize that both aspirin and combination therapy may have a chemopreventive effect, a higher number of baseline ACFs (&gt; 10) was needed to detect a difference between the two treatment effects. We previously reported a mean number of ACFs in adenomas of 6.2 ± 7.0 [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>], which is why we set &gt; 10 ACFs as an inclusion criterion. Consequently, we expect the trial to take longer because of the small number of patients who meet the inclusion criteria.
</p>
