<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par43">This trial may have the following limitations. First, ACFs are considered as a reliable surrogate biomarker of CRC [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>], although their biological significance still remains controversial. However, setting study endpoint as ACF has large merit to reduce efforts because ACFs are quantitative and it is possible to observe changes in a short period of time. Thus, we devised a trial using ACF as the primary endpoint to evaluate the chemopreventive effects of aspirin and metformin combination therapy. Second, an intervention period of 8 weeks may be too short to allow the reliable detection of differences between the groups. However, we showed in a previous study that oral administration of metformin for 1 month suppressed the formation of colorectal ACF in humans. Other reports show that ACFs decrease in number in 8 weeks with the use of NSAIDs [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. Therefore, we think that an intervention period of 8 weeks would be sufficient to evaluate the changes in the number of ACF. We previously conducted a short-term chemoprevention trial of metformin for colorectal ACF, and we showed the suppressive effect of the drug on the formation of ACF. Thereafter, we conducted a long-term metformin chemoprevention trial for colorectal polyps. We propose to repeat the same steps for the chemoprevention trial to investigate the combined use of aspirin and metformin. Third, our study lacks dose-response data. However, low-dose aspirin (100 mg/d) is used worldwide with reported chemopreventive effects on CRC and adenoma. Furthermore, we previously reported the effect of low-dose metformin (250 mg/d) on colorectal adenoma and ACF. Finally, our study lacks a metformin alone arm and double placebo arm, while the use of aspirin alone has not been established to suppress to the formation of ACFs. However, aspirin is one of the most efficiacious chemopreventive agents for the treatment of colorectal adenoma and CRC, which is why we used aspirin alone as the control arm in the present study. A four-arm study using a double placebo is needed in the future to investigate the combination effect of metformin and aspirin.
</p>
