<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Investigating the effects of health communication related to vaccines—as conducted within this study—is very important for several reasons: the latest research has shown that trust in science and also trust in doctors, scientific institutions, and governments has decreased (
 <xref rid="B31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>). Different factors may lead to less trust, such as the rapid development of the internet and social media, the complexity and pace of information available (
 <xref rid="B33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>), and a rising motivation to reject science among certain groups in society (
 <xref rid="B34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>). Decreased trust in science, institutions, and authorities may lead to uncertainty in individuals and, thus, to different (i.e., not health-promoting) behavior. For this reason, as well as the implications of the spread of fake news and social media, a new or different way of communicating scientific evidence about health-related issues becomes relevant (
 <xref rid="B33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>). A recent example of increasing anti-vaccination behavior in Italy, which led to increasing numbers of measles outbreaks, demonstrates one of the main challenges: a movie about vaccination against measles spread fake news. In this movie, it is claimed that autism is supposed to be an adverse effect of the vaccination against measles, mumps, and rubella. This movie, in addition to other reports carried by different media, led to insecurity about the risk of vaccination against measles in society, and to different vaccination behavior (
 <xref rid="B35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>). A previous study has shown that narratives have a stronger impact than statistical risk information on perceived vaccination risks. Furthermore, the same study emphasized that the number of narratives reporting adverse effects related to vaccination is inversely related to vaccination intentions (
 <xref rid="B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>). This indicates the relevance of information that goes beyond neutrally formulated texts. However, the texts themselves need to be rated as credible. In terms of the credibility, effects, and impact of science communication in the field of public health, the investigation of new and different forms of health communication is not only worthwhile but necessary. Using innovative approaches, such as including humor in communication strategies, may enable communicators to reach a wider audience (
 <xref rid="B36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>).
</p>
