<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ack>
 <title>Acknowledgements</title>
 <p>We thank all participating survivors of childhood cancer, without whom this study would not be possible. In addition to the co-authors of this paper, the PanCareLIFE consortium includes the following project partners: Pintail Ltd., Dublin, Ireland (Kylie O’Brien), Universität zu Lübeck, Germany (Thorsten Langer), Charité –Universitätsmedizin Berlin, Germany (Anja Borgmann-Staudt), Westfälische Wilhelms-Universität Münster, Germany (Antoinette am Zehnhoff-Dinnesen), Universität Bern, Switzerland (Claudia Kuehni) and Universitaetsklinikum Bonn, Bonn, Germany (Katja Baust). Data is, in addition to the institutions of the co-authors, provided by: Netherlands Cancer Institute (Floor van Leeuwen), Helios Kliniken Berlin Buch, Germany (Gabriele Strauss), Istituto Giannina Gaslini, Genoa, Italy (Dr. R Haupt, Dr. M-L Garré), Great Ormond Street Hospital (Alison Leiper), Medizinische Universität Graz, Austria (H Lackner), Uniwersytet Medyczny w Białymstoku, Bialystok, Poland (Anna Panasiuk, Maryna Krawczuk-Rybak), Heinrich Heine Universität Düsseldorf, Germany (Marina Kunstreich), Universität Ulm, Germany (Holger Cario), Klinikum Stuttgart, Olgahospital, Stuttgart, Germany (Stefan Bielack), Uniwersytet Gdánski, Poland (Joanna Stefanowicz), University College London Hospital, UK (Victoria Grandage).</p>
 <sec id="FPar1">
  <title>Funding</title>
  <p id="Par34">This work was supported by the PanCareLIFE project that has received funding from the European Union’s Seventh Framework Programme for research, technological development and demonstration under grant agreement no 602030.</p>
  <p id="Par35">UD: German Cancer Aid grant 108128 to UD; ERA-Net-TRANSCAN consortium, project number 01KT1310, and Euro Ewing Consortium EEC, project number EU-FP7 602856, both funded under the European Commission Seventh Framework Program FP7-HEALTH; Stiftung für krebskranke Kinder in Essen. The funding bodies did not have a role in the design or collection of data, neither will they have in analysis and interpretation of data.</p>
 </sec>
</ack>
