<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="p0090">In contrast to these approaches, delivery of IDS to the brain by JR-141 is achieved via the mechanism of receptor-mediated transcytosis of transferrin.
 <xref rid="bib18" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>18</sup>
 </xref> TfRs are expressed in brain capillary endothelial cells, a component of the BBB, which enables transferrin to cross the BBB.
 <xref rid="bib29" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>29</sup>
 </xref> We assume that JR-141 binds to TfR on the endothelial cells through the anti-TfR antibody region of the drug and is then transported into the cells and distributed in the brain parenchyma by as-yet-unidentified mechanisms, which prevent the neurotoxic accumulation of HS in the neurons. We have previously reported the penetration of human IDS fused with an engineered monoclonal antibody against murine TfRs into the brain parenchyma of MPS II model mice, which resulted in reductions in HS concentration in the brain, along with improvements in learning and memory.
 <xref rid="bib19" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>19</sup>
 </xref> These findings were then neatly replicated with human IDS with monoclonal antibody against human TfRs administered to human TfR-knockin mice and monkeys.
 <xref rid="bib18" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>18</sup>
 </xref> The HS concentrations in the mouse CSF correlated well with those in the mouse brain,
 <xref rid="bib20" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>20</sup>
 </xref> which justifies the use of HS concentrations as a biomarker reflecting neuropathological disease activities in MPS II, as discussed above. These preclinical findings further reinforce the positioning of HS concentrations in CSF both as a viable efficacy endpoint in clinical trials evaluating treatment response and also as a direct biomarker of ongoing neurodegeneration. Clinical pictures of CNS disorders in MPS II are too multifaceted and varied to allow a truly viable clinical efficacy endpoint to be established in the face of diverse disease progression and severity, as well as the paucity of evaluable patient populations worldwide for participation in clinical trials.
</p>
