<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract id="Abs1">
 <sec>
  <title>Background</title>
  <p id="Par1">The current standard postoperative treatment for stage II-IIIA non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) is a regimen of platinum doublet adjuvant chemotherapy. These regimens, which are the same as for solid NSCLC tumors, often cause severe adverse reactions in the treated patients. Therefore, an effective treatment regimen with fewer side effects is needed.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Methods/design</title>
  <p id="Par2">The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness and safety of S-1 monotherapy (80 mg/m
   <sup>2</sup> orally administrated twice daily, at day 1–14, 16 cycles) and cisplatin with vinorelbine combination therapy (cisplatin 80 mg/m
   <sup>2</sup> at day 1,vinorelbine 25 mg/m
   <sup>2</sup> at day 1, 8, 4 cycles) in patients with II/IIIA stage non-small-cell lung cancer who underwent a total resection. In addition, we will also evaluate the level of treatment side effects by assessing quality of life (QOL), work productivity and activity performance. The primary endpoint is a 2-year relapse free survival (RFS) and the second primary endpoints are 2-year overall survival (OS), rate of treatment completion, safety, work productivity and activity, and quality of adjusted life years (QALY). At the same time, we aim to obtain precise information required to perform future phase 3 randomized controlled trials. The study is designed to estimate the primary endpoint with accuracy determined as the width of its 95% confidence interval to be less than 20%. Recruitment started in May 2017 and is ongoing.
  </p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Discussion</title>
  <p id="Par3">This study has been conceived to establish a superior regimen for completely resected NSCLC based on efficacy, safety and QOL.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Trial registration</title>
  <p id="Par4">Registry number: 
   <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://upload.umin.ac.jp/cgi-open-bin/ctr/ctr_view.cgi?recptno=R000031434" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">UMIN000027435</ext-link>. Registered May 22, 2017.
  </p>
 </sec>
</abstract>
