<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fn-group>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>
   <bold>Twitter:</bold> @connor_urol, @TaimurShah, @KamalThippu, @LondonProstate1
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>
   <bold>Contributors:</bold> Conception and design of the ATLANTA trial: HUA, MJC, MW, TTS, TD, AF, AS, VK, MG, NS, JS, ED, FF, NKN and ME. All authors have read and approved the final manuscript: MJC, TTS, KS, ED, JS, FF, NS, MG, AF, NKN, ME, OFN, KTJ, DP, SG, DB, GH, JM, DS, MK, AI, CB, RAP, NA, CH, lS, BR, GH, SM, BK, SM, VK, TD, JNS, MW and HUA.
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>
   <bold>Funding:</bold> The trial was funded by the Wellcome Trust (204998/Z/16/Z).
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="COI-statement">
  <p>
   <bold>Competing interests:</bold> MJC’s research is support by University College London Hospitals (UCLH) Charity and the Wellcome Trust.
  </p>
  <p>KTJ is currently supported by a research grant from the UK National Institute of Health Research (NIHR) Clinical Research Network Eastern. He has received educational and travel grants from Bayer UK, Janssen Oncology, Pfizer; Roche, Takeda.</p>
  <p>HUA’s research is supported by core funding from the United Kingdom’s National Institute of Health Research (NIHR) Imperial Biomedical Research Centre. HUA currently receives funding from the Wellcome Trust, Prostate Cancer UK, MRC (UK), Cancer Research UK, Sonacare Inc., Trod Medical and Sophiris Biocorp for trials in prostate cancer. HUA was a paid medical consultant for Sophiris Biocorp, Sonacare Inc. and BTG in the past 3 years.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>
   <bold>Patient consent for publication:</bold> Not required.
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>
   <bold>Provenance and peer review:</bold> Not commissioned; externally peer reviewed.
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>
   <bold>Supplemental material:</bold> This content has been supplied by the author(s). It has not been vetted by BMJ Publishing Group Limited (BMJ) and may not have been peer-reviewed. Any opinions or recommendations discussed are solely those of the author(s) and are not endorsed by BMJ. BMJ disclaims all liability and responsibility arising from any reliance placed on the content. Where the content includes any translated material, BMJ does not warrant the accuracy and reliability of the translations (including but not limited to local regulations, clinical guidelines, terminology, drug names and drug dosages), and is not responsible for any error and/or omissions arising from translation and adaptation or otherwise.
  </p>
 </fn>
</fn-group>
