<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par66">Multiple myeloma (MM) is a plasma cell tumour and has an annual incidence in the UK of approximately 4500 new cases [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>]. Therapeutic options for patients with MM have changed in the last decade with the arrival of potent novel agents such as proteasome inhibitors and immunomodulatory drugs (IMiDs) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. Despite the depth of responses (DoRs) obtained with these strategies, almost all patients will relapse post first-line autologous stem cell transplantation (ASCT). The most appropriate strategy as first relapse management (second-line treatment) has evolved in recent years with an expanding portfolio of novel agents, driving response rates influencing the durability of response (DuR). A second ASCT, as part of relapsed disease management (salvage ASCT), has been shown to prolong the progression-free survival (PFS) and overall survival (OS) following a proteasome inhibitor-containing re-induction regimen, in the Cancer Research UK-funded National Cancer Research Institute (NCRI) Myeloma X (Intensive) study [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>]. Updated analysis showed significant improvement in second PFS amongst a salvage ASCT group of 67 months [52, ∞) vs. 35 months [31–43] in the weekly cyclophosphamide group. This result was backed up with a reduced hazard ratio (HR) of 0.37 and a statistically significant median difference of 15 months (67 months, 95% confidence interval, CI [55, ∞) vs. 52 months, 95% CI [42, 60]) in overall survival, in favour of salvage ASCT therapy with a reduced HR of 0.56 (0.35–0.90) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>]. The salvage ASCT activity in the UK has risen as a consequence of this trial and its findings, as evidenced by the British Society of Blood and Marrow Transplantation (BSBMT) data registry analysis [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>]. It is now recommended that salvage ASCT be considered for suitable patients by the International Myeloma Working Group (IMWG) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>] and the National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) NG35 guidance [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>].
</p>
