<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In the literature, other studies
 <sup>
  <xref rid="zoi201035r21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>,
  <xref rid="zoi201035r22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>,
  <xref rid="zoi201035r23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,
  <xref rid="zoi201035r24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>
 </sup> reported high false-negative rates (FNRs), which represent an incorrect biopsy pCR that is pathologically a non-pCR. Heil et al
 <sup>
  <xref rid="zoi201035r21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>
 </sup> included all biological subtypes with a partial or complete imaging response and reported an FNR of 17.8% (n = 398) with vacuum-assisted biopsy performed under either ultrasonographic or mammographic guidance. Tasoulis et al
 <sup>
  <xref rid="zoi201035r22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>
 </sup> reported an FNR of 18.7% (n = 166) with image-guided vacuum-assisted biopsy after NAC, which was performed in 86% of patients. Basik et al
 <sup>
  <xref rid="zoi201035r23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>
 </sup> included near-complete or radiologically complete response by triple-modality imaging (defined on MRI as no mass, with rapid rise or washout kinetics) and reported that the NRG Oncology BR005 trial
 <sup>
  <xref rid="zoi201035r25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>
 </sup> had an FNR of 50% (n = 98) with stereotactic core needle biopsy as well as an NPV of biopsy results for pCR of 77.5%. Vrancken-Peeters et al
 <sup>
  <xref rid="zoi201035r24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>
 </sup> included partially or radiologically complete response on MRI and reported that the Minimally Invasive Complete Response Assessment (MICRA) trial
 <sup>
  <xref rid="zoi201035r26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>
 </sup> had an interim FNR of 37% (n = 167) with ultrasound core needle biopsy and an interim NPV of biopsy results for pCR of 75.4%. The NRG Oncology BR005 trial
 <sup>
  <xref rid="zoi201035r25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>
 </sup> and the MICRA trial
 <sup>
  <xref rid="zoi201035r26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>
 </sup> both used post-NAC MRI to identify eligible patients, but MRI-guided biopsy was not performed. Vrancken-Peeters et al
 <sup>
  <xref rid="zoi201035r24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>
 </sup> also reported that vacuum-assisted biopsy had a lower FNR than core needle biopsy. Rauch et al
 <sup>
  <xref rid="zoi201035r14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>
 </sup> reported the highest accuracy of image-guided biopsy, with an FNR of 0% (n = 40) for vacuum-assisted biopsy performed by either stereotaxis (63%) or ultrasonography (37%), but they also reported that the ultrasound-guided biopsy subgroup analysis demonstrated an FNR of 40% and a PPV of the biopsy result for pCR of 60%. We were unable to reconcile this discrepancy on review of their published data.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="zoi201035r27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>
 </sup> Other studies are currently being conducted, including the NOSTRA-Feasibility Study.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="zoi201035r28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>
 </sup> Finally, at present, studies of a putative nonoperative paradigm are being conducted by the MD Anderson Cancer Center,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="zoi201035r29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>
 </sup> whereas others are in the planning stages. However, none of these studies have incorporated MRI-guided biopsy to diagnose a pCR, which, to our knowledge, represents the most sensitive imaged-based approach to date.
</p>
