<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="para0012">Study drug provided to participants is double-blinded rivaroxaban 10 mg or matching placebo taken once daily. This dose and duration of rivaroxaban was selected for PREVENT-HD primarily based on previous results in medically ill populations,
 <xref rid="bib0032" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>32</sup>
 </xref>
 <sup>,</sup>
 <xref rid="bib0034" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>34</sup>
 </xref>
 <sup>,</sup>
 <xref rid="bib0038" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>38</sup>
 </xref>
 <sup>,</sup>
 <xref rid="bib0039" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>39</sup>
 </xref> suggesting that the 10 mg once daily dose of rivaroxaban is the minimally effective dose needed to reach the trough level to prevent venous thromboembolic events in medically ill populations with high thrombotic risk and low risk of bleeding, including those with pneumonia and sepsis.
 <xref rid="bib0036" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>36</sup>
 </xref> Furthermore, the 10 mg once daily dose is FDA-approved for VTE prophylaxis following hip and knee arthroplasty and has trough levels approximating the 2.5 mg twice daily dose,
 <xref rid="bib0040" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>40</sup>
 </xref> which has been previously shown to be effective in preventing thrombotic events in patients with cardiovascular disease.
 <xref rid="bib0033" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>33</sup>
 </xref>
 <sup>,</sup>
 <xref rid="bib0035" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>35</sup>
 </xref> Though the 2.5 mg twice daily dose has shown efficacy in preventing both arterial and venous thrombotic events in these studies, the 10 mg once daily dose was favored for the current study given the efficacy demonstrated previously in similar medically ill populations. While there is a dearth of evidence that DOACs reduce the risk of arterial thrombosis in medically ill populations, recent emerging evidence suggests non-hemorrhagic stroke prevention with betrixaban
 <xref rid="bib0041" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>41</sup>
 </xref> and rivaroxaban
 <xref rid="bib0042" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>42</sup>
 </xref> in this population. In the MARINER study, a placebo controlled study of extended thromboprophylaxis in medically ill patients with rivaroxaban, 10 mg of rivaroxaban reduced the secondary composite end point of symptomatic VTE, myocardial infarction, non-hemorrhagic stroke, and cardiovascular death by 28% compared with placebo without a significant increase in major bleeding.
 <xref rid="bib0042" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>42</sup>
 </xref> Doses greater than 10 mg once daily of rivaroxaban have been associated with increased bleeding risk when used for secondary prophylaxis.
 <xref rid="bib0043" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>43</sup>
 </xref> Therefore, 10 mg once daily dose was selected to optimally balance the prevention of both venous and arterial thrombotic risk with the risk of excess bleeding.
</p>
