<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fn-group>
 <fn fn-type="abbr">
  <p>Abbreviations: TRPV2 = Transient receptor potential vanilloid 2, ESCC = esophageal squamous cell carcinoma, RFS = recurrence-free survival, OS = overall survival, CSC = cancer stem cell, CDDP = cisplatin, 5FU = 5-fluorouracil, CTCAE = Criteria for Adverse Events, DLT = Dose-limiting toxicity, MTD = maximum tolerated dose, CT = computed tomography, PET-CT = positron emission tomography CT, FAS = full analysis set, ORR = objective response rate.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>How to cite this article: Shiozaki A, Kudou M, Fujiwara H, Konishi H, Shimizu H, Arita T, Kosuga T, Yamamoto Y, Morimura R, Ikoma H, Kuriu Y, Kubota T, Okamoto K, Otsuji E. Clinical safety and efficacy of neoadjuvant combination chemotherapy of tranilast in advanced esophageal squamous cell carcinoma: Phase I/II study (TNAC). 
   <italic>Medicine</italic>. 2020;99:50(e23633).
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="financial-disclosure">
  <p>Funding: This study is funded by the Medical office, Division of Digestive Surgery, Department of Surgery, Kyoto Prefectural University of Medicine.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>Contact for Public and Scientific Queries and the investigator in charge of statistical analysis: AS.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>The physicians in charge of monitoring: RM</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>Countries of Recruitment: The recruitment has started in Japan at Novemver 5, 2019</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>Ethics Review: The study was approved by Kyoto Prefectural University of Medicine, Clinical Research Review Board in August 30, 2019 (Number: CRB5180001).</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>The Date of Registration in Primary Registry: November 5, 2019.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>Completion date of the study: March 31, 2029.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>Protocol version 1 (November 5, 2019).</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="equal">
  <p>AS and MK contributed equally to this work.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="COI-statement">
  <p>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="con">
  <p>The results of the present trial will be published by the selected author according to contributions for the achievement of the trail.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>Data sharing not applicable to this article as no datasets were generated or analyzed during the current study.</p>
 </fn>
</fn-group>
