<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In female wild ungulates, adverse side effects following a single immunization against GnRH appear to be minimal. Evaluation of biological side effects has been reported for numerous wild ungulate species including white-tailed deer [
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref013" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>, 
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref034" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>], elk [
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref015" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>, 
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref016" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>, 
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref035" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>], feral pigs [
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref036" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>], bison [
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref021" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>], and free-ranging horses [
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref017" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>, 
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref024" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]. A summary of results from these investigations indicate that GonaCon is reversible, safe for use in pregnant females, does not significantly change social behaviors [
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref037" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>] or negatively affect neonatal development, survival, or maturation [
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref015" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>, 
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref035" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>]. No adverse effects of vaccination have been shown to be related to general health, body condition, blood chemistry parameters, or hematology of treated animals. The most apparent pathological side effect has been the development and persistence of non-debilitating granulomatous and often purulent inflammation at the site of injection. In all studies, where post-mortem examinations have been conducted, injection-site lesions were pervasive, but in some species, such as white-tailed deer and elk, they were not apparent antemortem. Likewise, in cases where injection-site reactions have been documented, no clinical evidence of lameness, impaired mobility, or depression, have been reported [
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref013" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>, 
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref015" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>–
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref017" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>, 
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref021" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>, 
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref024" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>, 
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref034" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>, 
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref035" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>].
</p>
