<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="case-report"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.3 20070202//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName journalpublishing.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.3?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName jp2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Front Med (Lausanne)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Front Med (Lausanne)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Front. Med.</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Frontiers in Medicine</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2296-858X</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Frontiers Media S.A.</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">7987664</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fmed.2021.641948</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Medicine</subject><subj-group><subject>Case Report</subject></subj-group></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Case Report: Premature Ventricular Beats-Induced Chronic Cough and Cough Syncope</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>Yue</given-names></name><uri xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://loop.frontiersin.org/people/1171499/overview"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Hua</surname><given-names>Wen</given-names></name></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Na</given-names></name><xref ref-type="corresp" rid="c001"><sup>*</sup></xref><xref ref-type="author-notes" rid="fn002"><sup>&#x02020;</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Huaqiong</given-names></name><xref ref-type="corresp" rid="c002"><sup>*</sup></xref><xref ref-type="author-notes" rid="fn002"><sup>&#x02020;</sup></xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff><institution>Key Laboratory of Respiratory Disease of Zhejiang Province, Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, Second Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University School of Medicine</institution>, <addr-line>Hangzhou</addr-line>, <country>China</country></aff><author-notes><fn fn-type="edited-by"><p>Edited by: Piero Valentini, Universit&#x000e0; Cattolica del Sacro Cuore, Italy</p></fn><fn fn-type="edited-by"><p>Reviewed by: Gunnar N. Hillerdal, Karolinska University Hospital, Sweden; Danilo Buonsenso, Catholic University of the Sacred Heart, Italy</p></fn><corresp id="c001">*Correspondence: Na Li <email>linazju@zju.edu.cn</email></corresp><corresp id="c002">Huaqiong Huang <email>zr_hhq@zju.edu.cn</email></corresp><fn fn-type="other" id="fn001"><p>This article was submitted to Pulmonary Medicine, a section of the journal Frontiers in Medicine</p></fn><fn fn-type="other" id="fn002"><p>&#x02020;These authors have contributed equally to this work</p></fn></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>10</day><month>3</month><year>2021</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2021</year></pub-date><volume>8</volume><elocation-id>641948</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>15</day><month>12</month><year>2020</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>15</day><month>2</month><year>2021</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2021 Hu, Hua, Li and Huang.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2021</copyright-year><copyright-holder>Hu, Hua, Li and Huang</copyright-holder><license xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"><license-p>This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License (CC BY). The use, distribution or reproduction in other forums is permitted, provided the original author(s) and the copyright owner(s) are credited and that the original publication in this journal is cited, in accordance with accepted academic practice. No use, distribution or reproduction is permitted which does not comply with these terms.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract><p><bold>Background:</bold> Chronic cough is a common complaint that in rare cases can be caused by premature ventricular beats (PVCs).</p><p><bold>Materials and Methods:</bold> In this report, we present the case of a healthy 44-year-old female who presented persistent cough and cough syncope that was attributed to PVCs.</p><p><bold>Results:</bold> The cough disappeared after radiofrequency ablation, and no recurrence of arrhythmia or cough was observed.</p><p><bold>Conclusion:</bold> PVCs should be considered a probable cause of chronic cough and cough syncope in differential diagnosis.</p></abstract><kwd-group><kwd>chronic cough</kwd><kwd>syncope</kwd><kwd>premature ventricular beats</kwd><kwd>radiofrequency ablation</kwd><kwd>arrhythmia</kwd></kwd-group><counts><fig-count count="5"/><table-count count="0"/><equation-count count="0"/><ref-count count="15"/><page-count count="5"/><word-count count="1671"/></counts></article-meta></front><body><sec sec-type="intro" id="s1"><title>Introduction</title><p>Chronic cough, which is defined as a cough lasting for more than 8 weeks, is the most common symptom that accompanies a diverse range of respiratory diseases, non-respiratory conditions, and rarer conditions (<xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>, <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>). Various causes of chronic cough have been found, including upper airway cough syndrome, gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD)/laryngopharyngeal reflux disease, asthma, and non-asthmatic eosinophilic bronchitis (NAEB); however, almost 7% of all chronic coughs are unexplained (<xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>). This case report describes a patient with premature ventricular beats (PVCs) presenting with chronic cough and cough syncope.</p></sec><sec id="s2"><title>Case Presentation</title><p>This 44-year-old female presented with daily productive cough and expectoration for 4 years and experienced recurrence for more than half a year. The respiratory symptoms were predominantly nocturnal and more severe in the winter. She was diagnosed with chronic cough and was treated with cough medications for cough symptoms, which did not prevent the disease from worsening. Seven months prior, the chest film and spirometry test were almost normal; however, 4 months prior, the cough returned and the patient suffered from cough-related syncope for 3 h. She denied chest pain, chest distress, shortness of breath, heartburn, or acid regurgitation. She had no known allergies and denied smoking. The patient presented no abnormality on physical examination. White blood cell count, eosinophil count, and serum immunoglobulin E (39.1 IU/mL, normal value &#x0003c;100 IU/mL) were normal. Chest high-resolution CT (HRCT) (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1A</xref>), pulmonary ventilation and single-breath diffusing capacity of the lung for carbon monoxide were normal. The methacholine challenge test for bronchial hyperreactivity was negative (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1B</xref>). In pulmonary function testing, the forced vital capacity (FVC) was 2.99 L (100.9% of predicted value), the forced expiratory volume in 1 s (FEV<sub>1</sub>) was 2.45 L (96.5% of predicted value), and the FEV<sub>1</sub>/FVC ratio was 81.99% (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1C</xref>). The patient's electrocardiogram (ECG) showed normal sinus rhythm with frequent premature ventricular beats (PVCs) (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">Figure 2</xref>). The 24 h-Holter ECG monitor showed normal sinus rhythm with 27553 PVCs (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">Figure 3</xref>). The frequent occurrence of PVCs was associated with repetitive coughing. Two-dimensional color echocardiography was normal except for trivial regurgitant flow (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F4">Figure 4</xref>). Subsequent treatment with oral antiarrhythmic drugs was ineffective. Therefore, radiofrequency ablation of the arrhythmogenic focus was proposed. Surprisingly, cough disappeared after radiofrequency ablation, and no recurrence of arrhythmia or cough was observed (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F5">Figure 5</xref>).</p><fig id="F1" position="float"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>The examination of Chest high-resolution CT <bold>(A)</bold>, pulmonary function <bold>(B)</bold> and methacholine challenge test <bold>(C)</bold> in the patient.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fmed-08-641948-g0001"/></fig><fig id="F2" position="float"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>Electrocardiogram (ECG) showing normal sinus rhythm with premature ventricular complexes (PVCs).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fmed-08-641948-g0002"/></fig><fig id="F3" position="float"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>24 h-Holter monitoring showing normal sinus rhythm with premature ventricular complexes (PVCs) during coughing.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fmed-08-641948-g0003"/></fig><fig id="F4" position="float"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>Doppler echocardiogram recordings of blood flow during sinus rhythm and premature ventricular complexes (PVCs).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fmed-08-641948-g0004"/></fig><fig id="F5" position="float"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>ECG showing sinus rhythm after successful RF application.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fmed-08-641948-g0005"/></fig></sec><sec sec-type="discussion" id="s3"><title>Discussion</title><p>We report the case of a 44-year-old female who presented to our hospital for PVCs with chronic cough and cough syncope. Symptoms were resolved immediately with the suppression of the PVCs, supporting the causal relationship. The mechanism is uncertain. It has been proposed that PVC-induced cough happens due to the cardiopulmonary reflex (<xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>). Sebastian and his colleagues reported that a patient had premature ventricular complex-induced chronic cough and cough syncope and speculated that the cough reflex was triggered by stimulating sympathetic innervation in the right ventricular outflow tract or pulmonary artery (<xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>). Nimii et al. suggested PVC- induced haemodynamic changes in the pulmonary circulation as factors inducing chronic cough (<xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>). Another mechanism is the cough reflex, which either directly activates C-fibers in the left ventricular wall or distends the pulmonary artery and activates cough receptors as a result of augmented pulmonary blood flow following PVCs (<xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>).</p><p>At present, many mechanisms have been reported to be associated with cough syncope (<xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>). We suspect that pronounced hypotension and an inappropriate cough-triggered blood pressure-heart rate relationship during PVCs could contribute to syncope and reduce cerebral flow due to vagal modulation (<xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>, <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>).</p><p>Approximately 5% of patients with PVCs present with chronic cough (<xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>). In addition, some less common conditions also occur with chronic cough, such as idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis, eosinophilic bronchitis, and sarcoidosis. These were concluded to be the cause for chronic cough.</p></sec><sec sec-type="conclusions" id="s4"><title>Conclusion</title><p>Our patient's case demonstrated PVC-induced cough and cough syncope in a single healthy patient. We suspect that the PVCs might be responsible for coughing in our patient. Even though cough is a rare symptom, it is necessary to explain potential mechanisms between cough and PVC or other arrhythmias. PVCs should be considered a probable cause of chronic cough in the clinical setting.</p></sec><sec sec-type="data-availability" id="s5"><title>Data Availability Statement</title><p>The original contributions presented in the study are included in the article/supplementary material, further inquiries can be directed to the corresponding author/s.</p></sec><sec id="s6"><title>Ethics Statement</title><p>The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the Institutional Review Board for Human Studies of Second Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University School of Medicine (Hangzhou, China). The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. Written informed consent was obtained from the individual(s) for the publication of any potentially identifiable images or data included in this article.</p></sec><sec id="s7"><title>Author Contributions</title><p>YH examined the patient, ordered the needed tests, interpreted the data, and was a major contributor in finalizing the manuscript. WH interpreted the data and analyzed the results. NL and HH collected the needed data, analyzed and interpreted the results, and was a major contributor in finalizing the manuscript, and submitting it for publication. All authors read and approved the final manuscript.</p></sec><sec sec-type="COI-statement" id="conf1"><title>Conflict of Interest</title><p>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</p></sec></body><back><ack><p>We thank the patient for allowing us to publish this report.</p></ack><fn-group><fn fn-type="financial-disclosure"><p><bold>Funding.</bold> This work was supported in part by the General Project (grant nos. 81800074, 81901454) from the National Natural Science Foundation of China and the Youth Foundation Project of Zhejiang Province of China (grant no. LQ18H010002).</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="B1"><label>1.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Irwin</surname><given-names>RS</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Introduction to the diagnosis and management of cough: ACCP evidence-based clinical practice guidelines</article-title>. <source>Chest</source>. (<year>2006</year>) <volume>129</volume>:<fpage>25S</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>27S</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1378/chest.129.1_suppl.25S</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16428688</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B2"><label>2.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name><name><surname>Woodcock</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Chronic cough</article-title>. <source>N Engl J Med.</source> (<year>2016</year>) <volume>375</volume>:<fpage>1544</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>51</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1056/NEJMcp1414215</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27797316</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B3"><label>3.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Pratter</surname><given-names>MR</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Overview of common causes of chronic cough: ACCP evidence-based clinical practice guidelines</article-title>. <source>Chest</source>. (<year>2006</year>) <volume>129</volume>:<fpage>59S</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>62S</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1378/chest.129.1_suppl.59S</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 16428693?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16428693</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B4"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Morice</surname><given-names>AH</given-names></name><name><surname>Fontana</surname><given-names>GA</given-names></name><name><surname>Sovijarvi</surname><given-names>AR</given-names></name><name><surname>Pistolesi</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>KF</given-names></name><name><surname>Widdicombe</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>The diagnosis and management of chronic cough</article-title>. <source>Eur Respir J.</source> (<year>2004</year>) <volume>24</volume>:<fpage>481</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>92</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1183/09031936.04.00027804</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15358710</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B5"><label>5.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Stec</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Dabrowska</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Zaborska</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Bielicki</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Maskey-Warzechowska</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Tarnowski</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Premature ventricular complex-induced chronic cough and cough syncope</article-title>. <source>Eur Respir J.</source> (<year>2007</year>) <volume>30</volume>:<fpage>391</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>4</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1183/09031936.00062606</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 17666562?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17666562</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B6"><label>6.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Stec</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name><name><surname>Grabczak</surname><given-names>EM</given-names></name><name><surname>Bielicki</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Zaborska</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Krenke</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Krynski</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Diagnosis and management of premature ventricular complexes-associated chronic cough</article-title>. <source>Chest.</source> (<year>2009</year>) <volume>135</volume>:<fpage>1535</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>41</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1378/chest.08-1814</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 19318662?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19318662</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B7"><label>7.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Nimii</surname><given-names>AKY</given-names></name><name><surname>Sumita</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Okano</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Tambara</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name><surname>Fujita</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Cough reflex by ventricular premature contractions</article-title>. <source>Int Heart J.</source> (<year>2005</year>) <volume>46</volume>:<fpage>923</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>6</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1536/ihj.46.923</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 16272784?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16272784</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B8"><label>8.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hasdemir</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Musayev</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><name><surname>Kehribar</surname><given-names>DY</given-names></name><name><surname>Kartal</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Can</surname><given-names>LH</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Chronic cough and tachycardia-induced cardiomyopathy in a patient with idiopathic frequent, monomorphic premature ventricular contractions</article-title>. <source>Pacing Clin Electrophysiol.</source> (<year>2013</year>) <volume>36</volume>:<fpage>e156</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>8</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1540-8159.2011.03236.x</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 21967685?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21967685</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B9"><label>9.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Avramov</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name><surname>Sztriha</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name><surname>Makai</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Jambrik</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Rudas</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name><surname>Vecsei</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>[Mechanism of cough syncope]</article-title>. <source>Orv Hetil.</source> (<year>2004</year>) <volume>145</volume>:<fpage>1625</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1627</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15384860</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B10"><label>10.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Breathnach</surname><given-names>CS</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Cough syncope&#x02013;the mechanism in two cases</article-title>. <source>J Ir Med Assoc.</source> (<year>1964</year>) <volume>55</volume>:<fpage>15</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>16</lpage>.<?supplied-pmid 14157048?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14157048</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B11"><label>11.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Krediet</surname><given-names>CT</given-names></name><name><surname>Wieling</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name><surname>Edward</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Sharpey-Schafer was right: evidence for systemic vasodilatation as a mechanism of hypotension in cough syncope</article-title>. <source>Europace.</source> (<year>2008</year>) <volume>10</volume>:<fpage>486</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>8</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/europace/eun022</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 18310080?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18310080</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B12"><label>12.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McIntosh</surname><given-names>HD</given-names></name><name><surname>Estes</surname><given-names>EH</given-names></name><name><surname>Warren</surname><given-names>JV</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>The mechanism of cough syncope</article-title>. <source>Am Heart J.</source> (<year>1956</year>) <volume>52</volume>:<fpage>70</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>82</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0002-8703(56)90119-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">13326836</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B13"><label>13.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Benditt</surname><given-names>DG</given-names></name><name><surname>Samniah</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Pham</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Sakaguchi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Lurie</surname><given-names>KG</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Effect of cough on heart rate and blood pressure in patients with &#x0201c;cough syncope&#x0201d;</article-title>. <source>Heart Rhythm.</source> (<year>2005</year>) <volume>2</volume>:<fpage>807</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>13</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.hrthm.2005.04.022</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 16051114?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16051114</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B14"><label>14.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Malkoff</surname><given-names>MD</given-names></name><name><surname>Gomez</surname><given-names>CR</given-names></name><name><surname>Myles</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Cruz-Flores</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Cerebrovascular hemodynamic inefficiency of premature ventricular contractions</article-title>. <source>Angiology.</source> (<year>1996</year>) <volume>47</volume>:<fpage>51</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>6</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/000331979604700107</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 8546345?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8546345</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B15"><label>15.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Waldmann</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name><surname>Combes</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Narayanan</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name><surname>Sharifzadehgan</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Bouzeman</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Beganton</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Cough Syncope</article-title>. <source>Am J Med.</source> (<year>2017</year>) <volume>130</volume>:<fpage>e295</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>6</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.amjmed.2017.01.050</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28238688</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>