<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<table-wrap id="T1" position="float">
 <label>TABLE 1</label>
 <caption>
  <p>Author Submission Guidelines Relevant to Conflict of Interest Disclosures.</p>
 </caption>
 <table frame="hsides" rules="groups" cellspacing="5" cellpadding="5">
  <thead>
   <tr>
    <td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Journal</td>
    <td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">COPE member</td>
    <td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Conflict of Interest Policy from Author Submission Guidelines</td>
   </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
   <tr>
    <td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
     <italic>Behavior Modification</italic>
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td>
    <td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">No policy on journal website</td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
     <italic>Journal of Applied Behavior Analysis</italic>
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">No</td>
    <td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">No policy on journal website</td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
     <italic>Behavior Analysis in Practice/Journal of Behavioral Education/The Analysis of Verbal Behavior/The Psychological Record</italic>
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td>
    <td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Authors are requested to disclose interests 
     <italic>that are directly or indirectly related to the work submitted for publication</italic>. Interests within the last 3 years of beginning the work (conducting the research and preparing the work for submission) should be reported. Interests outside the 3-year time frame must be disclosed if they could reasonably be perceived as influencing the submitted work. Disclosure of interests provides a complete and transparent process and helps readers form their own judgments of potential bias. This is not meant to imply that a financial relationship with an organization that sponsored the research or compensation received for consultancy work is inappropriate …
    </td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
    <td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
    <td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
     <bold>Employment:</bold> Recent (while engaged in the research project), present or anticipated employment by any organization that may gain or lose financially through publication of this manuscript. This includes multiple affiliations (if applicable) …
    </td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
    <td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
    <td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
     <bold>Non-financial interests:</bold> In addition, authors are requested to disclose interests that go beyond financial interests that could impart bias on the work submitted for publication such as professional interests, personal relationships or personal beliefs (amongst others). Examples include, but are not limited to: position on editorial board, advisory board or board of directors or other type of management relationships; writing and/or consulting for educational purposes; expert witness; mentoring relations; and so forth
    </td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
     <italic>Perspectives on Behavior Science</italic>
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Yes</td>
    <td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">All authors are requested to include information regarding sources of funding, financial or non-financial interests, study-specific approval by the appropriate ethics committee for research involving humans and/or animals, informed consent if the research involved human participants, and a statement on welfare of animals if the research involved animals (as appropriate)</td>
   </tr>
   <tr>
    <td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">
     <italic>Journal of the Experimental Analysis of Behavior</italic>
    </td>
    <td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">No</td>
    <td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">No policy on journal website</td>
   </tr>
  </tbody>
 </table>
 <table-wrap-foot>
  <attrib>
   <italic>COPE = Committee on Publication Ethics.</italic>
  </attrib>
 </table-wrap-foot>
</table-wrap>
