<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par25">In recent years, not only the feasibility of ASCT in the elderly has been disputed, but also its efficacy. Most studies are retrospective analysis [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>]; some are even before the era of novel agents as proteasome inhibitors (PI) and immunomodulatory drugs (IMIDs) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>], and others use matched pair comparison [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>]. Notwithstanding its limitations, these studies found similar toxicity, TRM, and non-inferiority in EFS, OS, or disease response to ASCT in elderly patients, even when considering a higher age threshold for older cohorts as 70 years [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>]. In prospective studies [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>], patients aged over 65 years do not have an inferior outcome when compared to younger cohorts, considering ASCT is a safe and effective treatment for elderly and fit MM patients, either before [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>] or in the present era of novel induction agents [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>], which highlights the impact on global outcome that ASCT represents as a component on treatment algorithm in this group of patients [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>]. Data is more challenging, considering that there are no randomized trials appropriate to conclude about ASCT in this particular population with the availability of newer effective drugs, namely monoclonal antibodies and new-generation PI or IMIDs [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>]. In our study, response after transplant, EFS, and OS did not differ according to age in transplanted patients. Elderly patients had the same benefit comparing to younger patients, either in deepening of response after autologous transplantation or in survival as EFS and OS were not significantly shorter. More so, when compared to the non-transplanted age-adjusted cohort, patients who were transplanted had a significant improvement in EFS and OS, despite having similar disease features. Even though our results seem favorable to transplanted elderly patients, this study shares some of the limitations mentioned above, specifically regarding its retrospective nature, non-randomization of patients, and the subjective categorization for transplant eligibility of elderly patients.
</p>
