<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par26">Another matter of discussion, when considering autologous transplantation in elderly patients, is the ideal dose of Melphalan before ASCT. In our analysis, we can see that elderly patients have more toxicity indeed in all parameters with higher doses of melphalan as in previously published data [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>]. There is no consensus in the MM community, as some authors defend the use of an intermediate dose of 100 or 140 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup> demonstrating equal efficacy in CR rates, EFS, or OS but with lower toxicity [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>] or even lower TRM [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>]; other authors are in favor of MEL200 as they did not find any excessive toxicity or worse disease outcomes [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>]; and others conclude that reduced doses of melphalan can benefit selected cases, but higher doses are preferred [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>]. A recent prospective French study [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>] demonstrated that there was no difference in myelotoxicity, infections, TRM, or disease response between MEL200 and MEL140, but it was noticed that patients treated with MEL200 had better EFS rate. In our analysis, even though it was not statistically significant, we also noted a trend to a better EFS rate in MEL200 elderly patients when compared to elderly patients treated with reduced doses of melphalan (62 months vs 45 months). However, once again, this was a retrospective analysis of a small and highly selected group of elderly patients with no standardized approach, which limits its statistical power.
</p>
