<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par21">The VCd combination has been studied with different dosing schedules and intensity of all the three drugs. The initial combination by Reeder et al used twice weekly bortezomib along with intense dexamethasone dosing, and resulted in high response rates, but more toxicity related to the intense steroid schedule
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>
 </sup>. This was modified and a second cohort was studied with less intense steroids dosing and higher bortezomib dose (1.5 mg/m2) given once weekly, with comparable response rates
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>
 </sup>. The overall response rate was nearly 90% among the entire study cohort. The EVOLUTION trial also examined VCd with twice weekly bortezomib and with two different schedules of cyclophosphamide, one given 2 of the 3 weeks and another (modified VCd) with cyclophosphamide every week. The efficacy seen here is comparable with that observed with the VCD regimen in that trial: 75% for the VCd, though a 100% response was seen among the 17 patients treated with modified VCd. One of the largest trials with VCd was the phase 3 French trial comparing VCd with VTd, where bortezomib was given twice weekly with 500 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup> of cyclophosphamide and pulsed dose dexamethasone. The overall response rate was 83% in an intent to treat analysis among the VCd group, albeit with 4 cycles of therapy as this trial was intended to compare the two regimens for induction therapy prior to transplant. The current regimen is less intense compared to the VCd regimens studied, with weekly PI, weekly Dexamethasone and lower dose of cyclophosphamide (400 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup>). Also, the current trial included transplant eligible and non-eligible patients with patients up to 88 years of age and despite this the regimen was well tolerated with good efficacy. It is also important to compare and contrast the results with that seen with the VTd combination. This triplet has been extensively used in Europe and Asian countries, particularly given the cost and the access to lenalidomide. In the phase 3 trial, the response rates were significantly higher for the VTd regimen, making it an effective induction therapy. However, the neurotoxicity was considerable making it less acceptable to the older patient population and in those prolonged therpay is being considered.
</p>
