<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A 50-year-old woman, former smoker with a negative medical history, went to the emergency room in March 2020 for pain in the neck and left arm. No dyspnea or cough were reported. At clinical examination the upper left arm and the neck showed swelling edema and redness. Blood tests showed leukocytosis, C-reactive Protein and D-dimer elevated. SARS-CoV-2 and H1N1 nasal swabs were negative. An eco-color-doppler showed left upper extremity deep vein thrombosis (UEDVT). The anatomical extension of the thrombosis was up to the left axillary vein, left subclavian vein, left jugular vein. The patient was therefore treated with Low Molecular Weight Heparin (Enoxaparin) 8000 IU BID. The UEDVT was due to a mass in the upper anterior mediastinum compressing and displacing the left anonymous vein evident at a contrast medium Chest Computed Tomography (CT) (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1</xref>). Pulmonary Embolisms (PE) of the Right Lower Lobe (RLL) and Left Upper Lobe (LUL) were also present. At a PET-CT (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">Figure 2</xref>) an intense uptake of the mediastinal mass was evident suggesting a lymphoproliferative disease or lymph nodes' metastasis. An ultrasound-guided left supraclavicular lymph node biopsy was performed with negative culture and histological results. A surgical mediastinal mass biopsy by VATS was therefore planned, but a new SARS-CoV-2 nasal swab was positive. This, together to the pulmonary embolism, prompted us to delay the procedure. The patient was relocated in a dedicated SARS-CoV-2 department where she was treated with azithromycin and hydroxychloroquine for 10 days and long-term anticoagulation therapy. The patient was discharged in home isolation protocol 24 days after access (11 from positivity). After the execution of 2 negative SARS-CoV-2 control nasal swabs, respectively, 15 and 20 days after discharge, the patient was revaluated for the surgical procedure. Because the previous PET-CT dated back a couple of months before it was repeated. A complete regression of the mediastinal lesion was evident, confirmed also by a contrast medium CT, that showed also a resolution of the UEDVT.
</p>
