<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A number of studies have shown that pride may be influenced by culture (Stipek et al., 
 <xref rid="B46" ref-type="bibr">1989</xref>; Mauro et al., 
 <xref rid="B34" ref-type="bibr">1992</xref>; Stipek, 
 <xref rid="B45" ref-type="bibr">1998</xref>; Eid and Diener, 
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">2001</xref>; Scollon et al., 
 <xref rid="B42" ref-type="bibr">2004</xref>; Neumann et al., 
 <xref rid="B38" ref-type="bibr">2009</xref>). Eid and Diener (
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">2001</xref>) identified the differences between individualistic cultures and collectivistic cultures with respect to self-reflective emotions (e.g., pride and guilt). Of relevance to the current study is the finding that the frequency and intensity of pride were lower in collectivistic cultures than in individualistic cultures. Because Eid and Diener (
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">2001</xref>) used scenarios involving personal achievements, it is not known whether group or collective pride showed the same pattern of cultural differences. Recently, Sznycer and colleagues conducted two cross-cultural studies on pride-eliciting situations: one (Sznycer et al., 
 <xref rid="B48" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>) involving 16 countries across four continents, but all being Western, Educated, Industrialized, and Democratic (WEIRD) cultures, and the other (Sznycer et al., 
 <xref rid="B49" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>) involving 10 non-WEIRD small communities across Central and South Americas, Africa, and Asia. They found a high level of cross-cultural similarity (mean 
 <italic>r</italic> = 0.81) within the WEIRD samples and a much lower level of agreement among the non-WEIRD samples (
 <italic>r</italic> = 0.21). It is also worth noting that like Eid and Diener (
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">2001</xref>), Sznycer et al. (
 <xref rid="B48" ref-type="bibr">2017</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B49" ref-type="bibr">2018</xref>) focused on individual pride (all 10 scenarios in their 2018 study and 22 of the 25 scenarios in their 2017 study were about individual pride, with only three in their 2017 study being about relational pride; no scenarios covered national pride).
</p>
