<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Regarding interventions that may enhance RTW, systematic reviews suggest that medication, enhanced primary care, and psychotherapeutic interventions aimed at symptom reduction [e.g., cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT)] do not improve RTW among employees on sick leave due to mental health problems (
 <xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>). In contrast, psychotherapeutic interventions that included a work-focused component showed encouraging results (
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>–
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>). While work-focused interventions differ with studies and generally consist of multiple components (
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>), successful interventions appear to combine an early, gradual RTW with work-focused CBT and/or problem-solving therapy (
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>). Gradual RTW means that employees resume their work step-by-step in terms of work hours and tasks until they have fully returned to work. Interestingly, interventions that were effective in terms of RTW did not result in larger reductions in psychological complaints compared with control groups (
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>). Despite some promising findings, interventions with a work-focused component did not always enhance RTW (
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>–
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>). A recent meta-analysis (
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>) suggests that work-directed interventions (occupational therapy and multi-component work intervention incorporating work modification and support) combined with a clinical intervention can be effective in reducing sickness absence and that enhancing occupational or primary care with CBT and structured telephone outreach with care management that includes medication has the potential to reduce sick leave; however, the number of related studies is small. Salomonsson et al. (
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>) performed a randomized trial that compared the effects of CBT, RTW intervention, and a combination of them (COMBO) on a stress subgroup (
 <italic>n</italic> = 152 with adjustment disorder or exhaustion disorder) and DepAnxIn subgroup (
 <italic>n</italic> = 59 with depression, anxiety disorders, or insomnia). The stress subgroup showed a superior reduction of stress-related symptoms after CBT compared to RTW intervention, but there was no significant difference between the COMBO and RTW intervention or CBT. Moreover, there was no difference between treatments with respect to days on sick leave the year after randomization. In the DepAnxIn group, there was no significant difference between treatments with respect to symptom reduction. With respect to days on sick leave, patients had 92 fewer days on sick leave after RTW intervention compared to CBT and 76 fewer days on sick leave after COMBO compared to CBT. Thus, RTW intervention may be more effective than CBT for the DepAnxIn subgroup rather than the stress subgroup, but RTW intervention often includes CBT, and it seems difficult to identify the specific effects of RTW intervention. In addition, sick leave days are important because it reflects directly mental and physical health and indirectly work stress, which is linked to the effects of RTW intervention.
</p>
