<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract id="Abs1">
 <p id="Par1">Autologous stem cell transplantation (ASCT) is still debatable in treatment of patients over 65 years with multiple myeloma (MM). We performed a retrospective analysis of newly diagnosed MM patients who underwent ASCT between January 2010 and July 2016. A non-transplanted group with similar clinical characteristics, aged 65–70 years old, diagnosed and treated in the same timeline was used for comparison. We analyzed a total of 155 patients, 132 of which underwent ASCT (≤ 65 years, 
  <italic>n</italic> = 103, median 56 years; &gt; 65 years, 
  <italic>n</italic> = 29, median 67 years) and 23 non-transplanted (median 68 years). Conditioning consisted of melphalan 200 mg/m
  <sup>2</sup> (MEL200) in younger patients and melphalan 140 mg/m
  <sup>2</sup> (MEL140) in half of elderly patients. Stratifying by age, there were no statistically significant differences concerning transplant-related myelotoxicity and non-hematopoietic toxicity; however, elderly patients conditioned with MEL200 had higher needs of transfusional support and more days of intravenous antibiotics. Those patients also had higher needs of transfusional support, higher grade of mucositis (
  <italic>p</italic> = 0.028), and more days of intravenous antibiotics (
  <italic>p</italic> = 0.019) than the elderly transplanted with MEL140. Global transplant-related mortality was 3.8%. Survival was not influenced by age. Non-transplanted elderly patients had comparable disease features, and induction response was similar in both groups (before ASCT in the transplanted cohort). Survival of transplanted elderly patients was superior to non-transplanted (OS, 59 months vs 30 months, 
  <italic>p</italic> = 0.037; EFS, 45 months vs 27 months, 
  <italic>p</italic> = 0.014). Selected elderly patients when transplanted have similar disease response and survival as younger patients. A higher dose of melphalan has more toxicity, but it is globally a well-tolerated procedure.
 </p>
</abstract>
