<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par68">The non-inclusion criteria are as follow: 
 <list list-type="bullet">
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par69">Visceral metastases as defined by FDG-PET (or F-Choline-PET for prostate cancer) and cerebral CT or MRI performed</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par70">Previous systemic therapy for metastasis for patients with metachronous metastasis. Prostate and breast cancer patients remain eligible if hormonal treatment was initiated 6 months before enrollment.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par71">All bone metastasis requiring surgical treatment (spinal cord compression, fracture, …)</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par72">More than 3 bone metastases as defined by NaF-PET or conventional SPECT-CT scan and spinal MRI (if spinal bone metastases on NaF-PET)</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par73">Previous cancer within the 5 years before inclusion (except basal cell carcinoma of the skin, in situ carcinoma of the uterine cervix)</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par74">Previous radiotherapy on bone metastasis (e.g: antalgic radiotherapy)</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par75">Patient enrolled in another therapeutic trial</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par76">Pregnant women or breast feeding mothers,</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par77">Hypersensitivity to the active substance (FDG and NaF or F-Choline for prostate cancer) or to any of the excipients</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par78">Contraindication to MRI (in case of spinal metastases)</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par79">Patients deprived of liberty or placed under the authority of a tutor. Patients with any psychological, familial, sociological or geographical condition potentially hampering compliance with the study protocol and follow-up schedule; those conditions should be discussed with the patient before registration in the trial. Patients unable to understand the purpose of the study (language, etc.).</p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
