<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<notes notes-type="author-contribution">
 <title>Authors' contributions</title>
 <p>AS contributed to the Patient Information Sheet, participated in trial design and development of the protocol, designed the study database and drafted the manuscript. AJA conceived and designed the study, participated in trial design, coordination and development of the protocol and contributed to the Patient Information Sheet. AH contributed to the Patient Information Sheet, participated in trial design, coordination and development of the protocol and helped to draft the manuscript. DC designed the study, contributed to the Patient Information Sheet and helped to draft the manuscript. KB contributed to the Patient Information Sheet, participated in trial design, coordination and development of the protocol, designed the study database and helped to draft the manuscript. GJ contributed to the Patient Information Sheet, participated in trial design, coordination and development of the protocol and helped to draft the manuscript. CW contributed to the Patient Information Sheet and development of the protocol. JS contributed to the Patient Information Sheet and development of the protocol. MG contributed to the Patient Information Sheet and development of the protocol. JC contributed to the Patient Information Sheet and development of the protocol. KY contributed to coordination and development of the protocol and to the Patient Information Sheet. MD contributed to the Patient Information Sheet and development of the protocol. RO contributed to the Patient Information Sheet and development of the protocol. MC conceived and designed the study, coordination and development of the protocol and contributed to the Patient Information Sheet. GC conceived and designed the study, coordinated and developed the protocol, contributed to the Patient Information Sheet and helped to draft the manuscript. All authors read and approved the final manuscript. The trial will comply with the authorship criteria recommended by the International Committee of Medical Journal Editors.</p>
</notes>
