<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A worker may also be motivated to work hard if they expect the manager to adhere to a social norm of hard work. Under such conditions, the worker may expect that effort will be rewarded, irrespective of output. This latter point is related to the third ethical theory that informs moral judgment: virtue ethics. Virtue ethics is less concerned with evaluating actions and more concerned with evaluating people and whether they possess moral traits. A growing body of psychological research suggests that people intuitively and automatically make inferences about people’s moral traits (
 <xref rid="B54" ref-type="bibr">Todorov and Uleman, 2003</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B56" ref-type="bibr">Willis and Todorov, 2006</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B20" ref-type="bibr">Fiske et al., 2007</xref>). This tendency is observed across cultures (
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">Choi and Nisbett, 1998</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B34" ref-type="bibr">Lieberman et al., 2005</xref>) and even in young children (
 <xref rid="B25" ref-type="bibr">Hamlin et al., 2007</xref>). Observing effort is especially salient in judgments of virtue (
 <xref rid="B46" ref-type="bibr">Robinson et al., 2017</xref>), as effort influences people’s perception of the worker’s goals, intentions, and moral character (
 <xref rid="B40" ref-type="bibr">Pizarro and Tannenbaum, 2011</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B55" ref-type="bibr">Uhlmann et al., 2015</xref>). According to 
 <xref rid="B27" ref-type="bibr">Heider’s (1958)</xref> classical work, exertion of effort (i.e., how hard a person is trying to do something) signals a worker’s motivational force and the relative importance of the goal to the worker. Later research has supported the assertion that people infer goals from effortful behavior (
 <xref rid="B26" ref-type="bibr">Hassin et al., 2005</xref>). Many studies have highlighted the mediating role of the attribution of motivation in the judgment of moral character (
 <xref rid="B45" ref-type="bibr">Reeder and Spores, 1983</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B44" ref-type="bibr">Reeder et al., 2002</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B43" ref-type="bibr">Reeder, 2009</xref>). The more effort exerted by the worker, the more likely perceivers are to make inferences about the goal of the worker (
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">Dik and Aarts, 2007</xref>). Furthermore, the more effort a worker exerts in pursuing a goal, the more people perceive that goal as important to the worker (
 <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">Dik and Aarts, 2008</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">Bigman and Tamir, 2016</xref>). Thus, as long as the goal is seen as morally good, increased effort leads to improved judgments of moral virtue (e.g., 
 <xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">Cushman, 2008</xref>). If it is “the thought that counts” (
 <xref rid="B41" ref-type="bibr">Rand et al., 2015</xref>) and effort is taken as a proxy for that thought, then workers should be motivated to work hard in a game of luck in order to demonstrate their virtue. We thus hypothesize that:
</p>
