<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>ALS is an incurable neurodegenerative disease, and despite the substantial number of approaches that have been tested clinically, therapeutic options are still limited. Many hopes for the cure for ALS are placed in growth factors that show neuroprotective abilities and are known to promote the survival of neurons (e.g., NGF, BDNF, and others). However, their plasma delivery in pure protein form is rather ineffective, often due to their poor pharmacokinetic profiles and inability to cross the blood–brain barrier in substantial amounts [
 <xref rid="B34-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]. Therefore, in ALS, different stem and progenitor cell therapy approaches step forward, as stem cells are avid growth factors 'producers'. Human intrathecal transplantation of different stem cell populations, including bone marrow (BM)-derived hematopoietic stem and progenitor cells, have been previously attempted in patients with ALS, as well as in other neurological disorders, such as stroke, cerebral palsy, or injury of the spinal cord, with promising results and no relevant complications [
 <xref rid="B35-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>,
 <xref rid="B36-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>]. Importantly, in the experimental studies with stem cell therapies performed in ALS patients, different quantities of cells were transplanted, even in the same cohorts of subjects, due to the limited number of isolated cells available for a given patient, however, with good study outcomes [
 <xref rid="B37-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>]. In this study, we investigated the safety and feasibility of the administration of, previously described by our team [
 <xref rid="B15-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>], lineage-negative early hematopoietic progenitor cells derived from each patient's own bone marrow and their influence on the clinical course of ALS through the first, to our knowledge, intrathecal transplantation of Lin- cells at different doses to ALS patients. This selectively isolated cell population shows long-term self-renewal and paracrine secretion of various angiopoietic and neurotrophic factors [
 <xref rid="B14-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,
 <xref rid="B38-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>,
 <xref rid="B39-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>] on much higher levels than do other nucleated cells [
 <xref rid="B15-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]. Therefore, we have focused on potential/suggested trophic activity exerted by transplanted Lin- cells in a neural environment rather than on their direct engraftment and replacement of degenerating neurons in the nervous system affected by ALS. We have also tested for the first time whether Lin- cells transplantation might influence specific miRNA expression patterns observed in the CSF and in the peripheral blood plasma of ALS patients.
</p>
