<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Several studies in ALS mice models have correlated the increase in complement components with the disease progression, which might in part also explain our findings. In a recent study, deletion of the gene encoding C4 did not affect the disease course in high-expressing mutant SOD1G93A mice [
 <xref rid="B45-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">45</xref>]; however, the C3-dependent alternative complement pathway activation would still be possible. Local activation and increased expression of complement components signaling can contribute also to the recruitment of different mononuclear cells, including macrophages, that might accelerate the neuronal death, as observed in SOD1G93A mice [
 <xref rid="B49-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>]. In this notion, previously described selective inhibition of C5a–C5aR1 signaling ameliorated ALS pathology, reduced motor symptoms, and extended the survival of SOD1G93A mice [
 <xref rid="B50-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">50</xref>]. Likewise, in our recent study on the constitutive C3-deficiency in the neural retina, it was found that the lack of activated C3 resulted in lower expression of the cellular oxidative stress components and higher anti-apoptotic activity together with significantly increased expression of several gene sets associated with the maintenance of the physiological functions of the nervous system [
 <xref rid="B51-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">51</xref>]. Our actual observation of the significantly decreased C3 levels in the CSF in group I after Lin- cells administration may suggest temporary inhibition or at least a slowdown of neuroinflammatory processes, perhaps at least partially induced by Lin- cells transplantation. In contrast, the increase of C3 expression in group II of ALS patients might be a reflection of continuous local complement activation, which was not blocked sufficiently by the Lin- cells therapy approach. It should be stressed here that group II of ALS patients obtained a lower number of Lin- cells during transplantation in general compared to the ALS individuals representing group I in our study.
</p>
