<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Neurotrophic factors have been at the center of interest in ALS research for years. Neurotrophins are proposed as potential drugs and have been used in multiple approaches to decrease the disease progression in human, as well as in animal models [
 <xref rid="B52-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>,
 <xref rid="B53-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>,
 <xref rid="B54-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>,
 <xref rid="B55-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>,
 <xref rid="B56-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">56</xref>]. In our study, we have observed that a single injection of Lin- cells does not result in a prolonged change of BDNF and NGF levels in the CSF. In fact, due to the short half-life of both molecules, it might be the case that their concentrations in the CSF have changed shortly after cell injection, but in this study we examined the CSF collected before the Lin- cells transplantation and after one month, which could have been too distant a timepoint to observe actual changes in these proteins' concentrations. We can expect that the potential beneficial effects of elevated neurotrophins concentrations in the CSF of ALS patients may possibly be prolonged with repeated cell injections, but this approach would require additional cell isolations and further monitoring timepoints. Nevertheless, a portion of NTs released by the administered Lin- cells might as well infiltrate from the CSF through the BBB and thus temporarily influence the local NTs synthesis within other cells, mostly in patients from group I, who received a greater number of Lin- cells. Interestingly, we previously observed that the exposure of Lin- cells to NTs, could increase the local expression of other NTs, such as NT-3 expression following BDNF exposure [
 <xref rid="B57-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">57</xref>]. Therefore, the detected plasma concentration of BDNF and NGF might be a reflection of a systemic response after Lin- cells transplantation but could also arise from increased expression of NGF in skeletal muscle [
 <xref rid="B58-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">58</xref>] or altered astrocyte–motoneuron cross-talk [
 <xref rid="B59-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">59</xref>]. The observed results might also be due to generally low, often undetectable, levels of these proteins in the blood plasma [
 <xref rid="B60-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">60</xref>], which make NTs concentration assessment challenging. This hypothesis is supported by the fact that transcripts for BDNF are strongly downregulated in muscle biopsies from ALS patients [
 <xref rid="B61-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">61</xref>]; thus, the NTs released from Lin- cells may just cover the basic demands for these regulatory proteins in the nervous system and other tissues of ALS-affected human organisms.
</p>
