<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>MiRNAs operating as fine tuners of post-transcriptional events mediate neuronal gene expression, and their dysregulation becomes instrumental for understanding many diseases [
 <xref rid="B62-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">62</xref>,
 <xref rid="B63-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">63</xref>], including ALS. ALS is a motor neuron disorder, and it has been proven in various reports that ALS can be caused due to dysregulation of miRNAs and thus misexpression of proteins in cells. Recently, it has been postulated that disrupted signaling at the neuromuscular junction, caused by cytotoxicity associated with abnormal glutamate clearance and an overactive inflammatory response, results in neuromuscular degeneration. Dysregulation of key miRNAs triggers the alterations in motor neuron physiology, resulting in ALS pathology. Therefore, in the present study, we tested the expression profiles of five chosen miRNAs (myo-miRs, angio-miRs, and immuno-miRs) in the plasma and CSF of patients at two timepoints: before Lin- cells transplantation and a month after. Previous studies have also stressed that microRNA profiling in ALS patients is largely dependent on the disease duration and the patient's sex and age at onset [
 <xref rid="B64-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">64</xref>], and all these factors might have influenced our results. Overall, we have observed similarities in miRNA profiles between groups I and II. Because the number of Lin- cells transplanted varied between the groups, our miRNA results may suggest that the number of transplanted cells is not a main factor influencing miRNA profiles. However, the significant changes of several miRNA expression levels after Lin- cells administration may represent subtle neurological mechanisms modifications induced by the presence of biologically active Lin- cells in the area of the central nervous system after their intrathecal transplantation. Nevertheless, several miRNAs investigated in this study could potentially serve as biomarkers of disease activity and confirm previous observations in this field of molecular neurology.
</p>
