<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>MiR-378 is strongly implied in adipocyte gene expression and lipogenesis [
 <xref rid="B70-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">70</xref>]. Taken above, miR-378 might regulate adiponectin expression through a C/EBP binding site of the adiponectin promoter [
 <xref rid="B70-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">70</xref>]. MiR-378 is significantly upregulated in muscle cachexia, which can gradually develop in patients affected by ALS. The expression of miR-378 associates strongly and positively with catecholamine-stimulated lipolysis in adipocytes. This correlation is probably causal, because overexpression of miR-378 in human adipocytes increases catecholamine-stimulated lipolysis. Taken together, increased miR-378 expression in ALS patients could play an etiological role in degenerative cachexia-associated adipose tissue loss via effects on adipocyte lipolysis. In contrast, inhibition of miR-378 expression could attenuate stimulated lipolysis and reduce the expression of a set of genes (LIPE, PLIN1, and PNPLA2) encoding key lipolytic regulators [
 <xref rid="B71-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">71</xref>]. In our study, we observed the significant decrease of miR-378 expression in all ALS patients following Lin- cells transplantation, which might have an effect on the clinical outcomes in this patient cohort. Finally, some studies have also linked the aforementioned miR-378 with inflammation processes [
 <xref rid="B72-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">72</xref>,
 <xref rid="B73-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">73</xref>], as generally both lymphoid- and myeloid-related cells affect inflammation in a stimulating or inhibitory manner. In this notion, it is interesting whether the results of the miR-378 expression obtained in our study after cell transplantation may provide another potential explanation for the observed significantly lower concentration of pro-inflammatory C3 molecules in the CSF of ALS patients from group I, which obtained a greater quantity of Lin- cells during the Tx procedure.
</p>
