<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Peripheral blood, but not bone marrow-based MRD status, was highly predictive of PFS and OS in this study (4-year OS of 86.6% for MRD-negative patients compared to 28.6% for MRD-positive patients; (
 <italic>P</italic>&lt;0.0001). While for peripheral blood this is broadly in keeping with findings of the EU-MCL network for other treatment regimens,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b20-1040138" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>
 </sup> results concerning the prognostic impact of bone marrow molecular MRD, in patients treated with RiBVD, differ.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b20-1040138" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>
 </sup> The prognostic impact of MRD in patients treated with the R-BAC500 regimen has not been reported as yet.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b24-1040138" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>
 </sup> One avenue of investigation for clarification of these issues will be testing of ‘next generation’ cellular and molecular methods of MRD detection. Multi-parametric flow cytometry, although requiring very high levels of expertise, has been shown to be feasible and provide satisfactory sensitivity, when compared to highly standardized quantitative polymerase chain reaction methods in MCL.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b29-1040138" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>
 </sup> For molecular MRD, droplet digital polymerase chain reaction analysis is gaining interest
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b30-1040138" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>
 </sup> as is molecular MRD assessment in circulating cell-free DNA in B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b31-1040138" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>–
  <xref rid="b33-1040138" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>
 </sup> Combinatorial approaches (metabolic, cellular/molecular) as reported here for MCL, and in follicular lymphoma,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b34-1040138" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>
 </sup> will also be useful. Ultimately, careful investigation of residual disease, particularly by combinatorial approaches, will be needed to further refine MRD-driven precision medicine approaches in lymphoma, and other cancers.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b35-1040138" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>
 </sup>
</p>
