<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>We report the results of a prospective, phase II study by the French LYSA group. The study aimed to test the efficacy of six cycles of RiBVD, without maintenance therapy, for first-line treatment of MCL patients aged ≥65 years. With a median follow up of 52 months, the 2-year PFS of the 74 patients with analyzable data was 70%, thus reaching the primary objective of the study which was to improve median PFS by 6 months compared to the reported 18-month PFS for patients treated with R-CHOP.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b3-1040138" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,
  <xref rid="b4-1040138" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>
 </sup> The 4-year PFS (57.6%) observed here for RiBVD-treated patients is in line with the median PFS reported for the BR regimen (35.4 months) and other bortezomib-containing regimens such as 24.7 months for VR-CAP (bortezomib, rituximab, cyclophosphamide, doxorubicin, and prednisone) and 26 months for the RiPAD+C regimen (rituximab, bortezomib, doxorubicin, dexamethasone, and chlorambucil).
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b7-1040138" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>–
  <xref rid="b9-1040138" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>
 </sup> The favorable PFS with the RiBVD regimen may be related to the marked depth of response (75.7% rate of confirmed and unconfirmed complete responses according to the Cheson 1999 criteria; 78% rate of complete responses according to the Cheson 2007 criteria). Although not strictly comparable outside of a randomized trial, it is worth noting that complete response rates with other regimens are lower: R-CHOP (34%), BR (40%), VR-CAP (53%) and RiPAD+C (51%).
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b2-1040138" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,
  <xref rid="b3-1040138" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,
  <xref rid="b7-1040138" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,
  <xref rid="b8-1040138" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>
 </sup> The higher rate of complete responses (confirmed and unconfirmed) with the RiBVD regimen translated into higher molecular response rates [76% of patients (41/54) were MRD-negative in blood and/or bone marrow at the end of treatment] compared to published data for R-CHOP in older MCL patients [67% MRD negativity (54/81 patients)].
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b20-1040138" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>
 </sup> It is worth noting that 80% of patients in our study had high-risk MIPI scores and that 59% had ≥30% Ki67 positivity (range, 5% to 95% positivity) which appears high compared to the percentages in other studies in MCL patients over 65 years old (see 
 <italic>Online Supplementary Table S4</italic>).
</p>
