<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In 1946, Chambers first proposed using autologous bone implantation into the tarsal sinus to limit the excessive eversion of the subtalar joint. In 1952, Grice applied subtalar joint fusion and bone grafting into tarsal sinus for children with flatfoot. Post-operative complications such as degenerative arthritis of the adjacent joints and the walking difficulty on uneven roads occurred. Subsequently, Haraldsson and Lelivre modified the above methods and pointed out that it is essential to limit the subtalar joint's excessive valgus without the joint fusion. Since then, the concept prototype of the subtalar joint arthroereisis came into being. The ROM (range of motion) of the subtalar joint is greater in flexible flatfeet compared with healthy feet. Excessive valgus of the subtalar joint can cause the collapse of the medial foot arch, lateral subluxation of the talonavicular joint, and abduction of the forefoot, resulting in the inflammatory pain of the posterior tibial tendon insertion point, and the laxity of talonavicular joint capsule and spring ligament. Therefore, the symptoms of flexible flat feet are mainly medial pain, activity difficulty, inability to walk on uneven roads, and painful cramps. Most children can experience recovery with age, and only a small proportion of people have persistent symptoms. Surgery is indicated when they meet four or more of the following criteria (
 <xref rid="B24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>). ① No clinical or radiographic improvement after 2-year conservative treatment; ② Valgus angle of hindfoot &gt; 10°; ③ Achilles tendon contracture; ④ Viladot footprint type II, III, or IV; ⑤ Meary angle &lt; 10°; ⑥ Moreau-Costa- Bartani Angle &gt; 130° or Kite angle &gt; 25°. Besides, age is also an essential factor for surgery (
 <xref rid="B27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>). Most children can recover themselves before 8 years old, and surgery is not suitable for them. One purpose of subtalar joint arthroereisis is to reshape the bones and ligaments of the hindfoot during children's development. This process takes at least 2 years, and the remodeling time is not sufficient if the patient is more than 12 years. Therefore, surgery is indicated for children of 8 to 12 years. The patients in this study were 8–12 years old, and all met the above-mentioned surgical indications.
</p>
