<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Severe children flexible flatfeet have not only arch collapse and hindfoot valgus, but also talonavicular subluxation and abduction of the forefoot. For this deformity, subtalar joint arthroereisis alone cannot correct the deformity well. The traditional methods are mainly lateral extension osteotomy, such as Evans osteotomy or arthrodesis. Chou and Halligan (
 <xref rid="B32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>) reported that treatment of severe, painful pes planovalgus with hindfoot arthrodesis and wedge-Shaped tricortical allograft were reliable and could provide satisfactory correction of deformity, but arthrodesis could accelerate the degeneration of adjacent joints, so it should be used as the final treatment. Kumar and Sonanis (
 <xref rid="B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>) made a systematic review of the literature on lateral column lengthening in the treatment of children's pes planovalgus. The results showed that the incidence of complications of osteotomy was as high as 17.5% (18/103), including nerve related, pseudo joint, bone non-union and metal related complications accounted for 17.5% (18/103). For some specific cohorts' outcomes, there were some articles addressing the body weight effects on implant extrusion after the procedure that a higher BMI is related to implant extrusion and worse results after subtalar arthroereisis. Surgery improved the participation in physical activities as well as the emotional status and footwear issues (
 <xref rid="B33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>–
 <xref rid="B36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>). These studies have paid little attention to the importance of medial foot ligament structures, so if there is still significant forefoot abduction after subtalar arthroereisis, the medial spring ligament, the talonavicular capsule, and the superficial deltoid ligament tightening are indicated. The combined procedure can effectively correct remaining forefoot abduction and restore the mid-forefoot alignment. The 30 patients in this study did not have the above serious complications. Compared with the traditional osteotomy, the operation is straightforward, and the probability of post-operative complications is also reduced.
</p>
