<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Surgical excision is one of the main treatments for cutaneous SCC. Surgery requires consideration of recurrence rate, function preservation, patient expectation, and potential adverse reaction (
 <xref rid="B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>). The current literature on the surgical treatment of cutaneous SCC is conflicting, with no conclusive results on the effectiveness of various prognostic factors and surgical approaches for primary tumors (
 <xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>). According to the guidelines of care for the management of cutaneous SCC by the American Academy of Dermatology (
 <xref rid="B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>), for low-risk primary cutaneous SCC, standard excision is recommended with a margin width of 4 to 6 mm to a depth of the middle layer of subcutaneous adipose tissue by histologic margin assessment. For high-risk primary cutaneous SCC, Mohs micrographic surgery is recommended. Similar to this guidelines, for high risk cutaneous SCC that has not spread to lymph nodes, Mohs surgery or resection with complete circumferential peripheral and deep margin assessment or standard surgical excision is recommended by National Comprehensive Cancer Network (NCCN) guidelines (
 <xref rid="B21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>). Few studies have focused on the outcomes of SCC of the hand treated by surgical excision, and the use of amputation as a treatment for such SCC is controversial (
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>). In a retrospective study of 273 patients with SCC of the hand, the death rate from metastasis was 21% with amputation, compared with 7% with radiotherapy alone (
 <xref rid="B22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>). In the present case, the patient suffered from DD for 20 years with severe hand dysfunction and presented with a 1-year history of non-healing enlarging ulcerated nodule that was confirmed as SCC. According to the risk factors of NCCN guidelines (
 <xref rid="B21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>), the tumor occurred in an ulcer site on the hand with 20mm in size was of high-risk, and an axillary lymph node biopsy was required. Although the axillary lymph node biopsy was negative, the patient declined to receive Mohs surgery and selected amputation at the left wrist because of the serious functional impairment of her left hand and worried about recurrence.
</p>
