<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Up to 20–40% of patients with cancer, such as non-small cell lung cancer, breast cancer, melanoma, and renal cell carcinoma, will develop brain metastases (BM) (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>–
 <xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>). Primary and secondary brain tumors are often accompanied by peritumoral edema. Due to the limited intracranial space, peritumoral edema will further increase the intracranial pressure and aggravate clinical symptoms. Radiotherapy, as a basic component of the treatment of intracranial tumors, induces blood vessel damage and aggravates brain edema (
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>). The blood brain barrier can be damaged by tumor and radiotherapy which allows increased passage of plasma proteins and water into the extracellular compartment (
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>). In addition, angiogenic edema resulting from an increase of vascular permeability plays a key role in the development of intractable brain edema (
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>). The combination of edema caused by the tumor itself and radiotherapy is collectively referred to as intractable brain edema. Edema can increase intracranial pressure and cause associated neurologic symptoms, which seriously affects the quality of life of patients. Claudin and occludin can be downregulated by glucocorticoids in vasogenic edema to decrease capillary permeability and extravasation of fluid (
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>). Meanwhile, it can also decrease extent of cytokine-driven blood-brain barrier breakdown 
 <italic>via</italic> suppressing pro-inflammatory transcription factor NF-B and proinflammatory cytokines (
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>). Therefore, glucocorticoids, specifically dexamethasone, have become the gold standard for the management of tumor-associated edema (
 <xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>). However, glucocorticoids can lead to variety of adverse effects, including moon face, high blood pressure, high blood sugar, increased risk of infection, bone thinning (osteoporosis), and fractures, especially with prolonged use (
 <xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>). The investigation of other types of drugs is urgently needed to address this problem.
</p>
