<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Myeloproliferative neoplasms (MPN) are thought to be initiated and maintained from a mutated hematopoietic stem cell (HSC).
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b1-1040710" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>
 </sup> An acquired mutation in 
 <italic>JAK2</italic> (
 <italic>JAK2</italic>-V617F) is present in the majority of MPN patients.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b2-1040710" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>–
  <xref rid="b5-1040710" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>
 </sup> The interplay between the MPN HSCs and the stem cell niche is being increasingly recognized as crucial for the biology of the disease. Nestin-positive mesenchymal stem cells (nestin
 <sup>+</sup> MSCs) within the bone marrow (BM) niche are innervated by sympathetic nerve fibers and are important in regulating normal HSCs.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b6-1040710" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,
  <xref rid="b7-1040710" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>
 </sup> These nestin
 <sup>+</sup> MSCs are strongly reduced in BM from patients with MPN.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b8-1040710" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>
 </sup> In a mouse model of MPN expressing human 
 <italic>JAK2</italic>-V617F, this effect was found to be caused by early glial and sympathetic nerve damage and subsequent apoptosis of nestin
 <sup>+</sup> MSCs triggered by the mutant hematopoietic cells. 
 <italic>In vivo</italic> depletion of nestin
 <sup>+</sup> cells accelerated MPN progression. Conversely, MPN phenotype could be reversed by compensating for the sympathetic neuropathy by systemic administration of a β-3-sympathomimetic agonist. Mice with 
 <italic>JAK2</italic>-V617F-driven MPN treated with the β-3-sympathomimetic drug BRL37344 not only restored nestin
 <sup>+</sup> MSCs numbers, but also showed correction of thrombocytosis, neutrophilia, and BM fibrosis, and efficiently reduced mutant hematopoietic progenitor numbers in BM and peripheral blood (PB).
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b8-1040710" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>
 </sup> Treatment with BRL37344 also corrected the damage inflicted by the MPN clone on the stem cell niche and led to an increase in nestin
 <sup>+</sup> cells.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b8-1040710" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>
 </sup> Thus, β-3 sympathomimetic agonists represent a promising novel therapeutic approach to MPN by targeting the stem cell niche rather than the MPN clone itself.
</p>
