<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>After completion of the clinical trial, selected aliquots were thawed in batches and used for NK cell bright dim analysis, the Th17 assay, and the CD56-depletion experiment. NK bright and dim were assessed by staining samples for CD3-APC (UCHT-1), CD56-PE (B159), and CD16-FITC (CLB/FcGran1) all from BD Bioscience, then by flow cytometry determining the two different populations, which were visible on the CD3 and CD56 plots as the CD3
 <sup>−</sup>CD56
 <sup>bright</sup> or CD3
 <sup>−</sup>CD56
 <sup>dim</sup> populations, and gated using Flow Jo software (Tree Star Inc., Ashland, OR, USA). The Th17 analysis was done according to previously published protocol (
 <xref rid="B40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>), in brief, PBMC was incubated for at least 1 h after thawing in media containing RPMI1640, 10% FBS, 1% pen strep, 1% 
 <sc>l</sc>-glutamine. Samples were activated with soluble function grade anti-CD3 (OKT3 1.0 µg/ml; eBioscience, San Diego, CA, USA), soluble anti-CD28 (CD28.2; 1.0 µg/ml; eBioscience), neutralizing anti-IFN-γ and anti-IL-4 antibodies (5 µg/ml, R&amp;D systems, Minneapolis, MN, USA), and 10 ng/ml of recombinant human IL-23 (R&amp;D systems). The Th17 proportion was determined with CD3 and CD4 surface staining, followed by intracellular cytokine staining: samples were incubated for 4 h with ionomycin, phorbol myristate acetate, and brefeldin A, stained for CD3 (UCHT-1), and CD4 (RPA-T4), then fixed and permeabilized with a BD Cytofix/Cytoperm kit (BD Biosciences), followed by staining for IFN-γ (B27) and IL-17A (SCPL1362) antibodies from BD Biosciences. The proportion of Th17 cells was the percentage of cells with the phenotype CD3
 <sup>+</sup>CD4
 <sup>−</sup>IL-17A
 <sup>+</sup>IFN-γ
 <sup>−</sup>. The Th17 change was calculated by dividing the proportion after therapy by the proportion before therapy and multiplying by 100%. For the CD56-depletion, samples were thawed and incubated in media for at least 1 h. The samples were divided, half kept complete, the other half depleted with CD56 positive selection by magnetic activated cell sorting according to the manufacturer's instructions (Miltenyi Biotec, Auburn, CA, USA). Depletion was confirmed with flow cytometry using antibodies for CD3 (UCHT-1) and CD56 (B159). Complete or depleted samples were then incubated with functional grade anti-CD3 (OKT3 1.0 µg/ml; eBioscience), anti-CD28 (CD28.2; 1.0 µg/ml; eBioscience), and neutralizing anti-IFN-γ and anti-IL-4 antibodies (5 µg/ml, R&amp;D systems) for 4 days, then intracellular cytokine stained for IL-17A and IFN-γ, and supernatants analyzed for IL-17A using uncoated enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) kit for human IL-17A (eBioscience) and human IFN-γ (eBioscience).
</p>
