<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par42">In 2011, a case study reporting the placement of autologous BMSCs into the uterine cavity after curettage showed that the transplantation increased endometrial proliferation in a severe AS patient, who was then able to experience 8 weeks of pregnancy [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]. In 2014, a report on the subendometrial injection of CD34+ or cultured autologous BMCs in severe AS patients showed a slight increase in the endometrial thickness [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>]. In 2016, a case study was reported on 16 patients with refractory infertility who received autologous peripheral blood CD133+ cells into the spiral arteries of the uterus and were observed to experience endometrial reconstruction; two of the 16 patients with AS and one patient with a thin endometrium had live births [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>]. In the same year, a report on the transplantation of autologous menstrual blood-derived stromal cells into seven severe AS patients showed that two of them successfully conceived. In our previous study, we reported a successful transplanting of autologous mononuclear cells from the bone marrow/collagen complex into patients with severe IUA, who achieved pregnancies and live births after treatment [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]. In the current study, we report the results of the first phase I clinical trial of a clinical use-approved UC-MSC/collagen scaffold for the treatment of recurrent IUA. We demonstrate the clinical safety and efficacy of a clinical-grade UC-MSC/collagen scaffold. The UC-MSCs were obtained noninvasively. The hypoimmunogenic and nontumorigenic features of UC-MSCs make them especially advantageous for use in regenerative treatment [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>]. Therefore, UC-MSCs can occupy an intermediate position between the most versatile pluripotent ESCs/iPSCs and adult tissue-specific MSCs [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>]. Finally, but more importantly, it is easy to ensure quality control during the standardized production of UC-MSCs.
</p>
