<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>This patient developed leukemia 34 years after the exposure and experienced a long incubation period. The pathogenesis of leukemia may be different from that of total body irradiation. The skin of the patient's back was close to the X-ray detector probe for 30 min and was subjected to a large dose of local irradiation, resulting in penetrating injury from the skin of the back to the skin of the front chest. This resulted in local skin damage, as well as damage to the internal organs and hematopoietic tissues at the site. The gene mutation and chromosome aberration caused by DNA damage induced by ionizing radiation aggravated the instability of the cell genome that led to the loss of the normal growth regulation function of cells and promoted the malignant transformation of cells (
 <xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>). Relevant studies have shown that ionizing radiation can lead to cluster damage of DNA molecules and generate secondary DNA damage with the action of free radicals, which is difficult to repair, has a high error repair rate, and produces far-reaching biological effects (
 <xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>). The induction of chromosomal aberrations in human lymphocytes exposed to ionizing radiation provides a commonly used and quantifiable biological dosimeter that can reliably estimate the radiation dose to which people are exposed (
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>). In this case, chromosome aberration in peripheral blood lymphocytes was still detected within 20 years of follow-up after the exposure, and the distortion rate was maintained at 0.5%. The authors believe that regular medical follow-up is necessary for patients with acute radiation disease, especially for patients with continuous positive chromosome aberrations, and the possibility from aberrations and mutations to canceration cannot be ruled out. At the same time, in order to prevent the occurrence of similar accidents, radiological protection rules and regulations should be strictly observed in the workplace, to enhance the awareness of personal protection. Workers using radiographic detection should wear personal alarm devices, to detect accidental exposures in time, reduce and avoid occupational injuries, and protect the health and safety of workers.
</p>
