<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>This surgical intervention represents a unique approach to the management of a complex chondrosarcoma of the pelvis. The patient was given a general anesthetic and positioned in supine. The procedure commenced with a cystoscopy, bilateral retrograde pyelography and insertion of a left ureteral stent to alleviate obstruction. Significant distortion of the bladder and urethra were noted secondary to the external compression from the tumor. There was no local infiltration of the tumor into surrounding structures. The tumor was then approached via a longitudinal lower midline abdominal incision. Meticulous haemostasis was undertaken whilst dissection was performed to the level of the pubic body. This allowed the displacement of the pelvic viscera from around the tumor within the lesser pelvis, and detachment of the origins of the adductor musculature from the anterior external pelvic wall. At this stage, navigation pins were inserted into the iliac crest and registration of important bony pelvic landmarks with the computer navigation system was confirmed (Stryker Navigation System with Spinemap 3D 3.1 software®) (
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>) (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">Figure 2</xref>). Using navigation, the planned osteotomies were created through bilateral superior and inferior pubic rami to mobilize the tumor (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">Figures 3A,B</xref>). The tumor was carefully dissected from the bladder neck by rolling it forward away from the female pelvic viscera and surrounding internal pelvic neurovasculature and ultimately resected en-bloc from the patient without complication. Using the same navigation system, a preplanned segment of iliac bone was marked out on the ilium. This segment was matched in size and curve to the resected pubic bone using a pre-operative computer model. Osteotomy of the iliac graft was then computer-navigated (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">Figure 3C</xref>). The iliac crest graft was prepared with drill holes and secured with Arthrex fiber wire sutures (Arthrex FiberTape 2 mm ®) to the adjacent pubic rami (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">Figure 3D</xref>) (
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>). The right and left rectus abdominis musculature were sutured to the released ends of the right and left gracilis muscles. Two surgical suction drains were placed, one at the pubic resection site and the other at the iliac bone resection site. During the operation, the patient was transfused 4 units of packed red blood cells and 1 unit of fresh frozen plasma.
</p>
