<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par72">
 <list list-type="order">
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par73">Patients diagnosed with primary ALCL of the skin as the latest diagnosis (those with infiltration in other organs and a sALCL-like condition are regarded as eligible).</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par74">Those after the resection of all lesions.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par75">Those with active viral, bacterial, or fungal infection within 2 weeks before the initial administration of SGN-35.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par76">Those with ≥grade III heart failure (New York Heart Association (NYHA) severity classification), refractory coronary disease, arrhythmia, a left ventricular ejection fraction of &lt; 50%, angina pectoris, or acute ischemia or active conduction disorder on electrocardiography, or those with a history of myocardial infarction within 6 months before the initial administration of SGN-35.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par77">Those with refractory diabetes.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par78">Those with a history of other malignant tumors persisting for ≥3 years and complications. However, the following cancers are excluded:</p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
 <list list-type="bullet">
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par79">Completely resected non-melanoma skin cancer</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par80">Completely resected intraepithelial carcinoma</p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
 <list list-type="simple">
  <list-item>
   <label>7)</label>
   <p id="Par81">Those with intra-cerebral or meningeal infiltration.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>8)</label>
   <p id="Par82">Those with signs or symptoms suggesting progressive multifocal leukoencephalopathy.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>9)</label>
   <p id="Par83">Those with a history of severe hypersensitivity or allergy.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>10)</label>
   <p id="Par84">Human immunodeficiency virus antibody-, hepatitis B virus surface antigen (HBs) -, hepatitis B virus surface antigen antibody-, hepatitis B virus core antigen antibody-, or hepatitis C virus antibody-positive patients on a screening test. However, patients with a history of hepatitis B vaccination who are positive for HBs antibody alone will not be excluded.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>11)</label>
   <p id="Par85">Patients with liver cirrhosis.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>12)</label>
   <p id="Par86">Those in whom autologous stem cell transplantation was performed within 12 weeks before the initial administration of SGN-35.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>13)</label>
   <p id="Par87">Those in whom allogeneic stem cell transplantation was performed.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>14)</label>
   <p id="Par88">Those who received treatment for malignant tumors (radiotherapy, chemotherapy, and hormonal therapy) within 2 weeks before the initial administration of SGN-35. However, those who received biological preparations in a longer period: either 6 weeks before the initial administration of this drug or a period corresponding to 5-fold the half-life, will be excluded.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>15)</label>
   <p id="Par89">Those who received the systemic administration of adrenocorticohormones at a non-steady dose within 1 week before the initial administration of SGN-35.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>16)</label>
   <p id="Par90">Those who took drugs that inhibit CYP3A4 (clarithromycin, itraconazole, verapamil, and diltiazem) or ingested foods/supplements (such as grapefruit) within 1 week before the initial administration of SGN-35.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>17)</label>
   <p id="Par91">Those who took drugs that induce CYP3A4 (phenytoin, phenobarbital, rifampicin, carbamazepine) or ingested foods/supplements (such as St. John’s wort) within 2 weeks before the initial administration of SGN-35.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>18)</label>
   <p id="Par92">Those to whom other investigational drugs were administered within 4 weeks before the initial administration of SGN-35.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>19)</label>
   <p id="Par93">Those in whom medical instruments under a clinical study were used within 4 weeks before the initial administration of SGN-35.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>20)</label>
   <p id="Par94">Those with hypersensitivity to additives contained in the composition of SGN-35.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>21)</label>
   <p id="Par95">Pregnant (human chorionic gonadotropin-positive) or lactating patients.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>22)</label>
   <p id="Par96">Those who are not willing to conduct appropriate contraception from informed consent acquisition until 6 months after the final administration of the investigational drug.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>23)</label>
   <p id="Par97">Those with positive reactions on a pregnancy test at the time of screening.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>24)</label>
   <p id="Par98">Those in whom the chief investigator/investigators considered it difficult to perform this clinical study.</p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
