<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Several studies have demonstrated the potential usefulness of EEG as a biomarker related to treatment efficacy. Dawson et al. 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0013" ref-type="ref">13</xref> used EEG to measure treatment response to early intensive behavioral intervention based on the early start Denver model (ESDM) in a randomized controlled trial evaluating toddlers with ASD. Based on event related brain potentials (ERPs) to faces versus objects, it was found that the children who received ESDM behavioral intervention exhibited a faster neural response (shorter Nc ERP latency) when viewing faces than objects, whereas children receiving treatment as usual in the community showed the reverse pattern (shorter Nc latency to objects than to faces). Furthermore, children with ASD who had received ESDM showed a pattern of brain activity that was similar to a typically developing comparison group, characterized by increased cortical activation (reflected in decreased alpha power and increased theta power) while viewing faces compared with objects; the children receiving treatment as usual showed the reverse pattern. Normalized patterns of brain activity were correlated with improvements in social behavior. Faja et al. 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0014" ref-type="ref">14</xref> used face expertise training for individuals with ASD and found that the training was associated with improvement in recognition of inverted faces and timing of cortical responses recorded from ERPs. Additionally, Van Heck et al. 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0015" ref-type="ref">15</xref> used EEG markers of hemispheric symmetry to measure treatment response to the Program for the Education and Enrichment of Relational Skills in a randomized controlled trial for adolescents with ASD, finding that EEG symmetry was associated with more social contacts and knowledge and fewer ASD symptoms. These studies provide evidence that EEG is a promising efficacy biomarker in clinical trials for ASD.
</p>
