<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Although studies using EEG biomarkers in ASD clinical trials have primarily focused on alpha and theta activity, other frequency bands are relevant to ASD. Specifically, abnormalities in beta band activity (13–30 Hz), which has an established role in movement, movement preparation, and steady muscular contractions 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0028" ref-type="ref">28</xref>, 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0029" ref-type="ref">29</xref>, 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0030" ref-type="ref">30</xref>, 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0031" ref-type="ref">31</xref>, have been reported in ASD 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0016" ref-type="ref">16</xref>, 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0032" ref-type="ref">32</xref>, 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0033" ref-type="ref">33</xref>, 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0034" ref-type="ref">34</xref>, 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0035" ref-type="ref">35</xref>. Bangel et al. 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0036" ref-type="ref">36</xref> reported widespread reductions in beta phase synchrony in individuals with ASD during the presentation of globally coherent dot patterns, suggesting that disruptions in the beta band may contribute to the disrupted sensory and perceptual integration that is observed in ASD. Two studies have shown that beta band activity is disrupted during presentation of emotional faces in patients with ASD and typically developing individuals with high rates of ASD symptoms 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0037" ref-type="ref">37</xref>, 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0038" ref-type="ref">38</xref>. Another study found reduced long range beta connectivity in individuals with ASD during a visual name‐presentation task that included familiar names 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0039" ref-type="ref">39</xref>. Furthermore, reduced beta event related desynchronization during a motor imagery task was associated with ASD severity 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0033" ref-type="ref">33</xref>. Frohlich et al. 
 <xref rid="sct312347-bib-0040" ref-type="ref">40</xref> investigated EEG biomarkers in the 15q11.2‐q13.1 gene (Dup 15q syndrome), a genetic copy number variant that accounts for 1%–3% of ASD cases. Increased beta power in Dup15q patients compared to typically developing children was found, further supporting the use of beta band activity to characterize ASD and related conditions. Taken together, these findings suggest that beta band activity shows substantial promise as a potential biomarker for ASD, in addition to the commonly studied theta and alpha bands.
</p>
