<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ack>
 <title>Acknowledgements</title>
 <p>Support, project management and facilities to conduct the study were provided by Clinical Research Center, Umeå University Hospital. Thanks to the clinical trial unit in Umeå: Marja-Liisa Lammi Tavelin, Lisette Marjavaara, Emma Wede, Kristina Öjbrant, Ida Lundström and Anna Ramnemark for excellent ongoing help with the startup and continued work with the trial, thanks also to the Centre for Clinical Cancer studies at Karolinska Institute for skillful help (Sanna Nyström and Susanne Wallberg). We also thank Fredrik Granström at ITS (ICT Services and System Development at Umeå University) for helping us create the electronic Clinical Report Form, and also thanks to Sonja Huldén, judge of appeal, for legal support.</p>
 <p>Thanks also to all research personnel with all the work with starting up the trial at respective sites and for feedback to help us improve the trial: Frida Samuelsson, Jennie Bobeck, Mia Mickelsson, Helena Gisslén, Jenny Holm Fernström, Ann Carlstrand, Elisabeth Bengtsson, Kristina From, Sofia Sjöberg, Jennifer Amidi, Annika Löfgren, Suzy Lindberg, Malin Karlström, Mathias Cortés Rico, Malin Lindell, Beatrice Backman Lönn, Maria Casserdahl, Kerstin Almroth, Britt-Inger Dahlin, Ester Fridenström, Malin Hellgren, Rebecka Sundén , Ann-Charlotte Borgefeldt, Yvonne Pantzar, Cecilia Magnusson</p>
 <p>We thank the Data Safety and Monitoring board for taking on the responsibility of this important and crucial work to externally review the ongoing trial: Associate Professor Martin Eklund, Professor Annika Bergquist, Associate Professor Jan Adolfsson, Professor Lars Hagberg, Professor Jan-Erik Damber, and Senior Medical Advisor Helén Seeman-Lodding</p>
 <p>Thanks also to statistician Professor Marie Eriksson (Umeå Univerisity) for help with the randomization process.</p>
 <p>We also acknowledge the work from the biobanks in the different regions: Biobank West, Biobank North, Uppsala Biobank, Biobank facility at Malmö, Sundsvall, Linköping and Jönköping.</p>
 <p>The authors are grateful for the unconditional support received from Astellas Pharma Europe®. The trial is also funded by the Knut and Alice Wallenberg foundation (Andreas Josefsson)</p>
</ack>
