<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Oita Okanoue Hospital in Japan had a rehabilitation unit that conducted the RTW program. Strictly speaking, there were two programs—old and new. The old program was in effect from November 2013 to May 2017, and the new program has been implemented since June 2017. The last patient of this study started the new program on February 10, 2020, and this patient and other patients were followed up to September 1, 2020. The patients with new program were followed up for 577.4 ± 302.2 days (range: 62 to 1,096 days). The old program had entry criteria of Beck Depression Inventory scores equal to or &lt;12 and capability of pre-participation in pre-RTW program 3 times a week for 2 weeks, while the new one had entry criteria of Hamilton Depression Rating Scale scores equal to or &lt;9 and capability of pre-participation in pre-RTW program 3 times a week for 2 weeks. The schedule of the old program included office work, meeting, yoga, CBT, social skill training, and light sports, while that of the new program included an additional element of cognitive training such as operating a personal computer for composition, reading, calculation, and so on. Of the 77 participants (56 men and 21 women) in this study, 44 patients had attended the old program and 33 patients attended the new program. Their mean age was 43.2 ± 8.5 (standard deviation) years. The psychiatric diagnoses according to the International Classification of Diseases Tenth Revision were F31 (
 <italic>N</italic> = 9), F32 (
 <italic>N</italic> = 38), F34 (
 <italic>N</italic> = 1), F40 (
 <italic>N</italic> = 3), F41 (
 <italic>N</italic> = 1), F42 (
 <italic>N</italic> = 2), F43 (
 <italic>N</italic> = 21), F44 (
 <italic>N</italic> = 1), and F45 (
 <italic>N</italic> = 1). That is, there were 48 patients with mood disorders and 29 patients with anxiety disorders. The mean total work experience was 21.7 ± 9.7 years. The frequency of RTW program participation was 67.8 ± 41.2 times. Informed consent was obtained from 33 patients attending the new program, which was approved by the ethics committee of Oita University Faculty of Medicine, and the alternative opt-out method was applied to 44 patients attending the old program, which was approved by the ethics committee of Oita Okanoue Hospital.
</p>
