<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The design of the STAT2 trial resembled that of the STIM1
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b8-1031835" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
  <xref rid="b9-1031835" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>
 </sup> and TWISTER trials,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b10-1031835" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>
 </sup> with the aim of administering a TKI during a 2-year consolidation phase to obtain a sustained DMR before TKI discontinuation. In this trial, in contrast to the aforementioned studies, imatinib was replaced with nilotinib as the consolidation TKI therapy. However, the assessment of 
 <italic>BCR-ABL1</italic> and the definition of molecular recurrence in this trial are identical to those in the aforementioned studies.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b8-1031835" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>–
  <xref rid="b10-1031835" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>
 </sup> Nilotinib was administered instead of imatinib because previous studies had indicated that nilotinib could induce DMR in a greater number of patients than imatinib,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b1-1031835" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>–
  <xref rid="b3-1031835" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>
 </sup> thereby potentially increasing the number of patients who achieve successful TFR. The 2-year period of consolidation therapy in this study was selected as the STIM1
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b8-1031835" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
  <xref rid="b9-1031835" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>
 </sup> and TWISTER
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b10-1031835" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>
 </sup> trials required 2 years of sustained DMR before stopping imatinib therapy. Additionally, our retrospective study revealed that a DMR duration of at least 2 years was a significant predictive factor for successful TFR in Japanese CML patients.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b14-1031835" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>
 </sup> Therefore, the treatment duration for this trial involved a consolidation phase of 2 years, and sustained DMR without loss of MR
 <sup>4.5</sup> was confirmed by regular 
 <italic>BCR-ABL1
  <sup>IS</sup>
 </italic> RQ-PCR testing for 2 years.
</p>
