<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In this study, the identified predictive factor for successful 12-month TFR was UMRD with MR
 <sup>5</sup> before discontinuation of nilotinib. In the EURO-SKI trial, there were no differences in MMR status at 6 months after treatment stop between depths of molecular response (MR
 <sup>4.5</sup>
 <italic>versus</italic> no MR
 <sup>4.5</sup>).
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b15-1031835" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>
 </sup> However, our finding suggests that a deeper MR favors successful achievement of TFR in CML patients, which is consistent with data from previous studies.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b16-1031835" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,
  <xref rid="b17-1031835" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>
 </sup> Among four patients without TFR in the late TFR phase, in whom MR
 <sup>4.5</sup> loss occurred at 16, 16, 17, and 20 months, three patients had MRD before entering the TFR phase. It is difficult to determine the quantity of 
 <italic>BCR-ABL1</italic> mRNA below MR
 <sup>4.5</sup>/MR
 <sup>5</sup> because of the sensitivity of IS-RQ-PCR.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b18-1031835" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>
 </sup> However, UMRD with MR
 <sup>5</sup> before TFR is one of the minimum requirements for TFR and the sustained duration of DMR might be a surrogate marker for the magnitude of the MR or the eradication of MRD during TKI treatment.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b19-1031835" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,
  <xref rid="b20-1031835" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>
 </sup> Meanwhile, 1-year consolidation with either dasatinib or nilotinib, which are both second-generation TKI, was proposed in the DADI trial
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b11-1031835" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>
 </sup> and the ENEStop study,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b21-1031835" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>
 </sup> respectively. Although the 1-year consolidation enabled identification of enrolled patients who had sustained MR
 <sup>4.5</sup> and were eligible to stop treatment,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b21-1031835" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>
 </sup> it is still unknown whether 1 year of consolidation with a second-generation TKI is sufficient to achieve DMR/UMRD below MR
 <sup>4.5</sup>/MR
 <sup>5</sup> for TFR.
</p>
