<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.3 20070202//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName journalpublishing.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.3?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName jp2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Haematologica</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Haematologica</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="hwp">haematol</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Haematologica</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Haematologica</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">0390-6078</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1592-8721</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Ferrata Storti Foundation</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">6278989</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">29976742</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3324/haematol.2018.194571</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">1031806</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Article</subject><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Bone Marrow Failure</subject></subj-group></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Novel lineage depletion preserves autologous blood stem cells for
gene therapy of Fanconi anemia complementation group A</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Adair</surname><given-names>Jennifer E.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="af1-1031806">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="af2-1031806">2</xref><xref ref-type="author-notes" rid="fn1-1031806">*</xref><xref ref-type="corresp" rid="c1-1031806"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Chandrasekaran</surname><given-names>Devikha</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="af1-1031806">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Sghia-Hughes</surname><given-names>Gabriella</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="af1-1031806">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Haworth</surname><given-names>Kevin G.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="af1-1031806">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Woolfrey</surname><given-names>Ann E.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="af1-1031806">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="af2-1031806">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Burroughs</surname><given-names>Lauri M.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="af1-1031806">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="af2-1031806">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>Grace Y.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="af1-1031806">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Becker</surname><given-names>Pamela S.</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="af1-1031806">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="af2-1031806">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Kiem</surname><given-names>Hans-Peter</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="af1-1031806">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="af2-1031806">2</xref><xref ref-type="author-notes" rid="fn1-1031806">*</xref><xref ref-type="corresp" rid="c1-1031806"/></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="af1-1031806">
<label>1</label>Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center</aff><aff id="af2-1031806">
<label>2</label>University of Washington School of Medicine, Seattle, WA, USA</aff><author-notes><corresp id="c1-1031806"><bold>Correspondence:</bold><email>hkiem@fredhutch.org</email> or
<email>jadair@fredhutch.org</email></corresp><fn id="fn1-1031806"><label>*</label><p>JEA and H-PK contributed equally to this work.</p></fn></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><month>11</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epreprint"><day>05</day><month>7</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><volume>103</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>1806</fpage><lpage>1814</lpage><history><date date-type="received"><day>06</day><month>4</month><year>2018</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>04</day><month>7</month><year>2018</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright&#x000a9; 2018 Ferrata Storti
Foundation</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2018</copyright-year><license license-type="open-access"><license-p>Material published in Haematologica is covered by copyright. All rights are
reserved to the Ferrata Storti Foundation. Use of published material is
allowed under the following terms and conditions:</license-p><license-p><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/legalcode">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/legalcode</ext-link>.
Copies of published material are allowed for personal or internal use.
Sharing published material for non-commercial purposes is subject to the
following conditions:</license-p><license-p><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/legalcode">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/legalcode</ext-link>,
sect. 3. Reproducing and sharing published material for commercial purposes
is not allowed without permission in writing from the publisher.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri content-type="pdf" xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="1031806.pdf"/><abstract><p>A hallmark of Fanconi anemia is accelerated decline in hematopoietic stem and
progenitor cells (CD34 +) leading to bone marrow failure. Long-term treatment
requires hematopoietic cell transplantation from an unaffected donor but is
associated with potentially severe side-effects. Gene therapy to correct the
genetic defect in the patient&#x02019;s own CD34<sup>+</sup> cells has been
limited by low CD34<sup>+</sup> cell numbers and viability. Here we demonstrate
an altered ratio of CD34<sup>Hi</sup> to CD34<sup>Lo</sup> cells in Fanconi
patients relative to healthy donors, with exclusive <italic>in vitro</italic>
repopulating ability in only CD34<sup>Hi</sup> cells, underscoring a need for
novel strategies to preserve limited CD34<sup>+</sup> cells. To address this
need, we developed a clinical protocol to deplete
lineage<sup>+</sup>(CD3<sup>+</sup>, CD14<sup>+</sup>, CD16<sup>+</sup> and
CD19<sup>+</sup>) cells from blood and marrow products. This process
depletes &#x0003e;90% of lineage<sup>+</sup>cells while retaining
&#x02265;60% of the initial CD34<sup>+</sup>cell fraction, reduces total
nucleated cells by 1&#x02013;2 logs, and maintains transduction efficiency and
cell viability following gene transfer. Importantly, transduced
lineage<sup>&#x02212;</sup> cell products engrafted equivalently to that of
purified CD34<sup>+</sup> cells from the same donor when xenotransplanted at
matched CD34<sup>+</sup> cell doses. This novel selection strategy has been
approved by the regulatory agencies in a gene therapy study for Fanconi anemia
patients (<italic>NCI Clinical Trial Reporting Program Registry ID
NCI-2011-00202; <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://clinicaltrials.gov">clinicaltrials.gov</ext-link> identifier:
01331018</italic>).</p></abstract></article-meta></front><body><sec sec-type="intro"><title>Introduction</title><p>Fanconi anemia (FA) is a rare monogenic disease with a wide array and variable
presence of clinical symptoms, the hallmark of which is bone marrow (BM)
failure.<sup><xref rid="b1-1031806" ref-type="bibr">1</xref></sup> The
genetic basis of FA is a mutation in any one of 21 genes<sup><xref rid="b2-1031806" ref-type="bibr">2</xref></sup> whose protein components make up the
FA/breast cancer pathway responsible for DNA repair of inter-strand crosslinks
through nucleotide excision followed by homologous recombination. Resulting
compromises in genetic integrity are associated with a nearly uniform decline in
hematopoietic stem and progenitor cells (HSPCs), a 50% incidence of
myelodysplastic syndrome or acute myeloid leukemia by adolescence, and a 25%
lifetime incidence of head and neck squamous cell carcinoma or gynecological
cancer.<sup><xref rid="b3-1031806" ref-type="bibr">3</xref></sup> In some
patients, blood cell clones demonstrate spontaneous reversion to wild type (i.e.
somatic mosaicism) leading to improved and stable blood cell counts for up to 27
years.<sup><xref rid="b4-1031806" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="b6-1031806" ref-type="bibr">6</xref></sup> Thus, correction of the FA
hematopoietic defect could significantly alter the disease&#x02019;s clinical
course, and this has driven decades of research in HSPC gene therapy for FA.</p><p>While FA was recognized as an early candidate disorder for gene therapy, several
obstacles have been identified that have delayed clinical success.<sup><xref rid="b3-1031806" ref-type="bibr">3</xref></sup> Initial clinical trials
demonstrated a dramatic approximately 50-fold reduction in the number of true HSPCs
in FA patients relative to other gene therapy patients, such as those treated for
primary immune deficiencies.<sup><xref rid="b7-1031806" ref-type="bibr">7</xref></sup> Moreover, FA HSPCs were exceptionally fragile when manipulated
<italic>ex vivo</italic> for gene transfer. No treated patient has demonstrated
stable improvements in blood cell counts with long-term persistence of
gene-corrected blood cells. These studies highlighted two needs for innovation in
<italic>FA</italic> gene therapy: 1) to increase the number of available HSPCs
for gene transfer and infusion; and 2) to increase the engraftment potential of
these cells after gene transfer and infusion. Following the recommendations of the
International FA Gene Therapy Working Group,<sup><xref rid="b8-1031806" ref-type="bibr">8</xref></sup> we launched a phase I clinical trial of gene
therapy for FA complementation group A (FA-A) patients in 2011 (<italic><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://clinicaltrials.gov">clinicaltrials.gov</ext-link> identifier: 01331018</italic>). This trial
design incorporates several features aiming to improve HSPC numbers and fitness.
These include: i) a self-inactivating (SIN) lentiviral vector (LV) for transfer of
the <italic>FANCA</italic> cDNA regulated by a human phosphoglycerate kinase (hPGK)
promoter; ii) a short, overnight transduction to minimize <italic>ex vivo</italic>
manipulation, as well as addition of the antioxidant N-acetylcysteine (NAC)
throughout manipulation; and iii) culture under reduced oxygen (5%) to limit
oxidative DNA damage.<sup><xref rid="b9-1031806" ref-type="bibr">9</xref></sup></p><p>The target HSPC population for gene transfer expresses the CD34 cell surface protein
(CD34<sup>+</sup>). When stained with fluorophore-conjugated antibody against
CD34 and analyzed by flow cytometry, a small proportion of BM cells are
CD34<sup>+</sup>, representing both primitive stem cells and more committed
progenitors.<sup><xref rid="b10-1031806" ref-type="bibr">10</xref></sup> The
standard clinical procedure for isolating these cells first involves either BM
collection or mobilization of the cells into circulation through cytokine
stimulation with granulocyte colony stimulating factor (G-CSF) or, in certain
clinical scenarios, a combination of G-CSF and the chemokine receptor CXCR4
antagonist plerixafor, followed by peripheral blood leukapheresis (mAPH). Initial
isolation technologies relied on CD34 antigen expression on the cell surface and
utilized biotinavidin affinity, panning, or immununomagnetic bead-based approaches.
Expected yields were 50% of available CD34<sup>+</sup> cells with highly
variable purities, ranging from 20&#x02013;90% across techniques.<sup><xref rid="b11-1031806" ref-type="bibr">11</xref></sup> Of these, immunomagnetic
bead-based positive selection is the most widely-applied today, with the first US
Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approval of a clinical device for human use in
2014. Advances in this technology to include automation have improved reliability in
recovery to a mean yield of 70% with purities regularly over
90%.<sup><xref rid="b12-1031806" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,<xref rid="b13-1031806" ref-type="bibr">13</xref></sup> However, these values are
based on BM and mAPH products wherein 1&#x02013;3% of total cells express
CD34 antigen, and the majority of these cells display high levels of CD34. For FA
patients, the frequency of CD34<sup>+</sup> cells is much lower:
0.1&#x02013;1.5% in BM.<sup><xref rid="b14-1031806" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,<xref rid="b15-1031806" ref-type="bibr">15</xref></sup> This
implies that non-standard processes may be required to preserve the limited numbers
of HSPCs for gene transfer in FA.</p><p>Here we report HSPC collection results for the first 3 patients treated on our study.
Initially, this protocol proposed direct isolation of CD34<sup>+</sup> cells from BM
without prior attempts at mobilization. The addition of a mobilization regimen with
subsequent leukapheresis collections has permitted the evaluation of CD34 expression
patterns in both product types and provided evidence for the need for alternative
HSPC isolation strategies.</p></sec><sec sec-type="methods"><title>Methods</title><sec><title>Patient selection</title><p>This study was approved by an Institutional Review Board at Fred Hutchinson
Cancer Research Center (Fred Hutch) in accordance with the Declaration of
Helsinki and the FDA, and conformed to the National Institutes of Health
Guidelines for Research Involving Recombinant DNA Molecules. Informed consent
was obtained from all patients or guardians. FA patients aged 4 years or over
were diagnosed by a positive test for increased sensitivity to chromosomal
breakage with mitomycin C (MMC) or diepoxybutane. Correction of melphalan
hypersensitivity following retroviral transduction of the FANCA cDNA identified
Patient 3 as belonging to the FA-A complementation group. (<italic>Online
Supplementary Table S1</italic>). FA-A patients who demonstrated normal
karyotype in BM analyses as defined in the trial were considered eligible for
the study. Characteristics of enrolled patients are available in <xref rid="t1-1031806" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>.</p><table-wrap id="t1-1031806" position="float"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Clinical characteristics of 3 patients with Fanconi Anemia A genetic
defect enrolled in clinical trial NCT01331018.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="1031806.tab1"/></table-wrap></sec><sec><title>Lentiviral vectors</title><p>All SIN lentiviral (LV) vectors were produced with a third-generation split
packaging system and pseudotyped with vesicular stomatitis virus glycoprotein.
LV used to transduce healthy donor cells encoded either an enhanced green
fluorescent protein (eGFP) transgene (pRSC-PGK.eGFP-sW) or the full-length
<italic>FANCA</italic> cDNA (pRSC-PGK.FANCA-sW), both regulated by an hPGK
promoter. Research-grade vectors were produced by the Fred Hutch Vector
Production Core (Principal Investigator: HPK). Clinical-grade LV (pRSC-PGK.
<italic>FANCA</italic>-sW), was produced by the Indiana University Vector
Production Facility (IUVPF, IN, USA) using a large-scale, validated process
following Good Manufacturing Practices standards under an approved Drug Master
File held by IUVPF. Infectious titer was determined by serial transduction of
HT1080 human fibrosarcoma-derived cells and evaluated either by flow cytometry
for eGFP expression or by quantitative polymerase chain reaction (qPCR).</p></sec><sec sec-type="methods"><title>Study design and HSPC isolation</title><p>Patients underwent either BM harvest with a target collection goal of 15 cc/kg
body weight or were administered daily G-CSF (filgrastim; 16 &#x003bc;g/kg BID;
days 1&#x02013;6) and plerixafor (240 &#x003bc;g/kg/day; days 4&#x02013;6)
subcutaneously to mobilize CD34<sup>+</sup> cells. Mobilized patients were
subjected to large volume leukapheresis when circulating CD34<sup>+</sup> blood
cell counts were &#x02265;5 cells/ &#x003bc;L. Healthy donor blood products were
purchased from a commercial source (BM products; StemExpress, Folsom, CA, USA)
or institutional shared resources (mAPH products). Immunomagnetic beads were
from Miltenyi Biotech, GmbH (Auburn, CA, USA). For BM products, RBC were
debulked by hetastarch sedimentation prior to labeling on a CliniMACS
Prodigy&#x02122; device (Miltenyi Biotec GmbH, Germany). For mAPH products, an
initial platelet wash was performed prior to labeling. Custom programming for
lineage depletion was designed and executed on the CliniMACS Prodigy&#x02122;
device (Miltenyi Biotec, GmbH). Complete processing methods are included in the
<italic>Online Supplementary Materials and Methods</italic>.</p></sec><sec><title>Transduction</title><p>CD34-enriched cells were cultured on RetroNectin&#x02122; (Takara Bio, Mountain
View, CA, USA)-coated culture flasks at a density of 1&#x000d7;10<sup>6</sup>
cells/mL and 2.9&#x000d7;10<sup>5</sup> cells/cm<sup>2</sup> in
StemSpan&#x02122; ACF media (StemCell Technologies, Vancouver, BC, Canada),
supplemented with 4 &#x003bc;g/mL of protamine sulfate (American Pharmaceutical
Partners; APP, East Shaumburg, IL, USA), 100 ng/mL each of recombinant human
stem cell factor (rhSCF), thrombopoietin (rhTPO) and Flt-3 ligand (rhFLT3L) (all
from CellGenix GmbH, Freiburg, Germany), and 1 mM NAC (Cumberland
Pharmaceuticals, Nashville, TN, USA). Cells were immediately transduced at a
multiplicity of infection (MOI) of 5&#x02013;10 infectious units (IU)/cell.
Following 12&#x02013;24 hours of incubation at 37&#x000b0;C, 5%
CO<sub>2</sub> and 5% O<sub>2</sub>, cells were harvested for
infusion and/or analyses.</p></sec><sec><title>Transplantation in NSG mice</title><p>All animal work was performed under protocol 1864 approved by the Fred Hutch
Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee.
NOD.Cg-PrkdcscidIL2r&#x003b3;tmlWj/Szj (NOD/SCID/IL2r&#x003b3;<sup>null</sup>,
NSG) mice were housed at Fred Hutch in pathogen-free conditions approved by the
American Association for Accreditation of Laboratory Animal Care.
8&#x02013;12-week old mice received 275 cGy total body irradiation (TBI) from a
Cesium source. Four hours after TBI, 1&#x000d7;10<sup>6</sup> gene-modified
total nucleated cells (TNCs) re-suspended in 200 &#x003bc;L phosphate buffered
saline (D-PBS, Life Technologies Corporation, Grand Island, NY, USA) containing
1% heparin (APP) were infused <italic>via</italic> tail vein. Blood
samples were collected into ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid (EDTA) Microtainers
(BD Bioscience, San Jose, CA, USA) by retro-orbital puncture and diluted 1:1
with PBS prior to analysis. At necropsy, spleen and BM were collected. Tissues
were filtered through 70 &#x003bc;m mesh (BD Bioscience) and washed with
Dulbecco&#x02019;s PBS (D-PBS).</p></sec><sec><title>Colony-forming cell assays</title><p>Transduced cell products were seeded in standard CFC assays in methylcellulose
media (H4230, Stem Cell Technologies) as previously described<sup><xref rid="b16-1031806" ref-type="bibr">16</xref></sup> with the following
exceptions: to assess FANCA gene function, MMC (Sigma Aldrich, St. Louis, MO,
USA) was added at concentrations of 0 nM, 5 nM, 10 nM, or 20 nM. Complete colony
DNA extraction and PCR methods are included in the <italic>Online Supplementary
Materials and Methods</italic>.</p></sec><sec><title>Quantitative real-time PCR-based measurement of vector copy number</title><p>Vector copy number (VCN) per genome equivalent was assessed by TaqMan 5&#x02019;
nuclease quantitative real-time PCR assay in duplicate reactions with an
LV-specific primer/probe combination [forward,
5&#x02019;-TGAAAGCGAAAGGGAAACCA; reverse, 5&#x02019;-CCGTGCGCGCTTCAG; probe,
5&#x02019;-AGCTCTCTC-GACGCAGGACTCGGC (Integrated DNA Technologies; IDT,
Coralville, IA, USA)] and in a separate reaction with a
&#x003b2;-globin-specific primer/probe combination [forward,
5&#x02019;-CCTATCA-GAAAGTGGTGGCTGG; reverse,
5&#x02019;-TTGGACAGCAA-GAAAGTGAGCTT; probe,
5&#x02019;-TGGCTAATGCCCTGGCCCA-CAAGTA (IDT)]. Two standard curves were
established by serial dilution of gDNA isolated from a human cell line (HT1080)
confirmed to contain a single integrant of the same LV backbone and from
peripheral leukocytes collected from a healthy donor using both primer-probe
sets independently.</p><p>Individual colony gDNA samples were subjected to multiplex real-time TaqMan qPCR
to amplify the LV-specific product and an endogenous control (TaqMan Copy Number
Reference assay RNaseP, Thermo Fisher Scientific, Pittsburgh, PA, USA). Samples
with an average VCN &#x02265;0.5 were considered transduced.</p></sec><sec sec-type="methods"><title>Flow cytometry analysis of hematopoietic subsets</title><p>Stained cells were acquired on a FACSCanto&#x02122; II, FACSAria&#x02122; II or
FACS LSR II (all from BD Bioscience) and analyzed using FlowJo software v.10.0.8
(Tree Star Inc., Ashland, OR, USA). Analysis was performed on up to 20,000
cells. Gates were established using Full Minus One stained controls.</p><p>Antibodies included anti-human CD34 (clone 563), CD16 (clone 3G8), CD3 (clone
UCHT1), CD4 (clone L200), CD8 (clone RPA-T8), all from BD Biosciences; CD14
(clone 61D3, Thermo Fisher Scientific, Pittsburgh, PA, USA); CD19 (clone 4G7, BD
Pharmingen, San Diego, CA, USA); CD90 (clone 5E10), CD20 (clone 2H7), CD15
(clone W6D3), all from Biolegend (San Diego, CA, USA); CD133 (clone 293C3,
Miltenyi Biotec, GmbH); CD45 (clone D058-1283) and CD45RA (clone 5H9), both from
BD Horizon (San Jose, CA, USA).</p><p>For mouse samples, antibodies were anti-mouse CD45-V500 (561487, clone 30-F11),
anti-human CD45-PerCP (347464, clone 2D1), CD3-FITC (555332, clone UCHT1),
CD4-V450 (560345, clone RPA-T4), CD8-APCCy7 (557834, clone SK1), CD20-PE
(555623, clone 2H7), and CD14-APC (555824, clone 581), all from BD
Biosciences.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="results"><title>Results</title><sec><title>Diminished CD34<sup>Hi</sup> expressing cells in FA-A BM and mAPH</title><p>Two enrolled patients underwent BM harvest to collect available CD34<sup>+</sup>
HSPCs (Patients 1 and 2). The third patient underwent mobilization with
filgrastim and plerixafor followed by peripheral blood leukapheresis (Patient
3). All 3 patients demonstrated reduced CD34 expression and estimated numbers of
CD34<sup>+</sup> cells in screening BM aspirate samples prior to collection
and treatment, relative to healthy donor BM products, as well as in cell
products collected for CD34<sup>+</sup> cell isolation and gene transfer (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1-1031806">Figure 1</xref>). Two levels of CD34
expression were observed, CD34<sup>Lo</sup> [mean fluorescence intensity
(MFI)=3453&#x000b1;516], and CD34<sup>Hi</sup> (MFI=19731&#x000b1;4103).
Notably, the proportion of CD34<sup>Hi</sup> cells were markedly reduced in FA-A
patients relative to those observed in healthy donors (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1-1031806">Figure 1</xref>).</p><fig id="f1-1031806" position="float"><label>Figure 1.</label><caption><p>Diminished CD34<sup>Hi</sup> hematopoietic cells from Fanconi Anemia A
genetic defect (FA-A) patients. CD34 expression in baseline bone marrow
(BM) (Patients 1, 2, 3, and healthy donor 1) or mobilized leukapheresis
(mAPH) (Patient 3 and healthy donor 2) products was determined by
fluorescence staining and flow cytometry analysis. Positive cell
fractions are gated based on unstained and isotype stained control
samples into two levels of CD34 expression: low expression,
CD34<sup>Lo</sup>, or high expression, CD34<sup>Hi</sup>. The
average mean fluorescence intensity (MFI) of CD34<sup>Lo</sup>
population = 3453; standard error of the mean (SEM) = 516 and
CD34<sup>Hi</sup> population = 19731; SEM = 4103.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="1031806.fig1"/></fig></sec><sec><title>FA-A CD34<sup>Hi</sup> cells, but not CD34<sup>Lo</sup> cells, demonstrate
<italic>in vitro</italic> repopulating capacity</title><p>To determine which CD34<sup>+</sup> cells demonstrated repopulation potential, we
used colony-forming cell (CFC) potential as a surrogate. This required
sufficient blood product to flow-sort CD34<sup>Lo</sup> and CD34<sup>Hi</sup>
cells for <italic>in vitro</italic> assays. Only the mAPH product collected from
Patient 3 was sufficient for this study. For direct comparison, we sort-purified
CD34<sup>Lo</sup> and CD34<sup>Hi</sup> cells from a healthy donor mAPH
product. Only CD34<sup>Hi</sup> cells from the FA-A patient demonstrated
colony-forming potential (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2-1031806">Figure
2A</xref>). In the healthy donor, CD34<sup>Hi</sup> cells also demonstrated the
majority of CFC capacity in comparison with CD34<sup>Lo</sup> cells, and at much
higher levels as compared to the FA-A patient (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2-1031806">Figure 2B</xref>). These data suggest repopulating capacity
is restricted to CD34<sup>Hi</sup> cell fractions, underscoring the need to
preserve as many of these cells as possible for gene transfer processes.</p><fig id="f2-1031806" position="float"><label>Figure 2.</label><caption><p><italic>In vitro</italic> repopulation potential restricted to
CD34<sup>Hi</sup> hematopoietic cells. Mobilized leukapheresis from
FA-A Patient 3 (Panel A) and a healthy donor (Panel B) were in parallel
fluorescence stained with anti-CD34 antibody and sort-purified for
CD34<sup>Hi</sup> and CD34<sup>Lo</sup> cells. Total nucleated cells
(TNC) equivalent to 1500 CD34-expressing cells were seeded in CFC
assays. Percentage of CD34<sup>+</sup> cells seeded in the assay that
gave rise to colonies is represented as the % of colony-forming
cells.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="1031806.fig2"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Extensive loss of FA-A CD34<sup>Hi</sup> cells with direct clinical
purification protocols</title><p>The current clinical standard for CD34<sup>+</sup> cell enrichment is optimized
for collection of CD34<sup>Hi</sup> cells. However, in Patient 1, direct
enrichment of CD34<sup>+</sup> cells using this protocol was inefficient,
resulting in an approximately 3% yield and only
5.34&#x000d7;10<sup>6</sup> total CD34<sup>+</sup> cells available for gene
transfer (<xref rid="t2-1031806" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>). Moreover, the
purity of the enriched cell product was only 58.9%, and approximately
47% loss in viable cells was observed during culture and gene transfer.
Resulting gene-modified cells retained colony-forming capacity and demonstrated
acquired resistance to the potent DNA crosslinking agent MMC following
LV-mediated FANCA gene transfer (<xref rid="t3-1031806" ref-type="table">Table
3</xref>).</p><table-wrap id="t2-1031806" position="float"><label>Table 2.</label><caption><p>Isolation and lentiviral vector transduction of autologous Fanconi Anemia
A genetic defect HSPC.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="1031806.tab2"/></table-wrap><table-wrap id="t3-1031806" position="float"><label>Table 3.</label><caption><p>Transduction efficiency</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="1031806.tab3"/></table-wrap><p>In Patient 2, estimated losses during direct CD34 enrichment and gene transfer
were expected to reduce the cell product available for transduction to a level
lower than observed for Patient 1. Thus, an urgent amendment was filed with the
FDA to permit elimination of the direct CD34 enrichment steps and allow
transduction of the entire red blood cell (RBC)-depleted BM product. This
processing change preserved more CD34<sup>+</sup> cells (<xref rid="t2-1031806" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>), with improved transduction and viability
(<xref rid="t3-1031806" ref-type="table">Table 3</xref>). Together, these
data suggested that minimal manipulation of target CD34<sup>+</sup> cells from
FA-A patients could improve yield, gene transfer efficiency, and function
<italic>in vivo</italic>.</p></sec><sec><title>Development of a novel strategy to deplete lineage<sup>+</sup> cells</title><p>We hypothesized that depleting non-target mature B cells, T cells, monocytes, and
granulocytes would retain precious CD34<sup>+</sup> cells with minimal
manipulation, since CD34-expressing cells would not be directly labeled,
selected, or washed (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f3-1031806">Figure 3</xref>).
Building on our previous work automating cell selection and gene transfer using
the CliniMACS Prodigy&#x02122; device,<sup><xref rid="b17-1031806" ref-type="bibr">17</xref></sup> we designed a customized, automated
RBC debulking and immunomagnetic bead-based lineage specific depletion strategy
(<italic>Online Supplementary Materials and Methods</italic>). Four
different bead-conjugated antibody reagents were used in this approach: anti-CD3
(T-cell removal), anti-CD14 (monocyte removal), anti-CD16 (granulocyte and
NK-cell removal), and anti-CD19 (B-cell removal). This protocol was designed for
both BM and mAPH products.</p><fig id="f3-1031806" position="float"><label>Figure 3.</label><caption><p>Direct CD34 enrichment <italic>versus</italic> depletion of lineage
positive (+) cells. Products can include bone marrow (BM) or mobilized
apheresis product (mAPH) (1). BM products were first processed through
hetastarch sedimentation to deplete red blood cells (RBCs).
Leukapheresis products were first subjected to several washes to deplete
platelets. For direct CD34<sup>+</sup> cell selection, anti-CD34
antibody-bound immunomagnetic beads (microbeads) are used, whereas for
lineage depletion anti-CD3<sup>+</sup>, CD14<sup>+</sup>,
CD16<sup>+</sup>, and CD19<sup>+</sup>, microbeads are used (2). In
both cases, microbead-bound cells are retained on the column and
subjected to wash steps. When lineage depletion is used, CD34-expressing
cells undergo minimal manipulation during purification. Following
purification, cells are cultured and transduced with a VSV-G pseudotyped
lentiviral vector at a multiplicity of infection (MOI) of 5&#x02013;10
IU/ cell (3). Following ~16 hours of incubation cells are harvested (4).
<sup>*</sup>These processes were performed on the CliniMACS
Prodigy&#x02122; device from Miltenyi Biotec GmbH.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="1031806.fig3"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Lineage depletion preserves available CD34<sup>+</sup> cells for gene
transfer</title><p>A total of nine BM and ten mAPH products were processed to establish process
validity. An average 60% of BM CD45<sup>+</sup> cells and 50% of
mAPH CD45<sup>+</sup> cells expressed one of the four target markers (CD3, CD14,
CD16, or CD19) (<italic>Online Supplementary Figure S1A</italic> and
<italic>B</italic>, respectively). CD34<sup>+</sup> cell content in these
products ranged from 0.35-1.4% in BM and 0.06-0.9% in mAPH
products. The average process run time for BM products was ten hours, whereas
mAPH products were processed over 13 hours. Observed total nucleated cell (TNC)
reduction was approximately 1 log for both BM and mAPH products following
lineage depletion (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4-1031806">Figure 4A</xref>). All
target lineage<sup>+</sup> cells were depleted to less than 10% of
initial numbers, and CD34<sup>+</sup> cells were retained at
94.62&#x000b1;4.61% for BM products and 70.69&#x000b1;11.4% for
mAPH products (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4-1031806">Figure 4B</xref>).
Retention of available CD34<sup>Hi</sup> and CD34<sup>Lo</sup> cells was
observed and comparable or superior to that observed for the same products by
direct CD34-enrichment (<italic>Online Supplementary Figure S2</italic>).
Approximately 24% of BM CD34<sup>+</sup> cells were colony-forming in a
standard methylcellulose assay, while 51% of mAPH CD34<sup>+</sup> cells
formed colonies (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4-1031806">Figure 4C</xref> and
<italic>Online Supplementary Figure S3</italic>). However, following LV
transduction of these cells using the same protocol proposed for FA-A patient
cells, we observed consistent 50% rates of gene transfer into CFCs from
both cell product types (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4-1031806">Figure
4D</xref>). Analysis of single colonies demonstrated an average VCN per CFC of
0.7 for BM CD34<sup>+</sup> cells and 1.6 for mAPH CD34<sup>+</sup> cells. VCN
was also assessed in bulk transduced cells cultured for ten days <italic>in
vitro</italic>, demonstrating an average value of 5 for both BM and mAPH
products (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4-1031806">Figure 4E</xref>). Final cell
products tested for mycoplasma and sterility were negative, and endotoxin
testing demonstrated values within criteria for patient infusion.
Lineage-depleted and transduced cells from six mAPH and BM products each were
infused into immunodeficient (NSG) mice at a target cell dose of
1&#x000d7;10<sup>6</sup> TNC per mouse. On average, the CD34<sup>+</sup>
cell dose per mouse for BM products was 2.86&#x000d7;10<sup>4</sup>
CD34<sup>+</sup> cells [standard error of the mean
(SEM)=6.67&#x000d7;10<sup>3</sup>] and for mAPH products was
1.08&#x000d7;10<sup>5</sup> CD34<sup>+</sup> cells
(SEM=1.45&#x000d7;10<sup>4</sup>). Flow cytometry analysis on peripheral
blood was used to evaluate engraftment (human CD45<sup>+</sup>) and lineage
development into T cells (human CD3<sup>+</sup>), B cells (human
CD20<sup>+</sup>), and monocytes (human CD14<sup>+</sup>) over time (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4-1031806">Figure 4F</xref>). Both mAPH and BM products
demonstrated long-term engraftment over 20 weeks of monitoring. Engraftment
levels were comparable to results reported by Wiekmeijer <italic>et al</italic>.
with CD34<sup>+</sup> cells purified from BM and infused at similar cell
doses.<sup><xref rid="b18-1031806" ref-type="bibr">18</xref></sup></p><fig id="f4-1031806" position="float"><label>Figure 4.</label><caption><p>Multi-lineage engraftment of lineage depleted and transduced bone marrow
(BM) and mobilized apheresis products (mAPH) in NSG mice. Recovery of
total nucleated cells (TNC), CD34<sup>+</sup> cells and lineage positive
(+) cells (A and B). (C-E) Gene transfer efficiency. The colony-forming
potential of transduced cells in standard CFC assays is defined as the
plating efficiency (TNC). The colony-forming potential normalized to the
number of CD34<sup>+</sup> cells seeded is depicted as plating
efficiency (CD34<sup>+</sup>). The percentage of colonies analyzed
positive for the presence of lentivirus (LV) backbone by PCR analysis on
DNA extracted from individual colonies is depicted as transduction
efficiency. The vector copy number per cell in the bulk transduced
population is depicted as VCN. The average VCN per cell in the
individual CFC is depicted as single colony VCN. Data are representative
of the average of 9 healthy BM products and 10 healthy mAPH products.
Error bars represent the standard error of the mean. (F) Engraftment of
human CD45<sup>+</sup> cells and lineage development into T cells
(CD3<sup>+</sup>), monocytes (CD14<sup>+</sup>) and B cells
(CD20<sup>+</sup>) was determined by flow cytometry over 20 weeks
following infusion of lineage-depleted cell products. Data are
representative of 36 mice from 6 mAPH donors and 42 mice from 6 BM
donors, respectively. Error bars represent the Standard Error of the
Mean.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="1031806.fig4"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Lineage-depleted cell products xenoengraft equivalently to CD34-enriched
products</title><p>In this experiment, healthy donor BM products were divided into two aliquots. One
was lineage-depleted and the other CD34-enriched. Resulting cell populations
were transduced with the same LV vector under identical conditions and infused
into NSG mice at matched CD34<sup>+</sup> cell doses. We observed higher
CD34<sup>+</sup> cell retention with lineage depletion compared to CD34
selection, with no differences in transduction efficiency or colony-forming
potential (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5-1031806">Figure 5A and B</xref>). We
observed slightly higher, but not significantly different, levels of human
CD45<sup>+</sup> blood cell engraftment in mice receiving transduced,
lineage-depleted cells relative to mice receiving CD34-selected cells. We also
observed more stability of T-and B-cell engraftment in mice receiving
lineage-depleted cell products relative to mice receiving CD34-selected cell
products (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f5-1031806">Figure 5C</xref>).</p><fig id="f5-1031806" position="float"><label>Figure 5.</label><caption><p>Multi-lineage engraftment levels of lineage-depleted cell products in NSG
(NOD/SCID/IL2rg<sup>null</sup>) mice is comparable to CD34-enriched
cell products from the same donor. (A) Graph depicts percent recovery of
total nucleated cells (TNC) and CD34<sup>+</sup> cells from each arm
following depletion or enrichment. (B) Numbers of total and transduced
colony-forming cells (CFC) normalized to 1&#x000d7;10<sup>8</sup> cells
processed to each arm, and vector copy number (VCN) in the bulk
transduced cells following ten days of culture. Data are representative
of 2 healthy donor bone marrow products. Error bars represent the
Standard Error of the Mean. (C) Engraftment of human CD45<sup>+</sup>
cells and lineage development into T cells (CD3<sup>+</sup>), monocytes
(CD14<sup>+</sup>) and B cells (CD20<sup>+</sup>) was determined by
flow cytometry over 26 weeks following infusion. Data are representative
of 9 mice for the lineage depleted (Lin-) arm and 6 mice for the CD34
enriched (CD34) arm, respectively.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="1031806.fig5"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Lineage depletion protocol preserves limited FA CD34<sup>Hi</sup>
cells</title><p>These data collectively suggest that lineage-specific depletion preserved
available CD34<sup>+</sup> cells without compromising transduction efficiency or
cell fitness. Under FDA approval, the clinical protocol was modified to include
both BM and/or mAPH products, with lineage depletion as the method of
CD34<sup>+</sup> cell enrichment. Patient 3 (the first treated under the
modified protocol) was a 5-year old male with FA-A confirmed by complementation
studies. Baseline neutrophils averaged 1.7&#x000d7;10<sup>9</sup>/L and baseline
platelets averaged 32&#x000d7;10<sup>9</sup>/L in the six months prior to
treatment, with declining neutrophils and platelets over the prior 2-year
interval (<italic>Online Supplementary Figure S4</italic>). Mobilization of
&#x02265;10 CD34<sup>+</sup> cells/ &#x003bc;L peripheral blood was achieved
(<italic>Online Supplementary Figure S5A</italic>), and two successive
apheresis collections resulted in 8.5&#x000d7;10<sup>10</sup> TNC containing a
total 1.6&#x000d7;10<sup>8</sup> CD34<sup>+</sup> cells (<xref rid="t2-1031806" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>). The patient required a total of two
platelet transfusions and two packed red blood cell transfusions during
mobilization and leukapheresis (<italic>Online Supplementary Figure
S5B</italic>). Due to column limitations, 5&#x000d7;10<sup>10</sup> TNC
(equivalent to 9.5&#x000d7;10<sup>7</sup> total CD34<sup>+</sup> cells) were
subjected to lineage depletion, and the remainder were cryopreserved. Lineage
depletion resulted in a 94% reduction in TNC and a 56% retention
of available CD34<sup>+</sup> cells. CD34 purity was 1.6%, representing
a 1&#x02013;2 log-fold increase in the total number of CD34<sup>+</sup> cells
per kg available for transduction and infusion relative to Patients 1 and 2
(<xref rid="t2-1031806" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>). A total of
52.8&#x000d7;10<sup>6</sup> CD34<sup>+</sup> cells were transduced at an MOI
of 5 IU/cell, resulting in a final cell dose of 2.4&#x000d7;10<sup>6</sup> total
CD34<sup>+</sup> cells per kg with 99.3% viability based on trypan
blue dye exclusion. Approximately 26% of CFCs in this cell product were
transduced, displaying a mean VCN of approximately 1 (0.9) (<xref rid="t3-1031806" ref-type="table">Table 3</xref>). Thus, limited numbers of
available CD34<sup>+</sup> cells were indirectly enriched using lineage
depletion on a blood product from an FA-A patient without compromising
transduction efficiency.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="discussion"><title>Discussion</title><p>Here we confirm prior reports of inefficient CD34<sup>+</sup> cell enrichment from FA
patient blood products by direct, immunomagnetic bead-based separation, which is the
current standard protocol for isolating HSPCs.<sup><xref rid="b15-1031806" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>,<xref rid="b19-1031806" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="b21-1031806" ref-type="bibr">21</xref></sup>
We also demonstrate substantially reduced levels of CD34<sup>Hi</sup> cells in FA
patients relative to healthy donors, which likely contributes to poor positive
selection results in blood products from FA patients. Colony seeding assays
demonstrate that only CD34<sup>Hi</sup> cells contribute to <italic>in
vitro</italic> colony-forming potential in both FA and healthy donor blood
products, underscoring the need to preserve as many available CD34<sup>+</sup> cells
as possible during <italic>ex vivo</italic> manipulation for gene transfer. We
demonstrate a clinically viable procedure for depleting lineage positive cells to
indirectly enrich for CD34<sup>+</sup> cells that preserves the limited numbers of
these cells in FA-A patients without compromising viability, gene transfer, or
engraftment potential.</p><p>Importantly, the phenotype of limiting CD34<sup>+</sup> cell numbers is not
restricted to FA alone. Sickle cell disease (SCD) patients treated with hydroxyurea
also display reduced CD34<sup>+</sup> cell frequencies in BM, and there is a
contraindication to mobilization of available CD34<sup>+</sup> cells owing to an
increased risk of vaso-occlusive crisis.<sup><xref rid="b22-1031806" ref-type="bibr">22</xref></sup> Other inherited BM failure syndromes such as dyskeratosis
congenita also are associated with abnormal CD34<sup>+</sup> cell frequencies and
behavior.<sup><xref rid="b23-1031806" ref-type="bibr">23</xref></sup> As a
larger number of disease targets become relevant for gene therapy, additional
patient populations will likely display variable CD34<sup>+</sup> cell frequency and
antigen expression. These disease targets could also benefit from clinically viable
alternative selection procedures such as we have developed here.</p><p>Our observation of CFC potential in only the CD34<sup>Hi</sup> fraction in both FA
and healthy samples suggests that CD34<sup>Lo</sup> cells may not be contributing to
hematopoietic reconstitution. Notably, our data are from mAPH samples not BM, and we
will need more patients for confirmation. Additionally, the standard colony-forming
assay best defines progenitor cells, more so than true long-term repopulating
hematopoietic stem cells.<sup><xref rid="b24-1031806" ref-type="bibr">24</xref></sup> Alternatively, xenotransplant of purified cells into
immunodeficient mice could provide the most robust evidence for CD34<sup>+</sup>
cell function <italic>in vivo</italic>, but the very small numbers of these cells
may prove problematic to achieving relevant cell doses needed for these experiments.
Another <italic>in vitro</italic> assay, such as the long-term culture-initiating
cell assay,<sup><xref rid="b25-1031806" ref-type="bibr">25</xref></sup> may provide
additional insight into the desired target CD34<sup>+</sup> subpopulations for gene
therapy if they are present in either the CD34<sup>Hi</sup> or CD34<sup>Lo</sup>
populations in FA patients. In this regard, we recently demonstrated that the
CD34<sup>Hi</sup>CD45RA<sup>&#x02212;</sup>CD90<sup>+</sup> phenotype is
responsible for hematopoietic repopulation in non-human primates in the autologous,
myeloablative setting,<sup><xref rid="b16-1031806" ref-type="bibr">16</xref></sup>
and evaluation of this phenotype in the enrolled FA patients is ongoing. Critically,
our strategy of depleting cells expressing mature blood cell lineage markers
preserves all CD34<sup>+</sup> cell phenotypes for gene transfer and infusion, as
demonstrated by Patient 3, whose infused CD34<sup>+</sup> cell dose was the largest
received to date.</p><p>One characteristic of lineage-depleted cell products requiring additional study is
the presence and impact of other supporting cells on engraftment. Especially for
BM-derived products, our procedure does not include a marker to deplete mesenchymal
stem cells (MSC). While the engraftment potential of MSC manipulated <italic>ex
vivo</italic> in CD34<sup>+</sup> cell supportive media is unexplored, two
recent reports suggest that these cells are integral to BM function in FA, and can
be LV-transduced and functionally corrected to facilitate hematopoietic recovery and
function in a mouse model of FA.<sup><xref rid="b26-1031806" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>,<xref rid="b27-1031806" ref-type="bibr">27</xref></sup> For
mAPH-derived products, such as that infused into Patient 3, additional follow up
will be required to determine if a selective advantage is observed <italic>in
vivo</italic>. The improved transduction efficiency of lineage-depleted cell
products could reflect non-repopulating CD34<sup>&#x02212;</sup> cell uptake of LV.
However, we still observed a benefit in transduction of hematopoietic CFC, even at
the lower MOI of 5 IU/cell. One other possible explanation is the age and clinical
condition of Patient 3. To address this concern we compared our results in Patient 3
to the 4 FA patients enrolled in the FANCOSTEM clinical trial in Spain
(<italic><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://clinicaltrials.gov">clinicaltrials.gov</ext-link> identifier:
02931071</italic>).<sup><xref rid="b28-1031806" ref-type="bibr">28</xref></sup>
These 4 patients were aged 3&#x02013;7 years and demonstrated higher baseline blood
cell counts at the time of collection. All 4 patients received the same mobilization
regimen as Patient 3 reported here, but resulting mAPH products were subjected to
direct CD34 enrichment prior to transduction at an MOI of 100 IU/cell. The reported
mean VCN was 0.4&#x000b1;0.1 and ranged from 0.1 to 0.4 copies in individual CFC.
Our data with a higher VCN at lower MOI suggest that the mixed cell culture supports
transduction of hematopoietic progenitor cells, at least.</p><p>In conclusion, we describe an alternative strategy to a direct, immunomagnetic
bead-based selection of CD34-expressing cells that overcomes current barriers in
isolation of blood stem and progenitor cells especially for diseases like FA. Our
novel approach to preserve available CD34<sup>+</sup> cells during initial blood
product processing has the potential to improve gene therapy and gene editing in
settings of limited CD34<sup>+</sup> cell availability, including FA and other
diseases in which direct CD34 enrichment has proven inefficient, such as SCD.</p></sec>
<sec sec-type="supplementary-material">
<title>Supplementary Material</title>
<supplementary-material id="PMC_1" content-type="local-data">
<caption>
<title>Adair et al. Supplementary Appendix</title>
</caption>
<media mimetype="text" mime-subtype="html"
xlink:href="supp_2018.194571_haematol.2018.194571.DC1.html"/>
<media xlink:role="associated-file" mimetype="application" mime-subtype="pdf"
xlink:href="2018.194571.ADAIR_SUPPL.pdf"/>
</supplementary-material>
<supplementary-material id="PMC_2" content-type="local-data">
<caption>
<title>Disclosures and Contributions</title>
</caption>
<media mimetype="text" mime-subtype="html"
xlink:href="supp_2018.194571_haematol.2018.194571.DC2.html"/>
<media xlink:role="associated-file" mimetype="application" mime-subtype="pdf"
xlink:href="2018_194571-Disclosures_and_Contributions.pdf"/>
</supplementary-material>
</sec>
</body><back><ack><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>We thank our patients and their families. We thank the Fanconi Anemia Research Fund
for sponsoring patient travel and housing arrangements associated with this study.
We especially thank the Fred Hutch Cell Processing Facility and Seattle Cancer Care
Alliance for their support in enrollment and treatment of clinical trial patients.
We thank H. Crawford and K. Gonzalez for help in preparing the manuscript. We also
thank J. Chen and C. Ironside for excellent support in our mouse studies. This work
was primarily funded by a Sponsored Research Agreement between Fred Hutch and Rocket
Pharmaceuticals.</p></ack><fn-group><fn id="fn2-1031806"><p>Check the online version for the most updated information on this article, online
supplements, and information on authorship &#x00026; disclosures: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="www.haematologica.org/content/103/11/1806">www.haematologica.org/content/103/11/1806</ext-link></p></fn><fn id="fn3-1031806"><p><bold>Funding</bold></p><p>This work was also supported in part by grants and contracts to H-PK from the NIH
HHSN2680004 and HL122173 and by funds to JEA from the Fred Hutch. This research
was also funded in part through the NIH/NCI Cancer Center Support Grant P30
CA015704. H-PK is a Markey Molecular Medicine Investigator and received support
as the inaugural recipient of the Jos&#x000e9; Carreras/E. Donnall Thomas
Endowed Chair for Cancer Research and the Fred Hutch Endowed Chair for Cell and
Gene Therapy. JEA and H-PK are co-inventors on U.S. Provisional Patent
Applications #62/491,116 and #62/503,801 &#x0201c;Novel Manufacturing of Gene
Corrected Autologous Blood Cells for Gene Therapy.&#x0201d; JEA has previously
served as a consultant for Rocket Pharmaceuticals. H-PK is an active consultant
for Rocket Pharmaceuticals. The other authors declare that they have no
competing interests.</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="b1-1031806"><label>1.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Nalepa</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Clapp</surname><given-names>DW</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Fanconi anaemia and cancer: an intricate
relationship</article-title>. <source>Nat Rev Cancer</source>.
<year>2018</year>;<volume>18</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>168</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>185</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29376519</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b2-1031806"><label>2.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mamrak</surname><given-names>NE</given-names></name><name><surname>Shimamura</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Howlett</surname><given-names>NG</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Recent discoveries in the molecular pathogenesis
of the inherited bone marrow failure syndrome Fanconi
anemia</article-title>. <source>Blood Rev</source>.
<year>2017</year>;<volume>31</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>93</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>99</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27760710</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b3-1031806"><label>3.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Adair</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name><name><surname>Sevilla</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Heredia</surname><given-names>CD</given-names></name><name><surname>Becker</surname><given-names>PS</given-names></name><name><surname>Kiem</surname><given-names>HP</given-names></name><name><surname>Bueren</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Lessons learned from two decades of clinical
trial experience in gene therapy for Fanconi anemia</article-title>.
<source>Curr Gene Ther</source>.
<year>2017</year>;<volume>16</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>338</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>348</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28103787</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b4-1031806"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Asur</surname><given-names>RS</given-names></name><name><surname>Kimble</surname><given-names>DC</given-names></name><name><surname>Lach</surname><given-names>FP</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Somatic mosaicism of an intragenic FANCB
duplication in both fibroblast and peripheral blood cells observed in a
Fanconi anemia patient leads to milder phenotype</article-title>.
<source>Mol Genet Genomic Med</source>.
<year>2018</year>;<volume>6</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>77</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>91</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29193904</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b5-1031806"><label>5.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gregory</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names><suffix>Jr.</suffix></name><name><surname>Wagner</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name><name><surname>Verlander</surname><given-names>PC</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Somatic mosaicism in Fanconi anemia: evidence of
genotypic reversion in lymphohematopoietic stem cells</article-title>.
<source>Proc Natl Acad Sci USA</source>.
<year>2001</year>;<volume>98</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>2532</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2537</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11226273</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b6-1031806"><label>6.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mankad</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Taniguchi</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Cox</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Natural gene therapy in monozygotic twins with
Fanconi anemia</article-title>. <source>Blood</source>. <year>2006</year>;
<volume>107</volume>(<issue>8</issue>):<fpage>3084</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3090</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16397136</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b7-1031806"><label>7.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Verhoeyen</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name><surname>Roman-Rodriguez</surname><given-names>FJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Cosset</surname><given-names>FL</given-names></name><name><surname>Levy</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Rio</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Gene therapy in Fanconi anemia: A matter of
time, safety and gene transfer tool efficiency</article-title>. <source>Curr
Gene Ther</source>.
<year>2017</year>;<volume>16</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>297</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>308</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28067165</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b8-1031806"><label>8.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tolar</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Adair</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name><name><surname>Antoniou</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Stem cell gene therapy for Fanconi anemia:
report from the 1st International Fanconi Anemia Gene Therapy Working Group
meeting</article-title>. <source>Mol Ther</source>.
<year>2011</year>;<volume>19</volume>(<issue>7</issue>):<fpage>1193</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1198</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21540837</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b9-1031806"><label>9.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Becker</surname><given-names>PS</given-names></name><name><surname>Taylor</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name><name><surname>Trobridge</surname><given-names>GD</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Preclinical correction of human Fanconi anemia
complementation group A bone marrow cells using a safety-modified lentiviral
vector</article-title>. <source>Gene Ther</source>.
<year>2010</year>;<volume>17</volume>(<issue>10</issue>):<fpage>1244</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1252</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20485382</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b10-1031806"><label>10.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Syrjala</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Ruutu</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Jansson</surname><given-names>SE</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>A flow cytometric assay of CD34-positive cell
populations in the bone marrow</article-title>. <source>Br J
Haematol</source>.
<year>1994</year>;<volume>88</volume>(<issue>4</issue>):<fpage>679</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>684</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7529536</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b11-1031806"><label>11.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>RH</given-names><suffix>Jr</suffix></name></person-group>
<article-title>CD34+ selected cells in clinical
transplantation</article-title>. <source>Stem Cells</source>.
<year>1994</year>;
<volume>12</volume>(<issue>6</issue>):<fpage>577</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>585</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7533577</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b12-1031806"><label>12.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Spohn</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Wiercinska</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name><surname>Karpova</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Automated CD34+ cell isolation of peripheral
blood stem cell apheresis product</article-title>.
<source>Cytotherapy</source>.
<year>2015</year>;<volume>17</volume>(<issue>10</issue>):<fpage>1465</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1471</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25981397</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b13-1031806"><label>13.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Avecilla</surname><given-names>ST</given-names></name><name><surname>Goss</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Bleau</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Tonon</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name><name><surname>Meagher</surname><given-names>RC</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>How do I perform hematopoietic progenitor cell
selection&#x000bf;</article-title>
<source>Transfusion</source>.
<year>2016</year>;<volume>56</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>1008</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1012</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26919388</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b14-1031806"><label>14.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Muller</surname><given-names>LU</given-names></name><name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>DA</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Finding the needle in the hay stack:
hematopoietic stem cells in Fanconi anemia (Review)</article-title>.
<source>Mutat Res</source>.
<year>2009</year>;<volume>668</volume>(<issue>1&#x02013;2</issue>):<fpage>141</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>149</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19508850</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b15-1031806"><label>15.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kelly</surname><given-names>PF</given-names></name><name><surname>Radtke</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>von Kalle</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Stem cell collection and gene transfer in
Fanconi anemia</article-title>. <source>Mol Ther</source>.
<year>2007</year>;<volume>15</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>211</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>219</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17164793</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b16-1031806"><label>16.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Radtke</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Adair</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name><name><surname>Giese</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>A distinct hematopoietic stem cell population
for rapid multilineage engraftment in nonhuman primates</article-title>.
<source>Sci Transl Med</source>. <year>2017</year>;
<volume>9</volume>(<issue>414</issue>).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b17-1031806"><label>17.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Adair</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name><name><surname>Waters</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Haworth</surname><given-names>KG</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Semi-automated closed system manufacturing of
lentivirus gene-modified haematopoietic stem cells for gene
therapy</article-title>. <source>Nat Commun</source>.
<year>2016</year>;<volume>7</volume>:<fpage>13173</fpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27762266</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b18-1031806"><label>18.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wiekmeijer</surname><given-names>AS</given-names></name><name><surname>Pike-Overzet</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name><surname>Brugman</surname><given-names>MH</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Sustained engraftment of cryopreserved human
bone marrow CD34(+) cells in young adult NSG mice</article-title>.
<source>Biores Open Access</source>.
<year>2014</year>;<volume>3</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>110</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>116</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24940562</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b19-1031806"><label>19.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Read</surname><given-names>EJ</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Engraftment of hematopoietic progenitor cells
transduced with the Fanconi anemia group C gene (FANCC)</article-title>.
<source>Hum Gene Ther</source>. <year>1999</year>;
<volume>10</volume>(<issue>14</issue>):<fpage>2337</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2346</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10515453</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b20-1031806"><label>20.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Croop</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name><name><surname>Cooper</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Fernandez</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Mobilization and collection of peripheral blood
CD34+ cells from patients with Fanconi anemia</article-title>.
<source>Blood</source>.
<year>2001</year>;<volume>98</volume>(<issue>10</issue>):<fpage>2917</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2921</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11698271</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b21-1031806"><label>21.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Larghero</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Marolleau</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><name><surname>Soulier</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Hematopoietic progenitor cell harvest and
functionality in Fanconi anemia patients</article-title>.
<source>Blood</source>.
<year>2002</year>;<volume>100</volume>(<issue>8</issue>):<fpage>3051</fpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12382645</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b22-1031806"><label>22.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Uchida</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Fujita</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Hsieh</surname><given-names>MM</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Bone marrow as a hematopoietic stem cell source
for gene therapy in sickle cell disease: Evidence from rhesus and SCD
patients</article-title>. <source>Hum Gene Ther Clin Dev</source>.
<year>2017</year>;<volume>28</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>136</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>144</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28447889</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b23-1031806"><label>23.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Balakumaran</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Mishra</surname><given-names>PJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Pawelczyk</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Bone marrow skeletal stem/progenitor cell
defects in dyskeratosis congenita and telomere biology
disorders</article-title>. <source>Blood</source>. <year>2015</year>;
<volume>125</volume>(<issue>5</issue>):<fpage>793</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>802</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25499762</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b24-1031806"><label>24.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Coulombel</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Identification of hematopoietic stem/progenitor
cells: strength and drawbacks of functional assays</article-title>.
<source>Oncogene</source>.
<year>2004</year>;<volume>23</volume>(<issue>43</issue>):<fpage>7210</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>7222</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">15378081</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b25-1031806"><label>25.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Miller</surname><given-names>CL</given-names></name><name><surname>Eaves</surname><given-names>CJ</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Long-term culture-initiating cell assays for
human and murine cells</article-title>. <source>Methods Mol Med</source>.
<year>2002</year>;<volume>63</volume>:<fpage>123</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>141</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21437804</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b26-1031806"><label>26.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jacome</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Navarro</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Rio</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Lentiviral-mediated genetic correction of
hematopoietic and mesenchymal progenitor cells from Fanconi anemia
patients</article-title>. <source>Mol Ther</source>. <year>2009</year>;
<volume>17</volume>(<issue>6</issue>):<fpage>1083</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1092</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19277017</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b27-1031806"><label>27.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>He</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Xing</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>An abnormal bone marrow microenvironment
contributes to hematopoietic dysfunction in Fanconi anemia</article-title>.
<source>Haematologica</source>. <year>2017</year>;
<volume>102</volume>(<issue>6</issue>):<fpage>1017</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1027</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28341737</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="b28-1031806"><label>28.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Rio</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Navarro</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Guenechea</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Engraftment and in vivo proliferation advantage
of gene-corrected mobilized CD34(+) cells from Fanconi anemia
patients</article-title>. <source>Blood</source>.
<year>2017</year>;<volume>130</volume>(<issue>13</issue>):<fpage>1535</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1542</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28801449</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>