<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract>
 <title>Abstract</title>
 <p>We investigated the effects of CD34
  <sup>+</sup> cell therapy on right ventricular (RV) function in patients with nonischemic dilated cardiomyopathy (DCM). We enrolled 60 patients with DCM who were randomized to CD34
  <sup>+</sup> cell therapy (Stem Cells (SC) Group 
  <italic>n</italic> = 30), or no cell therapy (Controls, 
  <italic>n</italic> = 30). The SC Group received granulocyte‐colony stimulating factor, and CD34
  <sup>+</sup> cells were collected by apheresis and injected transendocardially. Patients were followed for 6 months. At baseline, the groups did not differ in age, gender, left ventricular ejection fraction, N‐terminal probrain natriuretic peptide, or parameters of RV function. At 6 months, we found a significant improvement in RV function in the SC Group (tricuspid annular plane systolic excursion [TAPSE]: +0.44 ± 0.64 cm, 
  <italic>p</italic> = .001; peak systolic tissue Doppler velocity of tricuspid annulus [St]: +1.5 ± 2.1 cm/s; 
  <italic>p</italic> = .001; percent of fractional area change [FAC]: +8.6% ± 5%, 
  <italic>p</italic> = .01), but not in Controls (TAPSE: −0.07 ± 0.32 cm, 
  <italic>p</italic> = .40; St: −0.1 ± 1.2 cm/s; 
  <italic>p</italic> = .44; FAC: −1.2% ± 3.2%, 
  <italic>p</italic> = .50). On repeat electroanatomical mapping, we found an improvement in interventricular septum viability in 19 of 30 patients from the SC Group; this correlated with the improvements in RV function (13/19 in the improved septum group versus 3/11 in the remaining cohort, 
  <italic>p</italic> = .029). These results suggest that patients with DCM, changes in RV function correlate with changes of viability of interventricular septum. CD34
  <sup>+</sup> cell therapy appears to be associated with improved right ventricular function in this patient cohort. (Clinical Trial Registration Information: 
  <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.clinicaltrials.gov" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">www.clinicaltrials.gov</ext-link>; NCT02248532). S
  <sc>tem</sc> C
  <sc>ells</sc> T
  <sc>ranslational</sc> M
  <sc>edicine</sc>
  <italic>2018;7:168–172</italic>
 </p>
</abstract>
