<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par14">Variations in long-term gonadal impairment in CCS who received the same treatment suggest that genetic variation may be an important determinant of gonadal impairment in CCS. Currently, only limited information is available on the role of genetic factors in the development of impaired gonadal reserve after childhood cancer treatment [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>]. One single center study has been performed which evaluated seven genetic single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) in 176 female CCS. These SNPs were selected based on the fact that they have been found to be associated with age at menopause in large genome wide association studies (GWAS) in the general female population [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>]. While one of these allelic variations in the 
 <italic>BRSK1</italic> gene (rs1172822) was found associated with a low anti-Müllerian hormone (AMH) level in CCS [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>], replication of this finding has not been reported so far. Meanwhile, many more SNPs have been reported to be associated with reproductive ageing in the general population coming from large-scale collaborative consortia [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>] but none have yet been investigated in CCS. In order to identify independent genetic determinants for therapy related gonadal impairment, substantially sized cohorts with well-documented clinical as well as treatment data are required. In addition, independent replication cohorts must be available to validate the results. One GWAS [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>] has been performed (with Affymetrix 6.0 SNP array) in the St. Jude Lifetime Cohort Study (SJLIFE) among 799 ethnically mixed female CCS, which included an independent replication cohort (genotyped with the Illumina Omni5 SNP array) of 1624 women from the ethnically mixed Childhood Cancer Survivor Study (CCSS). This GWAS did not identify a genome wide significant hit, but found a SNP (rs9999820) that was borderline significantly associated (
 <italic>p</italic> = 3.3*10
 <sup>− 7</sup>) with an increased risk of premature menopause, especially in the subgroup of CCS who had undergone ovarian irradiation. This haplotype, consisting of 4 SNPs, is associated with increased hippocampal 
 <italic>NPYR2</italic> gene expresssion, which is associated with a neuroendocrine pathway [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]. Noteworthy is that this GWAS evaluated the genetic variation in (self-reported) premature menopause, the latest manifestation of gonadal impairment or ageing.
</p>
