<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="research-article"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Publishing DTD v1.1 20151215//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName JATS-journalpublishing1.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 1.1?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName jp2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Medicine (Baltimore)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Medicine (Baltimore)</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">MEDI</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Medicine</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">0025-7974</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1536-5964</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Lippincott Williams &#x00026; Wilkins</publisher-name><publisher-loc>Hagerstown, MD</publisher-loc></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">7717794</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">MD-D-20-10625</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000023461</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="art-access-id">23461</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>6300</subject></subj-group><subj-group><subject>Research Article</subject><subject>Study Protocol Clinical Trial</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Music intervention improves the physical and mental status for patients with breast cancer</article-title><subtitle>A protocol of randomized controlled trial</subtitle></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Xiuting</given-names></name><degrees>MM</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>a</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Du</surname><given-names>Guangpeng</given-names></name><degrees>MB</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2"><sup>b</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Wei</given-names></name><degrees>MB</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3"><sup>c</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">http://orcid.org/0000-0003-4853-6421</contrib-id><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Fangfei</given-names></name><degrees>MB</degrees><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff4"><sup>d</sup></xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp"><sup>&#x02217;</sup></xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff1"><label>a</label>Department of Radiology</aff><aff id="aff2"><label>b</label>Department of General Medicine</aff><aff id="aff3"><label>c</label>Department of Neurology</aff><aff id="aff4"><label>d</label>Department of Urology, Jinan Central Hospital, Shandong, China.</aff><author-notes id="cor1"><corresp><label>&#x02217;</label>Correspondence: Fangfei Wang, Department of urology, Jinan Central Hospital, Shandong 250013, China (e-mail: <email>wangfangfei9521@126.com</email>).</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><day>4</day><month>12</month><year>2020</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>04</day><month>12</month><year>2020</year></pub-date><volume>99</volume><issue>49</issue><elocation-id>e23461</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>28</day><month>10</month><year>2020</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>2</day><month>11</month><year>2020</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2020 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2020</copyright-year><license license-type="open-access" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0" specific-use="CC-BY"><license-p>This is an open access article distributed under the Creative Commons Attribution License 4.0 (CCBY), which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited. <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</ext-link></license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xlink:href="medi-99-e23461.pdf"/><abstract><title>Abstract</title><sec sec-type="background"><title>Background:</title><p>Breast cancer is the most familiar cancer and the major cause of the cancer death in women worldwide. The breast cancer patients may suffer from severe mental and physical trauma. At present, there are few studies on the music therapy for patients with breast cancer. The objective of our paper is to assess the effect of music intervention on mental and physical state of breast cancer patients.</p></sec><sec sec-type="methods"><title>Methods:</title><p>The experiment will be implemented from June 2021 to June 2022 at Jinan Central Hospital. The experiment was granted through the Research Ethics Committee of Jinan Central Hospital (no.08847765). The inclusion criteria requires that the age of female patients ranges from 25 to 65 years old, and the pathological diagnosis of breast cancer requires radical mastectomy (containing extensive radical mastectomy and modified radical mastectomy). Patients who do not like to listen to music or have severe debilitating diseases or are allergic to the sound will be excluded. Patients in the intervention group are given music intervention, and in control group, patients do not receive any information about the music therapy in the period of this study. The primary outcome is quality of life, psychological distress. The secondary outcomes are the heart rate, blood pressure, as well as Visual Analog Scale (VAS).</p></sec><sec sec-type="results"><title>Results:</title><p>Table 1 will illustrate the postoperative outcomes after music interventions between groups.</p></sec><sec sec-type="conclusion"><title>Conclusion:</title><p>Music intervention can improve the mental and physical health of the breast cancer patients.</p></sec><sec><title>Trial registration:</title><p>This study protocol was registered in Research Registry (researchregistry6168).</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group><title>Keywords</title><kwd>breast cancer</kwd><kwd>mental</kwd><kwd>music intervention</kwd><kwd>physical</kwd><kwd>protocol</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group id="award1" award-type="Fundref"><funding-source>Natural Science Foundation of Shandong</funding-source><award-id>2018927735</award-id><principal-award-recipient>Fangfei Wang</principal-award-recipient></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>OPEN-ACCESS</meta-name><meta-value>TRUE</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>COUNTRY</meta-name><meta-value>UNITED STATES</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec><label>1</label><title>Introduction</title><p>Breast cancer is one of the major causes of the death among female patients between 35 and 50 years of age.<sup>[<xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]</sup> Because of its high incidence rate, huge medical expenses and high mortality rate, it has become a major public health burden.<sup>[<xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]</sup> The incidence rate of breast cancer is increasing worldwide and rising even faster in countries with lower rates.<sup>[<xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]</sup> According to data from the developed countries, it can be seen that 1 in 8 women is at risk of suffering from breast cancer.<sup>[<xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]</sup></p><p>The treatment of breast cancer generally begins with surgery, followed by a combination of a variety of adjuvant therapies, including hormone therapy, chemotherapy, and radiotherapy.<sup>[<xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]</sup> Nevertheless, these advanced treatments are inherently aggressive and increases the exposure of patients to the side-effects of treatment. Female patients with breast cancer, particularly the patients who have undergone radical mastectomy, are facing huge pressure in their life. This includes damaged body images due to the loss of breasts, which can result in enduring and experiencing the negative effects of subsequent unhealthy emotions.</p><p>The researches of the impacts of music therapy on the cancer patients with a variety of diagnoses have exhibited many benefits.<sup>[<xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]</sup> Listening to the relaxing music is effective in reducing the distress associated with treatment, relaxing, decreasing anxiety, increasing comfort, and reducing nausea and vomiting.<sup>[<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]</sup> Other relevant researches have also indicated that the music therapy is an effective treatment in arousing positive memories and emotions, improving life quality and the quality of sleep, emotion, self-awareness, enhancing mental health, and reducing psychological symptoms (involving fatigue, fear, anxiety, diastolic blood pressure, and worry). It is reported that the music therapy can directly reduce the patients pain through specific social emotional, psychological, and physiological mechanisms.<sup>[<xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]</sup> At present, there are few studies on the music therapy for patients with breast cancer. The objective of our paper is to assess the influences of the music intervention on mental and physical state of breast cancer patients.</p></sec><sec><label>2</label><title>Methods</title><p>The experiment will be implemented from June 2021 to June 2022 at Jinan Central Hospital. The experiment was granted through the Research Ethics Committee of Jinan Central Hospital (no.08847765) and recorded in research registry (researchregistry6168). Before the registration, the patients who are recruited receive written informed consent.</p><sec><label>2.1</label><title>Inclusion and exclusion criteria</title><p>Eighty patients with breast cancer are included in the trial. The inclusion criteria requires that the age of female patients ranges from 25 to 65 years old, and the pathological diagnosis of breast cancer requires radical mastectomy (containing extensive radical mastectomy and modified radical mastectomy). Patients who do not like to listen to music or have severe debilitating diseases or are allergic to the sound will be excluded.</p></sec><sec><label>2.2</label><title>The intervention group</title><p>In intervention group, patients are introduced to 5 kinds of music and 100 music names stored in music media library on the MP3 players. Music therapy is provided through the trained researchers. The patients are instructed to choose their favorite music, control the volume of music, and then listen to it through utilizing the headphones linked to MP3 player. The whole intervention time contains hospitalization time after conducting the radical mastectomy and 2 periods of chemotherapy. Patients are asked to listen to the music 3 times a day (30&#x0200a;minutes each time) in the morning, noon, and evening, respectively. During the postoperative hospitalization, if the patients miss listening to music, the researchers encourage her to adhere. Once the patients are discharged from the hospital, they are followed up via a researcher over the phone.</p></sec><sec><label>2.3</label><title>The control group</title><p>The patients in control group do not provide any music therapy information in the period of study and only offer the routine care, involving chemotherapy nursing care and breast cancer nursing care.</p></sec><sec><label>2.4</label><title>Outcomes</title><p>The main outcome, life quality, is detected via the Functional Assessment Cancer Therapy-General (FACT-G), with a total of 27 items, which utilizes the five-point (0&#x02013;4) agreement scale.<sup>[<xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]</sup> Mental distress is detected through utilizing Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS), which is a self-reported measure with a total of 14 items, and contains two 7 subscales to evaluate depression and anxiety.<sup>[<xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]</sup> The secondary outcomes are the heart rate, blood pressure, as well as Visual Analog Scale (VAS).</p></sec><sec><label>2.5</label><title>Statistical analysis</title><p>The analysis of all the data are conducted with the software of IBM SPSS Statistics for Windows, version 20 (IBM Corp., Armonk, NY, USA). Subsequently, all data obtained are expressed with proper characteristics, for instance, median, mean, percentage and standard deviation. Continuous and categorical variables are analyzed using &#x003c7;<sup>2</sup>-tests and independent <italic>t</italic> tests, respectively. Intention-to-treat analysis is used for the outcome assessments. <italic>P</italic> value less than .05 indicates that there is statistical significance.</p></sec></sec><sec><label>3</label><title>Results</title><p>Table <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">1</xref> will illustrate the postoperative outcomes after music interventions between groups.</p><table-wrap id="T1" orientation="portrait" position="float"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Postoperative outcomes after music interventions between groups.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups" border="0"><thead><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Outcomes</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Interventiongroup (N&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;40)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Control group (N&#x0200a;=&#x0200a;40)</td><td align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>P</italic> value</td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">FACT-G</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Physical Well-Being Subscale</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Social Well-Being Subscale</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Emotional Well-Being Subscale</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Functional Well-Being Subscale</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">HADS</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">HADS Anxiety Subscale</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">HADS Depression Subscale</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Visual analog scale</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn fn-type="other"><p>FACT-G = Functional Assessment Cancer Therapy-General, HADS = Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec><sec><label>4</label><title>Discussion</title><p>Breast cancer is the most familiar cancer and the major cause of the cancer death in women worldwide.<sup>[<xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,<xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]</sup> The breast cancer patients may suffer from severe mental and physical trauma, involving damaged body images, the loss of breasts, insomnia, fatigue, pain, depression, as well as other negative emotions.<sup>[<xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]</sup> These traumas may have a negative impact on the long-term life quality in the survivors of breast cancer. Medication and surgery may be effective, but there may be secondary effects and side effects, resulting in some negative psychological impacts.<sup>[<xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]</sup></p><p>Patients with breast cancer are more likely to have anxiety and depression symptoms. In turn, depression can cause digestive problems, sleep difficulties, fatigue, lowered immune function, prolonged arousal, morbid anxiety, helplessness as well as pessimism.<sup>[<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]</sup> Severe anxiety may induce patients to experience high blood pressure and increased heart rate. Furthermore, women undergoing breast cancer surgery generally experience pain after operation, which can lead to considerable psychological and physical impairment. The art therapy and cognitive-behavioral therapy are the most familiar methods to manage the psychological state of these patients.<sup>[<xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]</sup> Among those methods, music intervention is highly recommended. Music therapy is carried out through the well-trained music therapists with various experience in the area of music, it is a process of systematic treatment containing evaluation, treatment, and assessment. Although several articles have reported the application of musical therapy in breast cancer patients, the positive effect remains under debate. This research may provide an evidence regarding the topic.</p></sec><sec><label>5</label><title>Conclusion</title><p>Music intervention can improve the mental and physical health of the breast cancer patients.</p></sec><sec><title>Author contributions</title><p>Fangfei Wang plans the study design. Wei Liu reviews the study protocol. Guangpeng Du will recruit participants and collect data. Xiuting Li writes the manuscript. All of the authors have read, commented on, and contributed to the submitted manuscript.</p><p><bold>Conceptualization:</bold> Guangpeng Du.</p><p><bold>Data curation:</bold> Wei Liu.</p><p><bold>Funding acquisition:</bold> Fangfei Wang.</p><p><bold>Investigation:</bold> Wei Liu.</p><p><bold>Methodology:</bold> Wei Liu.</p><p><bold>Software:</bold> Xiuting Li.</p><p><bold>Writing &#x02013; original draft:</bold> Xiuting Li.</p><p><bold>Writing &#x02013; review &#x00026; editing:</bold> Fangfei Wang.</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn fn-type="abbr"><p>Abbreviations: FACT-G = Functional Assessment Cancer Therapy-General, HADS = Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale, VAS = Visual Analog Scale.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>How to cite this article: Li X, Du G, Liu W, Wang F. Music intervention improves the physical and mental status for patients with breast cancer: a protocol of randomized controlled trial. <italic>Medicine</italic>. 2020;99:49(e23461).</p></fn><fn fn-type="supported-by"><p>This study is supported by Natural Science Foundation of Shandong (2018927735).</p></fn><fn fn-type="COI-statement"><p>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p>The datasets generated during and/or analyzed during the current study are publicly available.</p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="R1"><label>[1]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Libson</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Lippman</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>A review of clinical aspects of breast cancer</article-title>. <source>Int Rev Psychiatry</source>
<year>2014</year>;<volume>26</volume>:<fpage>4</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>15</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24716497</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R2"><label>[2]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Furrukh</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Qureshi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Treatment of breast cancer; review and updates</article-title>. <source>J Ayub Med Coll Abbottabad</source>
<year>2018</year>;<volume>30</volume>:<fpage>264</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>74</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29938432</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R3"><label>[3]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Deng</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Global burden of breast cancer and attributable risk factors in 195 countries and territories, from 1990 to 2017: results from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2017</article-title>. <source>J Hematol Oncol</source>
<year>2019</year>;<volume>12</volume>:<fpage>140</fpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31864424</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R4"><label>[4]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Coughlin</surname><given-names>SS</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Epidemiology of breast cancer in women</article-title>. <source>Adv Exp Med Biol</source>
<year>2019</year>;<volume>1152</volume>:<fpage>9</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>29</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31456177</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R5"><label>[5]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Winters</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Martin</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Murphy</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Breast cancer epidemiology, prevention, and screening</article-title>. <source>Prog Mol Biol Transl Sci</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>151</volume>:<fpage>1</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>32</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29096890</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R6"><label>[6]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Anampa</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Makower</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Sparano</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Progress in adjuvant chemotherapy for breast cancer: an overview</article-title>. <source>BMC Med</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>13</volume>:<fpage>195</fpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26278220</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R7"><label>[7]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Draganescu</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Carmocan</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Hormone therapy in breast cancer</article-title>. <source>Chirurgia (Bucur)</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>112</volume>:<fpage>413</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>7</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28862117</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R8"><label>[8]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Castaneda</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name><name><surname>Strasser</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Updates in the treatment of breast cancer with radiotherapy</article-title>. <source>Surg Oncol Clin N Am</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>26</volume>:<fpage>371</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>82</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28576177</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R9"><label>[9]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>XM</given-names></name><name><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>KN</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Effects of music therapy on pain among female breast cancer patients after radical mastectomy: results from a randomized controlled trial</article-title>. <source>Breast Cancer Res Treat</source>
<year>2011</year>;<volume>128</volume>:<fpage>411</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>9</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21537935</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R10"><label>[10]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>XM</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>KN</given-names></name><name><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Effects of music therapy on anxiety of patients with breast cancer after radical mastectomy: a randomized clinical trial</article-title>. <source>J Adv Nurs</source>
<year>2012</year>;<volume>68</volume>:<fpage>1145</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>55</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21978087</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R11"><label>[11]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chuang</surname><given-names>CY</given-names></name><name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>WR</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>PC</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Effect of long-term music therapy intervention on autonomic function in anthracycline-treated breast cancer patients</article-title>. <source>Integr Cancer Ther</source>
<year>2011</year>;<volume>10</volume>:<fpage>312</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>6</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21382955</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R12"><label>[12]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mah</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name><surname>Swami</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Le</surname><given-names>LW</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Validation of the 7-item Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy-General (FACT-G7) as a short measure of quality of life in patients with advanced cancer</article-title>. <source>Cancer-Am Cancer Soc</source>
<year>2020</year>;<volume>126</volume>:<fpage>3750</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>7</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R13"><label>[13]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Saboonchi</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Wennman-Larsen</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Alexanderson</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Examination of the construct validity of the Swedish version of Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale in breast cancer patients</article-title>. <source>Qual Life Res</source>
<year>2013</year>;<volume>22</volume>:<fpage>2849</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>56</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23568598</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R14"><label>[14]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Waks</surname><given-names>AG</given-names></name><name><surname>Winer</surname><given-names>EP</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Breast cancer treatment: a review</article-title>. <source>JAMA</source>
<year>2019</year>;<volume>321</volume>:<fpage>288</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>300</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30667505</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R15"><label>[15]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fahad</surname><given-names>UM</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Breast cancer: current perspectives on the disease status</article-title>. <source>Adv Exp Med Biol</source>
<year>2019</year>;<volume>1152</volume>:<fpage>51</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>64</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31456179</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R16"><label>[16]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shinden</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Kijima</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Hirata</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Clinical characteristics of breast cancer patients with mental disorders</article-title>. <source>Breast</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>36</volume>:<fpage>39</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>43</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28942099</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R17"><label>[17]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Stanton</surname><given-names>AL</given-names></name><name><surname>Bower</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Psychological adjustment in breast cancer survivors</article-title>. <source>Adv Exp Med Biol</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>862</volume>:<fpage>231</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>42</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26059939</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R18"><label>[18]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>The status and correlates of depression and anxiety among breast-cancer survivors in Eastern China: a population-based, cross-sectional case-control study</article-title>. <source>BMC Public Health</source>
<year>2014</year>;<volume>14</volume>:<fpage>326</fpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24708474</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R19"><label>[19]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Art therapy for anxiety, depression, and fatigue in females with breast cancer: A systematic review</article-title>. <source>J Psychosoc Oncol</source>
<year>2019</year>;<volume>37</volume>:<fpage>79</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>95</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30422064</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="R20"><label>[20]</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name><surname>Feng</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Effects of cognitive behavioral therapy on quality of life and stress for breast cancer survivors: a meta-analysis</article-title>. <source>Minerva Med</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>108</volume>:<fpage>84</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>93</lpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27635602</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>