<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract id="ABS1">
 <p id="P2">Relapse is the main cause of treatment failure after allogeneic stem cell transplant (alloSCT) in acute myeloid leukemia (AML) and myelodysplastic syndromes (MDS). Injectable azacitidine can improve post-transplant outcomes but presents challenges with exposure and compliance. Oral CC-486 allows extended dosing to prolong azacitidine activity. We investigated use of CC-486 maintenance therapy after alloSCT.</p>
 <p id="P3">Adults with MDS or AML in morphologic complete remission at CC-486 initiation (42 to 84 days after alloSCT) were included. Patients received 1 of 4 CC-486 dosing schedules per 28-day cycle for up to 12 cycles. Endpoints included safety, pharmacokinetics, graft-versus-host disease (GVHD) incidence, relapse/progression rate, and survival.</p>
 <p id="P4">Of 30 patients, 7 received CC-486 once daily for 7 days per cycle (200 mg, n = 3; 300 mg, n = 4) and 23 for 14 days per cycle (150 mg, n = 4; 200 mg, n = 19 [expansion cohort]). Grades 3 to 4 adverse events were infrequent and occurred with similar frequency across regimens. Standard concomitant medications did not alter CC-486 pharmacokinetic parameters. Three patients (10%) experienced grade III acute GVHD and 9 experienced chronic GVHD. Of 28 evaluable patients, 6 (21%) relapsed or had progressive disease: 3 of 7 patients (43%) who had received 7-day dosing and 3 of 23 (13%) who had received 14-day dosing. Transplant-related mortality was 3%. At 19 months of follow-up, median overall survival was not reached. Estimated 1-year survival rates were 86% and 81% in the 7-day and 14-day dosing cohorts, respectively.</p>
 <p id="P5">CC-486 maintenance was generally well tolerated, with low rates of relapse, disease progression, and GVHD. CC-486 maintenance may permit epigenetic manipulation of the alloreactive response postallograft. Findings require confirmation in randomized trials. (
  <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://ClinicalTrials.gov" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">ClinicalTrials.gov</ext-link>
  <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT01835587" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">NCT01835587</ext-link>.)
 </p>
</abstract>
