<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>This 44-year-old female presented with daily productive cough and expectoration for 4 years and experienced recurrence for more than half a year. The respiratory symptoms were predominantly nocturnal and more severe in the winter. She was diagnosed with chronic cough and was treated with cough medications for cough symptoms, which did not prevent the disease from worsening. Seven months prior, the chest film and spirometry test were almost normal; however, 4 months prior, the cough returned and the patient suffered from cough-related syncope for 3 h. She denied chest pain, chest distress, shortness of breath, heartburn, or acid regurgitation. She had no known allergies and denied smoking. The patient presented no abnormality on physical examination. White blood cell count, eosinophil count, and serum immunoglobulin E (39.1 IU/mL, normal value &lt;100 IU/mL) were normal. Chest high-resolution CT (HRCT) (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1A</xref>), pulmonary ventilation and single-breath diffusing capacity of the lung for carbon monoxide were normal. The methacholine challenge test for bronchial hyperreactivity was negative (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1B</xref>). In pulmonary function testing, the forced vital capacity (FVC) was 2.99 L (100.9% of predicted value), the forced expiratory volume in 1 s (FEV
 <sub>1</sub>) was 2.45 L (96.5% of predicted value), and the FEV
 <sub>1</sub>/FVC ratio was 81.99% (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1C</xref>). The patient's electrocardiogram (ECG) showed normal sinus rhythm with frequent premature ventricular beats (PVCs) (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">Figure 2</xref>). The 24 h-Holter ECG monitor showed normal sinus rhythm with 27553 PVCs (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F3">Figure 3</xref>). The frequent occurrence of PVCs was associated with repetitive coughing. Two-dimensional color echocardiography was normal except for trivial regurgitant flow (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F4">Figure 4</xref>). Subsequent treatment with oral antiarrhythmic drugs was ineffective. Therefore, radiofrequency ablation of the arrhythmogenic focus was proposed. Surprisingly, cough disappeared after radiofrequency ablation, and no recurrence of arrhythmia or cough was observed (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F5">Figure 5</xref>).
</p>
