<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="para20">
 <boxed-text id="cetextbox10">
  <caption>
   <title>Research in context</title>
  </caption>
  <p id="para30">
   <bold>Evidence before this study</bold>
  </p>
  <p id="para40">CHOP combination chemotherapy (cyclophosphamide, doxorubicin, vincristine, and prednisolone) is widely used for treatment of peripheral T-cell lymphoma; however, outcomes with CHOP are poor for most patients. We investigated GEM-P chemotherapy (gemcitabine, methylprednisolone, and cisplatin) compared with CHOP in previously untreated patients with peripheral T-cell lymphoma. We searched PubMed on Dec 4, 2017, for English-language articles published from January, 1998, to October, 2017, and searched abstracts from the American Society of Hematology and American Society of Clinical Oncology published between 2015–17 with the search terms "T-cell lymphoma”, "chemotherapy”, and "gemcitabine”, excluding studies in which patients with non-nodal peripheral T-cell lymphoma forms were assessed exclusively. We identified 30 reports showing activity of gemcitabine in peripheral T-cell lymphoma; three with gemcitabine as monotherapy and nine with a combination of gemcitabine with platinum and steroids predominantly in pretreated populations, including three retrospective reports on GEM-P specifically in peripheral T-cell lymphoma. Different combinations of gemcitabine with other novel drugs, with or without the addition of platinum, in the treatment of peripheral T-cell lymphoma were also reported in the scientific literature, including one randomised trial that assessed the combination of gemcitabine, cisplatin, prednisolone and thalidomide versus CHOP in treatment-naive patients. However, there were no reported randomised studies on the combination of gemcitabine, platinum, and steroids alone versus CHOP in the front-line setting.</p>
  <p id="para50">
   <bold>Added value of this study</bold>
  </p>
  <p id="para60">Our phase 2 trial is one of the few randomised studies in previously untreated patients with peripheral T-cell lymphoma and is an important addition to the evidence-base. The findings confirm the poor outcomes for peripheral T-cell lymphoma within a prospective trial cohort and indicate that CHOP should remain the reference regimen at present. Our trial was the first prospective study to assess an 
   <sup>18</sup>F-FDG-PET-CT response in patients with peripheral T-cell lymphoma as part of a pre-planned substudy, and the data suggest that 
   <sup>18</sup>F-FDG-PET-CT might be a more sensitive tool than contrast-enhanced CT for determining response in peripheral T-cell lymphoma, as it might better distinguish between a residual fibrotic mass present after chemotherapy versus viable tumour. Furthermore, obtaining a complete response by 
   <sup>18</sup>F-FDG-PET-CT was independently prognostic for superior progression-free survival in multivariable analysis, whereas complete response by CT was not. Additionally, we reported the incidence and pattern of CNS relapse in peripheral T-cell lymphoma from a prospective trial. Determination of the subtype of peripheral T-cell lymphoma in our study was revised for around a fifth of the patients, highlighting the diagnostic challenges in peripheral T-cell lymphoma. Despite GEM-P showing non-significant inferiority for the endpoint of CT-based confirmed and unconfirmed complete response compared with CHOP, there were no differences in either progression-free survival or overall survival between the groups; future study design in this indication should be powered for primary endpoints of survival rather than complete response, which might not be an accurate surrogate endpoint (particularly when assessed by contrast-enhanced CT) in peripheral T-cell lymphoma.
  </p>
  <p id="para70">
   <bold>Implications of all the available evidence</bold>
  </p>
  <p id="para80">Taken together, current evidence supports the use of gemcitabine as an effective therapy in the management of peripheral T-cell lymphoma. However, our randomised phase 2 study did not suggest superiority of GEM-P over CHOP in the front-line setting for previously untreated patients and therefore, CHOP should remain the reference regimen in this indication for previously untreated patients. Although GEM-P has shown efficacy in patients with peripheral T-cell lymphoma, at present it should be reserved for patients with relapsed or refractory disease. A superior upfront induction regimen is urgently required for patients with treatment-naive peripheral T-cell lymphoma, and future incorporation of novel drugs could enhance the efficacy of front-line therapy in this indication. Trials are ongoing (
   <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://ClinicalTrials.gov" id="interrefs30" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">ClinicalTrials.gov</ext-link>
   <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="ctgov:NCT01777152" id="interrefs40" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">NCT01777152</ext-link>, 
   <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="ctgov:NCT01796002" id="interrefs50" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">NCT01796002</ext-link>, and 
   <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="ctgov:NCT02561273" id="interrefs60" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">NCT02561273</ext-link>) to address this research question.
  </p>
 </boxed-text>
</p>
