<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par10">Dermatological diseases are relatively common in diabetic patients, in which they manifest cutaneously as a variety of conditions such as bacterial and fungal infections, diabetic dermopathy, granuloma annulare, and necrobiosis lipoidica diabeticorum [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>]. Bullosis diabeticorum is a rare cutaneous disease, with 100 cases or case series reported in the literature [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>], characterized by spontaneous noninflammatory manifestations, painless subcutaneous fluid-filled vesicles varying in size from a few millimeters to a few centimeters. It is usually distributed in the lower extremities, in which there is an observed risk of developing secondary infection, including diabetic skin ulcer (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1a</xref>), osteomyelitis (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1b</xref>), or wet gangrene (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1c</xref>), even diabetic amputation. Presently the exact etiology of bullosis diabticorum is not well understood. Several studies revealed that its occurrence is closely related to diabetic patients with complications of microangiopathy [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>], neuropathy, and poor regulation of blood glucose [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>]. Bullosis diabeticorum is not uncommon in our clinical experience and observation; an average of 250 people with diabetes per year with foot problems (skin disease, ulcer, gangrene) were treated in the past 10 years, including about 60 cases with bullosis diabticorm. Thus, there is a bullosis diabeticorum incidence rate of 2.4% per year in our clinic. Bullosis diabticorum is prone to occur in patients with local microcirculation dysfunction (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2a</xref>-
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">d</xref>) and diabetic neuropathy (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2e</xref>-
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">h</xref>). Often, conservative treatment is often considered, while aggressive surgical debridement and subsequently skin grafting are indicated in more severe cases [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>]. Moreover, the elimination of causative factors is imperative for prevention of its recurrence and complications [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>]. In our previous study, we successfully treated diabetic critical limb ischemia with bone marrow mesenchymal stem cells (BMMSCs) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]. To further explore their benefits, we have administered BMMSC transplantation therapy to a patient with recurrent bullosis diabeticorum in the left lower limb complicated by limb ischemia and mild venous insufficiency.
</p>
