<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fig id="Fig6">
 <label>Fig. 6</label>
 <caption>
  <p>Efficacy of long-term SMOi-combined therapy in preclinical models. 
   <bold>a</bold>–
   <bold>c</bold> Concomitant expression analysis of collagen content and organization, integrin pathway activation and CSC-like characteristics at the tumor−stromal interface of the TNBC HCI-002 PDX model treated with vehicle (red) or the SMO inhibitor NVP-LDE225 (80 mg/kg/day; blue) (
   <italic>n</italic> = 5 biological replicates). 
   <bold>a</bold> Representative imaging (scale bars: 100 μm) and quantitative analysis of collagen abundance (left panel). Statistical significance was determined using unpaired two-tailed Student’s 
   <italic>t</italic> test with equal s.d. Corresponding graphs comparing fiber orientation (middle) and quantifying GLCM analysis (right panel) in the vehicle and SMOi-treated models. Unpaired two-tailed nonparametric Mann–Whitney 
   <italic>U</italic> test was used for determining statistical significance across distributions. 
   <bold>b</bold> Collagen I and III deposition detected and quantified by picrosirius red staining. Scale bars, 200 μm. Statistical significance was determined using unpaired two-tailed Student’s 
   <italic>t</italic> test with equal s.d. 
   <bold>c</bold> Representative immunofluorescence images and quantification of concomitant phospho-FAK (green) and the human CSC marker ALDH1 (red) expression in the HCI-002 model. The white arrows illustrate examples of co-staining within the epithelial population. Scale bars, 100 μm. 
   <italic>n</italic> = 3 biological replicates. Statistical significance was determined using Kruskal−Wallis test. 
   <bold>d</bold>–
   <bold>f</bold> TNBC HCI-002 PDX model treated with vehicle (blue), SMO inhibitor (NVP-LDE225; 80 mg/kg/day; magenta), chemotherapy (docetaxel; 15 mg/kg/week; dark orange) or NVP-LDE225 (80 mg/kg/day) + docetaxel (15 mg/kg/week; orange line) (
   <italic>n</italic> = 7 mice per treatment group). 
   <bold>d</bold> Tumor growth curves. Statistical significance was determined using unpaired Student’s 
   <italic>t</italic> test. 
   <bold>e</bold> Percentage of mice with detectable metastases in the lung, liver, and axillary lymph node in each treatment group. Statistical significance was determined using the Fisher’s exact test. 
   <bold>f</bold> Kaplan−Meier curves of mice overall survival of each treatment group. Statistical significance was determined using Log-rank test of NVP-LDE225 + docetaxel vs. docetaxel; *
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.05; ***
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.001; ****
   <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.0001. Bars on the graphs represent mean ± s.e.m.
  </p>
 </caption>
 <graphic xlink:href="41467_2018_5220_Fig6_HTML" id="d29e1755" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
</fig>
