<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract id="Abs1">
 <sec>
  <title>Background</title>
  <p id="Par1">Anti-CD19 chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T cells have shown promise in the treatment of B cell acute lymphocytic leukemia (B-ALL). However, its efficacy in B-ALL patients with extramedullary involvement is limited due to poor responses and neurotoxicity. Here, we utilized a third generation of CAR T cell vector, which contains the Toll/interleukin-1 receptor (ITR) domain of Toll-like receptor 2 (TLR2), to generate 1928zT2 T cells targeting CD19, and evaluated the efficacy of 1928zT2 T cells in relapse or refractory B-ALL patients with extramedullary involvement.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Methods</title>
  <p id="Par2">1928zT2 T cells were generated by 19-28z-TLR2 lentiviral vector transfection into primary human T lymphocytes. The anti-leukemia effect of 1928zT2 T cells were determined by killing assays and in xenografts. Three patients diagnosed as relapse or refractory ALL with extramedullary involvement were infused with 1928zT2 T cells, and the clinical responses were evaluated by BM smear, B-ultrasonography, PET/CT, histology, flow cytometry, qPCR, ELISA, and luminex assay.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Results</title>
  <p id="Par3">1928zT2 T cells exhibited enhanced effector function against CD19+ leukemic cells in vitro and in a xenograft model of human extramedullary leukemia. Notably, the 1928zT2 T cells eradicated extramedullary leukemia and induced complete remission in the three relapse and refractory ALL patients without serious adverse effects. 1928zT2 T cells expanded robustly in the circulation of these three patients and were detected in the cerebrospinal fluid of patient 3. These three patients experienced cytokine release syndrome (CRS) with grade 2 or 3, which remitted spontaneously or after tocilizumab treatment. None of the three patients suffered neurotoxicity or needed further intensive care.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Conclusions</title>
  <p id="Par4">Our results demonstrate that 1928zT2 T cells with TLR2 incorporation augment anti-leukemic effects, particularly for eradicating extramedullary leukemia cells, and suggest that the infusion of 1928zT2 T cells is an encouraging treatment for relapsed/refractory ALL patients with extramedullary involvement.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Trial registration</title>
  <p id="Par5">ClinicalTrials.gov identifier 
   <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.clinicaltrials.gov/NCT02822326" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">NCT02822326</ext-link>. Date of registration: July 4, 2016.
  </p>
 </sec>
</abstract>
