<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fig id="Fig5">
 <label>Fig. 5</label>
 <caption>
  <p>The 1928zT2 T cells exhibited potent anti-leukemia effect in patient 3. 
   <bold>a</bold> shows the development and therapeutic process of this ALL patient with CNS-3 status and extramedullary involvement. He was diagnosed as ALL in March, 2000. The first recurrence (RE1) involved in BM and CNS, and the second RE2 occurred in CNS again. The third relapse (RE3) was identified in CNS and EM in June, 2017. This patient also received fludarabine (F) and cytarabine (C) daily to achieve lymphodepletion and a split-dose infusion of 1928zT2 T cells (1 × 10
   <sup>6</sup> cells/kg) was applied. 
   <bold>b</bold> of the PET/CT data shows multiple organs involved by extramedullary ALL, including almost the entire pleura, peritoneum, pelvic fascia, pancreas, and multiple lymph nodes. Restage of PET/CT on D60 after cells infusion presented that no infiltration of cancer cells into the involved tissues at all. 
   <bold>c</bold> A biopsy of the right-sided supraclavicular node mass at baseline shows the presence of blasts, megakaryocytes, erythroblasts, and myeloid cells, proven to be extramedullary relapse. 
   <bold>d</bold> of B-mode ultrasound on tissues below xiphoid shows an inhomogeneous hypo-echoic mass about 3.0 × 1.9 cm in diameter before cells infusion and disappearance of the mass during the follow-up. 
   <bold>e</bold> shows the typical presence of leukemic blast cells (at least 5 blasts in the whole cytocentrifuged smear) in CSF at baseline (Pre-treatment) and only normal mature lymphocytes was seen at D18 and thereafter. 
   <bold>f</bold> of the flow-cytometric data shows that despite about 20.8% blasts with CD19
   <sup>+</sup>CD10
   <sup>+</sup> phenotype was observed in the WBC from CSF before cells infusion, there were undetectable levels of blasts at several time points after treatment. 
   <bold>g</bold> shows that 50% of the cerebrospinal cells were identified as XY-type recipient cells by FISH, indicating the relapse in the CSF. However, there were 100% recipient cells (XX) in CSF after 1928zT2 T cells infusion, suggested complete eradication of blasts in CSF
  </p>
 </caption>
 <graphic xlink:href="13045_2018_572_Fig5_HTML" id="MO5" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
</fig>
