<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fig id="Fig6">
 <label>Fig. 6</label>
 <caption>
  <p>The expansion of 1928zT2 T cells and relevant clinical changes in these patients. 
   <bold>a</bold> The results of flow-cytometric GFP-positive cells analysis in patient 1 showed the 1928zT2 T cells were expanded significantly which began on day 5, peak on day 12, and disappeared after day 92. The CD19-positive cells in periphery blood were dropped quickly within 10 days to the undetectable level and increased again. 
   <bold>b</bold> Patient 2 presented with the presence and elevation of GFP+1928zT2 T cells in the periphery blood from day 10 to day 50. The CD19+ cells were reduced significantly till undetectable. 
   <bold>c</bold> Since the patient 2 had the relapse also in the BM, we found the upregulation of 1928zT2 T cells in the BM, accompanied with eradication of CD19+ cells. 
   <bold>d</bold> The 1928zT2 T cells was expanded significantly on day 12 with 57% of T cells and was undetectable after day 17 in the patient 3. 
   <bold>e</bold> shows the presence of 1928zT2 T cells in CSF from patient 3 with a peak on day 18, indicating the trafficking ability of these cells. Consistently, the blast cells in CSF were undetectable after day 18. 
   <bold>f</bold> shows changes in body temperature after1928zT2 T infusion in these three patients. 
   <bold>g</bold> Patient 1 suffered from grade 2 CRS with fever from day 7 to day 13. IL-6 was elevated slightly with a peak level on day 11, coincided with the occurrence of CRS. The C-Reactive protein (CRP) was also increased. 
   <bold>h</bold> Patient 2 also suffered from CRS with grade 2 from day 9 to day 12 and the expression pattern of IL-6 and CRP was similar to patient 1. 
   <bold>i</bold> For the patient 3, IL-6 was elevated markedly with a peak level on day 10 and decreased after twice usage of tocilizumab, coincided with the occurrence of CRS from day 7 to day 15 (black arrows)
  </p>
 </caption>
 <graphic xlink:href="13045_2018_572_Fig6_HTML" id="MO6" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"/>
</fig>
