<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The severity of symptoms of anxiety and depression was higher in girls than in boys with developmental disabilities, which is consistent with results from previous studies (
 <xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>). Over one-third of girls experienced mild or stronger symptoms of anxiety and depression, whereas &lt;15% of boys experienced symptoms of anxiety, and 20% experienced symptoms of depression. We did not find significant differences between girls and boys in terms of the impact of the sum of experienced inconveniences on anxiety. However, the effect of interaction between gender and inconveniences was close to statistical significance (
 <italic>p</italic> = 0.070). This indicates that lockdown-related anxiety should be investigated further in larger samples. In our study, we also found that the number of lockdown-related inconveniences associated with depression symptoms affected participants differently depending on their gender. In girls, the number of difficulties related to lockdown considerably impacted their symptoms of depression. This result may indicate that girls with developmental disabilities are particularly vulnerable when it comes to coping with difficulties that arise in unexpected and burdensome situations, such as the COVID-19 lockdown. The sex differences in levels of anxiety and depression occur typically in general population (
 <xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>), and also in persons with intellectual disability (
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>). The possible explanations why the boys presented less symptoms in our study may concern social expectations regarding the male role in society, which may lead to underreporting of emotional problems (
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>), or variety of biological factors (
 <xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>). In our study a small number of boys seemed to show increase in emotional symptoms as a function of pandemic-related inconveniences. In future studies differences between boys who do and boys who do not develop emotional symptoms should also be an object of an in-depth analysis.
</p>
