<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The long cultivation time, high equipment requirements and unqualified sputum sample quality constitute important limitations of the diagnostic ability and use of pathogen−based detection, causing insufficient understanding and misdiagnosis of clinically diagnosed PTB (
 <xref rid="B37" ref-type="bibr">Yu et al., 2019</xref>). The resulting treatment delay and undertreatment represent important risk factors in the disease transmission and negatively affect the management of clinically diagnosed PTB (
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">Hernandez-Garduno et al., 2004</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B38" ref-type="bibr">Zhang et al., 2017</xref>). The recent recommendations of the WHO include non−pathogen−based detection to improve the identification of clinically diagnosed PTB using rapid and universal methods (
 <xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">Martinez and Andrews, 2019</xref>). Therefore, biomarkers of the host immune responses might provide key insights to solve this problem. Long non-coding RNA (lncRNA) is non-coding RNA with a length greater than 200 nucleotides. The change in the lncRNA is the earliest spatiotemporal event after the virus invasion to initiate the host response, which is the upstream event of proteomics and metabolomics and happens earlier than the generation of antibodies (
 <xref rid="B21" ref-type="bibr">Rossetti et al., 2013</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B39" ref-type="bibr">Zhao et al., 2016</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B23" ref-type="bibr">Tan et al., 2018</xref>). Accumulating evidence has indicated that lncRNA is closely associated with the occurrence or development of PTB and has the potential to be an early and noninvasive biomarker for clinically diagnosed PTB (
 <xref rid="B33" ref-type="bibr">Wang et al., 2015</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B32" ref-type="bibr">2019</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">Chen et al., 2017</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">Li et al., 2020</xref>). In a previous microarray analysis study of our research group, we showed that the expression of lncRNA n344917 (n344917 for short; located on chromosome 6: 85677082–85678394; lncRNA microarray data have been deposited in the Gene Expression Omnibus under accession no. 
 <ext-link ext-link-type="DDBJ/EMBL/GenBank" xlink:href="GSE119143" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">GSE119143</ext-link>) was significantly down-regulated in the peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC) of patients with clinically diagnosed PTB (FC = 2.5, 
 <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.05). According to the NONCODE database, n344917 was highly expressed in both lymphocytes and leukocytes, which suggests that it may be associated with the immune response to 
 <italic>M. tuberculosis</italic>. Specifically, it could be valuable to further investigate the application of n344917 in the identification of clinically diagnosed PTB.
</p>
