<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In this study, we monitored peripheral γδ T cell repertoire dynamics in a homogenous cohort of chronic HCV patients before and during DAA therapy. All HCV patients had similar characteristics by being persistently infected with the HCV genotype 1, by no development of liver cirrhosis and by receiving a short 8 weeks therapeutic drug treatment. It was reasonable to expect an impact of chronic HCV infection and its clearance on γδ T cell dynamics, because γδ T cells play a role in the antiviral defense of CMV, HCV, and other viruses (
 <xref rid="B22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B49" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B50" ref-type="bibr">50</xref>). During HCV infection, cytokine release (IFN-γ) by Vγ9JP
 <sup>+</sup>Vδ2
 <sup>+</sup> and non-Vγ9JP
 <sup>+</sup>Vδ2
 <sup>+</sup> may contribute to virus clearance, while HCV persistence is associated with low γδ T cell numbers and an impaired cytokine production (
 <xref rid="B22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>). By contrast, chronic HCV patients with high liver inflammation rather have increased frequencies of cytotoxic γδ T cells when compared with healthy subjects or patients with no liver inflammation. In our study, all chronic HCV patients included had no or only mild liver fibrosis and mild liver inflammation, which might explain that they displayed no significantly, elevated numbers of γδ T cells. Importantly, eradication of the viral infection resulted in significant improvement of liver stiffness and inflammation as revealed by fibroscan values and ALT levels. Overall, our TCR analyses showed that uncomplicated chronic HCV infection and rapid viral clearance had only minor effects on the peripheral γδ T cell compartment, indicating that more drastic immunological events are required for perturbation of peripheral γδ T cell repertoires (
 <xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>). However, we cannot exclude that TCR repertoires in the liver might be more affected by HCV clearance. Also, patients with liver cirrhosis may show more pronounced alterations of TCR repertoires during DAA therapy.
</p>
