<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>This study characterized, in addition to the analysis of total γδ T cell populations in peripheral blood, TRD repertoires of sorted Vγ9
 <sup>+</sup> and Vγ9
 <sup>−</sup> cells separately. As already demonstrated in preterm-infants and neonates, Vδ2 sequences pair mainly, but not exclusively with Vγ9JP
 <sup>+</sup> TRG sequences (
 <xref rid="B51" ref-type="bibr">51</xref>). Flow cytometric results and TRD repertoire analysis of this study pointed out that Vγ9
 <sup>−</sup>Vδ2
 <sup>+</sup> T cells are maintained until adulthood. While Vγ9
 <sup>+</sup> cells displayed a more homogenous Vδ-chain usage (mainly Vδ2), TRD repertoires of Vγ9
 <sup>−</sup> cells were more diverse and consisted of Vδ1
 <sup>+</sup>, Vδ2
 <sup>+</sup>, Vδ3
 <sup>+</sup>, but very little Vδ5
 <sup>+</sup> sequences. Clonal distributions and the complete absence of any shared expanded TRD clones collectively illustrated that similar to all γδ T cells (
 <xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>), Vγ9
 <sup>+</sup> and Vγ9
 <sup>−</sup> TRD repertoires are generally oligoclonal and individual. Although γδ TCR repertoires showed only minor alterations within patients with mild HCV infections, we identified several expanded Vγ9
 <sup>−</sup>Vδ3
 <sup>+</sup> γδ T cell clones present in the peripheral blood of some chronic HCV patients. In general, Vδ3
 <sup>+</sup> cells are highly enriched in the liver, but not in the blood, of healthy persons (
 <xref rid="B23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>). Since in routine clinical practice liver biopsies are no longer performed in uncomplicated HCV infection and patient sampling starts only after diagnosis of persistent HCV infection, we can only speculate that these liver-specific Vδ3
 <sup>+</sup> cells might undergo a HCV-induced clonal expansion to finally circulate in the peripheral blood of chronic HCV patients. Presence of NK cell markers and liver-homing markers (e.g., CD161) could strengthen the hypothesis Vδ3
 <sup>+</sup> γδ T cell clones can be associated with liver specificity. In addition, it should be worthwhile to investigate a potential HCV-related antigen specificity of expanded Vγ9
 <sup>−</sup>Vδ3
 <sup>+</sup> γδ T cell clones in future 
 <italic>in vitro</italic> studies.
</p>
