<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Another important finding of this study was the absence of significant and detectable effects of novel DAA therapy on γδ T cell frequencies and their TCR repertoires in peripheral blood. This is remarkable as the systemic inflammatory milieu shows profound changes already early during antiviral therapy—even though no complete restoration of various soluble inflammatory parameters occurs (
 <xref rid="B40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>). The effect of spontaneous clearance of acute HCV infection and a longitudinal follow-up would be an appropriate control; however, those patients are rarely seen in the clinics. It is conceivable that γδ T cells might contribute to successful resolution of the disease. Nevertheless, the finding that peripheral γδ T cell compartments and their associated TCR repertoires were highly stable even 1 year after viral elimination is in line with previous observations for other cell types. This may suggest that distinct imprints on the immune system by long-lasting HCV infection can persist for years despite eradication of HCV, which may have clinical implications for some hepatic and extrahepatic disease manifestations. For instance, no changes in the short-term risk to develop hepatocellular carcinoma upon DAA treated were observed in the analyzed cohort of HCV patients (
 <xref rid="B52" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>). With regard to NK cells, it has been suggested that phenotypic and functional alterations during chronic HCV infections could be restored upon DAA therapy (
 <xref rid="B53" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>). NK cell phenotypes were altered upon IFN-free DAA treatment further resulting in modifications of the transcription factor profiles (
 <xref rid="B54" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>). T cells have also been studied in HCV infection and during DAA-related viral eradication. The proliferative capacity of HCV-responsive CD8
 <sup>+</sup> T cells could be restored in part (
 <xref rid="B56" ref-type="bibr">56</xref>) and a decrease in PD-1 expression on CD8
 <sup>+</sup> T cells was observed upon successful DAA treatment (
 <xref rid="B55" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>). On the other hand, neither the frequency nor the phenotype of regulatory T cells was rescued upon viral clearance (
 <xref rid="B57" ref-type="bibr">57</xref>). Likewise, MAIT cells were reduced in frequency and their functions are affected by chronic HCV infection (
 <xref rid="B58" ref-type="bibr">58</xref>), and in particular peripheral MAIT cells could not be restored upon viral eradication (
 <xref rid="B39" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>). All these studies were analyzing the phenotypic and functional changes of given immune cells by flow cytometry. Our data now contribute that the frequency of peripheral γδ T cell populations is neither affected by uncomplicated chronic HCV infection with no liver inflammation 
 <italic>per se</italic> nor by rapid viral eradication upon DAA therapy. Likewise, conventional PEG-IFNα/Ribavirin therapy might not significantly change γδ T cell numbers; however, the presence of IFNα during this treatment regime may stimulate cytokine production by Vγ9
 <sup>+</sup>Vδ2
 <sup>+</sup> (
 <xref rid="B24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>). In this study, peripheral Vγ9
 <sup>+</sup> and Vγ9
 <sup>−</sup> cell TCR repertoires were largely undisturbed with regard to oligoclonality and TCR diversity by rapid viral clearance using IFN-free DAA therapies. During and after DAA treatment, peripheral γδ TCR repertoires displayed a high stability for up to 1 year, indicating that there is no dominant acute anti-HCV response of γδ T cells in patients with chronic HCV infection and also consistent with the assumption that chronic viral infection might leave a sustained footprint on the γδ T cell compartment in peripheral blood.
</p>
