<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Lung cancer remains the leading cause of tumor-related deaths worldwide. Its incidence has increased steadily by 10% annually (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>–
 <xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>). It can be divided into two histological subtypes: non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) and small cell lung cancer (SCLC). NSCLC accounts for approximately 85% of lung cancers, and includes adenocarcinoma, squamous cell carcinoma, adenosquamous carcinoma, and large cell carcinoma; SCLC accounts for 15% (
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>). Recently, targeted therapies based on driver genes and immune checkpoint inhibitors (ICIs) have led to a significant improvement in patient survival. ICIs are the mainstay of treatment for lung cancer (
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>). Programmed cell death 1 (PD-1)/programmed cell death-ligand 1 (PD-L1) inhibitors are the standard first-line and second-line therapies for patients with NSCLC without driver gene mutations (
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>). Sintilimab is an anti-PD-1 antibody that was co-developed by Innovent Biologics and Eli Lilly and Company. A combination of sintilimab and chemotherapy has been shown to result in a longer progression-free survival than chemotherapy alone in patients with untreated, locally advanced or metastatic NSCLC (
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>). However, the development of resistance to PD-1/PD-L1 inhibitors is one of the challenges in cancer treatment. It is well known that histological transformation to SCLC is a known mechanism of resistance in 3–14% of patients with epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) mutations receiving EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitors (EGFR-TKIs) (
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>–
 <xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>). Similarly, transformation of NSCLC to SCLC in patients receiving PD-1/PD-L1 inhibitors has been reported as a mechanism of resistance to PD-1/PD-L1 inhibitors (
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>–
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>). Unlike with EGFR-TKI therapy, repeat tissue biopsies are not usually performed at the time of NSCLC progression in patients treated with PD-1/PD-L1 inhibitors. Herein, we report two cases with squamous cell carcinoma that transformed into SCLC during treatment with PD-1 inhibitors. We also provide a detailed description of the histological examination of the pre-and post-transformation tissues, hitherto absent from prior reports (
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>–
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>).
</p>
