<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Multiple mechanisms regulate proper levels of protein expression; among these, microRNAs (miRNAs, miRs) are commonly seen as ‘master regulators’ [
 <xref rid="B26-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>]. MiRNAs are small, non-coding molecules, which regulate gene expression at the post-transcriptional level, usually binding the 3′-untranslated region of mRNA sequence [
 <xref rid="B27-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>]. Apart from their recognized role in cellular specification and pathophysiological mechanisms, the recent discovery of circulating miRNAs also suggests that they provide novel means for paracrine and systemic communication [
 <xref rid="B28-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]. In regards to ALS, recent studies have shown a correlation between miRNAs expression and microglia activation [
 <xref rid="B29-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>]. A group of muscle-specific miRNAs (“myo-miRs”) including miRNA-1, miRNA-206, and miRNA-133a/b, which are involved in the process of proliferation, plasticity, regeneration, and repair of muscle [
 <xref rid="B30-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>], might play a role in modulating the disease course in ALS, where degeneration of both upper and lower motoneurons leads to muscle atrophy. Recent findings also demonstrate a presumable role of other groups of miRNAs, including immune system-related miRNAs (“immuno-miRs”), such as miRNA-155 [
 <xref rid="B31-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>,
 <xref rid="B32-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>], and angiogenic-related miRNAs (“angio-miRs”), such as miRNA-378 [
 <xref rid="B33-ijms-19-01312" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>], in ALS pathology. In this study, we chose to investigate the expression levels of miR-1, -133a, -155, -206, and -378 for their role in the pathophysiological processes in ALS. To our knowledge, miRNA expression in the physiological fluids of ALS patients during the course of experimental lineage-negative (Lin-) cell therapy has not been studied so far.
</p>
