<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>P.G.R. reports advisory board participation for Celgene, Novartis and Takeda. C.C.H. reports research funding from Takeda, Celgene, ARNO Therapeutics, Janssen Pharmaceuticals, Karyopharm and Merck, and advisory board participation for Thrassos and InCyte. C.A.R. reports independent review committee membership for Millennium/Takeda clinical trial NCT01564537, advisory committee membership for Millennium, and consultancy fees from Celgene and Bristol Myers Squibb. D.H.V. reports stock ownership in Amgen, and honoraria from Celgene, Takeda, Janssen and Amgen. J.G.B. reports research funding from AbbVie, Acetylon, Amgen, Bluebird, Bristol Myers Squibb, Calithera, Celgene, Constellation, Curis, Epizyme, Janssen, Karyopharm, Kesios, Novartis, Onyx, Takeda and Tragara. M.L. reports research funding from Celgene and Takeda, and advisory board participation for Takeda. A.C. reports research funding from and advisory board participation for Millennium/Takeda, Celgene, Array Bio Pharma, Novartis Pharmaceuticals and Onyx, research funding from Janssen Pharmaceuticals and Bristol Myers Squibb, and consultancy fees from Janssen Pharmaceuticals and Bristol Myers Squibb. S.D.S. reports research funding from Seattle Genetics, Merck Sharp and Dohme Corp, Janssen Research and Development, LLC, Acerta Pharma BV, Pharmacyclics, Genentech and Portola Pharmaceuticals. N.R. reports consultancy for Onyx, Amgen, Millennium and Celgene. C.B., N.G. and D.B. report employment by Millennium Pharmaceuticals Inc., a wholly owned subsidiary of Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited. E.L. reports previous employment by Millennium Pharmaceuticals Inc., a wholly owned subsidiary of Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited. A.D.B. and J.E. report stock ownership in and employment by Millennium Pharmaceuticals Inc., a wholly owned subsidiary of Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited. R.B. reports honoraria from Celgene and research funding (to his institution) from Celgene, Takeda, Karyopharm, Merck, Bristol Myers Squibb, Novartis and Signal Genetics. M.H. and D.L. declare no competing financial interests.</p>
