<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In order that as many patients as possible can proceed to ASCT, it is important to achieve CR or PR after the induction chemotherapy before ASCT. In the present study, ORR and CR rates after R‐High‐CHOP/CHASER induction therapy were 95.6% (95% CI 84.9‐99.5%) and 82.2% (95% CI 68.0‐92.0%), respectively. In the Nordic MCL‐2 study, ORR and CR rates including uncertain CR were 96.3% and 54.4%, respectively.
 <xref rid="cas13719-bib-0008" ref-type="ref">8</xref> In the GELA phase II study, ORR and CR rates after induction therapy were 95% and 57%, respectively.
 <xref rid="cas13719-bib-0009" ref-type="ref">9</xref> In the European MCL Network phase III study, ORR and the CR including unconfirmed CR rate after alternating R‐CHOP/R‐DHAP were 94% and 55%, respectively.
 <xref rid="cas13719-bib-0010" ref-type="ref">10</xref> In a phase III LYSA study to evaluate the usefulness of rituximab maintenance treatment, induction therapy was 4 cycles of R‐DHAP (6.7% of patients received an additional 3 cycles of R‐CHOP), and ORR and CR rates were 94% and 74% (including 34% with unconfirmed CR), respectively.
 <xref rid="cas13719-bib-0011" ref-type="ref">11</xref> Thus, the high CR rate of 82.2% in the present study is notable. Recently, retrospective data of a nationwide study of MCL in Japan were reported.
 <xref rid="cas13719-bib-0022" ref-type="ref">22</xref> In that study, 501 patients with newly diagnosed MCL with a median age of 67 (range 22‐90) years treated with rituximab‐containing therapy between 1992 and 2012 were analyzed. PFS and OS at 5 years were 25% and 60%, respectively. These results are lower than in the present study (PFS of 52% and OS of 71% at 5 years). Although comparison is difficult, the most probable reason for these differences might be differences in the study populations: The median age was 67 years in the nationwide retrospective study and 59 years in the present study, and 48% of patients received R‐CHOP without ASCT in the retrospective nationwide study, whereas all patients in the present study received treatment with the intent of ASCT.
</p>
