<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>There are no firm recommendations on the use of ACEIs/ARBs in the perioperative period, because high level of evidence such as a randomized controlled trial with a large sample size is lacking. Previous observational studies suggested that withholding ACEIs/ARBs was associated with a lower incidence of intraoperative hypotension and a reduced risk of 30-day vascular events and all-cause mortality (
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>). However, a recent cohort study did not show an association between ACEIs/ARBs use and hypotension after general anesthesia induction in non-cardiac surgery (
 <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>). In addition, an open-label randomized trial suggested that preoperative ACEIs/ARBs management strategies did not affect vasoactive agent use or postoperative outcomes for cardiac surgical patients (
 <xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>). In a recent meta-analysis of 5 randomized controlled trials and 4 cohort studies in non-cardiac surgery, continuing ACEIs/ARBs was associated with an increased incidence of intraoperative hypotensive events, but an association between ACEIs/ARBs use and major cardiac events or mortality was not found (
 <xref rid="B30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>). Of note, the associated increase in hypotensive events in the ACEIs/ARBs continued group was mainly based on observational studies. In fact, only 3 randomized trials with a total of 75 patients reported intraoperative hypotension in this meta-analysis (
 <xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>). A significant limitation of observational data is that the apparent associations are often confounded by multiple factors that can be related to both exposures and outcomes, making it hard to interpret the data and offering a relatively low level of evidence for clinical practice.
</p>
