<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par35">Considerable research attention is being directed toward using local ablative radiotherapy in the management of OPD. A trial of stereotactic ablative body radiotherapy (SABR) is currently enrolling patients with oligoprogressive breast or lung cancer (NCT03808662). In this phase II study, 160 patients will be randomised to receive SABR to all OPD up to 5 lesions or standard of care which include chemotherapy or targeted therapy. This study aims to examine the role of SABR as a consolidative treatment for patients with limited OPD. The HALT trial (NCT03256981) is a phase II/III trial of SABR in patients with oncogenic driver mutation advanced lung cancer and OPD in three sites. Eligible patients will be randomised in a 2:1 ratio to receive SABR to all OPD and Tyrosine Kinase Inhibitor (TKI) or TKI alone. The primary outcome is progression-free survival (PFS) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>]. The STOP trial (NCT02756793) is a phase II study of patients with advanced NSCLC and OPD in up to 5 lesions. Patients in this study will receive standard of care therapy with or without SABR to all OPD. A phase II study of stereotactic radiotherapy (SRT) for OPD in up to 5 sites in patients with advanced renal cell carcinoma is ongoing (NCT02019576). Patients enrolled in this study will continue to receive targeted therapy. The primary endpoint of this study is 1-year local control and secondary endpoints are PFS and toxicity [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. Also, the TRAP trial (NCT03644303) is a phase II single-arm study of SABR to OPD in advanced castrate-resistant prostate cancer. Patients will be eligible for the study if they have OPD in ≤2 sites and is limited to the prostate, lymph nodes, bones and lung. The primary endpoint is PFS and secondary endpoints include local control, overall survival (OS), toxicity and time to change to the next line of therapy [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>].
</p>
