<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract>
 <sec id="s2001">
  <title>Purpose</title>
  <p>To evaluate the effectiveness and safety of lidocaine on postoperative quality of recovery and lung protection of patients undergoing thoracoscopic radical resection of lung cancer.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="s2002">
  <title>Patients and Methods</title>
  <p>Seventy ASA II–III patients undergoing thoracoscopic radical resection of lung cancer were randomly assigned into either the lidocaine group (Group L) or control group (Group C). Patients in Group L received lidocaine with a 1.5 mg/kg bolus before induction of anesthesia, followed by 2.0 mg/kg/h until the end of the operation while the patients in Group C received volume-matched normal saline at the same rate. The main outcome was the quality of recovery-40 score (QoR-40 score) at 24 h postoperatively. The peak airway pressure (Ppeak) and plateau airway pressure (Pplat), the partial pressure of oxygen in arterial blood (PaO
   <sub>2</sub>), partial pressure of carbon dioxide in arterial blood (PaCO
   <sub>2</sub>), alveolar-arterial oxygen gradient (A-aDO2), oxygenation index (OI), time to first flatus and defecation, intraoperative hemodynamics and opioid consumption were also recorded.
  </p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="s2003">
  <title>Results</title>
  <p>There were no statistically difference at patients' baseline characteristics. The QoR-40 score of Group L was significantly higher than that of Group C at 24 h after surgery (
   <italic>P</italic>=0.014). Ppeak, Pplat, and A-aDO
   <sub>2</sub> of Group L were significantly lower than those of Group C (
   <italic>P</italic>&lt;0.001, 
   <italic>P</italic>&lt;0.001, 
   <italic>P</italic>=0.025, respectively) after the ventilation recovery of both lungs, and the PaO
   <sub>2</sub> and OI of the Group L were significantly higher than those of Group C (
   <italic>P</italic>=0.027, 
   <italic>P</italic>=0.027, respectively). Time to first flatus and defecation in Group L was significantly lower compared with Group C (
   <italic>P</italic>=0.037, 
   <italic>P</italic>=0.025, respectively).
  </p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="s2004">
  <title>Conclusion</title>
  <p>Intravenous lidocaine can improve the quality of recovery of patients undergoing thoracoscopic radical resection of lung cancer, while also providing lung protection, favorable postoperative analgesia, a reduction in the time to first flatus and defecation after surgery.</p>
 </sec>
</abstract>
