<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par64">The assessment of the secondary endpoints will be performed as follows:
 <list list-type="order">
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par65">Incidence of CRBSI: swabs of the insertion site and catheter hubs as well as blood cultures (at least one from a peripheral vein) will be obtained when CRBSI is suspected. In the case of catheter removal, two 5-cm segments, a proximal subcutaneous segment and the tip, will be sampled using the sterile technique for culture. The incidence of CRBSI and the CRBSI attributed to luminal colonisation will be calculated for each group. The differential time to positivity will not be used to diagnose CRBSI. The development of CRBSI will be assessed during intervention and up to 30 days after the last intervention. The rate of CRBSI will be presented as the number of episodes of CRBSI per 1000 admission days</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par66">CVC removal: whenever it is necessary to remove the CVC because of occlusion, thrombosis, dislodgement or suspicion and/or documentation of infection, the tip is going to be sent for culture to the microbiology department, and the reasons for removal will be annotated in the data collection form and the database by the participating investigators. The need for CVC removal will be assessed during intervention and up to 30 days after the last intervention</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par67">Adverse reactions: any adverse reaction potentially associated with the administration of the lock solution will be annotated in the data collection form and the database by the participating investigators. Adverse events will be identified and classified according to the severity and the potential relationship with the lock solution. They will be assessed during the intervention</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par68">Overall (30-day) case-fatality rate: all patients included in the study will be followed up for a total of 30 days after the end of the intervention by the participating investigators. Death by any cause will be annotated in the data collection form and the database</p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
