<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Among certain other jobs, the correlation between effort and performance can be quite small. Effort may be positively correlated with observable outcomes, but these outcomes are also a function of random events outside the workers’ control. Examples include professional “psychics” who provide predictions of their customers’ personal life. While this profession may seem to be on the fringe of the labor market, the market for psychic prediction suggests otherwise: In 2017, the term “psychic” ranked as the 12
 <sup>th</sup> most expensive adword on Google (
 <xref rid="B23" ref-type="bibr">Guttmann, 2020</xref>). A survey of a French representative sample revealed that 19% of respondents had consulted a psychic or fortune-teller in their lifetime (
 <xref rid="B38" ref-type="bibr">Omnibus, 2018</xref>). Another example involves professional gamblers and sports betters, who approach gambling as a means of income rather than entertainment (
 <xref rid="B31" ref-type="bibr">Ladouceur and Walker, 1996</xref>). Estimates suggest that the number of professional gamblers in the United States is between 100,000 and 700,000 (
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">Bluth, 1997</xref>). As there may be an element of skill in some forms of gambling (
 <xref rid="B42" ref-type="bibr">Ranyard and Charlton, 2006</xref>), many seasoned gamblers give an impression of being skilled (
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">Delabbro and Winefield, 1999</xref>). However, studies show the relationship between effort and outcome is weak, and these skills are perhaps better understood as cognitive distortions (
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">Cantinotti et al., 2004</xref>). Being knowledgeable within the gambling field may even be detrimental to performance, as knowledgeable players may respond to minor cues they think are predictive, which turn out not to be predictive (
 <xref rid="B30" ref-type="bibr">Ladouceur et al., 1998</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">Andersson et al., 2005</xref>). In general terms, any worker whose primary goal is to make accurate predictions of future events in settings where making such predictions is difficult or impossible is likely to be working under conditions where exerting more effort will have little impact on the outcome (
 <xref rid="B49" ref-type="bibr">Silver, 2012</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B52" ref-type="bibr">Tetlock and Gardner, 2016</xref>).
</p>
