<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>We took in charge a 77-year-old patient with a total hip prosthetic infection due to 
 <italic>P. multocida</italic>. Interestingly, a cat bite occurred 1 year prior to diagnosis and the patient had been complaining of pain in her left hip after the bite. Infection was treated using a two-stage surgery associated with a 6 weeks course of antibiotics (ceftriaxone and ciprofloxacin). With this management, after a follow-up of 2 years, we've conclude to a cure of this infection. This unusual chronic presentation led us to look for a possible unknown immune deficit. As we previously described a case of chronic wound skin infection due to 
 <italic>Rhodococcus equi</italic> facilitated by a CD8+ T lymphocytes deficit (
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>), we looked for the same kind of deficit for this patient. Analyses revealed a CD8+ T lymphocytes deficit for both the percentage (15.5% - normal range: 31–40%) and the absolute value (205/mm
 <sup>3</sup> – normal range: 500–900/mm
 <sup>3</sup>). As a CD8+ T lymphocyte deficit can be the consequence of infections, a control was performed 4 months later, when the clinical evolution was favorable and antibiotics had been stopped for 2.5 months. The deficit was still noticeable (absolute value: 220/mm
 <sup>3</sup> and percentage: 17%). We then wondered if this deficit could play a role in the occurrence of this usually acute infection. Therefore, in a preliminary study, we performed T CD8+ lymphocytes analysis for other patients with acute 
 <italic>Pasteurella</italic> spp. infection (all patients gave their consent for this analysis). First, we randomly picked up two patients who previously presented an acute hand tendon sheath infection among patients who presented this type of infection during the past 4 years. In addition, during the same period of time, several patients were hospitalized and presented acute and sub-acute infections due to animal bites. The characteristics of these consecutive patients are summarized in 
 <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>. Two of them (patients 7 &amp; 8) with negative bacteriology samples, were treated with antibiotics (amoxicillin—clavulanate acid) prior to surgery, but clinical presentation was compatible with 
 <italic>Pasteurella</italic> spp. infection with an acute onset in the first few hours after the bite. All patients with 
 <italic>Pasteurella</italic> spp. infections had a CD8+ T lymphocytes deficit in percentage and 6 out of 8 had a deficit in absolute value. None of them presented a deficit in total lymphocytes count. The other biological parameters such as white blood cells, liver and renal function, inflammatory parameters were normal at the time of evaluation. None of them had a history of unusual infections.
</p>
