<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>High-volume hydraulic fracturing (fracking) is a relatively new and controversial technique of extracting oil and gas from shale formations deep beneath the earth's surface. Initially discovered in 1997, the practice combines more traditional methods of extraction with a horizontal drilling technique that involves fracturing shale with a "cocktail” of chemicals, sand, and water (
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">Rinaldi, 2015</xref>). Since 2008, a boom in fracking has brought temporary economic prosperity to rural communities at the same time that it has created significant environmental and human health concerns (
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">Fitzgerald et al., 2016</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">Murphy, 2020</xref>). While it is difficult to prove causal links between chemicals used in fracking and health problems, available research illustrates "significant associations” between emissions from fracking and negative health effects (
 <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">Wollin et al., 2020</xref>; see also; 
 <xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">Mrdjen and Lee, 2016</xref>). Although men make up 85% of the oil and gas extraction industry workforce (
 <xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">Energy Workforce and Technology Council, 2018</xref>), women and infants living proximal to fracking operations face unique health risks. Multiple studies have linked proximity to fracking to reproductive hardships including preterm birth (
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">Whitworth et al., 2018</xref>), decreased birth rate and decreased health (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">Currie et al., 2017</xref>), and congenital heart defects (
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">McKenzie, Allhouse, and Daniels, 2019</xref>). Despite such findings, struggles with reproduction are stigmatized and personalized, which in turn creates difficulties for those seeking to expose the harmful effects of toxic chemicals (
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">Layne, 2001</xref>). The fact that mainstream news depicts fracking as either an economic benefit 
 <italic>or</italic> an environmental concern further complicates this problem (
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">Krause and Bucy, 2018</xref>). That is, those who frame fracking as an environmental concern are frequently criticized as threatening a community's economic welfare made possible by the oil and gas industry.
</p>
