<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Despite significant concerns about the effects of fracking on reproductive health, the perceptions of women suffering such effects remain underexplored in scholarly research. Accordingly, this qualitative study examined the extent to which women who have experienced significant reproductive hardship and live near fracking operations attribute their struggles to their proximity to fracking. This study is grounded in Cognitive Dissonance Theory (CDT), which captures the ways in which individuals negotiate incongruities between cognitions or between cognitions and behaviors (
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">Harmon-Jones and Mills, 2019</xref>). The experience of dissonance leads to psychological discomfort; this, in turn, "motivates the person to reduce the dissonance and leads to avoidance of information likely to increase the dissonance” (
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">Harmon-Jones and Mills, 2019</xref>, p. 3). We consider CDT in the context of communities economically dependent upon oil and gas extraction while suffering negative health effects, focusing specifically on the Uintah Basin area of eastern Utah. In Uintah County, mining, quarrying, and oil and gas extraction make up the largest economic industry in the area (
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">Data United States of America, 2018</xref>), making environmental and human health concerns related to fracking especially controversial within the community. As chronicled in a 2015 issue of 
 <italic>Rolling Stone</italic>, a midwife living in the Uintah Basin noticed growing rates of stillbirth, miscarriage, and birth defects in the region around 2013. When she questioned whether such problems were linked to fracking operations, she received death threats and challenges to her reputation (
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">Solotaroff, 2015</xref>). It is within this context that our research participants grappled with economic dependence on fracking and reproductive challenges.
</p>
