<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract>
 <sec id="s2001">
  <title>Purpose</title>
  <p>Transcutaneous electrical acupoint stimulation (TEAS) is an innovative choice for postoperative pain management. However, the safety and effectiveness of this traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) therapy for patients who underwent gastrectomy is largely unknown. So, the purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and effectiveness of TEAS for patients who underwent gastrectomy.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="s2002">
  <title>Patients and Methods</title>
  <p>We recruited 96 patients with gastric cancer from May 2019 to November 2019; 82 patients were enrolled, and 81 patients completed. Patients were randomly assigned to TEAS group (TG) received TEAS on postoperative day (POD) 1–3 or control group (CG) at a 1:1 ratio. The primary outcomes were pain score and consumption of analgesics. The secondary were the time of first postoperative flatus and defecation, frequency of postoperative nausea, vomiting, distention, diarrhea, comfort of semi-fluid diet, Clavien-Dindo grade (C-D grade) and length of postoperative day. We performed hematological analysis to explore the possible mechanisms.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="s2003">
  <title>Results</title>
  <p>Overall, 81 patients were enrolled included in the analysis. Compared with CG, pain scores in TG were lower on POD 1–5 (average: 2.55±0.21 vs 3.10±0.42, 
   <italic>P</italic>&lt;0.001), and the use rate of opioids was lower (43.9 vs 75.0, 
   <italic>P</italic>=0.004); time of first postoperative flatus (55.63±16.74 vs 72.60±20.92, 
   <italic>P</italic>&lt;0.001) and defecation (72.20±16.24 vs 95.78±17.75, 
   <italic>P</italic>&lt;0.001) were shorter; the frequency of nausea were fewer (1.88±1.09 vs 2.58±0.77, 
   <italic>P</italic>=0.029) and patients were more comfortable with semi-fluid diet (7.63±0.63 vs 6.93±0.69, 
   <italic>P</italic>&lt;0.001); among the hematologic results, β-endorphin (β-End), interleukin-2 (IL-2), motilin (MTL) on POD 3, POD 5 were lower, 5-hydroxytryptamine (5-HT), interleukin-6 (IL-6), tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α) were higher. And no adverse event was reported.
  </p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="s2004">
  <title>Conclusion</title>
  <p>TEAS can relieve postoperative pain and promote the recovery of gastrointestinal function. Consequently, it can be an adjunctive therapy to enhance postoperative recovery for patients after gastrectomy.</p>
 </sec>
</abstract>
