<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par32">Gonadal impairment in CCS can be defined in many ways [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref>], and especially in international collaborations a clear consensus on the definition, as objective as possible, is needed. A separate work package within the PanCareLIFE consortium will combine seven criteria and several different questionnaires to assess clinical gonadal status in 20,000 subjects. For the current study, the primary endpoint AMH was chosen, which will be evaluated both linear as categorized. The secondary endpoint is gonadal impairment based on detailed information about menstrual history, FSH levels and information on usage of artificial reproductive techniques. AMH has the advantage to be as objective as possible, in comparison to questionnaire data that may be prone to recall bias or incorrect information given by the survivor. In addition, AMH can serve as a reliable surrogate marker for ovarian function while the primordial follicle pool is not yet depleted [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>]. The only reported GWAS investigating therapy induced fertility impairment in CCS, used premature menopause as primary outcome (clinically assessed in the discovery cohort and self-reported in the replication cohort) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]. Prior to the clinical manifestation of amenorrhea and increased levels of FSH, impaired gonadal function can be detected by the measurement of lower serum AMH levels [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>]. AMH in females is produced solely in the ovary by granulosa cells of small growing follicles and is considered a surrogate marker for ovarian function and ovarian reserve [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>]. Like the primordial follicle pool, AMH levels decrease from adolescence on, until menopause occurs. Even survivors who do not report premature menopause (or Primary Ovarian Insufficiency, POI, defined as menopause before the age of 40 years) can still have a poor ovarian function, potentially resulting in reduced fertility or a shorter reproductive window (e.g., early menopause or menopause between 40 and 45 years). This impairment of gonadal function can be identified by the evaluation of AMH levels.
</p>
