<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Four bilingual research assistants, one majoring in both psychology and English and the others majoring in psychology and passed College English Test Band 6 (CET-6, which is considered as proficient enough to read English newspaper articles and materials of general interests), were divided into two groups: One group classified 854 English and 1,589 Chinese items, and the other group classified 2,141 English and 1,497 Chinese items. These four coders were trained how to classify the text by type of pride: individual pride, relational pride, national pride, general pride (the items with little or no information to be coded by the above types of pride), and non-pride (the items with the keyword but not related to pride as an emotion, e.g., a pride of lions, see an example in 
 <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>). The two coders in each group practiced on 100 Chinese items and 100 English items and discussed any misclassifications. Finally, these two coders in each group independently coded all materials. For one group, the intercoder reliability (kappa coefficient) was 0.87 [95% CI: 0.85, 0.89] for the Chinese materials and 0.84 [95% CI: 0.81, 0.87] for the English materials. For the other group, the intercoder reliability was 0.90 [95% CI: 0.88, 0.92] for the Chinese materials and 0.82 [95% CI: 0.79, 0.84] for the English materials. A kappa coefficient of 0.81–1.00 is considered as showing as an almost-perfect agreement (Landis and Koch, 
 <xref rid="B26" ref-type="bibr">1977</xref>). For the items, the two coders disagreed (363 English items and 253 Chinese items); they were discussed and resolved in a group session involving the two coders as well as one of the corresponding authors. The non-pride items (170 English and 28 Chinese items) were excluded from further analysis, yielding 1,465 English items and 1,493 Chinese items from the blog genre and 1,360 English items and 1,565 Chinese items from the news genre in the final analysis.
</p>
