<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<notes>
 <title>Declarations</title>
 <notes id="FPar1">
  <title>Ethics approval and consent to participate</title>
  <p id="Par71">This study has been approved by the Erasmus Medical Centre Ethics Committee (ref. no. MEC-2018-114). The study will be conducted according to the principles of the Declaration of Helsinki (10th version, Fortaleza 2013) and in concordance with the Dutch Medical Research Improving Human Subjects Act and other applicable guidelines, regulations, and acts. In compliance with the International Conference on Harmonisation Good Clinical Practice and other applicable regulations, patients will be informed and asked for written informed consent by their treating physician, local investigators, or research nurse at one of the participating hospitals.</p>
 </notes>
 <notes id="FPar2">
  <title>Consent for publication</title>
  <p id="Par72">Not applicable.</p>
 </notes>
 <notes id="FPar3" notes-type="COI-statement">
  <title>Competing interests</title>
  <p id="Par73">Author-specific disclosures: KS: Honoraria: Novartis, Roche, MSD Oncology. Advisory board: Novartis, MSD, BMS, Pierre Fabre, Abbvie. All paid to the institution. MB: consultant and/or advisory board member: BMS, Novartis, Merck, Pierre Fabre. GH: consultant and/or advisory board member: Amgen, Roche, MSD, BMS, Pfizer, Novartis, Pierre Fabry. Research grant: BMS, Seerave. All paid to the institution. JG: Consultant and/or advisory board member: BMS, MSD, Pierre Fabre, Servier. AE: Study grant: Sanofi, Roche, BMS, TEVA, Idera. Travel expenses: MSD Oncology, Roche, Pfizer, Sanofi. Speaker Honoraria: Bristol-Myers Squibb, Novartis. Advisory Board: BMS, MSD Oncology, Amgen, Roche, Novartis, Sanofi, Pfizer, Ipsen, Merck, Pierre Fabre. MA: Consultant and/or advisory board member: BMS, Merck, Ipsen, Novartis, Pfizer, Pierre Fabre, Sanofi, Astellas. Research grant (not related to this paper): Pfizer. DP: Consultant and/or advisory board member: BMS, Amgen, Pierre Fabre. EK: Consultant and/or advisory board member: BMS, Novartis, Merck, Pierre Fabre. Research grant (not related to this paper): BMS. All paid to institution. MF: Research grants (paid to institution): Roche Nederland B.V., Daiichi Sankyo, Abbvie, Gilead Sciences Netherlands B.V., Astellas Pharma B.V. BR: Honoraria for lectures, SABs and consultancy (none related to the products or the aim of the described study): Amgen, Aptitude Health, AZ, BMS, Clinigen, IQVIA, MSD Oncology, Nvt, Pfizer, Roche. PR: Honoraria for lectures and Advisory Board from BMS, MSD Oncology, Novartis, Pierre Fabre, Roche. SS: Head of department, &gt; 150 agreements with external parties (paid to institute). Chair of Centre for Personalised Cancer Treatment (CPCT). Member of Supervisory board (paid to institute): SkylineDx. Patents: On assays detecting CECs, EpCAM-neg CTCs, CTC-ARv7 detection and outcome to cabazitaxel. JH: Research grants: Amgen, BMS, MSD, Novartis and Neon Therapeutics. Consultancy fees: AIMM, Achilles Tx, Amgen, AZ, Bayer, BMS, GSK, Immunocore, Ipsen, MSD, Merck Serono, Neon Tx, Neogene Tx, Novartis, Pfizer, Roche/Genentech, Sanofi, Seatlle Genetics, Third Rock Ventures, Vaximm. AV: Consultant and/or advisory board member: BMS, MSD, Merck, Ipsen, Eisai, Pfizer, Novartis, Pierre Fabre, Sanofi, Roche. All other authors declare no potential conflict(s) of interest.</p>
 </notes>
</notes>
