<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" article-type="brief-report"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.3 20070202//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName journalpublishing.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.3?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName nlm2jats3.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Front Psychol</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Front Psychol</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Front. Psychol.</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Frontiers in Psychology</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">1664-1078</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Frontiers Media S.A.</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">8175369</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2021.670243</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Psychology</subject><subj-group><subject>Brief Research Report</subject></subj-group></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Fitnesser&#x02019;s Intrinsic Motivations of Green Eating: An Integration of Theory of Planned Behavior and Hedonic-Motivation System Adoption Model</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Yuan</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1"><sup>1</sup></xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2"><sup>2</sup></xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>Bey-Fen</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3"><sup>3</sup></xref><xref ref-type="corresp" rid="c001"><sup>*</sup></xref><uri xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://loop.frontiersin.org/people/1240686/overview"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>Yen-Cheng</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff4"><sup>4</sup></xref><xref ref-type="corresp" rid="c002"><sup>*</sup></xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff1"><sup>1</sup><institution>Hubei University of Technology Engineering and Technology College</institution>, <addr-line>Wuhan</addr-line>, <country>China</country></aff><aff id="aff2"><sup>2</sup><institution>School of Management, Wuhan University of Technology</institution>, <addr-line>Wuhan</addr-line>, <country>China</country></aff><aff id="aff3"><sup>3</sup><institution>Department of Hospitality Management, Chung Hwa University of Medical Technology</institution>, <addr-line>Tainan</addr-line>, <country>Taiwan</country></aff><aff id="aff4"><sup>4</sup><institution>Department of Sport, Health, and Leisure, Chung Hwa University of Medical Technology</institution>, <addr-line>Tainan</addr-line>, <country>Taiwan</country></aff><author-notes><fn fn-type="edited-by"><p>Edited by: Fu-Sheng Tsai, Cheng Shiu University, Taiwan</p></fn><fn fn-type="edited-by"><p>Reviewed by: Jui-Mei Yien, University of Kang Ning, Taiwan; Maria Gianni, University of Macedonia, Greece</p></fn><corresp id="c001">*Correspondence: Bey-Fen Lee, <email>michelle@mail.hwai.edu.tw</email></corresp><corresp id="c002">Yen-Cheng Lu, <email>judo@mail.hwai.edu.tw</email></corresp><fn fn-type="other" id="fn004"><p>This article was submitted to Organizational Psychology, a section of the journal Frontiers in Psychology</p></fn></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>21</day><month>5</month><year>2021</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2021</year></pub-date><volume>12</volume><elocation-id>670243</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>20</day><month>2</month><year>2021</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>06</day><month>4</month><year>2021</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2021 Chen, Lee and Lu.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2021</copyright-year><copyright-holder>Chen, Lee and Lu</copyright-holder><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License (CC BY). The use, distribution or reproduction in other forums is permitted, provided the original author(s) and the copyright owner(s) are credited and that the original publication in this journal is cited, in accordance with accepted academic practice. No use, distribution or reproduction is permitted which does not comply with these terms.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract><p>Global climate change arouses people&#x02019;s attention to environmental protection and, therefore, changes consumption habits. Food overconsumption not only produces extra waste but also pollutes the environment. Therefore, it is important to understand the factors that motivate people to eat green, an eco-friendly way to consume food. To keep the body in good shape, the fitnessers concern more about diet than the general people. This study explored intrinsic motivations, such as social recognition, environmental ethics, curiosity, joy of purchase, perceived usefulness, subjective norm, and perceived behavior control as constructs that affect fitnesser&#x02019;s green eating intention. All constructs except curiosity have significant impacts on behavior intention. The results demonstrate that social recognition and environmental ethics have significant effects on curiosity, joy of purchase, perceived usefulness, subjective norm, and perceived behavior control. The mediation effects between social recognition and behavior intention are not supported. The mediators between environmental ethics and behavior intention are joy of purchase, perceived usefulness, subjective norm, and perceived behavior control.</p></abstract><kwd-group><kwd>intrinsic motivation</kwd><kwd>green eating</kwd><kwd>theory of planned theory</kwd><kwd>hedonic-motivation system adoption model</kwd><kwd>social recognition</kwd><kwd>environmental ethics</kwd></kwd-group><counts><fig-count count="1"/><table-count count="5"/><equation-count count="0"/><ref-count count="91"/><page-count count="10"/><word-count count="0"/></counts></article-meta></front><body><sec id="S1"><title>Introduction</title><p>With the rapid growth of the world&#x02019;s population and the increasing consumption of energy, environmental pollution caused by energy consumption has attracted wide attention. China has a population of 1.3 billion, accounting for 18.57% of the world&#x02019;s population. Also, China is the world&#x02019;s second largest economy (<xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">Barboza, 2010</xref>), and its food consumption and role in environmental protection cannot be ignored. Food is a basic need for human life and cannot be substituted. Food consumption accounts for 20&#x02013;30% of the environmental impact in the West (<xref rid="B84" ref-type="bibr">Tukker and Jansen, 2006</xref>).</p><p>Fast economic development not only brings people a better life but also causes the environment a heavy burden. To prevent the environment from being destroyed by increasing pollution, the government supported various green industries and encouraged people&#x02019;s green behaviors (<xref rid="B76" ref-type="bibr">Steg and Vlek, 2009</xref>). One of the behaviors is green eating, which is consuming food in an eco-friendly way. Key elements about eating green include eating locally grown foods, choosing organic foods if possible, limiting intake of processed or fast foods, and consuming meatless meals weekly (<xref rid="B87" ref-type="bibr">Weller et al., 2014</xref>). Green eating behavior can reduce energy consumption by not buying food in a distance and lessen waste production by eating fresh or organic food instead of processed food. For sustainable development, it is important to implement environmental protection education to the society, so as to understand the factors that influence green eating intention (<xref rid="B60" ref-type="bibr">Muposhi and Dhurup, 2017</xref>; <xref rid="B40" ref-type="bibr">Kim and Kim, 2018</xref>; <xref rid="B22" ref-type="bibr">Dalvi-Esfahani et al., 2020</xref>; <xref rid="B45" ref-type="bibr">Lacroix and Gifford, 2020</xref>).</p><p>Fitness has a broader meaning in Eastern countries. Not limited to bodybuilding, a fitness center could provide aerobics, sports, group classes, pools, steam rooms, Jacuzzis, saunas, or even massage rooms or lounge areas for social interaction. To maintain their body figure, fitnessers believe exercise can prevent aging, and selected diet can increase physical strength or even enhance immunity. For example, they tend to cut down on high sugar or starchy foods and eat high-fiber or low-calorie foods. Therefore, their awareness of food selection is more cautious than the general public. This study adopted the theory of planned behavior (TPB) to find out the determinants including social recognition, environmental ethics, curiosity, joy of purchase, perceived usefulness, subjective norm, and perceived behavior control to understand the impacts on fitnesser&#x02019;s intention of green eating.</p><p>Theory of planned behavior is an extensively applied research model in the intention for green eating (e.g., <xref rid="B59" ref-type="bibr">Mundorf et al., 2018</xref>; <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">Ahmad et al., 2020</xref>; <xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">Canova et al., 2020</xref>; <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">Carfora et al., 2020</xref>; <xref rid="B22" ref-type="bibr">Dalvi-Esfahani et al., 2020</xref>; <xref rid="B51" ref-type="bibr">Malan et al., 2020</xref>; <xref rid="B68" ref-type="bibr">Ruangkanjanases et al., 2020</xref>). However, prior studies have adopted or extended TPB in several aspects for predicting intention toward green eating, and there are still two major limitations that remain to be solved. First, few of the studies have elaborated on how antecedents affect the key components for green eating. These limitations drive the possibilities for further exploration in green behaviors. Therefore, this research applied TPB as a basic framework and further attempted to include a cognitive construct (i.e., social recognition, environmental ethics, curiosity, joy of purchase, and perceived usefulness) to measure its effect on intention toward green eating. Second, because intrinsic motivation has a greater impact on human behavior than extrinsic motivation (<xref rid="B21" ref-type="bibr">Csikszentmihalyi, 1990</xref>; <xref rid="B82" ref-type="bibr">Thomas and Velthouse, 1990</xref>), unlike the other scholars who apply only TPB in their studies, this study explored TPB, the hedonic-motivation system adoption model (HMSAM), and intrinsic constructs including social recognition and environmental ethics in the proposed model to examine fitnesser&#x02019;s acceptance of green eating.</p></sec><sec id="S2"><title>Literature Review and Theoretical Background</title><sec id="S2.SS1"><title>Theory of Planned Behavior</title><p>According to the theory of reasoned action (TRA), one&#x02019;s behavior is based on his behavior intention, and one&#x02019;s behavior intention is affected by his attitude and subjective norm (<xref rid="B25" ref-type="bibr">Fishbein and Ajzen, 1975</xref>). Originating from the TRA, TPB extends the TRA with perceived behavioral control as an antecedent variable of behavioral intention (<xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">Ajzen, 1991</xref>). TPB has been extensively adopted in explaining human behavior intention, not to mention environmental protection issues.</p><p>A number of studies agreed that TPB predicted different behaviors <italic>via</italic> external variables and antecedents (e.g., <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">Chen and Hung, 2016</xref>; <xref rid="B65" ref-type="bibr">Paul et al., 2016</xref>; <xref rid="B34" ref-type="bibr">Hsu et al., 2017</xref>; <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">Al-Jubari, 2019</xref>; <xref rid="B78" ref-type="bibr">Sun et al., 2019</xref>; <xref rid="B33" ref-type="bibr">Hoque and Hossan, 2020</xref>; <xref rid="B64" ref-type="bibr">Parash et al., 2020</xref>; <xref rid="B72" ref-type="bibr">Si et al., 2020</xref>; <xref rid="B85" ref-type="bibr">Uzun and Kilis, 2020</xref>). A meta-analysis conducted by <xref rid="B27" ref-type="bibr">Hagger et al. (2002)</xref> confirmed that the three aforesaid factors can be used to predict behavioral intentions and behavior. Therefore, this study hypothesized H<sub>1</sub> and H<sub>2</sub> as follows:</p><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p><bold>Hypothesis 1 (H<sub>1</sub>).</bold>
<italic>Fitnesser&#x02019;s subjective norm is positively correlated with their intention to eat green.</italic></p></list-item></list><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p><bold>Hypothesis 2 (H<sub>2</sub>).</bold>
<italic>Fitnesser&#x02019;s perceived behavior control is positively correlated with their intention to eat green.</italic></p></list-item></list></sec><sec id="S2.SS2"><title>Hedonic-Motivation System Adoption Model</title><p><xref rid="B86" ref-type="bibr">van der Heijden (2004)</xref> proposed his research result regarding hedonic-motivation system (HMS) by adding joy in the technology acceptance model (TAM) as a mediator between perceived ease of use and behavioral intention to use. Prior research indicated the influence of perceived usefulness on behavioral intention (e.g., <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">Chen et al., 2009</xref>, <xref rid="B17" ref-type="bibr">2013</xref>; <xref rid="B83" ref-type="bibr">Tsai et al., 2020</xref>). Moreover, empirical evidence also supported the relationship between perceived usefulness and purchase intention (e.g., <xref rid="B37" ref-type="bibr">Jamal and Sharifuddin, 2015</xref>; <xref rid="B58" ref-type="bibr">Moslehpour et al., 2018</xref>).</p><p>Grounded in flow-based cognitive absorption (CA), <xref rid="B50" ref-type="bibr">Lowry et al. (2012)</xref> improved the HMS by integrating intrinsic motivations, such as curiosity and joy in the HMSAM. <xref rid="B63" ref-type="bibr">Oluwajana et al. (2019)</xref> found that curiosity, joy, and perceived usefulness have a direct impact on behavior intention based on HMSAM. Past studies also provided empirical evidence linkages between behavioral intention intrinsic motivations (i.e., curiosity, joy, and perceived usefulness) (e.g., <xref rid="B44" ref-type="bibr">Koo and Choi, 2010</xref>; <xref rid="B71" ref-type="bibr">Shu, 2014</xref>; <xref rid="B57" ref-type="bibr">Mohammadi, 2015</xref>). According to the above discussion, this study proposed H<sub>3</sub>, H<sub>4</sub>, and H<sub>5</sub> as follows:</p><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p><bold>Hypothesis 3 (H<sub>3</sub>).</bold> Fitnesser&#x02019;s curiosity is positively correlated with their intention to eat green.</p></list-item></list><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p><bold>Hypothesis 4 (H<sub>4</sub>).</bold> Fitnesser&#x02019;s joy of purchase is positively correlated with their intention to eat green.</p></list-item></list><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p><bold>Hypothesis 5 (H<sub>5</sub>).</bold> Fitnesser&#x02019;s perceived usefulness is positively correlated with their intention to eat green.</p></list-item></list></sec><sec id="S2.SS3"><title>Social Recognition</title><p>Social recognition is about public acknowledgment of people&#x02019;s status, merits, or personality (<xref rid="B80" ref-type="bibr">Susewind and Walkowitz, 2020</xref>). <xref rid="B53" ref-type="bibr">Maslow&#x02019;s (1970)</xref> hierarchy of needs classifies human needs into five levels to motivate human behavior. Social recognition serves as a postconsumption feedback on the viability of this social function (<xref rid="B24" ref-type="bibr">Fischer et al., 2010</xref>; <xref rid="B54" ref-type="bibr">McPhail et al., 2011</xref>; <xref rid="B75" ref-type="bibr">Stead et al., 2011</xref>). Thus, fitnessers use environmentally friendly products, and the sense of society can satisfy their need for status, achievement, recognition, and self-esteem. Similarly, in prior empirical evidence, social recognition is one of the influential antecedents in the formation of individual perceptions (e.g., <xref rid="B20" ref-type="bibr">Chuang and Dellmann-Jenkins, 2010</xref>; <xref rid="B39" ref-type="bibr">Kim et al., 2016</xref>). Therefore, this study proposed the following hypotheses:</p><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p><bold>Hypothesis 6 (H<sub>6</sub>).</bold> Fitnesser&#x02019;s social recognition is positively correlated with the subjective norm to eat green.</p></list-item></list><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p><bold>Hypothesis 7 (H<sub>7</sub>).</bold> Fitnesser&#x02019;s social recognition is positively correlated with the perceived behavioral control to eat green.</p></list-item></list><p><xref rid="B52" ref-type="bibr">Martella et al. (2015)</xref> identified various human needs including social recognition and curiosity based on the gamification framework. To develop a successful constructivist-based learning environment, several issues including curiosity and social recognition that motivate students were the top priority (<xref rid="B30" ref-type="bibr">Herring, 2004</xref>).</p><p>As mentioned in the social attraction theory, society members who reflect the collective group standard may appear more attractive by other group members (<xref rid="B31" ref-type="bibr">Hogg and Hardie, 1991</xref>) and, hence, be beneficial from higher levels of social recognition, in which their subjective well-being is positively affected. Likewise, in a cross-country study regarding religious people, social recognition has a positive impact on happiness (<xref rid="B74" ref-type="bibr">Stavrova et al., 2013</xref>). Besides, prior research also found the linkage between social recognition and perceived usefulness (<xref rid="B89" ref-type="bibr">Wu and Chen, 2017</xref>). Therefore, our study proposed the following hypotheses:</p><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p><bold>Hypothesis 8 (H<sub>8</sub>).</bold> Fitnesser&#x02019;s social recognition is positively correlated with the curiosity to eat green.</p></list-item></list><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p><bold>Hypothesis 9 (H<sub>9</sub>).</bold> Fitnesser&#x02019;s social recognition is positively correlated with the joy to eat green.</p></list-item></list><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p><bold>Hypothesis 10 (H<sub>10</sub>).</bold> Fitnesser&#x02019;s social recognition is positively correlated with the perceived usefulness to eat green.</p></list-item></list></sec><sec id="S2.SS4"><title>Environmental Ethics</title><p>Environmental ethics ensures a healthy man&#x02013;nature relationship (<xref rid="B56" ref-type="bibr">Misra, 1995</xref>). In the beginning, the importance between humans and nature has been ignored, but now, humans have a new understanding of ecosystems and of keeping the balance of the cultural and biological diversity of humans and other forms of life (<xref rid="B47" ref-type="bibr">Leopold, 1949</xref>; <xref rid="B23" ref-type="bibr">Ellis and Ramankutty, 2008</xref>; <xref rid="B48" ref-type="bibr">Leopold et al., 2010</xref>). Including the extent of human decent obligations to the environment, environmental ethics focuses on the collective action of human beings on nature (<xref rid="B32" ref-type="bibr">Holden, 2005</xref>). Humans and other creatures form an interdependent system on Earth, and humans are not superior to other creatures (<xref rid="B81" ref-type="bibr">Taylor, 1986</xref>). <xref rid="B67" ref-type="bibr">Rolston (2020)</xref> refers to the basis of environmental ethics as natural love of an individual, and the original experience might be hedonic.</p><p>In a recent study in the United Kingdom regarding small and medium enterprise (SME) owners, <xref rid="B61" ref-type="bibr">North and Nurse (2014)</xref> discovered that they have strong moral and environmental ethics in running &#x0201c;normal&#x0201d; businesses while having curiosity about the problem of climate change and its solutions. Therefore, the concerns of environmental issues have been prevailed to the &#x0201c;normal&#x0201d; citizen. <xref rid="B55" ref-type="bibr">McShane (2007)</xref> stated that environmental ethics should not give up on intrinsic value, like joy. On the enjoyment of life, Chinese fitnessers have become more and more concerned about the impact of ecological degradation, and advertisement emphasizing eco-friendliness appears to having significant impact on their perception of perceived usefulness and credibility (<xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">Chan, 2004</xref>). Therefore, this study proposed the following hypotheses:</p><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p><bold>Hypothesis 11 (H<sub>11</sub>).</bold> Fitnesser&#x02019;s environmental ethics is positively correlated with the curiosity to eat green.</p></list-item></list><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p><bold>Hypothesis 12 (H<sub>12</sub>).</bold> Fitnesser&#x02019;s environmental ethics is positively correlated with the joy to eat green.</p></list-item></list><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p><bold>Hypothesis 13 (H<sub>13</sub>).</bold> Fitnesser&#x02019;s environmental ethics is positively correlated with the perceived usefulness to eat green.</p></list-item></list><p>In the study of food consumption (<xref rid="B41" ref-type="bibr">Kim, 2014</xref>), ecological concern refers to the concern about doing the right thing for animal welfare, the environment, and the ecosystem, which can be regarded as moral norms. Human should respect the environment <italic>via</italic> environmental ethics and beliefs and ensure the ethical connection between humans and the environment. These should also dominate the mind, as well as attitudes and behaviors (<xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">Chen and Hung, 2016</xref>). In this context, similar to the viewpoints of <xref rid="B47" ref-type="bibr">Leopold (1949)</xref>, <xref rid="B81" ref-type="bibr">Taylor (1986)</xref>, and <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">Arvola et al. (2008)</xref>, environmental ethics is significantly related to the three aforementioned factors in the TPB. Studies on ethical consumerism like <xref rid="B70" ref-type="bibr">Shaw and Shui (2002)</xref> used the TPB to explain customers&#x02019; behavioral intentions to purchase ethically produced goods. Therefore, the study proposed the following hypotheses:</p><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p><bold>Hypothesis 14 (H<sub>14</sub>).</bold> Fitnesser&#x02019;s environmental ethics is positively correlated with the subjective norm to eat green.</p></list-item></list><list list-type="simple"><list-item><p><bold>Hypothesis 15 (H<sub>1</sub><sub>5</sub>).</bold> Fitnesser&#x02019;s environmental ethics is positively correlated with the perceived behavior control to eat green.</p></list-item></list><p>According to the literature review and the hypotheses development, this study proposed a research model as shown in <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1</xref>.</p><fig id="F1" position="float"><label>FIGURE 1</label><caption><p>The research model.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fpsyg-12-670243-g001"/></fig></sec></sec><sec id="S3"><title>Research Method</title><p>Measurement scales for all constructs in this study were designed based on previous studies and were scored on a seven-point Likert scale, with higher scores indicating higher agreement with the question. Behavioral intention, subjective norm, and perceived behavioral control were adapted from <xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">Ajzen (1991)</xref>, <xref rid="B65" ref-type="bibr">Paul et al. (2016)</xref>, and <xref rid="B91" ref-type="bibr">Yadav and Pathak (2016)</xref>. Perceived usefulness with three items was adopted from <xref rid="B17" ref-type="bibr">Chen et al. (2013)</xref> and <xref rid="B90" ref-type="bibr">Wu et al. (2015)</xref>. Curiosity and joy with three items, respectively, were modified from <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">Agarwal and Karahanna (2000)</xref> and <xref rid="B50" ref-type="bibr">Lowry et al. (2012)</xref>. Social recognition with three scales was developed from <xref rid="B24" ref-type="bibr">Fischer et al. (2010)</xref> and <xref rid="B54" ref-type="bibr">McPhail et al. (2011)</xref>. Finally, environmental ethics had three items adopted from <xref rid="B29" ref-type="bibr">Henriques and Sadorsky (1999)</xref>. Before the formal questionnaire was sent out, a pilot test was conducted in order to revise the content of the questionnaire to avoid any discrepancies. Therefore, the content validity of this research could be improved, eliminating the occurrence of ambiguous words and inappropriate questioning through the pilot test.</p><p>The questionnaire was made available at a professional and famous online survey website<sup><xref ref-type="fn" rid="footnote1">1</xref></sup> and announced to the public in four major cities&#x02014;Beijing, Shanghai, Guangzhou, and Shenzhen in China. The beginning of the questionnaire briefly explains the definition of green eating, and the first question determines whether the respondent has the experience of green eating. Only fitnessers with green eating experience were invited to participate in the survey and were instructed to answer all questionnaire items.</p><p>Beginning in early July 2020, the data collection process lasted for 3 weeks. To improve external validity, we collected data only from active fitnessers, rather than from the general public. After removing seven invalid questionnaires, 786 valid responses were analyzed by AMOS 24. Among the samples of this study, 47.80% were male and 52.20% were female. Furthermore, 16.93% were aged under 25 years, 61.31% were 26&#x02013;45 years, 18.35% were 46&#x02013;65 years, and 3.41% were above the age of 66 years.</p></sec><sec id="S4"><title>Analysis Results</title><sec id="S4.SS1"><title>Measurement Model</title><sec id="S4.SS1.SSS1"><title>Construct Validity</title><p>This study followed the two-step approach of structural equation modeling (SEM) proposed by <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">Anderson and Gerbing (1988)</xref> to estimate the measurement and structural model. We chose SEM as the statistical method and AMOS as the analysis tool for two reasons. First, SEM is a family of statistical procedures that could handle the confirmatory factor analysis (CFA) and path analysis. Particularly, CFA is an important procedure to measure construct validity and the path analysis is adopted to evaluate the research hypotheses (<xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">Byrne, 2001</xref>; <xref rid="B43" ref-type="bibr">Kline, 2011</xref>). Second, AMOS is one of the recommended analysis tools to perform the results of SEM (<xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">Babin et al., 2008</xref>). The first step examined construct reliability and validity of the measurement model using CFA, and the second step checked the path effects and their significance of the structural model. The measurement model was assessed by using the maximum likelihood estimation (MLE) in terms of factor loadings, reliability of measurement, convergent validity, and discriminant validity.</p><p>As shown in <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>, all standardized factor loadings of questions are from 0.699 to 0.894. All composite reliability of the constructs ranging from 0.839 to 0.913 and Cronbach&#x02019;s alpha ranging from 0.828 to 0.913 exceed 0.7 as recommended by <xref rid="B62" ref-type="bibr">Nunnally and Bernstein (1994)</xref>, indicating that all constructs have internal consistency. Lastly, the average variance extracted (AVE) of the constructs ranging from 0.633 to 0.777 exceed 0.5 as suggested by <xref rid="B26" ref-type="bibr">Fornell and Larcker (1981)</xref> and <xref rid="B28" ref-type="bibr">Hair et al. (2010)</xref>, showing that all constructs have adequate convergent validity. These results demonstrated that all measurement items had convergent validity.</p><table-wrap id="T1" position="float"><label>TABLE 1</label><caption><p>Results of the measurement model.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups" cellspacing="5" cellpadding="5"><thead><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Construct</bold></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Item</bold></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Standardized factor loading</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" colspan="2" rowspan="1"><bold>Construct reliability</bold><hr/></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Convergent validity</bold></td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Alpha</bold></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>CR</bold></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>AVE</bold></td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SR</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SR1</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.867</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.902</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.921</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.756</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SR2</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.894</td><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SR3</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.847</td><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">EE</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">EE1</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.803</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.828</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.837</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.633</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">EE2</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.699</td><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">EE3</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.875</td><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">CU</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">CU1</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.805</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.850</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.850</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.655</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">CU2</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.813</td><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">CU3</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.809</td><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">JP</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">JP1</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.833</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.872</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.872</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.695</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">JP2</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.828</td><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">JP3</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.839</td><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PU</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PU1</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.816</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.843</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.844</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.644</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PU2</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.764</td><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PU3</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.826</td><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SN</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SN1</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.847</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.876</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.877</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.704</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SN2</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.861</td><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SN3</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.809</td><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PBC</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PBC1</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.808</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.838</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.839</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.635</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PBC2</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.826</td><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PBC3</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.755</td><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">BI</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">BI1</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.886</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.913</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.913</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.777</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">BI2</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.887</td><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">BI3</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.872</td><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="justify" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><attrib><italic>Alpha, Cronbach&#x02019;s alpha; CR, composite reliability; AVE, average variance extracted; SR, social recognition; EE, environmental ethics; CU, curiosity; JP, joy of purchase; PU, perceived usefulness; SN, subjective norm; PBC, perceived behavioral control; BI, behavioral intention.</italic></attrib></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><p>As shown in <xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>, the bold numbers in the diagonal direction represent the square roots of AVEs and the off-diagonal numbers are correlations among constructs. Most of the numbers in the diagonal direction are greater than the off-diagonal numbers, and all the correlations are lower than 0.85; therefore, discriminant validity appears to be adequate for this study.</p><table-wrap id="T2" position="float"><label>TABLE 2</label><caption><p>Discriminant validity of the measurement model.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups" cellspacing="5" cellpadding="5"><thead><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>SR</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>EE</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>CU</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>JP</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>PU</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>SN</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>PBC</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>BI</bold></td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SR</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>0.869</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">EE</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.589</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>0.796</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">CU</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.569</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.648</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>0.809</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">JP</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.660</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.748</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.704</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>0.834</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PU</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.562</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.691</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.719</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.797</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>0.802</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SN</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.634</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.640</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.559</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.746</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.662</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>0.839</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PBC</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.616</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.704</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.633</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.694</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.668</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.702</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>0.797</bold></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">BI</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.566</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.748</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.551</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.683</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.622</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.604</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.622</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>0.881</bold></td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><attrib><italic>The items on the diagonal in bold represent the square roots of the AVE; off-diagonal elements are the correlation estimates. SR, social recognition; EE, environmental ethics; CU, curiosity; JP, joy of purchase; PU, perceived usefulness; SN, subjective norm; PBC, perceived behavioral control; BI, behavioral intention.</italic></attrib></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec><sec id="S4.SS1.SSS2"><title>Detection of Common Method Bias</title><p>Preventive measures in this research were taken in order to reduce the common method bias (CMB) that may result from sample collection of a single respondent&#x02019;s cognitive information by self-reported measurement items and decrease the impact of CMB. In addition to anonymous surveys, this research attempted to hide the meaning of each question and separate measurement items for different constructs as much as possible. The variable results in <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">Tables 1</xref>, <xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">2</xref> had an appropriate degree of construct validity, which also indicated that the results were not largely affected by CMB. In addition, this study adopted Harman&#x02019;s single-factor test to evaluate the severity of CMB (<xref rid="B66" ref-type="bibr">Podsakoff et al., 2003</xref>). The model fit of the CFA for the 24 measurement items in this study was better than the single-factor model of CFA significantly. This result could be seen that the impact of CMB was not serious in this research.</p></sec></sec><sec id="S4.SS2"><title>Structural Model Analysis</title><p>By using the maximum likelihood method, this study performed structural model testing to estimate the hypothesized relationships of the proposed model. Model fit indicators determine the degree of whether the sample data fit the structural equation model. <xref rid="B69" ref-type="bibr">Schumacker and Lomax (2010)</xref> and <xref rid="B43" ref-type="bibr">Kline (2011)</xref> recommended a variety of criteria to determine the model fit of a structural model. <xref rid="B36" ref-type="bibr">Jackson et al. (2009)</xref> suggested that the commonly used model fit reporting guidelines are <italic>&#x003c7;</italic><sup>2</sup>, <italic>df</italic>, <italic>&#x003c7;</italic><sup>2</sup>/<italic>df</italic> ratio, GFI, RMSEA, SRMR, CFI, and TLI.</p><p><xref rid="T3" ref-type="table">Table 3</xref> demonstrates several model fit indicators and the thresholds recommended by previous studies. Except for <italic>&#x003c7;</italic><sup>2</sup>, all model fit indicators exceed the recommended levels suggested by <xref rid="B69" ref-type="bibr">Schumacker and Lomax (2010)</xref>. Because <italic>&#x003c7;</italic><sup>2</sup> is very sensitive to a large sample, the ratio of <italic>&#x003c7;</italic><sup>2</sup> to its degree of freedom was computed. For a good model fit, the ideal ratio should be below three. Instead of evaluating each index independently, <xref rid="B35" ref-type="bibr">Hu and Bentler (1999)</xref> proposed that more strict combination rules should be applied to model fit indices so the type I errors could be controlled. The model fit indicators satisfy most of the independent level of recommended fits and the combination rule. Thus, it has been proven that the proposed model of most of the constructs has a good fit.</p><table-wrap id="T3" position="float"><label>TABLE 3</label><caption><p>Model fit.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups" cellspacing="5" cellpadding="5"><thead><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Model fit</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Criteria</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Measurement model</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Structural model</bold></td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Chi-squared/<italic>df</italic></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x0003c;5</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.848</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.914</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">GFI</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x0003e;0.9</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.934</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.903</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">CFI</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x0003e;0.9</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.969</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.948</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">TLI</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x0003e;0.9</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.962</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.940</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">NFI</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x0003e;0.9</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.953</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.932</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">IFI</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x0003e;0.9</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.969</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.949</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">RMSEA</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x0003c;0.08</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.049</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.061</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SRMR</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x0003c;0.08</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.029</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.039</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><attrib><italic>Chi-squared/<italic>df</italic>, chi-squared divided by degrees of freedom; GFI, goodness-of-fit index; CFI, comparative fit index; TLI, Tucker&#x02013;Lewis index; NFI, normed fit index; IFI, incremental fit index; RMSEA, root-mean-square error of approximation; SRMR, standardized root-mean-square residual.</italic></attrib></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><p>The results support the research hypotheses regarding the validity of the research model (as shown in <xref rid="T4" ref-type="table">Table 4</xref>); 54.3% of CU can be explained by SR and EE constructs, 74.2% of JP can be explained by SR and EE constructs, 64.7% of PU can be explained by SR and EE constructs, 62.8% of SN can be explained by SR and EE constructs, 62% of PBC can be explained by SR and EE constructs, and 54% of BI can be explained by CU, JP, PU, SN, and PBC constructs.</p><table-wrap id="T4" position="float"><label>TABLE 4</label><caption><p>Structural model analysis.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups" cellspacing="5" cellpadding="5"><thead><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>DV</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>IV</bold></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Unstd. regression weight</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>SE</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold><italic>t</italic>-Value</bold></td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Std. path coefficient</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold><italic>R</italic><sup>2</sup></bold></td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">CU</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SR</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.145</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.042</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.447</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.163***</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.580</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">EE</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.689</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.057</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12.166</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.648***</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">JP</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SR</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.191</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.040</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.746</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.202***</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.783</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">EE</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.840</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.056</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">14.893</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.744***</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PU</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SR</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.082</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.045</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.848</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.065</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.685</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">EE</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.859</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.062</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">13.844</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.769***</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SN</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SR</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.261</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.043</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6.030</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.275***</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.613</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">EE</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.659</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.056</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">11.795</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.580***</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PBC</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SR</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.183</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.041</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.454</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.206***</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.650</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">EE</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.699</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.054</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12.896</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.660***</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">BI</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">CU</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.036</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.048</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.741</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.036*</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.549</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">JP</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.332</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.063</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.252</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.357***</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PU</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.126</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.055</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.278</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.134*</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SN</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.105</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.046</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.274</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.114*</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">PBC</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.200</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.054</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.712</td><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.201***</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><attrib><italic>DV, dependent variable; IV, independent variable; SR, social recognition; EE, environmental ethics; CU, curiosity; JP, joy of purchase; PU, perceived usefulness; SN, subjective norm; PBC, perceived behavioral control; BI, behavioral intention. *<italic>p</italic>-value &#x0003c; 0.05. ***<italic>p-</italic>value &#x0003c; 0.001.</italic></attrib></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec><sec id="S4.SS3"><title>Mediation Effects</title><p>Bootstrapping mediation analysis can provide confidence intervals to examine the indirect effects. One of the preferred bootstrapping mediation analysis methods is bias-corrected bootstrapping (<xref rid="B88" ref-type="bibr">Williams and MacKinnon, 2008</xref>), which is used in this study. As shown in <xref rid="T5" ref-type="table">Table 5</xref>, the total effect SR&#x02192;BI, <italic>p</italic> &#x0003e; 0.05, bias-corrected confidence interval (CI) does include zero [CI of SR&#x02192;BI = (&#x02013;0.051, 0.448)]. The existence of total effect was not supported. It was not necessary to test the mediation effect. The total effect ER&#x02192;BI, <italic>p</italic> &#x0003c; 0.05, bias-corrected CI does not include zero [CI of ER&#x02192;BI = (0.281, 0.919)]. The existence of total effect was supported. The indirect effect EE&#x02192;CU&#x02192;BI, <italic>p</italic> &#x0003e; 0.05, both bias-corrected CI includes zero [CI of EE&#x02192;CU&#x02192;BI = (&#x02013;0.036, 0.163)]. Consequently, the hypothesis of the existence of indirect effect was not supported. The indirect effect EE&#x02192;JP&#x02192;BI bias-corrected CI does not include zero [CI of EE&#x02192;JP&#x02192;BI = (0.094, 0.652)]. Thus, the hypothesis of the existence of indirect effect was supported. The indirect effect ENV&#x02192;PU&#x02192;BI bias-corrected CI does not include zero [CI of EE&#x02192;PU&#x02192;BI = (0.007, 0.405)]. Therefore, the hypothesis of the existence of indirect effect was supported. The indirect effect ENV&#x02192;SN&#x02192;BI bias-corrected CI does not include zero [CI of ENV&#x02192;SN&#x02192;CU = (0.007, 0.25)]. Consequently, the hypothesis of the existence of indirect effect was supported. The indirect effect ENV&#x02192;PBC&#x02192;BI bias-corrected CI does not include zero [CI of ENV&#x02192;PBC&#x02192;BI = (0.037, 0.401)]. Accordingly, the hypothesis of the existence of indirect effect was supported.</p><table-wrap id="T5" position="float"><label>TABLE 5</label><caption><p>Analysis of mediation effects.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups" cellspacing="5" cellpadding="5"><thead><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Parameter</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Estimate</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Lower</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold>Upper</bold></td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><bold><italic>p-</italic>Value</bold></td></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SR&#x02192;CU&#x02192;BI</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.005</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x02013;0.008</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.046</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.373</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SR&#x02192;JP&#x02192;BI</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.063*</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.009</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.177</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.015</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SR&#x02192;PU&#x02192;BI</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.010</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x02013;0.006</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.076</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.216</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SR&#x02192;SN&#x02192;BI</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.028*</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.000</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.088</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.043</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">SR&#x02192;PBC&#x02192;BI</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.036*</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.005</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.111</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.014</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">EE&#x02192;CU&#x02192;BI</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.025</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x02013;0.049</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.148</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.464</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">EE&#x02192;JP&#x02192;BI</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.279**</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.114</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.633</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.001</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">EE&#x02192;PU&#x02192;BI</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.010</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x02013;0.006</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.076</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.216</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">EE&#x02192;SN&#x02192;BI</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.028*</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.000</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.088</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.043</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">EE&#x02192;PBC&#x02192;BI</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.016</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x02013;0.015</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.086</td><td valign="top" align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.224</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><attrib><italic>SR, social recognition; EE, environmental ethics; CU, curiosity; JP, joy of purchase; PU, perceived usefulness; SN, subjective norm; PBC, perceived behavioral control; BI, behavioral intention. *<italic>p-</italic>value &#x0003c; 0.05. **<italic>p-</italic>value &#x0003c; 0.01.</italic></attrib></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec></sec><sec id="S5"><title>Conclusion</title><sec id="S5.SS1"><title>Theoretical Contributions</title><p>Due to the complex nature of sustainability, it is common for researchers to focus only on the economic aspect of environmental solutions and implications. However, this study explored fitnesser&#x02019;s intrinsic motivations of green eating. Most of the environmental studies suggested to address the extension of TPB in interpreting human behavior in ecological protection issues (e.g., <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">Bagheri et al., 2019</xref>; <xref rid="B79" ref-type="bibr">Suki and Suki, 2019</xref>; <xref rid="B72" ref-type="bibr">Si et al., 2020</xref>). Therefore, integrating only one theory is not sufficient to explain complicated human behavior. This study proposed a research model incorporating TPB and HMSAM to discuss the compact of social recognition and environmental ethics on fitnesser&#x02019;s green eating intention. In addition, the mediation effects of curiosity, joy, perceived usefulness, subjective norm, and perceived behavior control were investigated. The results supported hypotheses H<sub>1</sub> to H<sub>10</sub>. Both fitnessers&#x02019; social recognition and their environmental ethics are positively correlated with the HMSAM constructs such as curiosity, joy of purchase, and perceived usefulness and the TPB constructs like subjective norm and perceived behavior control.</p><p>Social recognition refers to the positive response of society to individual social behavior. The praise and recognition of others is helpful to promote one&#x02019;s social status. In this study, fitnessers with a higher level of social recognition tend to have a higher curiosity in understanding how green eating can protect environment, have greater pleasure when eating green, and have a better understanding of the usefulness of green eating in ecological protection.</p><p>Environmental ethics is the study of environmental issues from an ethical perspective. Since environmental protection has become a manifestation in today&#x02019;s society, many fitnessers are committed to environmental protection initiatives and are proud of being environmentalists. They are eager to learn more about environmental protection and hope to protect the environment better. They &#x0201c;feel better right now&#x0201d; when they have hedonic goals (<xref rid="B49" ref-type="bibr">Lindenberg and Steg, 2007</xref>). They feel that they are doing their part for environmental protection when they eat green and, therefore, feel happy inside.</p><p>Fitnessers with a rich knowledge of environmental protection may gain social recognition from their friends. On the other hand, to obtain social recognition, they want to know more or be curious about the mechanism between green eating and environmental protection. When they are involved in these issues, they have full understanding about what green eating can do to the environment. Consequently, they feel that eating green is useful for ecological protection and they are happy to do it in their daily lives. This explained the correlation between social recognition and joy of purchase. Similarly, fitnessers with higher environmental ethics have no doubt in their mind that green eating is useful for environmental protection.</p><p>Subjective norm is the perception of the social pressures that individuals experience when they take a particular behavior. It is not surprising that a consumer with a higher social recognition has a higher subjective norm. Fitnessers are possible to cater to their friends to gain higher social recognition, so they will not perform a certain behavior. In other words, they will comply with their friends, to follow the subjective norm, because it is important to raise their social recognition.</p><p>As mentioned above, people with higher social recognition have the tendency to cope with their friends better. That is, they have better control of themselves whether or not to perform a particular behavior. Similarly, if fitnessers have higher environmental ethics, they expect to be able to master their behavior and will not do anything that is harmful to the environment. This explained why fitnessers with a higher level of environmental ethics tend to have a higher joy of purchase. Therefore, both social recognition and environmental ethics have a positive impact on perceived behavior control.</p><p>This study not only explores the influence of social recognition and environmental ethics on behavior intention, but also discusses the mediation effects of curiosity, joy of purchase, perceived usefulness, subjective norm, and perceived behavior control. Based on the mediation effect analysis, since the total effect of social recognition to behavior intention is not significant, constructs between social recognition and behavior intention are not discussed. However, the total effect of environmental ethics to behavior intention is significant, and the mediation effects of joy of purchase, perceived usefulness, subjective norm, and perceived behavior are supported. In other words, except for the H<sub>11</sub> that fitnesser&#x02019;s curiosity is positively correlated with their intention to eat green being not supported, H<sub>12</sub>&#x02013;H<sub>15</sub> dealing with environmental ethics having impacts on the behavior intention through the four abovementioned mediators are all sustained.</p><p>Intrinsic value is the degree to which an activity is considered to be personally enjoyable (<xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">Chiu and Wang, 2008</xref>; <xref rid="B38" ref-type="bibr">Jiang et al., 2020</xref>). <xref rid="B77" ref-type="bibr">Straume and Vitters&#x000f8; (2012)</xref> claimed that the individuals&#x02019; feelings of joy or pleasure could affect their behavior. A number of empirical studies have also confirmed the positive effect of hedonic values on consumer behavior intention. Hedonic perception influenced fitnesser&#x02019;s intentions of adoption significantly (<xref rid="B73" ref-type="bibr">Song, 2014</xref>). <xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">Choi and Kim (2016)</xref> found that both enjoyment and perceived usefulness affected behavioral intention positively. Similarly, in this study, perceived usefulness mediated behavior intention. This result is supported by <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">Chang et al. (2005)</xref> in their search of quality antecedents. In a web learning tools study, <xref rid="B46" ref-type="bibr">Lai (2017)</xref> found that perceived behavior control mediated behavior intention, and so did the subjective norm. In a study of genetically modified foods, <xref rid="B42" ref-type="bibr">Kim et al. (2014)</xref> pointed out that subjective norm and perceived behavior control are positive determinants of behavior intention, though this research proves that both subjective norm and perceived behavior control are mediators between environmental ethics and behavior intention.</p></sec><sec id="S5.SS2"><title>Managerial Implications</title><p>There are four theoretical contributions of this article. First, this research combines TPB and HMSAM to extend the research on green eating and to build up the research model from social recognition, environmental ethics, and the two aforesaid models. Second, there is no prior research using the HMS adoption model in discussing fitnesser&#x02019;s intention in green eating. This study proves that joy of purchase and perceived usefulness positively affect fitnesser&#x02019;s behavior intention that has filled up the research gap. Third, this study indicates that the relationship between environmental ethics and behavior intention is mediated by joy of purchase, perceived usefulness, subjective norm, and perceived behavior control. Fourth, arousing fitnesser&#x02019;s social recognition and environmental ethics is helpful in increasing their intention of green eating. Unlike many previous studies that only focused on interpreting consumer behavior with TPB, this research raises the research domain to a different level by integrating social recognition and environmental ethics into the research model.</p><p>There are three practical contributions of this study. First, this study validates that increasing fitnesser&#x02019;s social recognition and environmental ethics can not only raise their joy of purchase, perceived usefulness, subjective norm, and perceived behavior control but also improve their behavioral intention toward green eating. If manufacturers want to increase their sales on green eating, other than increase fitnesser&#x02019;s social recognition and environmental ethics, they have to enhance fitnesser&#x02019;s abovementioned four elements to change fitnesser&#x02019;s behavior intention to eat green.</p><p>Second, fitnesser&#x02019;s joy of purchase, perceived usefulness, subjective norm, and perceived behavior control should be promoted so their intention to eat green will be influenced. Because the mediation effects of the said four constructs are significant in this study, companies can change the fitnesser&#x02019;s behavior intention to eat green if their aforesaid variables can be improved.</p><p>Third, this study demonstrates that fitnesser&#x02019;s social recognition and environmental ethics are positively associated with joy of purchase, perceived usefulness, subjective norm, and perceived behavior control and are also positively associated with fitnesser&#x02019;s behavior intention. Both fitnesser&#x02019;s social recognition and environmental ethics indirectly affect fitnesser&#x02019;s behavior intention to eat green positively <italic>via</italic> joy of purchase, perceived usefulness, subjective norm, and perceived behavior control.</p></sec><sec id="S5.SS3"><title>Research Limitations and Future Work</title><p>Although this study provided some useful insights and viewpoints, it had several limitations and should be addressed in further research. First, the aim of this study was to determine the constructs that influence fitnesser&#x02019;s behavior intention of green eating. Future research could try to integrate different theories and constructs to better interpret fitnesser&#x02019;s behavior intention in comparison with this study. Second, the sample collection and research design of this study were undertaken in China. Future research could broaden the sample collection by adding samples from other countries or areas. Multiculture comparison of consumer behavior intention could be explored if possible. Finally, this study deployed a questionnaire survey that only provided cross-sectional data. The concept of environmental protection and the innovation of green eating may change over time; therefore, future research should try to conduct a longitudinal study to reveal the different effects of social recognition and environmental ethics on fitnesser&#x02019;s behavior intention in different time periods.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="data-availability" id="S6"><title>Data Availability Statement</title><p>The original contributions presented in the study are included in the article/supplementary material, further inquiries can be directed to the corresponding author/s.</p></sec><sec id="S7"><title>Ethics Statement</title><p>Ethical review and approval was not required for the study on human participants in accordance with the local legislation and institutional requirements. Written informed consent for participation was not required for this study in accordance with the national legislation and the institutional requirements.</p></sec><sec id="S8"><title>Author Contributions</title><p>All authors listed have made a substantial, direct and intellectual contribution to the work, and approved it for publication.</p></sec><sec sec-type="COI-statement" id="conf1"><title>Conflict of Interest</title><p>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn id="footnote1"><label>1</label><p><ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.wjx.cn/">https://www.wjx.cn/</ext-link></p></fn></fn-group><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="B1"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Agarwal</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Karahanna</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2000</year>). <article-title>Time flies when you&#x02019;re having fun: cognitive absorption and beliefs about information technology usage.</article-title>
<source><italic>MIS Q.</italic></source>
<volume>24</volume>
<fpage>665</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>694</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/3250951</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B2"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ahmad</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ghazali</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Abdullah</surname><given-names>M. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nordin</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Mohd Nasir</surname><given-names>I. N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Mohd Farid</surname><given-names>N. A.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Green marketing and its effect on consumers&#x02019; purchase behaviour: an empirical analysis.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Int. Bus. Econ. Entrep.</italic></source>
<volume>5</volume>
<fpage>46</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>55</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B3"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ajzen</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1991</year>). <article-title>The theory of planned behavior.</article-title>
<source><italic>Organ. Behav. Hum. Decis. Process.</italic></source>
<volume>50</volume>
<fpage>179</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>211</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B4"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Al-Jubari</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2019</year>). <article-title>College students&#x02019; entrepreneurial intention: testing an integrated model of SDT and TPB.</article-title>
<source><italic>Sage Open</italic></source>
<volume>9</volume>:<issue>21582440198</issue>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/2158244019853467</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B5"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Anderson</surname><given-names>J. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gerbing</surname><given-names>D. W.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1988</year>). <article-title>Structural equation modeling in practice: a review and recommended two-step approach.</article-title>
<source><italic>Psychol. Bull.</italic></source>
<volume>103</volume>
<fpage>411</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>423</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1037/0033-2909.103.3.411</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B6"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Arvola</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Vassallo</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dean</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lampila</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Saba</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lahteenmaki</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2008</year>). <article-title>Predicting intentions to purchase organic food: the role of affective and moral attitudes in the Theory of Planned Behavior.</article-title>
<source><italic>Appetite</italic></source>
<volume>50</volume>
<fpage>443</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>454</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.appet.2007.09.010</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 18036702?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18036702</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B7"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Babin</surname><given-names>B. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hair</surname><given-names>J. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Boles</surname><given-names>J. S.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2008</year>). <article-title>Publishing research in marketing journals using structural equation modeling.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Mark. Theory Pract.</italic></source>
<volume>16</volume>
<fpage>279</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>286</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2753/mtp1069-6679160401</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B8"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bagheri</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bondori</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Allahyari</surname><given-names>M. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Damalas</surname><given-names>C. A.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2019</year>). <article-title>Modeling farmers&#x02019; intention to use pesticides: an expanded version of the theory of planned behavior.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Environ. Manag.</italic></source>
<volume>248</volume>:<issue>109291</issue>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2019.109291</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 31352279?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31352279</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B9"><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Barboza</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2010</year>). <source><italic>China Passes Japan as Second-Largest Economy.</italic></source>
<publisher-loc>New York, NY</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>The New York Times</publisher-name>, 15.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B10"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Byrne</surname><given-names>B. M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2001</year>). <article-title>Structural equation modeling with AMOS, EQS, and LISREL: comparative approaches to testing for the factorial validity of a measuring instrument.</article-title>
<source><italic>Int. J. Test.</italic></source>
<volume>1</volume>
<fpage>55</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>86</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1207/s15327574ijt0101_4</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B11"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Canova</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bobbio</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Manganelli</surname><given-names>A. M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Buying organic food products: the role of trust in the Theory of Planned Behavior.</article-title>
<source><italic>Front. Psychol.</italic></source>
<volume>11</volume>:<issue>575820</issue>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.575820</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 33192881?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33192881</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B12"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Carfora</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name><name><surname>di Massimo</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Rastelli</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Catellani</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Piastra</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Dialogue management in conversational agents through psychology of persuasion and machine learning.</article-title>
<source><italic>Multimed. Tools Appl.</italic></source>
<volume>79</volume>
<fpage>35949</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>35971</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11042-020-09178-w</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B13"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chan</surname><given-names>R. Y.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2004</year>). <article-title>Consumer responses to environmental advertising in China.</article-title>
<source><italic>Mark. Intell. Plann.</italic></source>
<volume>22</volume>
<fpage>427</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>437</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1108/02634500410542789</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B14"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>I. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hung</surname><given-names>W. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hwang</surname><given-names>H. G.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2005</year>). <article-title>An empirical study on the impact of quality antecedents on tax payers&#x02019; acceptance of Internet tax-filing systems.</article-title>
<source><italic>Gov. Inf. Q.</italic></source>
<volume>22</volume>
<fpage>389</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>410</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.giq.2005.05.002</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 32288164?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32288164</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B15"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>S. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>H. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>M. F.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2009</year>). <article-title>Determinants of satisfaction and continuance intention towards self-service technologies.</article-title>
<source><italic>Ind. Manag. Data Syst.</italic></source>
<volume>109</volume>
<fpage>1248</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1263</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1108/02635570911002306</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B16"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>S. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hung</surname><given-names>C. W.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>Elucidating the factors influencing the acceptance of green products: an extension of theory of planned behavior.</article-title>
<source><italic>Technol. Forecast. Soc. Change</italic></source>
<volume>112</volume>
<fpage>155</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>163</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.techfore.2016.08.022</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B17"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>S. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>M. L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>C. P.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2013</year>). <article-title>Integrating technology readiness into the expectation&#x02013;confirmation model: an empirical study of mobile services.</article-title>
<source><italic>Cyberpsychol. Behav. Soc. Netw.</italic></source>
<volume>16</volume>
<fpage>604</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>612</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1089/cyber.2012.0606</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 23790359?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23790359</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B18"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chiu</surname><given-names>C. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>E. T.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2008</year>). <article-title>Understanding Web-based learning continuance intention: the role of subjective task value.</article-title>
<source><italic>Inf. Manag.</italic></source>
<volume>45</volume>
<fpage>194</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>201</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.im.2008.02.003</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B19"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>Is the smartwatch an IT product or a fashion product? A study on factors affecting the intention to use smartwatches.</article-title>
<source><italic>Comput. Hum. Behav.</italic></source>
<volume>63</volume>
<fpage>777</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>786</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.chb.2016.06.007</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B20"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chuang</surname><given-names>N. K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dellmann-Jenkins</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2010</year>). <article-title>Career decision making and intention: a study of hospitality undergraduate students.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Hosp. Tour. Res.</italic></source>
<volume>34</volume>
<fpage>512</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>530</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/1096348010370867</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B21"><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Csikszentmihalyi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1990</year>). <source><italic>Flow: The Psychology of Optimal Experience.</italic></source>
<publisher-loc>New York, NY</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Harper and Row</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B22"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Dalvi-Esfahani</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Alaedini</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nilashi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Samad</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Asadi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Mohammadi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Students&#x02019; green information technology behavior: beliefs and personality traits.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Clean. Prod.</italic></source>
<volume>257</volume>:<issue>120406</issue>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.120406</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B23"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ellis</surname><given-names>E. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ramankutty</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2008</year>). <article-title>Putting people in the map: anthropogenic biomes of the world.</article-title>
<source><italic>Front. Ecol. Environ.</italic></source>
<volume>6</volume>
<fpage>439</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>447</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1890/070062</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B24"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fischer</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>V&#x000f6;lckner</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sattler</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2010</year>). <article-title>How important are brands? A cross-category, cross-country study.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Mark. Res.</italic></source>
<volume>47</volume>
<fpage>823</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>839</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1509/jmkr.47.5.823</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 11670861?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11670861</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B25"><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fishbein</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ajzen</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1975</year>). <source><italic>Belief, Attitude, Intention and Behavior.</italic></source>
<publisher-loc>Reading, MA</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Addison-Wesley</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B26"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fornell</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Larcker</surname><given-names>D. F.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1981</year>). <article-title>Evaluating structural equation models with unobservable variables and measurement error.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Mark. Res.</italic></source>
<volume>18</volume>
<fpage>39</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>50</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/3151312</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B27"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hagger</surname><given-names>M. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chatzisarantis</surname><given-names>N. L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Biddle</surname><given-names>S. J.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2002</year>). <article-title>A meta-analytic review of the theories of reasoned action and planned behavior in physical activity: predictive validity and the contribution of additional variables.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Sport Exerc. Psychol.</italic></source>
<volume>24</volume>
<fpage>3</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>32</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1123/jsep.24.1.3</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B28"><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hair</surname><given-names>J. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Black</surname><given-names>W. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Babin</surname><given-names>B. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Anderson</surname><given-names>R. E.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2010</year>). <source><italic>Multivariate Data Analysis: A Global Perspective</italic></source>, <edition>7th Edn</edition>. <publisher-loc>Upper Saddle River, NJ</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Pearson Prentice Hall</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B29"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Henriques</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sadorsky</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1999</year>). <article-title>The relationship between environmental commitment and managerial perceptions of stakeholder importance.</article-title>
<source><italic>Acad. Manag. J.</italic></source>
<volume>42</volume>
<fpage>87</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>99</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/256876</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B30"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Herring</surname><given-names>M. C.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2004</year>). <article-title>Development of constructivist-based distance learning environments: a knowledge base for K-12 teachers.</article-title>
<source><italic>Q. Rev. Distance Educ.</italic></source>
<volume>5</volume>
<fpage>231</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>242</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B31"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hogg</surname><given-names>M. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hardie</surname><given-names>E. A.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1991</year>). <article-title>Social attraction, personal attraction, and self- categorization-, a field study.</article-title>
<source><italic>Pers. Soc. Psychol. Bull.</italic></source>
<volume>17</volume>
<fpage>175</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>180</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/014616729101700209</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B32"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Holden</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2005</year>). <article-title>Achieving a sustainable relationship between common pool resources and tourism: the role of environmental ethics.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Sustain. Tour.</italic></source>
<volume>13</volume>
<fpage>339</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>352</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/09669580508668561</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B33"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hoque</surname><given-names>M. Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hossan</surname><given-names>M. A.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Understanding the influence of belief and belief revision on consumers&#x02019; purchase intention of liquid milk.</article-title>
<source><italic>Sage Open</italic></source>
<volume>10</volume>:<issue>2158244020922972</issue>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B34"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hsu</surname><given-names>C. L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>C. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yansritakul</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2017</year>). <article-title>Exploring purchase intention of green skincare products using the theory of planned behavior: testing the moderating effects of country of origin and price sensitivity.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Retail. Cons. Serv</italic></source>. <volume>34</volume>
<fpage>145</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>152</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B35"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>L. T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bentler</surname><given-names>P. M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1999</year>). <article-title>Cutoff criteria for fit indexes in covariance structure analysis: conventional criteria versus new alternatives.</article-title>
<source><italic>Struct. Equ. Modeling</italic></source>
<volume>6</volume>
<fpage>1</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>55</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/10705519909540118</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B36"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jackson</surname><given-names>D. L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gillaspy</surname><given-names>J. A.</given-names><suffix>Jr.</suffix></name><name><surname>Purc-Stephenson</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2009</year>). <article-title>Reporting practices in confirmatory factor analysis: an overview and some recommendations.</article-title>
<source><italic>Psychol. Methods</italic></source>
<volume>14</volume>
<fpage>6</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>23</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1037/a0014694</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 19271845?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19271845</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B37"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jamal</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sharifuddin</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2015</year>). <article-title>Perceived value and perceived usefulness of halal labeling: the role of religion and culture.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Bus. Res.</italic></source>
<volume>68</volume>
<fpage>933</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>941</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jbusres.2014.09.020</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B38"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>R. D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Implicit theories and engagement in math among Chinese adolescent students: a moderated mediation model of intrinsic value and academic self-efficacy.</article-title>
<source><italic>Front. Psychol.</italic></source>
<volume>11</volume>:<issue>1325</issue>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.01325</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 32676046?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32676046</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B39"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>K. C.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>Hospitality and tourism management students&#x02019; study and career preferences: comparison of three Asian regional groups.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Hosp. Leis. Sport Tour. Educ.</italic></source>
<volume>19</volume>
<fpage>66</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>84</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jhlste.2016.05.002</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B40"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>W. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>K. S.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2018</year>). <article-title>Pro-environmental intentions among food festival attendees: an application of the value-belief-norm model.</article-title>
<source><italic>Sustainability</italic></source>
<volume>10</volume>:<issue>3894</issue>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/su10113894</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B41"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Y. G.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>Ecological concerns about genetically modified (GM) food consumption using the Theory of Planned Behavior (TPB).</article-title>
<source><italic>Procedia Soc. Behav. Sci.</italic></source>
<volume>159</volume>
<fpage>677</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>681</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.sbspro.2014.12.467</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B42"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>Y. G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jang</surname><given-names>S. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>A. K.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>Application of the theory of planned behavior to genetically modified foods: moderating effects of food technology neophobia.</article-title>
<source><italic>Food Res. Int.</italic></source>
<volume>62</volume>
<fpage>947</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>954</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.foodres.2014.03.057</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B43"><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kline</surname><given-names>R. B.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2011</year>). <source><italic>Principles and Practice of Structural Equation Modeling</italic></source>, <edition>3 Edn</edition>. <publisher-loc>New York, NY</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Guilford</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B44"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Koo</surname><given-names>D. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Choi</surname><given-names>Y. Y.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2010</year>). <article-title>Knowledge search and people with high epistemic curiosity.</article-title>
<source><italic>Comput. Hum. Behav.</italic></source>
<volume>26</volume>
<fpage>12</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>22</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.chb.2009.08.013</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B45"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lacroix</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gifford</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Targeting interventions to distinct meat-eating groups reduces meat consumption.</article-title>
<source><italic>Food Qual. Prefer.</italic></source>
<volume>86</volume>:<issue>103997</issue>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.foodqual.2020.103997</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B46"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lai</surname><given-names>H. J.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2017</year>). <article-title>Examining civil servants&#x02019; decisions to use Web 2.0 tools for learning, based on the decomposed theory of planned behavior.</article-title>
<source><italic>Interact. Learn. Environ.</italic></source>
<volume>25</volume>
<fpage>295</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>305</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/10494820.2015.1121879</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B47"><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Leopold</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1949</year>). <source><italic>A Sand County Almanac and Sketches Here and There.</italic></source>
<publisher-loc>New York, NY</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B48"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Leopold</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Voelkel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dethier</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Caine</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2010</year>). <article-title>Mountain permafrost&#x02013;a valid archive to study climate change? Examples from the Rocky Mountains Front Range of Colorado, USA.</article-title>
<source><italic>Nova Acta Leopoldina</italic></source>
<volume>112</volume>
<fpage>281</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>289</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B49"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lindenberg</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Steg</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2007</year>). <article-title>Normative, gain and hedonic goal frames guiding environmental behavior.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Soc. Issues</italic></source>
<volume>63</volume>
<fpage>117</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>137</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1540-4560.2007.00499.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B50"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lowry</surname><given-names>P. B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gaskin</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Twyman</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hammer</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Roberts</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>Taking &#x02018;fun and games&#x02019; seriously: proposing the hedonic-motivation system adoption model (HMSAM).</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Assoc. Inf. Syst.</italic></source>
<volume>14</volume>
<fpage>617</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>671</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.17705/1jais.00347</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B51"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Malan</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Amsler Challamel</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Silverstein</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hoffs</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Spang</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Pace</surname><given-names>S. A.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Impact of a scalable, multi-campus &#x0201c;Foodprint&#x0201d; seminar on college students&#x02019; dietary intake and dietary carbon footprint.</article-title>
<source><italic>Nutrients</italic></source>
<volume>12</volume>:<issue>2890</issue>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/nu12092890</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 32971829?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32971829</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B52"><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Martella</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kray</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Clementini</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2015</year>). &#x0201c;<article-title>A gamification framework for volunteered geographic information</article-title>,&#x0201d; in <source><italic>AGILE 2015</italic></source>, <role>eds</role>
<person-group person-group-type="editor"><name><surname>Bacao</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Santos</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Painho</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<publisher-loc>Cham</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name>), <fpage>73</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>89</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-16787-9_5</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B53"><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Maslow</surname><given-names>A. H.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1970</year>). <source><italic>Motivation and Personality.</italic></source>
<publisher-loc>New York, NY</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Harper and Row</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B54"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McPhail</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chapman</surname><given-names>G. E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Beagan</surname><given-names>B. L.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2011</year>). <article-title>Too much of that stuff can&#x02019;t be good&#x0201d;: Canadian teens, morality, and fast food consumption.</article-title>
<source><italic>Soc. Sci. Med.</italic></source>
<volume>73</volume>
<fpage>301</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>307</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2011.05.022</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 21689876?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21689876</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B55"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>McShane</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2007</year>). <article-title>Why environmental ethics shouldn&#x02019;t give up on intrinsic value.</article-title>
<source><italic>Environ. Ethics</italic></source>
<volume>29</volume>
<fpage>43</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>61</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5840/enviroethics200729128</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B56"><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Misra</surname><given-names>R. P.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1995</year>). <source><italic>Environmental Ethics: A Dialogue of Cultures.</italic></source>
<publisher-loc>Delhi</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Concept Publishing Company</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B57"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mohammadi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2015</year>). <article-title>Social and individual antecedents of m-learning adoption in Iran.</article-title>
<source><italic>Comput. Hum. Behav.</italic></source>
<volume>49</volume>
<fpage>191</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>207</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.chb.2015.03.006</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B58"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Moslehpour</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Pham</surname><given-names>V. K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wong</surname><given-names>W. K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bilgi&#x000e7;li</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2018</year>). <article-title>e-purchase intention of Taiwanese consumers: sustainable mediation of perceived usefulness and perceived ease of use.</article-title>
<source><italic>Sustainability</italic></source>
<volume>10</volume>:<issue>234</issue>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/su10010234</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B59"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mundorf</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Redding</surname><given-names>C. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Paiva</surname><given-names>A. L.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2018</year>). <article-title>Sustainable transportation attitudes and health behavior change: evaluation of a brief stage-targeted video intervention.</article-title>
<source><italic>Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health</italic></source>
<volume>15</volume>:<issue>150</issue>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/ijerph15010150</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 29346314?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29346314</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B60"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Muposhi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dhurup</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2017</year>). <article-title>The influence of green marketing tools on green eating efficacy and green eating behaviour.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Econ. Behav. Stud.</italic></source>
<volume>9</volume>
<fpage>76</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>87</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22610/jebs.v9i2.1651</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B61"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>North</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nurse</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>&#x02018;War Stories&#x02019;: morality, curiosity, enthusiasm and commitment as facilitators of SME owners&#x02019; engagement in low carbon transitions.</article-title>
<source><italic>Geoforum</italic></source>
<volume>52</volume>
<fpage>32</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>41</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.geoforum.2013.12.007</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B62"><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Nunnally</surname><given-names>J. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bernstein</surname><given-names>I. H.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1994</year>). <source><italic>Psychometric Theory</italic></source>, <edition>3rd Edn</edition>. <publisher-loc>New York, NY</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>McGraw-Hill</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B63"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Oluwajana</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Idowu</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nat</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Vanduhe</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fadiya</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2019</year>). <article-title>The adoption of students&#x02019; hedonic motivation system model to gamified learning environment.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Theor. Appl. Electron. Commer. Res.</italic></source>
<volume>14</volume>
<fpage>156</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>167</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4067/S0718-18762019000300109</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 27315006?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27315006</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B64"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Parash</surname><given-names>M. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Suki</surname><given-names>N. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shimmi</surname><given-names>S. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hossain</surname><given-names>A. T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Murthy</surname><given-names>K. D.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Examining students&#x02019; intention to perform voluntary blood donation using a theory of planned behaviour: a structural equation modelling approach.</article-title>
<source><italic>Transfus. Clin. Biol.</italic></source>
<volume>27</volume>
<fpage>70</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>77</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.tracli.2020.02.002</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 32139133?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32139133</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B65"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Paul</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Modi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>Predicting green product consumption using theory of planned behavior and reasoned action.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Retail. Cons. Serv</italic></source>. <volume>29</volume>
<fpage>123</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>134</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B66"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Podsakoff</surname><given-names>P. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>MacKenzie</surname><given-names>S. B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>J. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Podsakoff</surname><given-names>N. P.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2003</year>). <article-title>Common method biases in behavioral research: a critical review of the literature and recommended remedies.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Appl. Psychol.</italic></source>
<volume>88</volume>
<fpage>879</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>904</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1037/0021-9010.88.5.879</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 14516251?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14516251</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B67"><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Rolston</surname><given-names>H.</given-names><suffix>III</suffix></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <source><italic>A New Environmental Ethics: The Next Millennium for Life on Earth.</italic></source>
<publisher-loc>Abingdon</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Routledge</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B68"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ruangkanjanases</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>You</surname><given-names>J. J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chien</surname><given-names>S. W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>S. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chao</surname><given-names>L. C.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Elucidating the effect of antecedents on consumers&#x02019; green purchase intention: an extension of the Theory of Planned Behavior.</article-title>
<source><italic>Front. Psychol.</italic></source>
<volume>11</volume>:<issue>1433</issue>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.01433</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 32793023?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32793023</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B69"><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Schumacker</surname><given-names>R. E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lomax</surname><given-names>R. G.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2010</year>). <source><italic>A Beginner&#x02019;s Guide to Structural Equation Modeling</italic></source>, <edition>3 Edn</edition>. <publisher-loc>Abingdon</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Taylor and Francis Group, LLC</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B70"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shaw</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shui</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2002</year>). <article-title>An assessment of ethical obligation and self-identity in ethical consumer decision-making: a structural equation modeling approach.</article-title>
<source><italic>Int. J. Consum. Stud.</italic></source>
<volume>26</volume>
<fpage>286</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>293</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1046/j.1470-6431.2002.00255.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B71"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shu</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>Continual use of microblogs.</article-title>
<source><italic>Behav. Inf. Technol.</italic></source>
<volume>33</volume>
<fpage>666</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>677</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/0144929x.2013.816774</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B72"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Si</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>J. G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lan</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Understanding intention and behavior toward sustainable usage of bike sharing by extending the theory of planned behavior.</article-title>
<source><italic>Resour. Conserv. Recycl.</italic></source>
<volume>152</volume>:<issue>104513</issue>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.resconrec.2019.104513</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B73"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>Understanding the adoption of mobile innovation in China.</article-title>
<source><italic>Comput. Hum. Behav.</italic></source>
<volume>38</volume>
<fpage>339</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>348</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.chb.2014.06.016</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B74"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Stavrova</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fetchenhauer</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Schl&#x000f6;sser</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2013</year>). <article-title>Why are religious people happy? The effect of the social norm of religiosity across countries.</article-title>
<source><italic>Soc. Sci. Res.</italic></source>
<volume>42</volume>
<fpage>90</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>105</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ssresearch.2012.07.002</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 23146600?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23146600</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B75"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Stead</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>McDermott</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>MacKintosh</surname><given-names>A. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Adamson</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2011</year>). <article-title>Why healthy eating is bad for young people&#x02019;s health: identity, belonging and food.</article-title>
<source><italic>Soc. Sci. Med.</italic></source>
<volume>72</volume>
<fpage>1131</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1139</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2010.12.029</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 21429646?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21429646</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B76"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Steg</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Vlek</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2009</year>). <article-title>Encouraging pro-environmental behaviour: an integrative review and research agenda.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Environ. Psychol.</italic></source>
<volume>29</volume>
<fpage>309</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>317</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jenvp.2008.10.004</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B77"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Straume</surname><given-names>L. V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Vitters&#x000f8;</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>Happiness, inspiration and the fully functioning person: separating hedonic and eudaimonic well-being in the workplace.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Posit. Psychol.</italic></source>
<volume>7</volume>
<fpage>387</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>398</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/17439760.2012.711348</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B78"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2019</year>). <article-title>Improving cycling behaviors of dockless bike-sharing users based on an extended theory of planned behavior and credit-based supervision policies in China.</article-title>
<source><italic>Front. Psychol.</italic></source>
<volume>10</volume>:<issue>2189</issue>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2019.02189</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 31632319?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31632319</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B79"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Suki</surname><given-names>N. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Suki</surname><given-names>N. M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2019</year>). <article-title>Examination of peer influence as a moderator and predictor in explaining green purchase behaviour in a developing country.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Clean. Produc</italic></source>. <volume>228</volume>
<fpage>833</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>844</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B80"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Susewind</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Walkowitz</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Symbolic moral self-completion&#x02013;social recognition of prosocial behavior reduces subsequent moral striving.</article-title>
<source><italic>Front. Psychol.</italic></source>
<volume>11</volume>:<issue>560188</issue>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.560188</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 33013599?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33013599</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B81"><mixed-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Taylor</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1986</year>). <source><italic>Respect for Nature: A Theory of Environmental Ethics.</italic></source>
<publisher-loc>Princeton, NJ</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Princeton University Press</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B82"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Thomas</surname><given-names>K. W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Velthouse</surname><given-names>B. A.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1990</year>). <article-title>Cognitive elements of empowerment: an &#x02018;interpretive&#x02019; model of intrinsic task motivation.</article-title>
<source><italic>Acad. Manag. Rev.</italic></source>
<volume>15</volume>
<fpage>666</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>681</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/258687</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B83"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tsai</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>Y. P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ruangkanjanases</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Understanding the effects of antecedents on continuance intention to gather food safety information on websites.</article-title>
<source><italic>Front. Psychol.</italic></source>
<volume>11</volume>:<issue>579322</issue>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2020.579322</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 33424693?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33424693</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B84"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tukker</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jansen</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2006</year>). <article-title>Environmental impacts of products: a detailed review of studies.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Ind. Ecol.</italic></source>
<volume>10</volume>
<fpage>159</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>182</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1162/jiec.2006.10.3.159</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B85"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Uzun</surname><given-names>A. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kilis</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Investigating antecedents of plagiarism using extended theory of planned behavior.</article-title>
<source><italic>Comput. Educ.</italic></source>
<volume>144</volume>:<issue>103700</issue>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.compedu.2019.103700</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B86"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>van der Heijden</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2004</year>). <article-title>User acceptance of hedonic information systems.</article-title>
<source><italic>MIS Q.</italic></source>
<volume>28</volume>
<fpage>695</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>704</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2307/25148660</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B87"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Weller</surname><given-names>K. E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Greene</surname><given-names>G. W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Redding</surname><given-names>C. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Paiva</surname><given-names>A. L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lofgren</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nash</surname><given-names>J. T.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2014</year>). <article-title>Development and validation of green eating behaviors, stage of change, decisional balance, and self-efficacy scales in college students.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Nutr. Educ. Behav.</italic></source>
<volume>46</volume>
<fpage>324</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>333</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jneb.2014.01.002</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 24613445?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24613445</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B88"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>MacKinnon</surname><given-names>D. P.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2008</year>). <article-title>Resampling and distribution of the product methods for testing indirect effects in complex models.</article-title>
<source><italic>Struct. Equ. Modeling</italic></source>
<volume>15</volume>
<fpage>23</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>51</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/10705510701758166</pub-id>
<?supplied-pmid 20179778?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20179778</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B89"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2017</year>). <article-title>Continuance intention to use MOOCs: integrating the technology acceptance model (TAM) and task technology fit (TTF) model.</article-title>
<source><italic>Comput. Hum. Behav.</italic></source>
<volume>67</volume>
<fpage>221</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>232</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.chb.2016.10.028</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B90"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>J. H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>C. W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>C. T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H. J.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2015</year>). <article-title>Green purchase intentions: an exploratory study of the Taiwanese electric motorcycle market.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Bus. Res.</italic></source>
<volume>68</volume>
<fpage>829</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>833</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jbusres.2014.11.036</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B91"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yadav</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Pathak</surname><given-names>G. S.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2016</year>). <article-title>Young consumers&#x02019; intention towards buying green products in a developing nation: extending the theory of planned behavior.</article-title>
<source><italic>J. Clean. Prod.</italic></source>
<volume>135</volume>
<fpage>732</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>739</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2016.06.120</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>