<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">Plerixafor is a small molecule that selectively antagonizes chemokine receptor-4 (CXCR-4) by blocking the binding of its cognate ligand, stromal cell-derived factor-1 (SDF-1). Plerixafor was shown to increase the mobilization of CD34
 <sup>+</sup> cells into the peripheral blood and offers a treatment option for patients undergoing stem cell mobilization for auto-HSCT. In a randomized phase II study in patients with NHL or multiple myeloma, plerixafor was well tolerated, and the combination of plerixafor and granulocyte colony-stimulating factor (G-CSF) increased the likelihood of obtaining ≥5 × 10
 <sup>6</sup> CD34
 <sup>+</sup> cells/kg in fewer apheresis days compared with G-CSF as a single agent [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>]. Subsequently, two phase III, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter studies demonstrated that the combination of plerixafor plus G-CSF was well tolerated, and mobilized significantly higher numbers of stem cells than G-CSF alone in patients with NHL or multiple myeloma [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>]. Plerixafor is approved in multiple regions for use in combination with G-CSF for the mobilization of HSCs in patients with NHL or multiple myeloma undergoing high-dose chemotherapy followed by auto-HSCT. In Europe, it is approved for use in such patients whose cells mobilize poorly. During the regulatory review of data from the two pivotal studies, a trend for a lower proportion of patients achieving the target of ≥5 × 10
 <sup>6</sup> CD34
 <sup>+</sup> cells/kg in ≤4 days of apheresis in those weighing &lt;85 kg compared with &gt;85 kg was noted in the NHL study (AMD3100-3101). The US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) suggested that this may be due to lower drug exposure in patients with lower body weight, and requested that this finding be explored in a controlled clinical setting. The FDA requested that a clinical study should be performed in NHL patients comparing the standard weight-based (WB) dosing regimen to a fixed dosing regimen in patients weighing ≤70 kg. Therefore, a clinical study in NHL patients to compare the standard, approved, subcutaneously (SC) administered, WB plerixafor dosing regimen of 0.24 mg/kg with a fixed-dose (FD) regimen of 20 mg/kg SC in patients with NHL weighing ≤70 kg after both sets of patients had received G-CSF for 4 days was conducted. We report here the results from this study.
</p>
