<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="para0004">COVID-19 has rapidly emerged as the world's most pressing infectious threat. The novel severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2 (SARS Co-V-2) responsible for this condition has proven to be readily transmissible, with significant morbidity and a high case fatality rate
 <xref rid="bib0001" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>1</sup>
 </xref>. SARS Co-V-2 has further demonstrated wide-ranging systemic effects, including significant immunologic, pulmonary, gastrointestinal, cardiac, and neurologic manifestations.
 <xref rid="bib0002" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>2</sup>
 </xref>
 <sup>,</sup>
 <xref rid="bib0003" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>3</sup>
 </xref> A particularly concerning risk that has emerged with COVID-19 is the development of an activated coagulation system associated with macrovascular and microvascular thrombosis and overall poor prognosis.
 <xref rid="bib0004" ref-type="bibr">4.</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib0005" ref-type="bibr">5.</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib0006" ref-type="bibr">6.</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib0007" ref-type="bibr">7.</xref> The incidence of venous or arterial thrombotic events in hospitalized patients may be as high as 1 in 6, and up to 1 in 3 in patients requiring intensive care depending on whether surveillance imaging for asymptomatic venous thromboembolism (VTE) is performed.
 <xref rid="bib0005" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>5</sup>
 </xref>
 <sup>,</sup>
 <xref rid="bib0007" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>7</sup>
 </xref>
 <sup>,</sup>
 <xref rid="bib0008" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>8</sup>
 </xref> Due to this pronounced hypercoagulable state, attention has focused on antithrombotic treatment to reduce morbidity and mortality in COVID-19. Retrospective analyses suggest lower mortality rates for hospitalized patients with COVID-19 who received prophylactic anticoagulation, compared to those who did not.
 <xref rid="bib0009" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>9</sup>
 </xref>
 <sup>,</sup>
 <xref rid="bib0010" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>10</sup>
 </xref> Preliminary reports from ongoing prospective trials suggest improved outcomes with therapeutic heparin in moderately ill,
 <xref rid="bib0011" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>11</sup>
 </xref> but not in critically ill,
 <xref rid="bib0012" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>12</sup>
 </xref> adults hospitalized with COVID-19. Current expert guidance includes prophylactic-dose anticoagulant treatment to decrease the risk of thrombotic complications in hospitalized patients with COVID-19.
 <xref rid="bib0013" ref-type="bibr">13.</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib0014" ref-type="bibr">14.</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib0015" ref-type="bibr">15.</xref>
</p>
