<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="para0005">While acknowledging the potential benefit of post-hospitalization thromboprophylaxis, expert opinion and guidance statements have disagreed on the need for primary thromboprophylaxis in outpatients with COVID-19 with thrombotic risk factors.
 <xref rid="bib0016" ref-type="bibr">16.</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib0017" ref-type="bibr">17.</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib0018" ref-type="bibr">18.</xref> The underlying mechanisms of the hypercoagulable state in patients with COVID-19 are not clear.
 <xref rid="bib0017" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>17</sup>
 </xref> A key question is: when in the course of SARS-Co-V-2 infection does thrombotic risk reach a critical, yet modifiable point? There are data supporting activated thrombin as a key pathogenetic driver of pulmonary compromise in COVID-19. Fibrinogen and D-dimer concentrations are often already elevated at the time of hospital admission,
 <xref rid="bib0004" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>4</sup>
 </xref>
 <sup>,</sup>
 <xref rid="bib0019" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>19</sup>
 </xref> and elevated D-dimer concentrations are found in almost half of hospitalized patients with nonsevere disease.
 <xref rid="bib0020" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>20</sup>
 </xref> Additionally, up to half of venous thromboembolic events in hospitalized patients in one series were diagnosed within the first 24 hours of admission.
 <xref rid="bib0008" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>8</sup>
 </xref> We hypothesize that the increased risk of thrombotic events, attributable to a thrombotic-inflammatory status associated with reduced mobility, begins prior to severe clinical manifestations of COVID-19, and includes patients who do not require hospitalization. Multiple autopsy series have reported venous thromboembolism and widespread pulmonary microthrombi in decedents with COVID-19,
 <xref rid="bib0021" ref-type="bibr">21.</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib0022" ref-type="bibr">22.</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib0023" ref-type="bibr">23.</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib0024" ref-type="bibr">24.</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib0025" ref-type="bibr">25.</xref>, 
 <xref rid="bib0026" ref-type="bibr">26.</xref> suggesting a role of direct endothelial injury in the development of COVID-19 pulmonary manifestations (
 <xref rid="fig0001" ref-type="fig">Figure 1</xref> ). Therefore, we hypothesize that intervening to decrease thrombotic risk earlier in the course of COVID-19, especially in patients with known risk factors for thrombosis, will significantly decrease thrombotic complications and reduce disease progression to the point where hospitalization could be avoided.
</p>
