<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Chronic kidney disease (CKD) should be acknowledged twice in the context of an allo-HSCT clinical study design. Decline in renal function is common among post-HSCT patients and may progress into CKD. Incidence rates of CKD among studies are highly variable, with values ranging from 13% to 66%.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="bibr38-1534735418756736" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>,
  <xref rid="bibr39-1534735418756736" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>
 </sup> The main implication of post-HSCT renal damage is the due diligence that should be exercised when administering herbal medicine. Basic research demonstrates that 
 <italic>Rehmannia glutinosa</italic> and the combination of 
 <italic>Astragalus membranaceus</italic> and 
 <italic>Angelica sinensis</italic>—constituents of SYT—may actually exert a renoprotective effect. However, until further evidence is collected, it is impossible to rule out potentially deleterious drug interactions.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="bibr40-1534735418756736" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>,
  <xref rid="bibr41-1534735418756736" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>
 </sup> In our preliminary study, we determined that the administration of SYT to patients would be reassessed in cases where the glomerular filtration rate dropped below 50 mL/min/1.73 m
 <sup>2</sup> or if serum creatinine levels rose to double that of baseline. Adequate consideration should also be given to patients with pretransplantation kidney disorders. Abnormal renal function is considered a major risk factor for HSCT. However, collective experience and practices among institutions may strongly vary.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="bibr42-1534735418756736" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>,
  <xref rid="bibr43-1534735418756736" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>
 </sup> Although renal function does not appear in the above-mentioned inclusion/exclusion criteria, these should be explicitly defined in cooperation with the oncologists participating in the trial, in order to avoid the occurrence of selection bias and survivorship bias.
</p>
