<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par30">With the combination with famitinib, 75% of patients received three cycles of concurrent cisplatin, which showed slightly higher rates of compliance with cisplatin during radiation compared with those recorded in the Intergroup 0099 trial (63%) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>], Singapore trial (71%) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>], and Hong Kong NPC-9901 trial (52%) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>]. The 3-year PFS and DMFS were 70% and 75% for these local advanced NPC patients. At the single famitinib stage, most common famitinib-related toxicities were grade I–II, and fewer side effects were noted in this study in terms of leukopenia, neutropenia, thrombocytopenia, and hypertension compared with previously published incidence rates of advanced solid malignancy refractory to standard therapy [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>]. This is likely because the patients enrolled in this study had not received any previous treatment, and were in better general health. A meta-analysis of VEGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitors in 23 trials showed that the incidence of bleeding events was 16.7% [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref>]. Nevertheless, the incidence of haemorrhage in our study was only 10%, which was much lower than the results of Hui et al., who reported high incidence rates of haemorrhage (64.3%) for recurrent or metastatic NPC patients [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>]. The incidence of hypertension in this trial was 50%, which was similar to the incidence of hypertension (42.9%) for sunitinib administered to recurrent or metastatic NPC patients [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>] and was significantly less than that for sunitinib (92%) in renal cell carcinoma [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR44">44</xref>]. The most common grade 3–4 adverse events were leukopenia (90%), neutropenia (55%), radiation mucositis (20%), and thrombopenia (20%). The rates of grade 3–4 toxicity of the bone marrow in this trial were higher than in other trials during CCRT in patients with NPC, which were recorded as 12.6%–32% [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>] for leukopenia and 13.2% [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>] for neutropenia. We considered that famitinib plus CCRT increased the toxicities of the bone marrow, which, however, were tolerable. Grade 3–4 radiation mucositis was found in 20%, which compares favourably to the rates recorded in the Hong Kong NPC-9901 trial (62%) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>] and the Singapore trial (48.1%) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>] as well as with the addition of cetuximab or bevacizumab to standard chemoradiation (77%–87%) [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref>].
</p>
