<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Autologous-HSCT is a promising new therapy for aggressive MS, which can abrogate clinical relapses and stabilize brain MRI lesions. The reconstituting immune system has a lesser neuroinflammatory capacity in post-aHSCT samples. This suggests that changes had occurred following treatment, which decrease disease progression. The data presented here demonstrate that NK cells reconstitute rapidly following aHSCT, while CD4
 <sup>+</sup> T cells remained below BL for up to 21 months. One explanation for functional suppression of CD4 T cells could be that conventional regulatory T cells (CD3
 <sup>+</sup> CD4
 <sup>+</sup> FoxP3
 <sup>+</sup> CD25
 <sup>+</sup> CD127
 <sup>−</sup>) that were shown to rapidly reconstitute following a non-ablative aHSCT in MS were suppressing CD4 T cells (
 <xref rid="B46" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>). However, in the Canadian ablative cohort, regulatory T cells were only transiently increased in MS patients after aHSCT, and returned to BL by 9 months post-treatment (
 <xref rid="B40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>). Another possibility is that thymic atrophy accounts for the low Th cell counts. However, the re-emergence of recent thymic emigrant naive T cells, and the broad clonal diversity that developed in MS patients who underwent aHSCT, suggests that the thymus (which exhibits decreased function early after chemotherapy) is still sufficient to facilitate T cell maturation and selection (
 <xref rid="B40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B47" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>). In this study, we tested the hypothesis that NK cells were playing a regulatory role in the reconstituting immune system. NK cells correlated inversely with the change in Th17 cells, and depleting NK cells from aHSCT samples resulted in a higher proportion of Th17 cells. Th1 cells were also inhibited by NK cells, albeit to a lesser extent than Th17 cells. These results indicate that NK cells reconstitute rapidly, possibly due to incomplete ablation or presence of NK cells in the graft, following aHSCT and suppress the re-emergence of Th17 cells.
</p>
