<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract>
 <title>Abstract</title>
 <sec sec-type="background">
  <title>Background:</title>
  <p>The incidence of malnutrition in patients with esophageal cancer is high, which seriously affects the therapeutic effect and quality of life. Oral nutritional supplement is the first choice of nutritional support recommended by current guidelines, which can supplement the lack of energy and protein in patients with esophageal cancer, improve nutritional status and improve the quality of life, but there are few clinical studies. Therefore, the purpose of this randomized controlled trial is to evaluate the effect of oral nutritional supplement therapy on nutritional status and quality of life in patients with esophageal cancer treated undergoing radiotherapy and chemotherapy.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec sec-type="methods">
  <title>Methods:</title>
  <p>This is a prospective randomized controlled trial to study the effects of oral nutritional supplement therapy on nutritional status and quality of life in patients with esophageal cancer undergoing radiotherapy and chemotherapy. This study is approved by the Clinical Research Society of our hospital. Patients will be randomly divided into ONS group and traditional diet group. The nutritional status, quality of life score and adverse reactions will be observed before and after radiotherapy and chemotherapy. The data will be analyzed by SPSS 16.0.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec sec-type="discussion">
  <title>Discussion:</title>
  <p>This study will evaluate the effect of oral nutritional supplement therapy on nutritional status and quality of life of patients with esophageal cancer undergoing radiotherapy and chemotherapy. The results of this experiment will establish clinical evidence for the application of oral nutritional supplement therapy in patients with esophageal cancer undergoing radiotherapy and chemotherapy.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>OSF Registration number:</title>
  <p>DOI 10.17605/OSF.IO/9ZW34.</p>
 </sec>
</abstract>
