<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>CCS is a rare stromal soft tissue tumor similar to melanoma and soft tissue sarcoma but has a different genetic history. The clinical features of CCS lack specificity, which often manifests as slow painless local growth of the mass, and patients can experience local pain, itching, movement restrictions, easy postoperative recurrence, or metastasis (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>). CT and MRI have limited diagnostic value for CCS, and CCS is confirmed by biopsy pathology and IHC staining; its variants often need molecular testing. The classic histological feature of soft tissue CCS is a small cluster of polygonal cells and spindle cells, characterized by hyaline to slightly basophilic cytoplasm and vesicular nuclei with prominent nucleoli separated by fine fibers (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>). Both CCS and malignant melanoma originate from melanocyte differentiation, so they are positive for common melanocyte markers such as S-100, HMB-45, MelanA, and NKI/C3 (
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>). We cannot easily distinguish them by immunohistochemistry. Hence, the use of fluorescence 
 <italic>in situ</italic> hybridization or reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) is essential for diagnosing CCS and distinguishing CCS from primary and metastatic melanoma (
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>). The cytogenetic feature of CCS is t (12; 22) (q13; q12), resulting in a chimeric EWSR1/ATF1 gene in which the EWS 3' terminus at 22q is replaced by the ATF1 3' terminus at 12q. Therefore, EWSR1/ATF1 can be used as a marker to distinguish CCS from melanoma (
 <xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>). In this case, NGS was a feasible method to help pathologically diagnose CCS as the diagnosis was difficult to determine after biopsy and immunohistochemistry. The EWSR1-ATF1 fusion also supported the diagnosis of pulmonary CCS.
</p>
