<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Various preclinical data support the therapeutic potential of transplantation with mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) for treating various intractable neonatal disorders including bronchopulmonary dysplasia (BPD) 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0011" ref-type="ref">11</xref>, 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0012" ref-type="ref">12</xref>, 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0013" ref-type="ref">13</xref>, 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0014" ref-type="ref">14</xref> and hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy (HIE) 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0015" ref-type="ref">15</xref>. Human umbilical cord blood (UCB) is a promising source of MSCs. In comparison to adult tissue‐derived MSCs, its advantages include easier extraction, lower immunogenicity 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0016" ref-type="ref">16</xref>, higher in vitro proliferation capacity 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0017" ref-type="ref">17</xref>, 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0018" ref-type="ref">18</xref>, and better in vivo therapeutic efficacy 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0019" ref-type="ref">19</xref>. Recently, we have shown that xenotransplantation of human UCB‐derived MSCs significantly attenuates brain injury and the progress of PHH after severe IVH in immunocompetent newborn rats 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0015" ref-type="ref">15</xref>, 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0020" ref-type="ref">20</xref>, 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0021" ref-type="ref">21</xref>. Furthermore, we have observed that treatment of BPD in premature infants with intratracheal transplantation of allogeneic human UCB‐derived MSCs is safe, feasible, and not associated with adverse respiratory, growth, or neurodevelopmental effects 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0022" ref-type="ref">22</xref>. This was confirmed by follow‐up of the same infants for up to 2 years of corrected age (CA) 
 <xref rid="sct312351-bib-0023" ref-type="ref">23</xref>. Collectively, these findings suggest that the transplantation of allogeneic human UCB‐derived MSCs may be a novel and promising therapeutic modality for treating severe IVH in premature infants. However, the safety of this approach has not yet been tested in a clinical setting. Here, we report a phase I dose‐escalating clinical study assessing the safety and feasibility of intraventricular transplantation of human UCB‐derived MSCs into premature infants with severe IVH.
</p>
