<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par17">
 <list list-type="order">
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par18">Aged between 18 and 75 years;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par19">Patients who were histologically diagnosed with gastric adenocarcinoma (including gastroesophageal junction adenocarcinoma), stage III by pathological examination (based on the eighth edition of the AJCC Cancer Staging Manual);</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par20">Patients are able to provide reports of disease-related pathological diagnosis.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par21">Patients underwent D2 radical resection within 6 weeks prior to random enrollment and achieved R0 resection;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par22">Patients are able to receive chemotherapy within 7 days after randomization.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par23">The patient had not previously received anti-tumor treatment (including systemic chemotherapy and local radiotherapy), except for surgery of the primary lesions;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par24">ECOG status score 0 or 1;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par25">Hematological examination shows no obvious signs of hematological disease, absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥1.5× 10
    <sup>9</sup>/L, platelet count ≥100× 10
    <sup>9</sup> /L, hemoglobin (Hb) ≥90 g/L, white blood cells (WBC) ≥3.0× 10
    <sup>9</sup>/L, and no bleeding tendency before enrollment;
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par26">Liver function tests: alanine aminotransferase (ALT), aspartate aminotransferase (AST), and alkaline phosphatase (ALP) are all ≤2.5 × the upper limit of normal (ULN), and serum bilirubin ≤1.5 × ULN. For patients with Gilbert's disease, serum bilirubin is ≤3 × ULN.</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par27">Renal function test: serum creatinine (Cr) ≤1.5 × ULN or creatinine clearance &gt; 60 ml/min (calculated according to the Cockroft-Gault equation);</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <p id="Par28">Patients can understand the study; patients and/or legal representatives voluntarily agree to participate in this study and signed the informed consent.</p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
