<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par20">There is a need for new ways to inform and involve patients, hence there is a strong call for digitalized tools to be used in healthcare. To be effective, however, digital tools must be developed based on research that also follows quality standards [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>]. More and more, patients request they are provided information through videos, accessible for later review at home and for sharing with loved ones, as many patients travel substantial distances to receive care [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>]. Furthermore, videos and audio-visual materials have proven to be successful communication tools and the format also supports the distribution and sharing of information with others [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>]. Virtual reality (VR) has the inherent potential to be interactive because its content is generated in real time, not ahead of time, which makes the experience even more immersive [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>]. Specifically, VR differs from other forms of media because it induces the sense of "presence”, i.e., the feeling of "being there” inside the virtual experience produced by the technology [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>]. VR-interventions for cancer patients were investigated in a meta-analysis by Zeng et al. [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>], showing its effects on improved learning through cognitive training and significantly decreased fatigue. A recent study indicated that a virtual reality education for breast cancer patients could improve RT knowledge and perhaps decrease anxiety as well as was appreciated by the patients [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>]. Moreover, virtual reality radiotherapy educational program could have a positive effect on patients prior to their initial RT session by providing them with useful content and decreasing their anxiety about the process, thus increasing the patient RT comprehension [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>].
</p>
