<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>All operations were performed by one chief surgeon of foot and ankle surgery, and his assistants were attending surgeons. And the chief surgeon has more than 50 cases of flatfoot orthopedic surgery experience for adults or children. The surgery was performed under the epidural anesthesia. The thigh tourniquet was used. Firstly, the Silverskold test was performed. For gastrocnemius release, the posterior-medial incision at the lower middle calf was used, ~2–3 cm. The gastrocnemius tendon-abdominal joint was exposed, followed by cutting off the tendon part sharply to make the ankle dorsiflexion &gt;10° when the knee was in extension. Attention should be taken to protect the sural nerve. For Achilles tendon lengthening, a 4 cm medial incision was made and the "
 <italic>Z</italic>-shape” lengthening was performed to make the ankle dorsiflexion &gt; 15° when the knee was in fully extension. Then the subtalar arthroereisis was performed. The hip on the ipsilateral side was uplifted by sandbag to avoid excessive external rotation of the foot, conducive to the exposure of the sinus tarsi. A longitudinal 2 cm incision was made under the lateral malleolus tip, at the body surface projection of sinus tarsi. Pay attention to protect the branches of the superficial nerve and avoid damage to the talus and calcaneus's interosseous ligament. Followed cutting the fascia layer, the phalangeal extensor muscles were pulled distally. The stripper was inserted into the tarsal sinus along the talar neck after the full exposure of the tarsal sinus. The talus head was raised upward and rearward to restore its physiological position and correct the pronation of the hindfoot (
 <xref rid="B24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>). A guidewire was inserted into the tarsal sinus in the direction of the tunnel. After confirming the guidewire position with C-arm, the trial model was plugged along the guidewire from small to large. The weight-bearing AP, lateral, and calcaneal axial perspectives were taken after each implantation to evaluate the positional relationship of the mid-hind foot bones, joint motion and the implant position until the appropriate size was determined. If the size is too small, the deformity correction is not sufficient, and the implantation loosening can occur. If the size is too large, the deformity is overcorrected, and it may result in persistent pain of the tarsal sinus. The lateral edge of the implant should overlap with the talus's lateral edge, but the medial edge of the implant should not exceed the midline of the talus neck (
 <xref rid="B25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>). Satisfactory corrections: the talus axis is almost consistent with the first metatarsal axis in lateral film (&lt;5°).
</p>
