<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par18">In the field of MM, the approval of novel agents has significantly advanced and improved the range of therapeutic options and the clinical outcome. Median survival times of more than 4 years have been achieved, leading to a paradigm shift in treatment, also for non-transplant, elderly patients (reviewed in [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>]). However, these results are mainly derived from clinical trials enrolling a highly selected patient population. Are the results conferrable to the patients in routine care? For non-transplant patients, the VISTA trial reported a median OS of 56.4 months for patients receiving VMP [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>], and the FIRST trial reported a median OS of 48.5 months for patients treated in the MPT arm [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>]. In our cohort, median OS was 52.0 months with 42% of the patients receiving VMP. While the survival data for the potentially trial-eligible patients in our analysis (median OS 58.6 months) were similar to the survival times reported in these phase III clinical trials, trial-ineligible patients had inferior outcomes (median OS 34.2 months) despite similar first-line treatment and a similar proportion of patients receiving second-line treatment (52 vs. 58%). Related findings of inferior outcomes for patients not fulfilling the criteria for trial eligibility have been reported for other malignancies like metastatic colorectal cancer [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>] or metastatic renal cell carcinoma [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]. The difference in survival times between potentially trial-eligible and -ineligible patients appeared smaller when DSS was analysed, although these data have to be considered preliminary due to the small number of events. This might implicate that not only the malignancy but also other factors like the comorbidities influence the survival of trial-ineligible patients. Aside from specific disease characteristics, there are multiple known prognostic factors for not only survival in patients with MM: foremost age but also performance status and prevalence of comorbidities like renal or lung disease [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>–
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>]. The frailty score of the International Myeloma Working Group predicting survival and toxicities is based on age, comorbidities, as well as cognitive and physical conditions [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>], and the revised Myeloma Comorbidity Index incorporates renal, lung, and Karnofsky performance status impairment, frailty, and age as significant risks for OS [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>].
</p>
