<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>K.Y. has received research funding from AbbVie, ARIAD Pharmaceuticals, Celgene, Chugai, Eisai, Gilead Sciences, MSD, Novartis, Ono, Solasia Pharma, and Takeda. K.To. has received research funding from Abbvie, Ono, Eisai, GlaxoSmithKline, Janssen Celgene, Chugai, Pharmaceuticals, Mundipharma, Novartis, Pharmaceutical, SERVIER, and Takeda; and honoraria from Celgene, Chugai, Eisai, HUYA, Bioscience, Janssen Pharmaceuticals, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Mundipharma, Ono Pharmaceutical, Takeda, and Zenyaku Kogyo; and advisory remuneration from Celgene. K.A. has received research funding from KyowaHakko‐Kirin and Takeda. T.S. has received honoraria from KyowaHakko‐Kirin and Takeda. N.Ta. has received honoraria from Takeda. I.H. has received honoraria from Bristol‐Meyers‐Squibb and Celgene; and research funding from Bristol‐Meyers‐Squibb, KyowaHakko‐Kirn, and Chugai. H.N. has received honoraria from Takeda, Chugai Pharma, and Mundipharma; and research funding from Bayer Yakuhin, Takeda, Abbvie, Chugai Pharma, Janssen, Mundipharma, Celgene, AstraZeneca, Ono, Bristol‐Myers‐Squibb, Gilead Sciences, and Otsuka. K.U. has received research funding from Astellas, Kyowahakko‐Kirin, and Daiichi Sankyo; and honoraria from Novartis. K. Ohya received research funding from Ono Pharmaceutical, Chugai, Bristol‐Meyers‐Squibb, Kyowahakko‐Kirin, and Janssen; and honoraria from Novartis and Celgene. D.M. has received honoraria from Takeda, Janssen, Eisai, Biomedis International, Celgene, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Fujifilm, Ono Pharmaceutical, Mundipharma International, Chugai Pharma, MSD, and Zenyaku Kogyo; and research funding from Takeda, Janssen, Eisai, Biomedis International, Celgene, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Fujifilm, Ono Pharmaceutical, Mundipharma International, Chugai Pharma, MSD, Zenyaku Kogyo, GlaxoSmithKline, Abbvie, Astellas Pharma, Amgen Astellas, BioPharma, Otsuka, Novartis, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Pfizer, Solasia Pharma, and AstraZeneca. S.Na. has received research funding from Chugai and Kyowahakko‐Kirin. T.H. has received advisory remuneration from SymBio. K.Tu has received research funding from Chugai Pharma, Mundipharma, Celgene, and Takeda. M.O., Y.Mo., M.W., N.U., M.K., H.G., M.T., K.No., N.Tsu., N.F., Y.Y., K.Ohni., K.Mi, K.S., H.K., N.K., T.U., K.K., K. Ohma. and Y.Ma. have no conflicts of interest to declare.</p>
