<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ack>
 <p>The authors would like to acknowledge all the patients who participated in this study as well as additional investigators of the BTH1677 NSCLC Study Team including Prof. Martin Wolf, MD, Clinic Kassel GmbH, Medical Clinic IV, Clinic for Haematology and Oncology, Germany; Christian Schumann, MD, Universitätsklinikum Ulm, Ulm, Germany; J. Thaddeus Beck, MD, Highlands Oncology Group, Rogers, AR, USA; Wolfgang Schütte, MD, Hospital Martha-Maria, Halle Dölau, Clinic for Internal Medicine II, Halle (Saale), Germany; Jens Kollmeier, MD, Helios Clinic Emil von Behring, Lung Clinic Heckeshorn, Specialist Department 1: Clinic for Pneumology, Pneumological Oncology, Berlin, Germany; Prof. Frank Griesinger, MD, Pius-Hospital Oldenburg, Centre of Radiotherapy and Medical Oncology, Dept. Medical Oncology, Oldenburg, Germany; Nashat Gabrail, MD, Gabrail Cancer Center – Canton, Canton, OH, USA; Athanassios Argiris, MD, University of Texas Health Science Center at San Antonio Cancer Therapy and Research Center, San Antonio, TX, USA; Martin Sebastian, MD, Clinic of Johannes Gutenberg University of Mainz, III. Medical Clinic, Mainz, Germany; Nandagopal Vrindavanam, MD, Signal Point Clinical Research Center, LLC, Middletown, OH, USA; Satish Shah, MD, Gettysburg Cancer Center, Gettysburg, PA, USA; Veena Charu, MD, Pacific Medical Center, Anaheim, CA, USA; Benjamin George, MD, San Antonio Military Medical Center, Ft. Sam Houston, TX, USA; Vincent Hansen, MD, Northern Utah Associates, Ogden, UT, USA; Neil Senzer, MD, Mary Crowley Medical Research Center, Dallas, TX, USA; David Zenk, MD, Iowa Blood and Cancer Care, Medical Office Plaza, Cedar Rapids, IA, USA. The authors would also like to acknowledge former Biothera Pharmaceuticals, Inc. employees Ada Braun, MD, PhD and Corina Taitt, MD for assistance in closing the study, data cleaning, and data analysis as well as current Biothera Pharmaceuticals, Inc. employees Mable Ma, PhD for data review and Blaine Rathmann, BS and Katie Ertelt, BS for assistance in assaying beta glucan levels in serum samples. Also acknowledged are Susan Goebel for assistance in statistical programming, VirtualScopics, Inc. for blinded central radiology reviews and analysis, and Chastity Bradley, PhD and Molly Nixon, PhD of Synchrogenix for medical writing assistance.</p>
 <sec id="FPar1">
  <title>Funding</title>
  <p id="Par76">This work was supported by Biothera Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="FPar2">
  <title>Availability of data and materials</title>
  <p id="Par77">At this time, Biothera does not provide access to individual patient data due to the study protocol's requirements for patient privacy and confidentiality. Only regulatory authorities and Biothera may have access to individual patient data. All data generated (by treatment group) or analyzed during this study are included in this published article.</p>
 </sec>
</ack>
