<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract id="Abs1">
 <title>Summary</title>
 <p id="Par1">
  <italic>Background</italic> CD37 is expressed on B-cell lymphoid malignancies, thus making it an attractive candidate for targeted therapy in non-Hodgkin lymphoma (NHL). IMGN529 is an antibody-drug conjugate comprising a CD37-binding antibody linked to the maytansinoid DM1, a potent anti-mitotic agent. 
  <italic>Methods</italic> This first-in-human, phase 1 trial recruited adult patients with relapsed or refractory B-cell NHL. The primary objective was to determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) and recommended phase 2 dose. Secondary objectives were to evaluate safety, pharmacokinetics, and preliminary clinical activity. IMGN529 was administered intravenously once every 3 weeks, and dosed using a conventional 3 + 3 dose-escalation design. 
  <italic>Results</italic> Forty-nine patients were treated at doses escalating from 0.1 to 1.8 mg/kg. Dose limiting toxicities occurred in eight patients and included peripheral neuropathy, febrile neutropenia, neutropenia, and thrombocytopenia. The most frequent treatment-emergent adverse events were fatigue (39%), neutropenia, pyrexia, and thrombocytopenia (each 37%). Adverse events led to treatment discontinuation in 10 patients (20%). Eight patients (16%) had treatment-related serious adverse events, the most common being grade 3 febrile neutropenia. The MTD (with growth factor support) was 1.4 mg/kg every 3 weeks. IMGN529 plasma exposure increased monotonically with dose and was consistent with target-mediated drug disposition. Five (13%) of 39 response-evaluable patients achieved an objective response (one complete response and four partial responses), four of which occurred in the subgroup of patients with diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. 
  <italic>Conclusions</italic> The manageable safety profile of IMGN529 and preliminary evidence of activity, particularly in DLBCL patients, support the continued development of this novel CD37-targeting agent.
 </p>
 <sec>
  <title>Electronic supplementary material</title>
  <p>The online version of this article (10.1007/s10637-018-0570-4) contains supplementary material, which is available to authorized users.</p>
 </sec>
</abstract>
