<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<list list-type="bullet">
 <list-item>
  <p>
   <bold>Education:</bold> This part consists of a broad range of educational content during hospitalization and after discharge including psychological, general exercise, medical and health videos and texts about COVID-19 patients. The educational material required for COVID-19 patients will be provided using valid educational resources and experts' consensus.
  </p>
  <p>To improve the content in later versions of the software, at the end of each educational medium, the patient will be asked to rate the content and help us increase the quality of services.</p>
 </list-item>
 <list-item>
  <p>
   <bold>Contacting Care Providers:</bold> This part serves the following functions:
  </p>
  <list list-type="order">
   <list-item>
    <p>Support by other medical staff besides the attending physicians such as psychologists who cannot be physically present in the clinic for safety matters.</p>
   </list-item>
   <list-item>
    <p>Patient-physician communication via software in hours later than daily visits. Besides filling out an improvement checklist, the patient can write a text about personal queries and concerns.</p>
   </list-item>
   <list-item>
    <p>Physician's (or any other therapist's) feedback for patient. Upon seeing the patient's text, the therapist can send a text-based or audio message as the response (to relieve the patient).</p>
    <p>Contacting care providers will be disabled at the end of the study (2 weeks after discharge).</p>
   </list-item>
  </list>
 </list-item>
 <list-item>
  <p>
   <bold>Symptoms Self-report:</bold> SarveDigital will help COVID-19 patients record their symptoms and, thus, their physician will be able to monitor and control their condition from a distance. Patients will be asked to enter their health symptoms such as fever, sore throat, dry cough, difficulty breathing or the shortness of breath, and loss of taste or smell at least three times a week into the application. Each symptom will be rated on a 4-point scale (e.g., “no fever,” “mild fever,” “moderate fever,” and “high fever”).
  </p>
  <p>These data will automatically be sent to the physicians' portal so that the physician will be aware of the patient's health status. It should be noted that the attending physician and the psychologist assigned will be able to access physicians' portal via their mobile phone with a username and password. This will ensure the privacy and security of the patient's information and the relevant classified information (
   <xref rid="B26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>).
  </p>
 </list-item>
 <list-item>
  <p>
   <bold>Care Providers' Biography:</bold> This part introduces the key information about the attending physician and psychologist who will communicate with the patient. The aim is to increase the trust the patient places in them to easily share concerns, queries and else.
  </p>
 </list-item>
</list>
