<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>DCP-001 expresses a range of shared TAAs and HLA haplotypes that together cover more than 70% of the Caucasian population. It presents a highly potent, standardized and fully scalable vaccine platform that is widely applicable. Here, data of a phase-I trial of DCP-001 vaccination in elderly AML patients in CR1/CR2 or with smoldering disease are presented. The vaccine proved safe and a treatment regimen of four biweekly i.d. DCP-001 injections was feasible, thus meeting the primary objectives of the study. The obtained results further suggest that in patients with demonstrable immune competence and maintained peripheral T cell rates, DCP-001 can induce a multi-functional immune response to the vaccine, its AML progenitors, common shared leukemia-associated antigens (LAA), as well as to antigens in autologous leukemic blasts. Although the study size is too small to draw definitive conclusions, the observed immune responses may have translated into a long-term clinical benefit in those patients who were in CR at the time of vaccination, and therefore, would have been in a less immune-suppressed state. Typically, the inclusion criteria employed in this trial would select for patients with an average life expectancy of 3–6 months [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref>]. It is, therefore, remarkable that 6 of the 12 enrolled patients in this trial survived for more than 6 months after start of treatment (Fig. 
 <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>, median overall survival 36 months), with one patient still alive at the time of writing. Clearly, the small number of patients enrolled in this trial with as primary endpoint safety and feasibility does not allow for firm conclusions with regards to clinical outcome. As such, the results from this trial should be regarded as hypothesis generating. The hypothesis that DCP-001 induces immune responses against the patient’s leukemic blasts, translating into clinical benefit in immune competent patients who are in CR at the time of vaccination, will now be investigated in a multi-center randomized phase II trial in AML patients in CR1.
</p>
