<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par63">As a secondary objective, DCP-001-induced immune responses were assessed. Allogeneic DC vaccines have been shown to induce and support antitumor immunity in part through generation of allo-response-induced pro-inflammatory conditions conducive to Th1 skewing and in part through the direct priming of tumor-reactive or cross-reactive T cells [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>]. The observed induction of DTH responses against the vaccine and increased post-vaccination DTH reactivity in five of the tested patients are in line with the induction and boosting of systemic Th1 responses. Both CD4 and activated (based on a rise in Granzyme B and TIA expression) CD8 T cell responses were induced, as judged by immunohistochemistry analyses of biopsies taken from the DTH site. Results from in vitro proliferation assays with pre- and post-vaccination T cells in response to DCP-001 were in line with these observations. Vaccination-induced proliferative responses were noted upon in vitro restimulation in six out of nine patients, which may have included responses to both allogeneic and tumor-associated antigens. These DCP-001-induced T cell responses were marked by increased release of Th1 cytokines, either alone or combined with the release of Th2 and Th17 cytokines. The observation of CD8
 <sup>+</sup> T cell proliferative responses to DCP-001 progenitors in five patients further indicated the induction of effector T cells able to respond to leukemic blasts lacking high levels of costimulatory molecules. Vaccination-induced or enhanced T cell responses to WT-1, PRAME, NY-ESO-1, and MAGE-A3 were observed in 4 out of 8 evaluable patients in this study. Whereas WT-1 and PRAME are expressed by DCP-001, NY-ESO-1 and MAGE-A3 are not. This suggests that T cell responses may have been both directly primed or re-stimulated by DCP-001 (or after cross-presentation of its contents), or indirectly through bystander activation and/or epitope spreading. Overall, these results demonstrate the development of cell-mediated immune responses to vaccination at all doses tested. Finally, also induction of humoral responses were observed to DCP-001, its progenitors and importantly, also to autologous leukemic blasts. The latter unequivocally demonstrates the induction of immunity against autologous AML blasts by the allogeneic DCP-001.
</p>
