<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>This patient's clinical manifestations were anemia, hemorrhage, diabetes, hyperopia, astigmatism, megaloblastic anemia with ringed sideroblasts, and severe thrombocytopenia, which are the main symptoms of TRMA. Molecular genetics revealed the c.515G&gt;A(p.G 172D) homozygous mutation in 
 <italic>SLC19A2</italic>. Sanger sequencing and gene chip proved that the disease was caused by maternal UPD. Thiamine was effective. Thus, the patient was diagnosed with TRMA. Four TRMA patients have been reported to have anemia and diabetes (
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>–
 <xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>). Among them, two were siblings (
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>), whose gene detections both showed C.1409insT homozygous mutation of Gene 
 <italic>SLC19A2</italic>. The other two were unrelated by blood, one of which had paternal c.484 C&gt;T and maternal c.1001 G&gt;A compound heterozygous mutation of 
 <italic>SLC19A2</italic> (
 <xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>), and the other was complicated with eye diseases (
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>). All 4 patients presented mild/moderate anemia. Borgna-Pignatti et al. (
 <xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>) and Labay et al. (
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>) reported, respectively, 2 patients (who were cousins) in a family with the c.515G&gt;A (p.G 172D) mutation in 
 <italic>SLC19A2</italic>. Clinical manifestations were anemia (mild-to-moderate), diabetes, deafness, growth and development retardation, eye diseases, and megaloblasts and ringed sideroblasts in the bone marrow. After 2 weeks of thiamine treatment, their hemocytes returned to normal, and their insulin dosage was reduced (
 <xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>). The patient reported here presented the clinical manifestations of severe anemia and thrombocytopenia, but no deafness, growth and development retardation, or eye diseases. Therefore, this patient was not completely identical to the other patients with a genetic variation at this site. It could be due to racial differences, but the exact reason is unknown. The gene chip assay showed that the patient had a homozygosis zone of 248.31 Mb in ROH (1p36.33q44), inherited from her mother. It was speculated that this case was induced by maternal UPD involved c.515G&gt;A (p.G 172D) homozygous mutation of 
 <italic>SLC19A2</italic>. The combined application of high-throughput sequencing, first-generation sequencing, and gene chip detection enabled the complete and accurate diagnosis of TRMA and the identification of its pathogenesis. Cytological function verification testing showed that the c.515G&gt;A (p.G 172D) mutation of 
 <italic>SLC19A2</italic> might cause the misfolding of the THTR-1 protein that cannot then be completely glycosylated and locate to the target cell membrane, failing to transport thiamine and impaired thiamine absorption (
 <xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>).
</p>
