<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Therefore, it was speculated that the DNA damage in the peripheral lymphocytes in this patient might be caused by intracellular thiamine deficiency due to the mutation of 
 <italic>SLC19A2</italic> in lymphocytes. Several UPD cases were reported regarding ROH (1p36.33q44), all of which were accompanied by clinical chromosome 1 abnormalities. In dense osteogenesis imperfecta, the primary gene involved is CTSK, and the patients mainly present anterior fontanelle closure delay, multiple fractures, short stature, osteosclerosis, and acroosteolysis (
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>). A case with speckled dyschondroplasia had changes in the GNPAT gene and mainly presented proximal long bone shortening, cataract, abnormal facial appearance, development retardation, and cerebellar atrophy (
 <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>). According to reports of cases with the Hutchinson-Gilford progeria syndrome, the primarily involved gene is LMNA, and the patients mainly present short stature, joint degeneration, and atherosis (
 <xref rid="B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>). In patients with Zellweger syndrome, the primarily involved gene is PEX1, and the patients mainly present hypotonia, hepatic enlargement, abnormal facial bone development, epilepsy, and craniofacial abnormalities (
 <xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>). Patriarchal sex single diploid involving A III genes results in glycogen III glycogen storage disease and severe dysplasia (
 <xref rid="B20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>). The case reported here, induced by UPD in ROH (1p36.33q44), developed none of the clinical manifestations described above. Unlike the other cases, the major gene involved in this case was 
 <italic>SLC19A2</italic>, which is the first UDP report in 
 <italic>SLC19A2</italic>, causing TRMA. Unlike typical TRMA, the patient reported here had severe thrombocytopenia, no deafness, growth retardation, no heart disease, and no neurological disease. The patient had no deafness, which might be because she was young, or it might be a new feature of UPD-induced c.515G&gt;A(p.G172D) mutation of 
 <italic>SLC19A2</italic>. After 10 days of oral thiamine, the Hb and PLT levels returned to normal, the reticulocytes increased, and the requirement for insulin for blood glucose control could be decreased. The treatment was effective.
</p>
