<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Concurrently with foaling and behavior observations, we evaluated and compared potential adverse side-effects of treatment on injection-site reactions, body condition, success of existing pregnancy, and neonatal survival in treated and control mares. We made assessments of these potential side-effects monthly during the primary foaling season and opportunistically for the remainder of the year. We observed each mare for the presence or absence of visible lesions, swellings, or discharge at the injection site. In addition, we documented evidence of lameness (e.g. limping, gait alteration, reluctance to stand or bear weight on a limb), as well as behavioral depression, muscle tremors, or other systemic reactions that could be related to the vaccine treatment. We classified injection-site reactions according to the following criteria: 1) 
 <bold>abscess</bold>–an open sore usually with fluid drainage or discharge, 2) 
 <bold>swelling</bold>–a raised area of tissue of variable size and shape with no visible fluid drainage, 3) 
 <bold>lameness–</bold>any abnormal range of movement or stiffness in the leg where the vaccine injection was delivered, 4) 
 <bold>none–</bold>no observable reaction [
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref052" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>]. These categories were not mutually exclusive with respect to a single observation and both sides of the animal were observed, when possible. For these observations, we approached as near as possible to individual horses (≤ 50 m) and assessed and photographed each injection-site reaction for later evaluation. At the same time, we visually evaluated body condition of each mare and scored condition as previously described [
 <xref rid="pone.0201570.ref053" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>]. We evaluated the success of the existing pregnancy by comparing foaling proportions between treated and control groups in 2010 and 2014. We measured neonatal survival as the proportion of foals surviving to 14 days of age and post-natal survival to 200 days.
</p>
