<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par19">The majority of treatment-emergent adverse events, including fatigue, pyrexia, nausea, and diarrhea, were primarily grade 1–2. At low doses (≤ 0.4 mg/kg) without prophylaxis, early-onset grade 3–4 neutropenia and febrile neutropenia emerged as toxicities of note. Peri-infusional steroid use decreased their incidence and permitted further escalation to 1.0 mg/kg. At this level, patients showed delayed-onset febrile neutropenia and neutropenia - which prompted the introduction of granulocyte growth factor prophylaxis. This facilitated neutrophil count recovery and enabled escalation sufficient to declare an MTD. Overall, neutropenia, febrile neutropenia, and thrombocytopenia were the most frequently observed grade ≥ 3 adverse events and the primary DLTs observed. The underlying mechanisms of these myelosuppressive effects are likely linked to off-target effects derived from the microtubule-disrupting function of the DM1 payload in IMGN529. Neutropenia is more consistently observed in ADCs that contain a MMAE payload [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>], including brentuximab vedotin [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>], and was recently identified as a key toxicity of polatuzumab vedotin, a CD79b-targeting ADC, as part of a dose-escalation study in B-cell NHL patients [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. Thrombocytopenia has been reported for other DM1-containing conjugates, however is more widespread for calicheamicin-utilizing ADCs [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>]. Indeed, the incidence and severity observed in this study compare favorably to those seen in NHL patients treated with inotuzumab ozogamicin, a CD22-targeted ADC containing calicheamicin, where these events were the leading cause of serious adverse events, dose modifications, and discontinuations [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>]. The remaining DLT, peripheral neuropathy, was observed in one patient treated at 0.8 mg/kg; however due to an overall low frequency across the safety population, the relevance of this potential toxicity remains undefined.
</p>
