<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par21">Although only moderate clinical activity was seen across the heterogeneous NHL population, the signals of efficacy observed in patients with DLBCL are encouraging, particularly given that all had advanced disease and were heavily pretreated. While stable disease was most commonly seen in indolent and intermediate types of lymphoma (FL and MCL), the confirmed tumor responses tended to cluster in patients diagnosed with DLBCL. A lack of available tumor tissue precluded complete biomarker analyses and thus no correlations between activity and cell of origin classification or CD37 expression could be determined. However, immunohistochemical detection of CD37 was seen on all evaluable samples. Moreover, it is notable that the patient who achieved a complete response had non-GCB DLBCL, a molecular subtype that confers a poorer prognosis than those of GCB origin [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>], as well as high CD37 expression. The duration of response for the additional DLBCL responders lasted as long as 8.4 months, providing further evidence that IMGN529 has meaningful activity in patients with refractory, aggressive disease. Importantly, our findings validate CD37 as a rational target for therapeutic intervention in DLBCL. To date, the initial human evaluations of the CD37-targeting agent TRU-016 have been conducted either as monotherapy in patients with chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) or as part of combinations in indolent lymphomas [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>] and therefore the efficacy results seen here cannot be directly compared to those studies. Currently, there is another CD37-targeting ADC in development, AGS67E, which comprises MMAE conjugated to an antibody component that lacks the intrinsic apoptotic and ADCC activity present in IMGN529 [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>]. A phase 1 study of AGS67E monotherapy in patients with relapsed/refractory NHL and CLL is ongoing and final results are not yet available; however interim reports have similarly identified objective responses in DLBCL patients as part of that trial [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>]. Of note, delayed-onset neutropenia was also identified as a dose-limiting toxicity in the study, which similarly required growth factor support in order to allow escalation to proceed.
</p>
