<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" article-type="brief-report"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.3 20070202//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName journalpublishing.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.3?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName nlm2jats3.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><?covid-19-tdm?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Front Pharmacol</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Front Pharmacol</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Front. Pharmacol.</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Frontiers in Pharmacology</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">1663-9812</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Frontiers Media S.A.</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">8155348</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">683529</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fphar.2021.683529</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Pharmacology</subject><subj-group><subject>Perspective</subject></subj-group></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Synergy Between Vitamin D and Sex Hormones in Respiratory Functionality of Patients Affected by COVID-19</article-title><alt-title alt-title-type="left-running-head">Peruzzu et al.</alt-title><alt-title alt-title-type="right-running-head">Vitamin D and Sex Hormones in COVID-19</alt-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Peruzzu</surname><given-names>Daniela</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref><xref ref-type="author-notes" rid="fn1">
<sup>&#x02020;</sup>
</xref><uri xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/990474/overview"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Pagano</surname><given-names>Maria Teresa</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref><xref ref-type="author-notes" rid="fn1">
<sup>&#x02020;</sup>
</xref><uri xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/1034724/overview"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Pierdominici</surname><given-names>Marina</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref><uri xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/428663/overview"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Ruggieri</surname><given-names>Anna</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref><uri xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/549567/overview"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Antinori</surname><given-names>Andrea</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">
<sup>2</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>D&#x02019;Offizi</surname><given-names>Gianpiero</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">
<sup>2</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Petrosillo</surname><given-names>Nicola</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">
<sup>2</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Palmieri</surname><given-names>Fabrizio</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">
<sup>2</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Piselli</surname><given-names>Pierluca</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">
<sup>2</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Boumis</surname><given-names>Evangelo</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">
<sup>2</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Notari</surname><given-names>Stefania</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">
<sup>2</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Nicastri</surname><given-names>Emanuele</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">
<sup>2</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Agrati</surname><given-names>Chiara</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">
<sup>2</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Ippolito</surname><given-names>Giuseppe</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">
<sup>2</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Gagliardi</surname><given-names>Maria Cristina</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref><xref ref-type="corresp" rid="c001">*</xref><uri xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/545157/overview"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Capobianchi</surname><given-names>Maria Rosaria</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">
<sup>2</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Ortona</surname><given-names>Elena</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref><uri xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/300008/overview"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><collab>INMI-ISS COVID-19 Team</collab></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff1">
<label><sup>1</sup></label>Center for Gender Specific Medicine, Istituto Superiore di Sanit&#x000e0;, <addr-line>Rome</addr-line>, <country>Italy</country>
</aff><aff id="aff2">
<label><sup>2</sup></label>National Institute for Infectious Diseases, Lazzaro Spallanzani, IRCCS, <addr-line>Rome</addr-line>, <country>Italy</country>
</aff><author-notes><fn fn-type="edited-by"><p>
<bold>Edited by:</bold>
<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/149762/overview">Geoffrey Brown</ext-link>, University of Birmingham, United Kingdom</p></fn><fn fn-type="edited-by"><p>
<bold>Reviewed by:</bold>
<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/412948/overview">Maurizio Simmaco</ext-link>, Sapienza University of Rome, Italy</p><p>
<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/360159/overview">Sandro La Vignera</ext-link>, University of Catania, Italy</p></fn><corresp id="c001">*Correspondence: Maria Cristina Gagliardi, <email>mariacristina.gagliardi@iss.it</email></corresp><fn fn-type="other"><p>This article was submitted to Experimental Pharmacology and Drug Discovery, a section of the journal Frontiers in Pharmacology</p></fn><fn fn-type="equal" id="fn1"><label><sup>&#x02020;</sup></label><p>These authors have contributed equally to this work</p></fn></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>13</day><month>5</month><year>2021</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2021</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="pmc-release"><day>13</day><month>5</month><year>2021</year></pub-date><!-- PMC Release delay is 0 months and 0 days and was based on the <pub-date pub-type="epub"/>. --><volume>12</volume><elocation-id>683529</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>21</day><month>3</month><year>2021</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>28</day><month>4</month><year>2021</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2021 Peruzzu, Pagano, Pierdominici, Ruggieri, Antinori, D&#x02019;Offizi, Petrosillo, Palmieri, Piselli, Boumis, Notari, Nicastri, Agrati, Ippolito, Gagliardi, Capobianchi and Ortona.</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2021</copyright-year><copyright-holder>Peruzzu, Pagano, Pierdominici, Ruggieri, Antinori, D&#x02019;Offizi, Petrosillo, Palmieri, Piselli, Boumis, Notari, Nicastri, Agrati, Ippolito, Gagliardi, Capobianchi and Ortona</copyright-holder><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License (CC BY). The use, distribution or reproduction in other forums is permitted, provided the original author(s) and the copyright owner(s) are credited and that the original publication in this journal is cited, in accordance with accepted academic practice. No use, distribution or reproduction is permitted which does not comply with these terms.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract><p>The outcome of COVID-19 appears to be influenced by vitamin D status of population. Although epidemiological data indicate that COVID-19 produces more severe symptoms and higher mortality in elderly in comparison to young patients and in men in comparison to women to date sex and age differences in vitamin D status in infected patients have not been evaluated yet. In this study we evaluated the levels of circulating 25(OH)D in patients hospitalized for COVID-19 divided accordingly to their sex and age. We also correlated 25(OH)D levels with patient&#x02019;s respiratory status (i.e., PaO2/FiO2 ratio) and with sex hormones plasma levels to analyze the potential relationship of these parameters. We found no significant differences in plasma levels of 25(OH)D between pre- and post-menopausal female patients and age matched male patients. Interestingly, the 25(OH)D plasma levels positively correlated to PaO2/FiO2 ratio only in young patients, regardless of their sex. We also found a significantly positive correlation between 17&#x003b2;-estradiol and 25(OH)D in elderly women and between testosterone and 25(OH)D in elderly men, supporting the role of sex hormones in maintaining 25(OH)D levels. In conclusion, we suggest that a synergy between vitamin D and sex hormones could contribute to the age-related outcome of COVID-19.</p></abstract><kwd-group><kwd>SARS-CoV-2</kwd><kwd>vitamin D</kwd><kwd>sex hormones</kwd><kwd>gender</kwd><kwd>sex differences</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source id="cn001">Ministero della Salute<named-content content-type="fundref-id">10.13039/501100003196</named-content></funding-source><award-id rid="cn001">12371817</award-id></award-group></funding-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="s1"><title>Introduction</title><p>The outcome of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) appears to be influenced by the interaction among genetic, hormonal and environmental factors. In this context, low levels of circulating 25-hydroxyvitamin D [25(OH)D], the biomarker of vitamin D status, represent a risk factor for COVID-19 and 1,25(OH)2 vitamin D(3) (the active metabolite of vitamin D) seems to play a protective role in this disease by controlling the cytokine storm, enhancing the production of antimicrobial peptides and maintaining the integrity of the epithelium (<xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">Pagano et al., 2020</xref>; <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">Hutchings et al., 2021</xref>). Moreover, 1,25(OH)2 vitamin D(3), by increasing the expression of angiotensin-converting enzyme (ACE)2, the functional receptor for SARS-CoV-2, induces ACE2/Ang&#x02010;(1-7)/MasR axis activity and inhibits renin and the ACE/Ang II/AT1R axis. This process leads to the protection against acute lung injury/acute respiratory distress syndrome (<xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">Xu et al., 2017</xref>; <xref rid="B3" ref-type="bibr">Gagliardi et al., 2020</xref>; <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">Kumar et al., 2020</xref>; <xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">Malek Mahdavi, 2020</xref>). In the same vein, 17&#x003b2;-estradiol increases the expression of ACE2 also playing a protective role in COVID-19 (<xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">Seeland et al., 2020</xref>). Although epidemiological data indicate that COVID-19 produces more severe symptoms and higher mortality in elderly in comparison to young patients and in men in comparison to women (<xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">Pagano et al., 2020</xref>; <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">Chen et al., 2021</xref>), to date, sex, and age differences in vitamin D status in infected patients have not been evaluated yet. Hence aim of this study was to analyze the levels of circulating 25(OH)D in patients hospitalized for COVID-19 divided accordingly to their sex and age. We also correlated 25(OH)D levels with patient's respiratory status and with sex hormones plasma levels to analyze the potential relationship of these parameters.</p></sec><sec sec-type="methods" id="s2"><title>Methods</title><p>To address this issue, we measured plasma levels of 25(OH)D, testosterone and 17&#x003b2;-estradiol from 160 adult patients (80 females and 80 males divided in four subgroups: A, 40 pre-menopausal females under 45&#x000a0;years; B, 40 males under 45&#x000a0;years; C, 40 post-menopausal females over 55&#x000a0;years; D, 40 males over 55&#x000a0;years) admitted to Lazzaro Spallanzani Hospital, Rome, Italy between March and September 2020, positive for SARS-CoV-2 by RT&#x02013;PCR from nasopharyngeal swabs, and able to provide informed consent. Plasma samples were collected at clinical admission. Partial pressure of oxygen/inspired oxygen concentration ratio (PaO2/FiO2 ratio), representing a valuable clinical measure of the patient&#x02019;s respiratory status, were recorded during clinical admission. ELISA kits for 25(OH)D (MyBioSource, San Diego, CA, United States) testosterone (R&#x00026;D Systems, Minneapolis, MN, United States) and 17&#x003b2;-estradiol (Abcam, Cambridge, United Kingdom) were used according to manufactures&#x02019; instructions. Statistical analysis was performed by the Mann&#x02013;Whitney <italic>U</italic> test and Spearman&#x02019;s rank correlation using GraphPad Prism (GraphPad Software, San Diego, CA, United States). A <italic>p</italic> value &#x0003c;0.05 was considered statistically significant.</p></sec><sec sec-type="results" id="s3"><title>Results</title><p>No significant differences in plasma levels of 25(OH)D were detected between female and male patients and among the four subgroups of patients divided according to sex and age (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1A</xref>). Interestingly, the 25(OH)D plasma levels positively correlated to PaO2/FiO2 ratio only in young patients (subgroups A and B, <italic>p</italic> = 0,03 and <italic>p</italic> = 0,01 respectively, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1B</xref>), regardless of the sex of patients. The here observed age-dependent vitamin D association with respiratory functionality in COVID-19 patients suggested the involvement of sex hormones in vitamin D effects. Hence, we correlated 25(OH)D levels with sex hormones plasma levels and we observed a significantly positive correlation between 17&#x003b2;-estradiol and 25(OH)D in elderly women (subgroup C, <italic>p</italic> = 0.01, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">Figure 2A</xref>) and between testosterone and 25(OH)D in elderly men (subgroup D, <italic>p</italic> = 0.04, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">Figure 2B</xref>), supporting the role of sex hormones in maintaining 25(OH)D levels.</p><fig id="F1" position="float"><label>FIGURE 1</label><caption><p>Detection of plasma levels of 25(OH)D and its correlation with PaO2/FiO2 ratio in COVID&#x02010;19 patients. <bold>(A)</bold> Analysis of plasma levels of 25(OH)D detected into female and male patients (left panel) and among the 4 subgroups of patients: A, 40 pre-menopausal females under 45 years; B, 40 males under 45 years; C, 40 post-menopausal females over 55 years; D, 40 males over 55 years. Data referred to plasma levels of 25(OH)D are reported as mean &#x000b1; SD. <bold>(B)</bold> Correlation and linear regression analysis of plasma levels of 25(OH)D and PaO2/FiO2 ratio in female and male patients categorized into four groups: A, 40 pre-menopausal females under 45 years (A: &#x0003c; 45 yrs); B, 40 males under 45 years (B: &#x0003c; 45 yrs); C, 40 post-menopausal females over 55 years (C: &#x0003e; 55 yrs); D, 40 males over 55 years (D: &#x0003e; 55 yrs). A significantly positive correlation between plasma levels of 25(OH)D and PaO2/FiO2 ratio is observed in subgroups A and B. The Spearman's rho (R) and <italic>P</italic> values were determined using the Spearman's rank correlation analysis. Solid lines represent best fits as estimated by linear regression analysis. *, <italic>P</italic> &#x0003c; 0.05 was considered statistically significant.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fphar-12-683529-g001"/></fig><fig id="F2" position="float"><label>FIGURE 2</label><caption><p>Correlation of plasma 25(OH) vitamin D levels with 17&#x003b2;-estradiol and Testosterone in COVID-19 patients. <bold>(A)</bold> Correlation and linear regression analysis of plasma levels of 25(OH)D and 17&#x003b2;-estradiol in female and male patients categorized into four groups: A, 40 pre-menopausal females under 45 years (A: &#x0003c; 45 yrs); B, 40 males under 45 years (B: &#x0003c; 45 yrs); C, 40 post-menopausal females over 55 years (C: &#x0003e; 55 yrs); D, 40 males over 55 years (D: &#x0003e; 55 yrs). A significantly positive correlation between plasma levels of 25(OH)D and 17&#x003b2;-estradiol is observed in subgroup C. <bold>(B)</bold> Correlation and linear regression analysis of plasma levels of 25(OH)D and testosterone into four groups. A significantly positive correlation between plasma levels of 25(OH)D and testosterone levels is observed in males and in subgroup D. The Spearman's rho (R) and <italic>P</italic> values were determined using the Spearman's rank correlation analysis. Solid lines represent best fits as estimated by linear by linear regression analysis. *, <italic>P </italic>&#x0003c; 0.05 was considered statistically significant.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fphar-12-683529-g002"/></fig></sec><sec sec-type="discussion" id="s4"><title>Discussion</title><p>In this study we analyzed the 25(OH)D plasma levels in patients with COVID-19 divided accordingly to their sex and age and we found a positive correlation between vitamin D status and respiratory functionality only in young patients, regardless of their sex. This result was consistent to previous studies on the association of serum 25(OH)D concentration with the improved lung function, in both females and males (<xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">Ganji et al., 2020</xref>). We asked whether in young patients, sex hormones could impact vitamin D status and effects. Actually, estrogen has been suggested to enhance vitamin D actions, by increasing the expression of the nuclear vitamin D receptor gene (<xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">Cheema et al., 1989</xref>) and by decreasing the expression of CYP24A1, the cytochrome P450 component of the 25-hydroxyvitamin D(3)-24-hydroxylase enzyme which catabolizes the active form of vitamin D. In turn, vitamin D influences peripheral estrogen metabolism modulating in a tissue-specific way the function of the cytochrome P450 19 aromatase (CYP19), the enzyme that produces 17&#x003b2;-estradiol from testosterone (<xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">Lundqvist et al., 2011</xref>). Moreover, low levels of vitamin D have been also independently associated with low levels of testosterone in healthy middle-aged men (<xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">Giagulli et al., 2021</xref>; <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">Papadopoulos et al., 2021</xref>). Accordingly, we found a significantly positive correlation between 17&#x003b2;-estradiol and 25(OH)D in elderly women and between testosterone and 25(OH)D in elderly men supporting the role of sex hormones in preserving 25(OH)D levels. A relationship between hormones of the hypothalamic&#x02013;pituitary&#x02013;testicular (HPT) axis and vitamin D status has been established (<xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">Lee et al., 2012</xref>). In this context, further studies are needed to evaluate gonadotropin levels in male patients in order to clarify the role of vitamin D/HPT axis in COVID-19.</p><p>In conclusion, it is tempting to hypothesize that the synergy between vitamin D and sex hormones could contribute to the age-related outcome of COVID-19. Controlled studies are needed to determine the role of vitamin D supplementation in combination with estrogens or androgens in improving respiratory function of female and male patients, respectively.</p><p>All in all, the collection, analysis and report of data on COVID-19 disaggregated by sex and age seem to be a duty to achieve the appropriateness of the prevention, treatment and control of the disease.</p></sec><sec id="s5"><title>INMI-ISS COVID-19 Team</title><p>Simona Anticoli, Maria Bellenghi, Veronica Bordoni, Marta Camici1, Rita Casetti, Carlotta Cerva, Pierangelo Chinello, Eleonora Cimini, Davide Roberto Donno, Maria Luisa Dupuis, Francesca Faraglia, Katia Fecchi, Roberta Gagliardini, Germana Grassi, Rachele Di Lorenzo, Manuela Macchione, Gaetano Maffongelli, Gianfranco Mattia, Eugenia Milozzi, Silvia Mosti, Giada Pontecorvi, Rossella Puglisi, Alessandra Sacchi, Eleonora Tartaglia, Serena Vita.</p></sec></body><back><ack><p>We acknowledge the National Institute for Infectious Diseases staff for their assistance in collecting the data.</p></ack><sec sec-type="data-availability" id="s6"><title>Data Availability Statement</title><p>The data that support the findings of this study are available from the corresponding author.</p></sec><sec id="s7"><title>Ethics Statement</title><p>The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by National Institute for Infectious Diseases, Lazzaro Spallanzani, IRCCS, Rome, Italy. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study.</p></sec><sec id="s8"><title>Author Contributions</title><p>DP and MTP performed experiments and analyzed data with equal contribution, MP and AR revised the manuscript, AA, GD, NP, FP, PP, EB, SN, EN, CA, GI, and MRC have participated in the research and in the acquisition of data, EO and MCG designed the study and wrote the manuscript. All authors approved the submitted version.</p></sec><sec id="s9"><title>Funding</title><p>This work was funded by the Italian Ministry of Health (COVID-2020-12371817 and Ricerca Corrente, Linea 1).</p></sec><sec sec-type="COI-statement" id="s10"><title>Conflict of Interest</title><p>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</p></sec><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="B1"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Cheema</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Grant</surname><given-names>B. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Marcus</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>1989</year>). <article-title>Effects of Estrogen on Circulating "free" and Total 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D and on the Parathyroid-Vitamin D axis in Postmenopausal Women</article-title>. <source>J. Clin. Invest.</source>
<volume>83</volume>, <fpage>537</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>542</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1172/JCI113915</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2492309</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B2"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Klein</surname><given-names>S. L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Garibaldi</surname><given-names>B. T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Osevala</surname><given-names>N. M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2021</year>). <article-title>Aging in COVID-19: Vulnerability, Immunity and Intervention</article-title>. <source>Ageing Res. Rev.</source>
<volume>65</volume>, <fpage>101205</fpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2020.101205</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33137510</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B3"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gagliardi</surname><given-names>M. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tieri</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ortona</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ruggieri</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>ACE2 Expression and Sex Disparity in COVID-19</article-title>. <source>Cell Death Discov.</source>
<volume>6</volume>, <fpage>37</fpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41420-020-0276-1</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32499922</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B4"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ganji</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Al-Obahi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yusuf</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dookhy</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Serum Vitamin D Is Associated with Improved Lung Function Markers but Not with Prevalence of Asthma, Emphysema, and Chronic Bronchitis</article-title>. <source>Sci. Rep.</source>
<volume>10</volume>, <fpage>14118</fpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-67967-7</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32814803</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B5"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Giagulli</surname><given-names>V. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Guastamacchia</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Magrone</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jirillo</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lisco</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>De Pergola</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2021</year>). <article-title>Worse Progression of COVID&#x02010;19 in Men: Is Testosterone a Key Factor?</article-title>
<source>Andrology</source>
<volume>9</volume>, <fpage>53</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>64</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/andr.12836</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32524732</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B6"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Hutchings</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Babalyan</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Baghdasaryan</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Qefoyan</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sargsyants</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Aghajanova</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2021</year>). <article-title>Patients Hospitalized with COVID-19 Have Low Levels of 25-hydroxyvitamin D</article-title>. <source>Endocrine</source>
<volume>71</volume>, <fpage>267</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>269</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s12020-020-02597-7</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33452994</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B7"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gupta</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Banerjee</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Letter: Does Vitamin D Have a Potential Role against COVID-19?</article-title>
<source>Aliment. Pharmacol. Ther.</source>
<volume>52</volume>, <fpage>409</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>411</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/apt.15801</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32432810</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B8"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>D. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Tajar</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Pye</surname><given-names>S. R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Boonen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Vanderschueren</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bouillon</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>Association of Hypogonadism with Vitamin D Status: the European Male Ageing Study</article-title>. <source>Eur. J. Endocrinol.</source>
<volume>166</volume> (<issue>1</issue>), <fpage>77</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>85</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1530/EJE-11-0743</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22048968</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B9"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lundqvist</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Norlin</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wikvall</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2011</year>). <article-title>1&#x003b1;,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D3 Exerts Tissue-specific Effects on Estrogen and Androgen Metabolism</article-title>. <source>Biochim. Biophys. Acta (Bba) - Mol. Cel Biol. Lipids</source>
<volume>1811</volume>, <fpage>263</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>270</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.bbalip.2011.01.004</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B10"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Malek Mahdavi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>A Brief Review of Interplay between Vitamin D and Angiotensin&#x02010;converting Enzyme 2: Implications for a Potential Treatment for COVID &#x02010;19</article-title>. <source>Rev. Med. Virol.</source>
<volume>30</volume>, <fpage>e2119</fpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/rmv.2119</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32584474</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B11"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Pagano</surname><given-names>M. T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Peruzzu</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ruggieri</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ortona</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gagliardi</surname><given-names>M. C.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Vitamin D and Sex Differences in COVID-19</article-title>. <source>Front. Endocrinol.</source>
<volume>11</volume>, <fpage>567824</fpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fendo.2020.567824</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B12"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Papadopoulos</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Samplaski</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2021</year>). <article-title>Why Does COVID&#x02010;19 Kill More Elderly Men Than Women? Is There a Role for Testosterone?</article-title>
<source>Andrology</source>
<volume>9</volume>, <fpage>65</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>72</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/andr.12868</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32681716</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B13"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Seeland</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></name><name><surname>Coluzzi</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Simmaco</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Mura</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bourne</surname><given-names>P. E.</given-names></name><name><surname>Heiland</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group> (<year>2020</year>). <article-title>Evidence for Treatment with Estradiol for Women with SARS-CoV-2 Infection</article-title>. <source>BMC Med.</source>
<volume>18</volume>, <fpage>369</fpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12916-020-01851-z</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33234138</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B14"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name></person-group> (<year>2017</year>). <article-title>Vitamin D Alleviates Lipopolysaccharide-Induced Acute Lung Injury via Regulation of the Renin-Angiotensin System</article-title>. <source>Mol. Med. Rep.</source>
<volume>16</volume>, <fpage>7432</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>7438</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3892/mmr.2017.7546</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28944831</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>