<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Acuity Brands provided freestanding light fixtures (Figure 
 <xref rid="cam41690-fig-0002" ref-type="fig">2</xref>) delivering a CS value of 0.3 for the active, bright white light (BWL) condition (1300 lux at the eye level of the patients) and a CS of 0.1 for the dim white light (DWL) condition (90 lux at the eye level of the patients). Therefore, the BWL was designed to deliver circadian active light while the DWL was designed to deliver circadian inactive light. Ambient light illuminated the entire room. As is shown in Figure 
 <xref rid="cam41690-fig-0003" ref-type="fig">3</xref>, both BWL (
 <italic>M</italic> = 0.339, SEM = 0.06) and DWL (
 <italic>M</italic> = 0.116, SEM = 0.055) were successful in delivering light at the intended CS values. The light fixtures, previously programmed to the respective light condition, remained in the patients' hospital rooms for the duration of hospitalization and were calibrated to turn on every morning from 7 to 10 
 <sc>am</sc>. During this time, patients were instructed to go about their normal activities, which could include leaving their hospital room. Based on prior research, 30 minutes a day of circadian active bright white light was sufficient in reducing fatigue.
 <xref rid="cam41690-bib-0033" ref-type="ref">33</xref> A 3‐hour time frame was chosen to ensure at least 30 minutes of exposure regardless of activity from 7 to 10 
 <sc>am</sc>. In order to verify that the correct dose of light was received, Daysimeters, light meters calibrated to measure CS, were placed behind the patient's bed, on the light fixture, and on their chest, worn as a pendant by the patient during waking hours for the entire hospital stay. The Daysimeter is a research tool manufactured by the Lighting Research Center at Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute; they are not commercially available.
 <xref rid="cam41690-bib-0034" ref-type="ref">34</xref> As hypothesized, those in the BWL condition received light of a significantly (
 <italic>P</italic> &lt; 0.0001) higher CS value than those in the DWL (Figure 
 <xref rid="cam41690-fig-0003" ref-type="fig">3</xref>).
</p>
