<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Using G-CSF to mobilize HSCs has revolutionized the treatment of blood malignancies as it often replaces the classical bone marrow transplant (
 <xref rid="B34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>). Instead of harvesting bone marrow surgically from the pelvis bone, which requires, e.g., general anesthesia, the cells of interest are collected from the peripheral blood. Yet again, there is growing evidence that G-CSF treatment alters more physiological functions than the blood cell count (
 <xref rid="B22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>). Our study analyzed key neutrophil functions, i.e., chemotaxis, ROS production, and phagocytosis, in isolated neutrophils from the peripheral blood of HSC donors and allogeneic transplant recipients by using well-established 
 <italic>in vitro</italic> stimuli and assays. The individuals included in our study received standard dosages of G-CSF (10 μg/kg/d) and the resulting plasma concentrations were in the expected ranges (
 <xref rid="B34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>). As expected, G-CSF treatment substantially increased the number of neutrophils in the circulation. When analyzing the functionality of these neutrophils, we revealed that if derived from healthy HSC donors treated with G-CSF, the cells showed reduced 
 <italic>ex vivo</italic> chemotaxis toward fMLF. Other key functions tested, i.e., ROS production and phagocytosis, seemed to remain unaltered. Strikingly, the chemotactic impairment observed in neutrophils from HSC donors persisted in the group of allogeneic transplant recipients. Even after transplantation and novel granulopoiesis within the transplant recipient, newly emerging neutrophils showed the same migration defect as the neutrophils from the HSC donors. Of note, the recipients themselves received no prophylactic G-CSF. According to our data, it took several weeks until normal neutrophil activity was regained. Notably, we observed the chemotactic impairment even though the allogeneic transplant recipient group was heterogeneously composed with diversity regarding the underlying disease. Nevertheless, these patients frequently receive immunosuppressive therapy, such as steroids or calcineurin inhibitors, which in turn were shown to impair neutrophil functions. However, the effects of these type of drugs are usually pleiotropic and do not specifically target neutrophil chemotaxis. For instance, calcineurin inhibitors can impair chemokinesis of neutrophils on vitronectin (
 <xref rid="B36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>), reduce oxidative burst induced by fMLF (
 <xref rid="B37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>) and diminish phagocytic activity (
 <xref rid="B38" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>). Further, the content of immature neutrophils was &lt;2% in both, full blood and neutrophil isolation fractions—even after G-CSF treatment.
</p>
