<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Our results confirm previous studies describing impaired neutrophil functionality in allogeneic transplant recipients. Sosa et al. reported that neutrophil chemotaxis is impaired up to 4 months after HSC transplantation (
 <xref rid="B39" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>) and Katoh et al. observed a decrease in chemotactic activity for up to 12 months (
 <xref rid="B40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>). Azzara et al. even pointed toward a reduced motility of neutrophils from chemotherapy patients treated with G-CSF (
 <xref rid="B41" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>). Still, these studies were performed with neutrophils from cancer patients while we also included otherwise healthy HSC donors yet observed similar abnormalities. This implies that G-CSF treatment in general affects neutrophils and is supported by Kerst et al. who described phenotypically and functionally altered neutrophils upon G-CSF treatment in healthy donors (
 <xref rid="B42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>). Few studies addressed the impact of G-CSF administration on neutrophils in healthy individuals, in our case HSC donors. Dale and coworkers investigated the combined impact of G-CSF and corticosteroids on neutrophil function (
 <xref rid="B43" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>), whereas Höglund and colleagues similar to our study investigated the singular effect of G-CSF (
 <xref rid="B44" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>). The authors observed a reduced migratory activity of neutrophils after several doses of G-CSF and the transient nature of this effect, as it disappeared several weeks after treatment. Our study confirms and extends on these findings, since we directly combine investigations of healthy HSC donors with allogeneic transplant recipients as well as linking our observations to CRP and IL-8 levels and direct 
 <italic>in vitro</italic> effects as discussed in more detail below. Interestingly, 
 <italic>in vitro</italic> studies triggering neutrophils directly with G-CSF observed a rapid stimulation of random mobility that declined within about half an hour (
 <xref rid="B45" ref-type="bibr">45</xref>). In our experiments showing reduced mobility due to G-CSF treatment, neutrophils were incubated with G-CSF for that same amount of time and subsequently challenged with fMLF to induce active movement. Taken together, these observations suggest a possible “exhaustion” of chemotactic potential due to random mobility if neutrophils are directly challenged with G-CSF. Notably, in our study, reduced 
 <italic>in vitro</italic> chemotaxis did unlikely result from decreased surface exposure of the fMLF receptor.
</p>
