<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>
 <italic>Aspergillus</italic> can cause fungal endocarditis, mainly in patients after organ transplantation and artificial heart valve implantation. Foreign body implantation and immunosuppression are high risk factors (
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>). This patient with chronic renal failure, long-term dialysis treatment, combined with renal anemia, impaired immunity, and a long-term indwelling catheter in the internal jugular vein, was of a high-risk group of fungal infection. Since the common pathogens of dialysis catheter-related infections and IE are bacteria (
 <xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>), empirical treatments are generally antibacterial treatments. Additionally, in 
 <italic>Aspergillus</italic> infection, 93% of blood culture results were negative (
 <xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>), which increased the difficulty of early diagnosis, prompt treatment and caused high mortality (
 <xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>). In our case, the patient's blood culture was negative at the beginning, so she was only given empirical antibacterial therapy. Fortunately, this patient has survived well after being diagnosed with 
 <italic>A. flavus</italic> infection and receiving voriconazole therapy. Siddiqui BK also reported a case of IE caused by 
 <italic>A. flavus</italic> in a hemodialysis patient (
 <xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>). In the case they reported, because the blood cultures were persistently negative, they also used vancomycin and moxifloxacin for empirical treatment at the beginning. But unfortunately, because at that time they could not use methods like mNGS to assist in rapid diagnosis when the patient was alive, the patient developed pulseless bradycardia and expired despite resuscitation efforts. After the patient died, autopsy showed disseminated aspergillosis with a 1 × 1.5 cm vegetation on aortic valve and the grew aspergillus flavus on culture.
</p>
