<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A 51-year-old Chinese woman visited the hospital because of chest tightness for 10 days. Her chest CT showed a 2.3 cm × 2 cm nodule in her left lung. Multiple plaques were seen on the left pleura. Pleural effusion, compression atelectasis, and swollen hilar lymphadenopathy in the left lung can be seen on contrast-enhanced CT (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
  <bold>Figure 1A</bold>
 </xref>). From November 19, 2018, after admission to the hospital, obvious tumor cells could not be found in the repeated pleural effusion tests (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
  <bold>Figure 2A</bold>
 </xref>). Additionally, bronchoscopy, neck lymph nodes, and brain CT showed no apparent abnormalities. A biopsy of the left pleural mass was performed on November 20, 2018. The histopathologic findings revealed an epithelioid tumor with fibrous vascular nests and strands surrounding it. Some cells were hyaline, and mitotic figures were seen. Positive staining for Ki-67 (approximately 40%), Sy, Melan-A, Hmb45, and S-100 was detected by immunohistochemistry using monoclonal antibodies (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
  <bold>Figure 2B</bold>
 </xref>). The patient had no previous skin lesions and had no history of previous excision of the skin or other lesions. We used bevacizumab 200 mg for left intrathoracic treatment on December 7, 2018, for patients with self-reported chest tightness improved with this treatment. Because this primary pathological type of lung disease is rare, we sent a pleural biopsy sample for the next-generation sequencing of tissue samples to FoundationOne CDX on December 14, 2018; NGS revealed an EWSR1-ATF1 fusion, CDKN2A/b loss, and MTAP loss (
 <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">
  <bold>Table 1</bold>
 </xref>). We also confirmed that PD-L1 as a target by immunohistochemistry using an anti-PD-L1 IHC 22C3 pharmDx (Dako) antibody (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
  <bold>Figures 2C, D</bold>
 </xref>). Because the PD-L1 target did not perform as expected, we performed immunofluorescence analysis (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f3">
  <bold>Figure 3</bold>
 </xref>) with the OPAL™ Multiplex IHC (Akoya) Kit. Immune microenvironment-related markers, including CD8, TIM3, PD-L1, LAG3, CD163, and TIGIT, were examined to find a new therapeutic target. Only TIGIT was observed in positive cells ≥1%, and there were &lt;1% positive cells for the other markers. CD8 and TIM3 showed colocalization, but no colocalization was identified between the other markers. TIGIT is one of the most promising and potential targets in the new generation of immunotherapy drugs, and several anti-TIGIT monoclonal antibodies have been studied. The outcome of the PET-CT scan on December 20, 2018, showed that the patient’s pleural effusion improved after bevacizumab treatment (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
  <bold>Figure 1B</bold>
 </xref>). However, the patient refused further treatment after the diagnosis of pulmonary CCS. Follow-up until her death on June 27, 2019.
</p>
