<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<notes notes-type="COI-statement">
 <sec id="FPar1">
  <title>Conflict of interest</title>
  <p>Dai Maruyama reports research funding from Mundipharma K.K., Chugai Pharma, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Ono Pharmaceutical, Celgene, Janssen, GlaxoSmithKline, Eisai, Takeda, SERVIER, and Abbvie, MSD, and receiving honoraria from Mundipharma K.K., Takeda, Janssen, Eisai, Biomedis International, Celgene, Sanofi, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Fujifilm, Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Ono Pharmaceutical, and Chugai Pharma. Toshiki Uchida reports receiving an honorarium from Janssen. Yoshinobu Maeda reports research funding from Chugai Pharma, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, and Ono Pharmaceutical, and an honorarium from Mundipharma K.K. Hirokazu Nagai reports research funding from Chugai Pharma, Mundipharma K.K., Eisai, Sanofi K.K., Janssen, Takeda, Ono Pharmaceutical, and Kyowa Hakko Kirin. Hirohiko Shibayama reports research funding from Takeda, Janssen, Ono Pharmaceutical, Astellas, Teijin Pharma, Shionogi, Taiho, and Mundipharma KK, and honoraria from Takeda, Celgene, Novartis, Janssen, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, and Mundipharma KK. Kiyoshi Ando reports research funding from Mundipharma K.K. Isao Yoshida reports research funding from Kyowa Hakko Kirin and Chugai Pharma, and receiving honoraria from Mundipharma K.K., Celgene, and Kyowa Hakko Kirin. Michihiro Hidaka reports research funding from Mundipharma K.K. and Chugai Pharma. Tohru Murayama reports research funding from Celltrion, and honoraria from Nippon Shinyaku, Taiho Pharma, Janssen, Siemens, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Novartis, Celgene, Ono Pharmaceutical, Pfizer, and Bristol-Myers Squibb. Junji Suzumiya reports research funding from Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Chugai-Roche, Shinnipponkagaku-PPD, Astellas, Toyama Chemical, Eisai, Takeda, Sumitomo Dainippon, Shionogi, Taiho, Yakult, and SymBio, and receiving honoraria from Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Chugai-Roche, Janssen, Eisai, Takeda, Sumitomo Dainippon, Otsuka, Celgene, Alexion, Novartis, Pfizer, AstraZeneca, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Merck, Ono Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly, Shire, Gilead, and Zenyaku. Kazuo Tamura reports receiving honoraria from Ono Pharmaceutical, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, and Eli Lilly. Ryuzo Ueda reports research funding and an honorarium from Kyowa Hakko Kirin, serving as a consultant for Mundipharma K.K. and Terumo, and receiving an honorarium from Chugai Pharma. Kensei Tobinai reports receiving research funding from Mundipharma K.K., Chugai Pharma, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Ono Pharmaceutical, Celgene, Janssen, GlaxoSmithKline, Eisai, Takeda, Servier, and Abbvie, and honoraria from Zenyaku Kogyo, Eisai, Takeda, Mundipharma K.K., Janssen, HUYA Bioscience International, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Celgene, Chugai Pharma, and Ono Pharmaceutical. All remaining authors declared that they have no conflicts of interest.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="FPar2">
  <title>Ethical approval</title>
  <p>All procedures performed in studies involving human participants were in accordance with the ethical standards of the institutional and/or national research committee and with the 1964 Helsinki declarations and its later amendments or comparable ethical standards.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="FPar3">
  <title>Informed consent</title>
  <p>Informed consent was obtained from all individual participants included in this study.</p>
 </sec>
</notes>
