<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A recent study described that withdrawal of therapy in 19 compromised AATD patients was associated with poor health outcomes as demonstrated by an increased mean (±standard error) number of exacerbations per patient (1.5 ± 0.2 vs. 0.5 ± 0.1, 
 <italic>p</italic> = 0.002) and an increase in the mean number of hospitalizations in the same patients (0.7 ± 0.1 vs. 0.2 ± 0.1, 
 <italic>p</italic> = 0.003) compared to the same period in the previous year (
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">Gazzettaufficiale, 2012</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">McElvaney et al., 2020</xref>). To avoid the abrupt cessation of augmentation therapy, it has been necessary to activate a home treatment, which is in use in only a few EU countries. In Italy, even though home therapy with alpha-1 antitrypsin has been authorized since 2013 (
 <xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">Gazzettaufficiale, 2012</xref>), it is still an unimplemented practice. Home therapy for such patients should be part of the Italian long-term care system. However, due to the system's complexity, systemic problems regarding the offer of care and eligibility of services can occur owing to the lack of integration between Regions' and Municipalities' health policies. AADT augmentation therapy has been demonstrated to be well-tolerated and generally safe. Few and generally mild side effects have been reported and rarely required major interventions or interruption of therapy. Some authors describe side effects typical of intravenous infusion of proteins, including delayed fever resolving spontaneously over 24 h, urticaria, nausea, fatigue and dizziness. Dyspnea, probably related to absolute protein load in the infusion, flu-like symptoms, and, rarely, anaphylactic shock have also been described. No deaths related to AATD augmentation therapy are reported (
 <xref rid="B11" ref-type="bibr">Wencker et al., 1998</xref>; 
 <xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">Stoller et al., 2003</xref>). Adverse events commonly occur during the first administrations. Initial alpha one antitrypsin administrations are recommended in a hospital setting and in the presence of experienced operators. Currently, there is no literature about the outcomes of safety and quality of life of AATD patients in home treatment.
</p>
