<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par12">The primary end point of the phase 1 portion of this trial was to assess the maximum tolerated dose (MTD). The phase 1 portion of the study was expected to require a minimum of 6 and a maximum of 12 evaluable patients. For the phase 2 portion of this trial, the primary end point was the rate of complete or very good partial response. A success was defined as a CR or VGPR noted as the objective status on two consecutive evaluations. All patients meeting the eligibility criteria who signed a consent form and received at least one dose of the drug were evaluable for response, with the exception of patients who were determined to be a major treatment violation. The sample size for the phase 2 portion of the study was calculated using a one-stage binomial design. The 6 patients treated at the MTD in the phase 1 portion were also included in the phase 2 portion for overall sample size estimation. A maximum of 35 additional evaluable patients were planned to be accrued at the MTD dose level for a maximum of 41 evaluable patients in the phase 2 portion of this study. An additional 4 patients were accrued to account for ineligibility, cancellation, major treatment violation, or other reasons. With 41 evaluable patients, the study provided 90% power to test the null hypothesis that the ≥ VGPR rate is at most 40% vs. the alternative hypothesis that the ≥ VGPR rate is at least 60%, with a 1-sided significance level of 
 <italic>α</italic> = 0.10. For toxicity assessment, all patients who received at least 1 dose of study drug were included in the analysis. Overall survival (OS) was defined as the time from study entry to death due to any cause. Progression-free survival (PFS) was defined as the time from study entry to the earliest date of documentation of disease progression or death due to any cause. Duration of response (DOR) was defined as the time from first evidence of a response until the time of disease progression. Time-to-event measures were estimated using the Kaplan–Meier method.
</p>
