<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="para230">Transplantation-eligible patients receiving KCRD proceeded to high-dose melphalan and autologous stem-cell transplantation. Patients receiving immunomodulatory-based triplets (CTD 
 <italic>vs</italic> CRD) followed a response-adapted approach: those with complete response or very good partial response (assessed according to International Myeloma Working Group [IMWG] criteria) proceeded to autologous stem-cell transplantation in the transplantation-eligible pathway, whereas transplantation-ineligible patients proceeded directly to maintenance randomisation. For maintenance therapy, 100 days after autologous stem-cell transplantation or once a maximum response was achieved for transplantation-ineligible patients, patients initially received lenalidomide 25 mg per day (orally on days 1–21 of each 28-day cycle) or were observed without lenalidomide therapy. Following a protocol amendment on Sept 14, 2011, and after accrual of 442 patients, patients were allocated (1:1:1) to receive lenalidomide 10 mg per day (orally on days 1–21 of each 28-day cycle), lenalidomide 10 mg per day (orally on days 1–21 of each 28-day cycle) plus vorinostat 300 mg per day (orally on days 1–7 and 15–21 of each 28-day cycle), or observation. After accrual of 615 more patients, a further protocol amendment on June 28, 2013, allocated patients to receive lenalidomide 10 mg per day (orally on days 1–21 of each 28-day cycle) or observation in a 2:1 ratio, and the lenalidomide plus vorinostat group was discontinued. This change was proposed by the Myeloma XI Trial Management Group and approved by the Myeloma XI Data Monitoring and Ethics Committee (DMEC) on June 24, 2011. The change in dose was based on emerging results from previous studies using 10 mg lenalidomide weighted against the potential for late toxicity (increased secondary primary malignancy), which was being reported in other trials at that time. Maintenance treatment continued until progressive disease in the absence of toxicity. Here, we report outcomes for patients receiving lenalidomide alone versus observation. Patients receiving lenalidomide in combination with vorinostat will be reported elsewhere when the primary endpoint has been met in that group.
</p>
