<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par31">Participants will be excluded if they:
 <list list-type="simple">
  <list-item>
   <label>i.</label>
   <p id="Par32">have Kellgren and Lawrence grade 1 (indicating questionable disease) or grade 4 (indicating severe disease);</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>ii.</label>
   <p id="Par33">have lateral joint space narrowing greater than or equal to medial joint space narrowing on x-ray using the Osteoarthritis Research Society International (OARSI) atlas [
    <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>];
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>iii.</label>
   <p id="Par34">had injection into the target knee joint of glucocorticoid in the past 3 months or hyaluronic acid in the past 6 months,</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>iv.</label>
   <p id="Par35">had any autologous blood product or stem cell preparation in the past;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>v.</label>
   <p id="Par36">had knee surgery on their target knee within past 12 months;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>vi.</label>
   <p id="Par37">have systemic or inflammatory joint disease such as rheumatoid arthritis;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>vii.</label>
   <p id="Par38">have a history of crystalline or neuropathic arthropathy;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>viii.</label>
   <p id="Par39">had a knee joint replacement or high tibial osteotomy on their target knee;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>ix.</label>
   <p id="Par40">plan for joint surgery in the target knee in next 12 months;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>x.</label>
   <p id="Par41">have other muscular, joint or neurological condition affecting lower limb function;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>xi.</label>
   <p id="Par42">have a needle phobia;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>xii.</label>
   <p id="Par43">have immunosuppression or acute infective processes;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>xiii.</label>
   <p id="Par44">have cancer or other tumours in the last 3 years, or undergone any treatment for cancer or tumours in the last 3 years;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>xiv.</label>
   <p id="Par45">have a bleeding disorder or are receiving anti-coagulation therapy;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>xv.</label>
   <p id="Par46">have the presence of a warm, tense joint effusion;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>xvi.</label>
   <p id="Par47">have a platelet count &lt; 150,000/μL;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>xvii.</label>
   <p id="Par48">have any other medical condition precluding participation in the study including contraindication to MRI such as a pacemaker;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>xviii.</label>
   <p id="Par49">pregnancy;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>xix.</label>
   <p id="Par50">are unwilling to discontinue non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drug and other analgesic usage, with the exception of paracetamol for rescue pain relief, from 2 weeks before the baseline assessment until the 12-month follow-up assessment;</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>xx.</label>
   <p id="Par51">have a body mass index (BMI) &gt; 40 kg/m
    <sup>2</sup> because of problems fitting into the MRI machine knee coil;
   </p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>xxi.</label>
   <p id="Par52">unable to attend the six study appointments over 12 months; and</p>
  </list-item>
  <list-item>
   <label>xxii.</label>
   <p id="Par53">cannot understand written/spoken English.</p>
  </list-item>
 </list>
</p>
