<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract id="Abs1">
 <sec>
  <title>Background</title>
  <p id="Par1">Pixantrone is recommended in relapsed and refractory non-Hodgkin lymphoma (NHL) or heavily pretreated NHL patients. Its conditional approval in Europe was based on results from the open-label, randomized, phase 3 PIX301 study, comparing pixantrone monotherapy with physician's choice of treatment in 140 patients with relapsed or refractory aggressive NHL.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Methods</title>
  <p id="Par2">This post-hoc analysis of the PIX301 study investigated possible correlations between patient characteristics and clinical response in 17 patients (24%) treated with pixantrone who achieved a complete response (CR) or an unconfirmed complete response (CRu) at study end.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Results</title>
  <p id="Par3">These patients (10 male and 7 female) had a median age of 61 (range 41–75) years, and the most common diagnoses were diffuse large B-cell lymphoma (
   <italic>n</italic> = 10) and transformed indolent lymphoma (
   <italic>n</italic> = 4). Most had received two prior lines of therapy (
   <italic>n</italic> = 12). There was wide variation in the time from diagnosis to study entry (219–4777 days). Among the 17 patients who achieved a CR/CRu with pixantrone, 6 had stable or progressive disease as a response to their last regimen, 7 had a partial response, and 4 had a CR/CRu. Four patients from the pixantrone group survived without progression for more than 400 days. Prior response to previous therapies did not appear to affect long-term response to pixantrone.
  </p>
 </sec>
 <sec>
  <title>Conclusions</title>
  <p id="Par4">These observations suggest that pixantrone monotherapy in patients with multiply relapsed or refractory aggressive NHL who had received at least two prior therapies can be associated with durable responses and long-term remission, and this may be unrelated to the clinical response to the last therapy.</p>
 </sec>
</abstract>
