<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>There is plausible pre-clinical evidence both 
 <italic>in vitro</italic> and 
 <italic>in vivo</italic> that mTOR inhibition could be beneficial in AML. mTOR is a serine/threonine protein kinase that is predominantly modulated by PI3K-AKT-dependent mechanisms and acts as a central regulator of cellular metabolism, growth and survival.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b4-1031654" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>
 </sup> Dysregulation of the mTOR pathway is closely associated with cancers including AML,
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b5-1031654" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,
  <xref rid="b6-1031654" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>
 </sup> and other human diseases. Part of the rationale is the evidence of constitutive activation of the PI3K-AKT pathway in 90% of AML samples and the demonstration that this activation is central to the survival of AML blasts but not to that of normal CD34
 <sup>+</sup> cells.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b7-1031654" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>
 </sup> The concept that everolimus may have the potential to eliminate leukemia-initiating stem cells while sparing normal hematopoietic stem cells is also appealing. 
 <italic>In vivo</italic> evidence in NOD/SCID mice has suggested that mTOR regulates a critical cell survival pathway in AML stem cells.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b8-1031654" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>,
  <xref rid="b9-1031654" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>
 </sup> In preliminary unrandomized clinical trial, the mTOR inhibitor sirolimus was administered as a single agent to nine relapsed, refractory or poor-risk AML patients for 28 days resulting in partial responses in four, and stable disease in a fifth patient.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b10-1031654" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>
 </sup> Dephosphorylation of downstream effectors of mTOR was demonstrated. In an ongoing UK trial, 11 elderly patients with primary, relapsed AML have been treated with the combination of low-dose Ara-C and sirolimus. Following a single 28-day course of treatment, of the seven patients eligible for analysis, one had achieved a complete remission, four had obtained a partial remission, one had profoundly hypocellular bone marrow and one patient was a non-responder (Das Gupta, 
 <italic>unpublished data</italic>). Patients in this trial reliably maintained trough sirolimus levels of 8-16 ng/mL, which are consistent with the published concentrations required to inhibit AML cell growth 
 <italic>in vitro</italic>. The feasibility of combining mTOR inhibition (sirolimus) with intensive chemotherapy had also been assessed in AML patients in conjunction with the more intensive MEC (mitoxantrone, etoposide and cytarabine) chemotherapy regimen in a phase I dose escalation study and reported in abstract form. In this study standard renal transplant doses of sirolimus were well tolerated and did not increase the non-hematologic toxicity of MEC chemotherapy with a median time to neutrophil recovery of 27 days.
 <sup>
  <xref rid="b11-1031654" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>
 </sup> Based on this background information, the NCRI AML17 trial included the option for eligible patients to be randomized to receive, or not, the mTOR inhibitor everolimus daily between consolidation chemotherapy courses.
</p>
