<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="para130">After enrolment (
 <xref rid="sec1" ref-type="sec">appendix p 13</xref>), patients received three courses of MATRix
 <xref rid="bib13" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>13</sup>
 </xref> followed by three courses of RICE, each delivered every 3 weeks. Patients enrolled at initial lymphoma diagnosis (chemotherapy-naive patients) with extensive and life-threatening extra-CNS disease received one or two courses of R-CHOP (rituximab 375 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup> as an intravenous infusion on day 1; cyclophosphamide 750 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup> as an intravenous bolus on day 1; doxorubicin 50 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup> as an intravenous bolus on day 1; vincristine 1·4 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup> [maximum 2 mg] as an intravenous bolus on day 1; prednisone 75 mg per day orally on days 1–5). The MATRix regimen was rituximab 375 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup> as an intravenous infusion on day 0; methotrexate 3·5 g/m
 <sup>2</sup>, the first 0·5 g/m
 <sup>2</sup> in 15 min followed by 3 g/m
 <sup>2</sup> as a 3 h intravenous infusion on day 1; cytarabine 2 g/m
 <sup>2</sup> every 12 h, in 1 h intravenous infusions on days 2 and 3; and thiotepa 30 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup> in a 30 min intravenous infusion on day 4.
 <xref rid="bib13" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>13</sup>
 </xref> The RICE regimen was rituximab 375 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup> on day 1; etoposide 100 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup> per day in 500–1000 mL over a 1 h intravenous infusion on days 1, 2, and 3; ifosfamide 5 g/m
 <sup>2</sup> in 1000 mL in a 24 h intravenous infusion with mesna support on day 2; and carboplatin area under the curve of 5 in 500 mL in a 1 h intravenous infusion on day 2. Intrathecal chemotherapy was indicated in every enrolled patient regardless of cerebrospinal fluid cytology status because conventional cytology examination is associated with frequent false negative results, particularly when flow cytometry is not routinely used.
 <xref rid="bib6" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>6</sup>
 </xref> Accordingly, a dose of intrathecal liposomal cytarabine 50 mg or conventional triple-drug chemotherapy (intrathecal methotrexate 12 mg, cytarabine 50 mg, and hydrocortisone 50 mg) was delivered on day 5 of every course of MATRix and on day 4 of every course of RICE. Per protocol, antimicrobial prophylaxis followed institutional guidelines; however, oral antiviral, antifungal, and antipneumocystic prophylaxis plus conventional doses of recombinant granulocyte-colony stimulating factor (G-CSF; exact molecule chosen by investigators) from day 6 to 12 of every chemotherapy course was suggested.
</p>
