<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="para140">The protocol mandated that patients with stable or progressive disease during MATRix treatment would immediately switch to the RICE regimen (
 <xref rid="sec1" ref-type="sec">appendix p 13</xref>), with patients with subsequent CNS progression events receiving whole-brain radiotherapy before proceeding with autologous HSCT consolidation. The whole-brain radiotherapy dose was 36 Gy plus a tumour-bed boost of 10 Gy. The whole brain was irradiated by two opposite lateral fields, including the first two cervical vertebrae and the posterior two-thirds of the eyes, which had to be shielded after 30 Gy (photons of 4–10 MeV, 180–200 cGy per day, five weekly fractions). Autologous peripheral blood stem cells were collected after the second course of MATRix and were processed according to conventional guidelines. Patients with a complete or partial response after MATRix–RICE and with adequate autologous peripheral blood stem cell harvest received autologous HSCT (
 <xref rid="sec1" ref-type="sec">appendix p 13</xref>). Myeloablative chemotherapy consisted of carmustine 400 mg/m
 <sup>2</sup> in 500 mL glucose 5% solution in a 1–2 h infusion on day −6; thiotepa 5 mg/kg in saline solution in 2 h infusions every 12 h on day −5 and −4, supported by autologous HSCT. In case of carmustine unavailability, the recommended conditioning regimen was: thiotepa 5 mg/kg in 100 mL of saline solution by 2 h infusion on day −6 and −5; busulfan 3·2 mg/kg (administered in four doses per day corresponding to 0·8 mg/kg each dose) by 2 h infusion or 3·2 mg/kg as a once daily infusion given over 3 h, on days −4, −3, and −2. Patients with residual disease in the brain parenchyma after autologous HSCT received whole-brain radiotherapy; patients with residual disease in the cerebrospinal fluid after autologous HSCT received additional, intensified intrathecal chemotherapy (methotrexate 12 mg plus cytarabine 50 mg plus hydrocortisone 50 mg on days 1 and 8 each month for 3 months, or thiotepa 10 mg plus rituximab 25 mg on days 4 and 11 each month for 3 months, or both).
</p>
