<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.2 20190208//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" article-type="case-report"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.3 20070202//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName journalpublishing.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.3?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName jp2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Front Oncol</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Front Oncol</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Front. Oncol.</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Frontiers in Oncology</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2234-943X</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Frontiers Media S.A.</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">8023327</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fonc.2021.658907</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Oncology</subject><subj-group><subject>Case Report</subject></subj-group></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>A Patient With Focal Myositis and Primary Cutaneous Diffuse Large B-Cell Lymphoma: A Case Report</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Quanxin</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>Cheng</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">
<sup>2</sup>
</xref><xref ref-type="author-notes" rid="fn001">
<sup>*</sup>
</xref><uri xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://loop.frontiersin.org/people/1212579"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Li</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff1">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref><xref ref-type="author-notes" rid="fn001">
<sup>*</sup>
</xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="aff1">
<sup>1</sup>
<institution>Cadre Ward Two, General Hospital of Central Theater Command of the People&#x02019;s Liberation Army</institution>, <addr-line>Wuhan</addr-line>, <country>China</country>
</aff><aff id="aff2">
<sup>2</sup>
<institution>Department of Oncology, General Hospital of Central Theater Command of the People&#x02019;s Liberation Army</institution>, <addr-line>Wuhan</addr-line>, <country>China</country>
</aff><author-notes><fn fn-type="edited-by"><p>Edited by: Nihal Ahmad, University of Wisconsin-Madison, United States</p></fn><fn fn-type="edited-by"><p>Reviewed by: Nicola Pimpinelli, University of Florence, Italy; Mauro Alaibac, University of Padua, Italy</p></fn><corresp id="fn001">*Correspondence: Li Wang, <email xlink:href="mailto:w18062575475@163.com" xlink:type="simple">w18062575475@163.com</email>; Cheng Xu, <email xlink:href="mailto:xucheng11med@163.com" xlink:type="simple">xucheng11med@163.com</email></corresp><fn fn-type="other" id="fn002"><p>This article was submitted to Skin Cancer, a section of the journal Frontiers in Oncology</p></fn></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>23</day><month>3</month><year>2021</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2021</year></pub-date><volume>11</volume><elocation-id>658907</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>26</day><month>1</month><year>2021</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>02</day><month>3</month><year>2021</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2021 Wu, Xu and Wang</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2021</copyright-year><copyright-holder>Wu, Xu and Wang</copyright-holder><license xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"><license-p>This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License (CC BY). The use, distribution or reproduction in other forums is permitted, provided the original author(s) and the copyright owner(s) are credited and that the original publication in this journal is cited, in accordance with accepted academic practice. No use, distribution or reproduction is permitted which does not comply with these terms.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract><p>We report a rare case of a 92-year-old male, with a history of statin/ezetimibe intake, complained of pain and swelling of left forearm. The patient was diagnosed with focal myositis at first. Symptoms aggravated after 2 months of immunomodulatory therapy, and accompanied with protrusion lesion at left elbow. Biopsy of the protrusion lesion turned out to be primary cutaneous diffuse large B-cell lymphoma.</p></abstract><kwd-group><kwd>statin</kwd><kwd>ezetimibe</kwd><kwd>focal myositis</kwd><kwd>PCDLBCL</kwd><kwd>CK-MB</kwd></kwd-group><counts><fig-count count="4"/><table-count count="0"/><equation-count count="0"/><ref-count count="19"/><page-count count="5"/><word-count count="1153"/></counts></article-meta></front><body><sec sec-type="intro" id="s1"><title>Introduction</title><p>Focal myositis (FM) is a rare and benign dysimmune disease characterized as a rapidly growing solitary mass within a single muscle, which usually involved in lower limbs and experienced self-regression in most cases (<xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>). Although several reported cases suggest some triggering factors such as nerve lesions, traumatic muscle lesions and autoimmune diseases (<xref rid="B2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="B4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>), the etiology of FM remains unclear.</p><p>Primary cutaneous diffuse large B-cell lymphoma (PCDLBCL), leg type is a rare malignancy, which make up approximately 4% of all cutaneous lymphomas and 20% of all primary cutaneous B cell lymphomas (CBCLs) (<xref rid="B5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>). PCDLBCL commonly occurs on one or both legs, with 10 to 15% of cases involving other sites. The 5-year survival of PCDLBCL is approximately 50%, which is far worse than other CBCLs (<xref rid="B6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>, <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>).</p><p>Here we report an old male patient with left forearm lesion, considered FM at first, while diagnosed with PCDLBCL 4.5 months later, and the patient finally succumbed to severe infection.</p></sec><sec id="s2"><title>Case Presentation</title><p>A 92-year-old male, claimed left forearm swelling for 5 months, and aggravated with pain for 3 weeks. The patient denied recent special illness, travel and injury. Medical history included hypertension, sick sinus syndrome, cardiac pacemaker implantation and hyperlipemia. He had taken rosuvastatin 10 mg/ezetimibe 10 mg discontinuously for 20 months and withdrawn both for 5 months. Current medications are Amlodipine Besylate.</p><p>Physical examination showed Lateral elbow joint swelling and obvious tenderness of left forearm. Laboratory test showed elevated level of creatine phosphate kinase isoenzyme (CK-MB 85.52 ng/ml), erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR), C-reactive protein (CRP) and Carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA) were within normal ranges. Antinuclear antibody assay showed positive result. The patient refused to accept magnetic resonance imaging, instead, Ultrasonography was performed and showed hypo-echoic area in superficial fascia layer of the left forearm (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f1">
<bold>Figure 1</bold>
</xref>). Ultrasonography guided incisional muscle biopsy were performed. Muscle biopsy (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
<bold>Figures 2A, B</bold>
</xref>
<bold>)</bold> showed focal muscle fiber degeneration, increased perimysial cells, and a few inflammatory cells infiltrate around the interstitial blood vessels.</p><fig id="f1" position="float"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>Ultrasonography of left forearm before the diagnosis of focal myositis.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fonc-11-658907-g001"/></fig><fig id="f2" position="float"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>
<bold>(A)</bold>: left forearm biopsy, HE &#x000d7; 100. <bold>(B)</bold>: left forearm biopsy, HE &#x000d7; 200. <bold>(C)</bold>: Protrusion lesion biopsy of left elbow, HE &#x000d7; 100. <bold>(D)</bold>: Protrusion lesion biopsy of left elbow, HE &#x000d7; 400.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fonc-11-658907-g002"/></fig><p>Patient was diagnosed with focal myositis after a multidisciplinary consultation and treated with prednisone (initial dose 30 mg po qd, 5 mg dose reduction per week) and leflunomide (10 mg po qd). Left forearm swelling and tenderness improved accompanied with the decrease of CK-MB level. One month later, left forearm swelling aggravated. Leflunomide was replaced by methotrexate (10 mg po per week), and dosage of prednisone was increased to 30 mg po qd and kept for one month. The serum level of CK-MB decreased to normal and the dosage of prednisone was reduced to 25 mg po qd. But since then left forearm swelling was getting worse, accompanied with protrusion lesion at left elbow (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f3">
<bold>Figure 3</bold>
</xref>) and elevated skin temperature in local, meanwhile the patient claimed severe fatigue and lost self-care ability, regimen of methotrexate plus prednisone was abandoned. Another blood test showed an elevated serum CEA level (9.45 ng/ml), CRP level (174.15 mg/ml) and white blood cell count (11.9 &#x02217; 10<sup>9</sup>/L). Chest radiography indicated the existence of infection and Interstitial inflammation of both lungs. Protrusion lesion biopsy of left elbow was taken and antibiotics were used to control infection. The protrusion lesion biopsy turned out to be PCDLBCL (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
<bold>Figures 2C, D</bold>
</xref>
<bold>)</bold>, immunohistochemical staining: PCK (&#x02212;), VIM (+), S-100 (&#x02212;), HMB45 (&#x02212;),CD3 (+, sporadic), CD20 (+, diffused), CD30 (&#x02212;), Ki67 (+, &#x0003e;90%), EBER (&#x02212;), ALK (&#x02212;), CyclinD1 (&#x02212;), CD5 (+, sporadic), CD15 (&#x02212;), PAX-5 (+), CD79a (+), CD10 (&#x02212;), CD21&#x000a0;(&#x02212;), Bcl-6 (+), Mum-1 (+), P53 (+, sporadic), C-myc (+, 30%), Bcl-2 (+, diffused). Due to poor physical condition and severe lung infection, patient was suggested with best supportive care and died of respiratory failure. Dynamic change of serum CK-MB levels during the course were shown in <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
<bold>Figure 4</bold>
</xref>. Written informed consent was obtained from the patient at the diagnosis of PCDLBCL, ethical approval was waived according to the Declaration of Helsinki.</p><fig id="f3" position="float"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>Protrusion lesion of left elbow.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fonc-11-658907-g003"/></fig><fig id="f4" position="float"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>Dynamic change of serum CK-MB levels during the course.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="fonc-11-658907-g004"/></fig></sec><sec sec-type="discussion" id="s3"><title>Discussion</title><p>FM shared some clinical features with many diseases such as nodular or granulomatous myositis and soft tissue tumors, which brings difficulties for FM diagnosis. Clinical symptoms, magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), blood tests and biopsy help to make an accurate diagnosis. In our case, despite the lack of MRI, clinical course, physical examination, elevated CK-MB and pathology support the diagnosis.</p><p>In this case, the patient has received rosuvastatin/ezetimibe for a long time before the occurrence of left forearm tenderness. Statins are a group of drugs that reduce the levels of triglycerides and cholesterol in blood by inhibiting HMG-CoA reductase, an enzyme involved in rate limiting step in cholesterol synthesis, the incidence of statin-induced myotoxicity is estimated as 0.1&#x02013;0.5% in cases of monotherapy (<xref rid="B8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>). Ezetimibe inhibits cholesterol absorption from the small intestine by blocking the Niemann-Pick C1-like protein (<xref rid="B9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>). Both statins and ezetimibe intake are reported to be associated with induction of myositis (<xref rid="B10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="B12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>).</p><p>Interestingly, Ye et&#x000a0;al. showed that statin intake may reduce the risk of diffuse large B cell lymphoma (<xref rid="B13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>). Though statins may play a role in cancer prevention through cholesterol and cholesterol independent pathways (<xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>&#x02013;<xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>), statins may induce myositis in rare situations, and inflammation is one of the cancer-causing factors (<xref rid="B17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>, <xref rid="B18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>). In addition to our report, we noticed another reported case diagnosed with both statin-induced myopathy and extranodal marginal zone lymphoma (<xref rid="B19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>). As we know, inflammation is one of the cancer-causing factor, in this case, the persistent focal myositis, possibly caused by statins/ezetimibe, may play a role in the oncogenesis of primary cutaneous large B-cell lymphoma.</p></sec><sec sec-type="data-availability" id="s4"><title>Data Availability Statement</title><p>The original contributions presented in the study are included in the article/supplementary material. Further inquiries can be directed to the corresponding authors.</p></sec><sec id="s5"><title>Ethics Statement</title><p>The studies involving human participants were reviewed and approved by the ethics committee of the General Hospital of Central Theater Command. The patients/participants provided their written informed consent to participate in this study. Written informed consent was obtained from the individual(s) for the publication of any potentially identifiable images or data included in this article.</p></sec><sec id="s6"><title>Author Contributions</title><p>QW offered the case and collected the data. CX prepared the manuscript. LW revised the manuscript. All authors contributed to the article and approved the submitted version.</p></sec><sec sec-type="COI-statement" id="s7"><title>Conflict of Interest</title><p>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</p></sec></body><back><ack><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>We thank the patient for his cooperation and support for academic communication, and thank the department of pathology for providing diagnostic support.</p></ack><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="B1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Devic</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Gallay</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name><surname>Streichenberger</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Petiot</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Focal myositis: A review</article-title>. <source>Neuromuscul Disord NMD</source> (<year>2016</year>) <volume>26</volume>:<page-range>725&#x02013;33</page-range>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.nmd.2016.08.014</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lunde</surname><given-names>HM</given-names></name><name><surname>Skeie</surname><given-names>GO</given-names></name><name><surname>Bertelsen</surname><given-names>AK</given-names></name><name><surname>Karlsen</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Miletic</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Lindal</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Focal myositis&#x02013;neurogenic phenomenon</article-title>? <source>Neuromuscul Disord NMD</source> (<year>2012</year>) <volume>22</volume>:<page-range>350&#x02013;4</page-range>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.nmd.2011.10.023</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Auerbach</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Fanburg-Smith</surname><given-names>JC</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Rushing</surname><given-names>EJ</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Focal myositis: a clinicopathologic study of 115 cases of an intramuscular mass-like reactive process</article-title>. <source>Am J Surg Pathol</source> (<year>2009</year>) <volume>33</volume>:<page-range>1016&#x02013;24</page-range>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/PAS.0b013e31819e63fe</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sarui</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Maruyama</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Ito</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name><surname>Yamakita</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Takeda</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Nose</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Necrotising myositis in Behcet&#x02019;s disease: characteristic features on magnetic resonance imaging and a review of the literature</article-title>. <source>Ann Rheum Dis</source> (<year>2002</year>) <volume>61</volume>:<page-range>751&#x02013;2</page-range>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/ard.61.8.751</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Pinter-Brown</surname><given-names>LC</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Diagnosis and Management of Cutaneous B-cell Lymphoma</article-title>. <source>Dermatol Clinics</source> (<year>2015</year>) <volume>33</volume>:<page-range>835&#x02013;40</page-range>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.det.2015.05.003</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Vermeer</surname><given-names>MH</given-names></name><name><surname>Geelen</surname><given-names>FA</given-names></name><name><surname>van Haselen</surname><given-names>CW</given-names></name><name><surname>van Voorst Vader</surname><given-names>PC</given-names></name><name><surname>Geerts</surname><given-names>ML</given-names></name><name><surname>van Vloten</surname><given-names>WA</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Primary cutaneous large B-cell lymphomas of the legs. A distinct type of cutaneous B-cell lymphoma with an intermediate prognosis. Dutch Cutaneous Lymphoma Working Group</article-title>. <source>Arch Dermatol</source> (<year>1996</year>) <volume>132</volume>:<page-range>1304&#x02013;8</page-range>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/archderm.132.11.1304</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Grange</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Bekkenk</surname><given-names>MW</given-names></name><name><surname>Wechsler</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Meijer</surname><given-names>CJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Cerroni</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name><surname>Bernengo</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Prognostic factors in primary cutaneous large B-cell lymphomas: a European multicenter study</article-title>. <source>J Clin Oncol Off J Am Soc Clin Oncol</source> (<year>2001</year>) <volume>19</volume>:<page-range>3602&#x02013;10</page-range>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1200/JCO.2001.19.16.3602</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sirvent</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Mercier</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Lacampagne</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>New insights into mechanisms of statin-associated myotoxicity</article-title>. <source>Curr Opin Pharmacol</source> (<year>2008</year>) <volume>8</volume>:<page-range>333&#x02013;8</page-range>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.coph.2007.12.010</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Garcia-Calvo</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Lisnock</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Bull</surname><given-names>HG</given-names></name><name><surname>Hawes</surname><given-names>BE</given-names></name><name><surname>Burnett</surname><given-names>DA</given-names></name><name><surname>Braun</surname><given-names>MP</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>The target of ezetimibe is Niemann-Pick C1-Like 1 (NPC1L1)</article-title>. <source>Proc Natl Acad Sci USA</source> (<year>2005</year>) <volume>102</volume>:<page-range>8132&#x02013;7</page-range>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1073/pnas.0500269102</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Asbach</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Paetsch</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name><surname>Stawowy</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name><surname>Sander</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Fleck</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Statin-associated focal myositis</article-title>. <source>Int J Cardiol</source> (<year>2009</year>) <volume>133</volume>:<page-range>e33&#x02013;4</page-range>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2007.08.109</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wagner</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Muhldorfer-Fodor</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Prommersberger</surname><given-names>KJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Schmitt</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Statin-induced focal myositis of the upper extremity. A report of two cases</article-title>. <source>Eur J Radiol</source> (<year>2011</year>) <volume>77</volume>:<page-range>258&#x02013;60</page-range>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ejrad.2010.12.031</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Garcia-Valladares</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name><surname>Espinoza</surname><given-names>LR</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Ezetimibe-induced relapsing polymyositis</article-title>. <source>J&#x000a0;Rheumatol</source> (<year>2010</year>) <volume>37</volume>:<fpage>472</fpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3899/jrheum.090660</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20147486</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B13"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ye</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Righolt</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Johnston</surname><given-names>JB</given-names></name><name><surname>Banerji</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name><surname>Gibson</surname><given-names>SB</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>. <article-title>Associations between statin use and risk of non-Hodgkin lymphomas by subtype</article-title>. <source>Int J Cancer</source> (<year>2018</year>) <volume>143</volume>:<page-range>971&#x02013;9</page-range>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/ijc.31373</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B14"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Vallianou</surname><given-names>NG</given-names></name><name><surname>Kostantinou</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Kougias</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Kazazis</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Statins and cancer</article-title>. <source>Anti-cancer Agents Med Chem</source> (<year>2014</year>) <volume>14</volume>:<page-range>706&#x02013;12</page-range>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2174/1871520613666131129105035</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B15"><label>15</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Demierre</surname><given-names>MF</given-names></name><name><surname>Higgins</surname><given-names>PD</given-names></name><name><surname>Gruber</surname><given-names>SB</given-names></name><name><surname>Hawk</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name><surname>Lippman</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Statins and cancer prevention</article-title>. <source>Nat Rev Cancer</source> (<year>2005</year>) <volume>5</volume>:<page-range>930&#x02013;42</page-range>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nrc1751</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B16"><label>16</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Murai</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Cholesterol lowering: role in cancer prevention and treatment</article-title>. <source>Biol Chem</source> (<year>2015</year>) <volume>396</volume>:<fpage>1</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>11</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1515/hsz-2014-0194</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25205720</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B17"><label>17</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Murata</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Inflammation and cancer</article-title>. <source>Environ Health Prev Med</source> (<year>2018</year>) <volume>23</volume>:<fpage>50</fpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12199-018-0740-1</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30340457</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B18"><label>18</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Singh</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Mishra</surname><given-names>MK</given-names></name><name><surname>Aggarwal</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Inflammation, Immunity, and Cancer</article-title>. <source>Mediators Inflammation</source> (<year>2017</year>) <volume>2017</volume>:<fpage>6027305</fpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1155/2017/6027305</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="B19"><label>19</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Michiels</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Dierickx</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Taelman</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name><surname>Tousseyn</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Lenaerts</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>De Langhe</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>One biopsy, two diagnoses: statin-induced autoimmune myopathy in combination with extranodal marginal zone lymphoma</article-title>. <source>Clin Exp Rheumatol</source> (<year>2017</year>) <volume>35</volume>:<fpage>717</fpage>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28516888</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>