<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>A limitation on all HR‐QoL studies has been the high proportion of missing data. Although the returned questionnaires were largely complete, there was a substantial number of questionnaires missing at each time point, the baseline questionnaire having the worst return rate. To avoid the exclusion of a large proportion of patient data at later time points, MICE was implemented to impute any missing question answers or baseline measurements. MICE was chosen as it is a suitable stochastic method which is easy to implement (
 <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://stats.idre.ucla.edu/sas/seminars/multiple-imputation-in-sas/mi_new_1/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">https://stats.idre.ucla.edu/sas/seminars/multiple-imputation-in-sas/mi_new_1/</ext-link>), and has been applied in a number of recent clinical trials (Ali 
 <italic>et al</italic>, 
 <xref rid="bjh15459-bib-0003" ref-type="ref">2013</xref>; Coates 
 <italic>et al</italic>, 
 <xref rid="bjh15459-bib-0004" ref-type="ref">2015</xref>; Neoptolemos 
 <italic>et al</italic>, 
 <xref rid="bjh15459-bib-0018" ref-type="ref">2017</xref>). MICE assumes that the missing data are missing at random (MAR). i.e., the data is missing conditional on the information that is observed. MAR is an untestable assumption; however, it was thought to be acceptable as the questionnaires were administered at definitive (randomisation‐based) rather than subjective (treatment‐ or disease‐based) time points. In addition, sensitivity analyses also showed that results obtained using MICE were consistent with those obtained in a complete case analysis. An alternative criticism could be the choice to exclude any corrections for multiplicity. As only a subset of the total number of endpoints (4 out of 20) and time points (3 out of 7) were pre‐specified and modelled as of primary interest (generating 36 out of a possible 1020 tests) it was deemed not necessary. However, had we adjusted for the 36 simultaneous tests the results and conclusions would not have deviated from those discussed here given the small number of statistically significant results.
</p>
