<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Food was removed 12 h prior to anesthesia and BAL procedures. A clinical exam was performed on all cynomolgus macaques to ensure they were healthy. BALs were performed on anesthetized animals with intramuscular injection of Zoletil 50 (tiletamine and zolazepam – Virbac, France) at 3 mg/kg and Rompun 2% (xylazine – Elanco, Germany) at 0.8 mg/kg. Once anesthetized, the macaques were positioned in sternal recumbency on a lifting surgical table. A heating mat was used to limit the hypothermia and one drop of Ocry-gel (carbopol – TVM, France) was applied to the cornea of each eye to prevent dryness. A laryngoscope Miller (Alcyon, France – reference 8017974) was used to visualize the epiglottis, then Xylocaine 5% (lidocaine – Aspen France) was sprayed for local anesthesia. The tongue was gently extended outward with soft pliers after the local anesthetic was allowed to take effect. Macaques were intubated using an uncuffed endotracheal tube with a diameter of 3.5 mm (Alcyon, France – reference 8362375). A silicon spray (Alcyon France – reference 8040708) was used to lubricate the endotracheal tube. Then, a collection catheter (40 cm long, Vygon, France - reference 6281365) was passed down the endotracheal tube to infuse a solution of 5 mL/kg of isotonic sodium chloride NaCl 0.9% at 37°C, based on internal experience and previously published BAL procedure (
 <xref rid="B7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>). The infusion and the collection were done using a syringe of 50 mL (BD Plastipak, Becton, Dickinson and Company, USA New Jersey), and about half of the solution was recovered. The duration of the procedure between the anesthesia and the collection was ~15 min. Right after the collection, the catheter was pulled off and the macaques were placed under the surveillance of the clinical veterinarian on a recovery table also equipped with heat mats. The endotracheal tube was connected to an oxygen supply, oxygenation, and cardiac rhythm were monitored with a PM60VET oximeter (Mindray Medical – reference 8288905 at Alcyon, France). An average of 15 min was necessary until oxygen and heart rate returned to normality (&gt;95% of oxygen and ~100 beats per minute). For a faster awakening, 0.04 mL/kg of Antisedan (atipamezole – Orion corporation, Finland) was injected into the animals by intramuscular route. No untoward effect was noted during or following fluid instillation and the macaques woke up normally after 1 h.
</p>
