<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par24">Mortality from GvHD and infection accounted for the vast majority of NRM in Haplo-HSCT. In our study, NRM was 9.4%, which was comparable to Haplo-HSCT with PTCy regimen and significantly lower than ATG-based GvHD prophylaxis regimens. No patient died from GvHD and only two patients died from infection. Because of the poor immunologic reconstitution, the rate of susceptibility to infection in Haplo-HSCT is higher than HLA-matched HSCT, especially with ATG-based regimens. Tischer et al. [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>] retrospectively compared the incidence of virus infections and outcomes in the context of immune reconstitution between PTCy and ATG-based regimens. The results showed that the incidence of herpes virus infection was markedly lower in the PTCy group (22%) than in the ATG group (93%) and the recovery of CD4
 <sup>+</sup> T cells on day +100 was faster in the PTCy group. CMV reactivation was also lower in the PTCy group than in the ATG group (30 
 <italic>vs</italic> 57%), virus infection-related mortality (VIRM) was significantly lower in the PTCy group (1-year VIRM, 0% PTCy 
 <italic>vs</italic> 29% ATG; 
 <italic>p</italic> = 0.009). Twenty-five percent of the patients in the ATG group but no patient in the PTCy group developed PTLD. In our study, median CD4
 <sup>+</sup> lymphocyte counts were 104/μl on day +100, which were similar with ATG-based regimens (102/μl) and lower than with PTCy (206/μl) at the same time, but on day +120, CD4+ lymphocyte counts with 240/μl reached the level on day +100 in the PTCy group and higher than that (157/μl) on+180 days in the ATG-based group [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>]. These data might imply that immune recovery was faster in our study than with ATG-based regimens and just a little slower than with PTCy regimen. The CIs of CMV and EBV reactivation by day +180 were 37.5% (95% CI, 19.8−55.2%) and 40.6% (95% CI, 22.6−58.6%), respectively, which were lower than with ATG-based regimens and comparable to the PTCy regimen.
</p>
