<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<abstract>
 <p>We determined the incidence of disability related to chronic graft-
  <italic>versus</italic>-host disease (bronchiolitis obliterans, grade ≥2 keratoconjunctivitis sicca, sclerotic features or esophageal stricture) for three categories of alternative donor: cord blood, haplorelated marrow or peripheral blood with post-transplant cyclophosphamide, and unrelated single HLA-allele mismatched peripheral blood. Among 396 consecutive hematopoietic cell transplant recipients, 129 developed chronic graft-
  <italic>versus</italic>-host disease with 3-year cumulative incidences of 8% for cord blood, 24% for haplorelated grafts, and 55% for unrelated single HLA-allele mismatched peripheral blood. Disability rates were significantly lower for cord blood [hazard ratio (HR) 0.13; 95% confidence interval (CI): 0.1-0.4] and for the haplorelated group (HR 0.31; 95% CI: 0.1-0.7) compared to the rate in the group transplanted with unrelated single HLA-allele mismatched peripheral blood. Cord blood recipients were also &gt;2-fold more likely to return to work/school within 3 years from the onset of chronic graft-
  <italic>versus</italic>-host disease (HR 2.54; 95% CI: 1.1-5.7, 
  <italic>P</italic>=0.02), and the haplorelated group trended similarly (HR 2.38; 95% CI: 1.0-5.9, 
  <italic>P</italic>=0.06). Cord blood recipients were more likely to discontinue immunosuppression than were recipients of unrelated single HLA-allele mismatched peripheral blood (HR 3.96; 95% CI: 1.9-8.4, 
  <italic>P</italic>=0.0003), similarly to the haplorelated group (HR 4.93; 95% CI: 2.2-11.1, 
  <italic>P</italic>=0.0001). Progression-free survival and non-relapse mortality did not differ between groups grafted from different types of donors. Our observations that, compared to recipients of unrelated single HLA-allele mismatched peripheral blood, recipients of cord blood and haplorelated grafts less often developed disability related to chronic graft-
  <italic>versus</italic>-host disease, and were more likely to resume work/school, should help better counseling of pre-hematopoietic cell transplant candidates.
 </p>
</abstract>
