<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par3">Ixazomib citrate (MLN9708) is an investigational inhibitor of the 20S proteasome that represents the first orally bioavailable proteasome inhibitor to be evaluated for treatment of MM
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>
 </sup>. Ixazomib citrate is a modified peptide boronic acid and is the citrate ester of ixazomib (MLN2238), the biologically active moiety. Ixazomib citrate rapidly hydrolyzes to ixazomib upon contact with aqueous solution or plasma. Ixazomib preferentially binds the β
 <sub>5</sub> site of the 20S proteasome at lower doses, with inhibition of the β
 <sub>1</sub> and β
 <sub>2</sub> sites at higher concentrations. Compared to bortezomib, nonclinical studies have shown that ixazomib has a faster dissociation rate from the proteasome. Ixazomib has demonstrated antitumor activity in a range of tumor xenograft models, including MM models
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>
 </sup>. In clinical trials, ixazomib has shown promising activity as a single agent in patients with relapsed and refractory MM, with very low rates of peripheral neuropathy observed in single agent trials
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>
 </sup>. Ixazomib has shown considerable efficacy in combination with immunomodulatory drugs in newly diagnosed and relapsed, refractory myeloma
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>,
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>–
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>
 </sup>. It is approved is over 50 countries for use in relapsed myeloma, based on the results of a phase 3 trial demonstrating improved PFS when added to lenalidomide and dexamethasone. Given the significant clinical activity of the VCD regimen in previously untreated MM, we wanted to explore the efficacy of replacing bortezomib with ixazomib in combination with cyclophosphamide and dexamethasone.
</p>
