<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>After the patient entered the room, ECG, BP, SpO
 <sub>2</sub>, and P
 <sub>ET</sub>CO
 <sub>2</sub> were routinely monitored, and the contralateral upper extremity venous access was opened. The contralateral radial artery was punctured and catheterized under local anesthesia (heparin anticoagulation is retained the blood samples are collected and arterial invasive blood pressure is monitored). The Anesthesia index (AI) was used to monitor the depth of anesthesia, and the TOF was used to monitor the degree of muscle relaxation. Anesthesia induction consisted of an intravenous injection of midazolam 0.06 mg/kg, sufentanil 0.5 μg/kg, etomidate 0.3 mg/kg, cisatracurium besylate 0.15 mg/kg and remifentanil 1 μg/kg. When the TOF value dropped to zero, an F37 or F35 double-lumen bronchial tube was inserted through the mouth using a fiberoptic bronchoscope positioning for males and females, respectively, but the specific size of double-lumen bronchial tube is adjusted according to the actual situation of patients. After tracheal intubation, mechanical ventilation was performed. Inhaled oxygen concentration was maintained at 60% and oxygen flow at 2 L/min, V
 <sub>T</sub>6–8 mL/kg, RR 10–14 times/min, inhalation–expiration ratio 1:2, RR 12–16 times/min in OLV. Other ventilation parameters remained unchanged and P
 <sub>ET</sub>CO
 <sub>2</sub> was maintained at 35–45 mmHg. Maintenance of anesthesia was achieved via an intravenous pump injection of propofol 4–12 mg/kg/h, remifentanil 0.2–0.3 μg/kg/h, and cisatracurium 0.06–0.12 mg/kg/h. The propofol infusion rate was adjusted to maintain the depth of anesthesia index value between 40 and 60 and to maintain the heart rate (HR) and mean arterial pressure (MAP) fluctuation range within 20% of the baseline value. Intraoperative intravenous infusion of Sodium Potassium Magnesium Calcium and Glucose Injection which consisted of crystalloid solution (multiple electrolytes of sodium, potassium, magnesium, calcium, glucose) and succinyl gelatin in a volume ratio of 2:1. Propofol was stopped 5 min before the end of the operation. Intravenous atropine injection of 0.25–0.50 mg was given while intraoperative HR was below 50 beats/min, and esmolol 10–20 mg was administered when the HR was higher than 100 beats/min. When MAP exceeded 20% of the baseline, if AI was higher than 60, propofol infusion rate should be increased to maintain AI at 40–60. If AI is between 40 and 60, MAP is still 20% higher than the baseline, a remifentanil bolus of 0.5 μg/kg is given every 2 min to deepen the depth of anesthesia and maintain hemodynamic stability. To avoid the inhibition of hypoxic pulmonary vasoconstriction by sevoflurane, induction, and maintenance should avoid the use of sevoflurane. If this was not sufficient to control MAP, intravenous urapidil 15–25 mg was administered. Conversely, an intravenous injection of ephedrine 3–6 mg or phenylephrine 40–80 μg was administered if MAP was reduced by more than 20% of the preoperative level.
</p>
