<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ack>
 <title>Authors’ contributions</title>
 <p>JPR, NHR, NF, and ML designed the study. JPR, IM, and GF supervised the study. GF, NF, ML, DaM, and DeM were involved in data collection, NA in data management, and IM in project management. DeM and DaM were clinical monitors and audited treatment and follow-up assessments. DeM was involved in compilation, record keeping, and statistical summaries. NF, ML, DaM and DeM performed the statistical analysis, and interpreted the data. NF, ML, DaM, DeM, DA, SK, and NHR searched the literature. NF, ML, and DeM wrote and edited the first draft of this manuscript, organized the manuscript layout, and created the figures. DA edited this manuscript to its final form and revised the figures. SK and ANP reviewed the analyses and manuscript, and provided academic feedback. All authors provided feedback and helped shape the research, analysis and manuscript. All authors read and approved the final manuscript.</p>
 <sec id="FPar1">
  <title>Acknowledgements</title>
  <p id="Par40">The authors would like to thank Jay Lenner for management and updating study information on clinicaltrials.gov, as well as MediStem Panama and Stem Cell Institute staff for their laboratory, medical and administrative assistance.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="FPar2">
  <title>Competing interests</title>
  <p id="Par41">NHR and JPR are shareholders of Translational Biosciences, MediStem Panama, and the Stem Cell Institute. The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="FPar3">
  <title>Availability of data and materials</title>
  <p id="Par42">The datasets generated and/or analyzed during the current study are available from the corresponding author on reasonable request.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="FPar4">
  <title>Ethics approval and consent to participate</title>
  <p id="Par43">The study was approved by the Panamanian Institutional Review Board (Comité Nacional de Ética de la Investigación, IORG0007644) under Protocol Number TBS-UCMSC-001. The study was designed in the spirit of ethical principles with origin in the Declaration of Helsinki or equivalent, and consistent with Good Clinical Practices. All subjects and donors gave informed consent to participate in the study.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="FPar5">
  <title>Consent for publication</title>
  <p id="Par44">Not applicable.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="FPar6">
  <title>Funding</title>
  <p id="Par45">The study sponsor was Translational Biosciences. The study sponsor had no role in the design of this study, its execution, analysis, interpretation of the data, writing, or decision to submit results.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="FPar7">
  <title>Publisher’s Note</title>
  <p id="Par46">Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p>
 </sec>
</ack>
