<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Patient was diagnosed with focal myositis after a multidisciplinary consultation and treated with prednisone (initial dose 30 mg po qd, 5 mg dose reduction per week) and leflunomide (10 mg po qd). Left forearm swelling and tenderness improved accompanied with the decrease of CK-MB level. One month later, left forearm swelling aggravated. Leflunomide was replaced by methotrexate (10 mg po per week), and dosage of prednisone was increased to 30 mg po qd and kept for one month. The serum level of CK-MB decreased to normal and the dosage of prednisone was reduced to 25 mg po qd. But since then left forearm swelling was getting worse, accompanied with protrusion lesion at left elbow (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f3">
  <bold>Figure 3</bold>
 </xref>) and elevated skin temperature in local, meanwhile the patient claimed severe fatigue and lost self-care ability, regimen of methotrexate plus prednisone was abandoned. Another blood test showed an elevated serum CEA level (9.45 ng/ml), CRP level (174.15 mg/ml) and white blood cell count (11.9 ∗ 10
 <sup>9</sup>/L). Chest radiography indicated the existence of infection and Interstitial inflammation of both lungs. Protrusion lesion biopsy of left elbow was taken and antibiotics were used to control infection. The protrusion lesion biopsy turned out to be PCDLBCL (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f2">
  <bold>Figures 2C, D</bold>
 </xref>
 <bold>)</bold>, immunohistochemical staining: PCK (−), VIM (+), S-100 (−), HMB45 (−),CD3 (+, sporadic), CD20 (+, diffused), CD30 (−), Ki67 (+, &gt;90%), EBER (−), ALK (−), CyclinD1 (−), CD5 (+, sporadic), CD15 (−), PAX-5 (+), CD79a (+), CD10 (−), CD21 (−), Bcl-6 (+), Mum-1 (+), P53 (+, sporadic), C-myc (+, 30%), Bcl-2 (+, diffused). Due to poor physical condition and severe lung infection, patient was suggested with best supportive care and died of respiratory failure. Dynamic change of serum CK-MB levels during the course were shown in 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="f4">
  <bold>Figure 4</bold>
 </xref>. Written informed consent was obtained from the patient at the diagnosis of PCDLBCL, ethical approval was waived according to the Declaration of Helsinki.
</p>
