<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Several growth factors are currently approved or are under clinical development in the United States (US) for the management of chemotherapy‐induced neutropenia. Filgrastim (Neupogen®, Amgen, Thousand Oaks, CA) is the methionylated recombinant human granulocyte‐colony stimulating factor (G‐CSF) expressed in 
 <italic>E. coli</italic> and is administered as a daily subcutaneous injection (or by intravenous infusion) in conjunction with myelosuppressive chemotherapy to increase the circulating levels of neutrophils and thereby reduce the duration of severe neutropenia 
 <xref rid="cam41388-bib-0006" ref-type="ref">6</xref>. However, a full response to filgrastim requires multiple daily injections due to a short (several hours) half‐life. Pegfilgrastim (Neulasta®, Amgen, Thousand Oaks, CA), the polyethylene glycol‐conjugated form of G‐CSF, is a long‐acting myeloid growth factor that is administered subcutaneously (SC) on a more convenient, less frequent dosing schedule (i.e., as a single dose administered once‐per‐cycle of chemotherapy) and has demonstrated improved reduction of neutropenia over both placebo and filgrastim 
 <xref rid="cam41388-bib-0007" ref-type="ref">7</xref>, 
 <xref rid="cam41388-bib-0008" ref-type="ref">8</xref>, 
 <xref rid="cam41388-bib-0009" ref-type="ref">9</xref>, 
 <xref rid="cam41388-bib-0010" ref-type="ref">10</xref>, 
 <xref rid="cam41388-bib-0011" ref-type="ref">11</xref>, 
 <xref rid="cam41388-bib-0012" ref-type="ref">12</xref>, 
 <xref rid="cam41388-bib-0013" ref-type="ref">13</xref>. Two additional (currently not approved in the US) glyco‐pegylated growth factors, lipegfilgrastim and balugrastim, as well as a pegfilgrastim biosimilar, LA‐EP2006, have demonstrated noninferiority to pegfilgrastim as once‐per‐cycle administrations in Phase 3 trials conducted in patients with breast cancer 
 <xref rid="cam41388-bib-0014" ref-type="ref">14</xref>, 
 <xref rid="cam41388-bib-0015" ref-type="ref">15</xref>.
</p>
