<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>(1) Patients presented in one of the three clinics with vertigo or dizziness in the course of routine care. (2) A standard patient history was taken. Patients underwent a routine physical neurological, neuro-otological, and neuro-ophthalmological examination, including diagnostic maneuvers for BPPV. Standardized non-invasive laboratory testing with the video-head impulse test and caloric testing was performed. (3) The diagnosis of pcBPPVcan was made using the current diagnostic criteria (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>). (4) The patient was informed about the study. (5) The patient gave his/her written consent. (6) Randomization (1:1) to each of the treatment groups, one-by-one in consecutive order. This was documented on a randomization list kept at each participating site, containing the number, SM or SM+, name, and date of birth of the patient. (7) SM or the SM+ (
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F1">Figure 1</xref> and 
 <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SM1">Supplementary Video 1</xref> of SM+) was carried out once. The angle of the head was measured using an AppStore App (“Kompass”) installed on iPhones, which can also be used as an inclinometer, so that standardized examination conditions were guaranteed. The Sémont maneuver means horizontal, i.e., 0°; SM+ means 60° beyond earth horizontal; each of the three positions (with the head turned toward the unaffected side) was maintained for 60 s: (1) movement of the patient's body toward the affected side; (2) movement of the body toward the unaffected side; (3) sitting upright. Fifteen to sixty minutes after the first therapeutic maneuver, a second diagnostic maneuver was performed to check the effect of the first maneuver, i.e., whether positional vertigo and/or positional nystagmus can be induced. Depending on randomization to SM or SM+, the patient independently carried out SM or SM+ three times in the morning, three times at noon, and three times in the evening as instructed. The patient noted how many days after the start of the SM or SM+ maneuver it took for him/her to no longer experience positional vertigo. The time point was the first maneuver in the morning of the day on which the patient was not able to induce positional spinning vertigo. This was documented by the patient using a standardized evaluation sheet. On the day of inclusion, patients received a written form with a standardized questionnaire and an envelope that they had to send back to the center.
</p>
