<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In the present study, TIAs were more frequently delayed and hemorrhages were observed only as peri-procedural events. AIS and TIA may be related to in-stent thrombosis with either reduced flow or emboli in the parent artery territory, whereas SAH were consecutive to per-procedural perforation. PH mechanism have been widely discussed considering adverse events consecutive to the use of antiplatelet agents (i.e., hemorrhagic worsening of a vessel perforation), or hyperperfusion syndrome after FD (
 <xref rid="B1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>). In the present cohort several imaging patterns, including MRI imaging suggest the occurrence of AIS hemorrhagic transformations for PH mechanism. 
 <xref ref-type="fig" rid="F2">Figure 2</xref> illustrates the case of a patient who presented with a neurological deficit 4 days after the procedure. Diffusion-weighted hypersignals co-localized with PH were supporting the ischemic mechanism, with in-stent thrombosis documented in the follow-up angiography. In respect to the 12 patients experiencing a TIA, a therapeutic change was undertaken mostly by the reintroduction of the antiplatelet therapy. Afterwards, none of the 12 patients presented a recurrent stroke. Of note, seven complications occurred within the first month following an antiplatelet agent cessation. These cases raise the question of the antiplatelet therapy optimal duration for FD. This duration and the nature of antiplatelet therapy remains unclear according to a recent meta-analysis (
 <xref rid="B14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>), which describes a 6.5% of ischemic complications vs. 3.9% of hemorrhagic complications after FD procedure. A prolonged use of antiplatelet therapy may lower ischemic complications but increase the hemorrhagic risk. Two other studies did systematic reviews and found similar rates, with an oassociation between ischemic complication and a duration of clopidogrel inferior to 6 months (
 <xref rid="B15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>, 
 <xref rid="B16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>). There is therefore a need to identify the population at higher risk of ischemic events. Patients with large MCA or vertebrobasilar aneurysms are potentially the subgroup of patients requiring a prolonged antiplatelet therapy. Additional evidences are needed to identify the patients that may benefit from a prolonged anti-thrombotic therapy.
</p>
