<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par88">We will conduct an intention-to-treat analysis whereby all participants will be included in the study in the group to which they were randomised. Analysis will be conducted by a biostatistician blinded to treatment group, with two-sided hypothesis tests and 
 <italic>p</italic>-values &lt; 0.05 significant. If the proportion of missing data exceeds 5%, missing outcome data will be imputed using multiple imputation methodology, and sensitivity to the missing at random assumption will be investigated [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>]. Changes from baseline will be presented for each group at 2- and 12-month time points using the mean change and 95% confidence intervals. For continuous outcomes (e.g. pain, cartilage volume, physical function), longitudinal analyses will be conducted, with differences in mean change (follow-up minus baseline) compared between the groups using mixed linear regression models with the baseline value, stratifying variables (Kellgren and Lawrence grade and injecting site) and an interaction between month and treatment group as covariates, including random effects for participants [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref>]. Models including baseline cartilage volume, age, gender, body mass index and cross-sectional area of the medial tibial plateau from MRI [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>] will also be fit. Appropriate transformations of outcome measures will be considered if needed to meet statistical assumptions (e.g. linearity, normality and homogeneity of residuals) as assessed using diagnostic plots. Binary outcomes will be compared between groups using risk differences calculated after fitting longitudinal regression models for binary outcomes, adjusted for stratification variables and accounting for clustering of measurements within participants. The other MRI-derived measurements (MOAKS, bone marrow lesion size and cartilage defects) will be compared between groups using appropriate models, adjusting for age, gender, body mass index, and the stratifying variables. The model for cartilage defects will also be adjusted for cross-sectional area of the medial tibial plateau [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>]. If appropriate, the effect of PRP on primary outcomes under hypothetical full adherence to assigned treatment will be investigated. The success of blinding will be assessed using the James Blinding Index [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref>].
</p>
