<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par17">Overall, the mechanism by which sertraline disrupts bone health and regeneration remains largely unknown. To try and elucidate if sertraline affects healing through direct modulation of serotonin within the fracture site, we investigated if serotonin levels were altered with sertraline treatment. We found that 5HT levels were significantly depleted with treatment, but TG2 serotonin transporter levels, while modulated, were not significantly downregulated. The maintenance of TG2 levels could be due to TG2 being involved in the transportation of other molecules;
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref>
 </sup> therefore, the reduction of one molecule, serotonin, would not substantially affect TG2 levels. Further investigation into the expression levels of serotonin-related genes showed that none of the cell types utilized in this study amplified 
 <italic>Thp2</italic>, the neuronal tryptophan hydroxylase.
 <sup>
  <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref>
 </sup> However, it was found that E1 cells showed a downregulation of both 
 <italic>Tph1</italic> and 
 <italic>Slc6a4</italic> at 7 days with sertraline treatment, indicating that sertraline may modulate the ability of pre-osteoblasts to synthesize serotonin or respond to extracellular serotonin through its cell surface receptor. WT cells showed a significant increase in both 
 <italic>Tph1</italic> and 
 <italic>Slc6a4</italic> at 7 days with sertraline treatment. The difference between the WT and E1 cellular response to sertraline treatment could be due to the WT population having a variety of cell types within it that respond to sertraline treatment by upregulating these genes. Interestingly, C2C12 cells did not amplify any of the serotonin-related genes, indicating that C2C12 cells might be involved in serotonin signalling pathways. Due to the observed disorganization of the collagen matrix within the sertraline-exposed animals, we investigated the 
 <italic>Col1a1</italic> and 
 <italic>Col1a2</italic> genes to determine if sertraline treatment directly affects the ability of E1, C2C12, BMSC or WT cells to produce collagen. We found that treatment reduced the expression levels of both of these genes at 7 days with low- and high-dose sertraline treatment for E1 and C2C12 cell types. The downregulation of these genes could explain the inhibited bone remodelling that occurred in our fracture model despite evidence that osteoblasts had enhanced ALP activity with sertraline exposure. The inhibition of these cells' capacity to produce collagen and therefore an organized matrix would hamper the ability of osteoblasts to lay down mineralized bone.
</p>
