<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="Par30">Even though not a primary endpoint, it should be highlighted that in the pre-plerixafor era 24/39 poor mobilizers (62%) proceeded to transplantation. After the introduction of plerixafor, 44/51 poor mobilizers (86%) could proceed to transplantation (
 <italic>p</italic> &lt; 0.01). This difference was even more marked in poor mobilizers with initial CD34+ count ≤ 10 cells/µl where 7/15 (47%) of patients in the pre-plerixafor era and 33/40 (83%) of patients in the plerixafor proceeded to transplantation respectively (
 <italic>p</italic> = 0.02). This may in part be explained by an increase in the proportion of patients reaching at least 2.0 × 10
 <sup>6</sup> cells/kg; however, such an increase was only observed in patients with CD34+ count ≤ 10 cells/µl, (67 vs 90% in the pre-plerixafor and plerixafor era, respectively) and not in patients with initial CD34+ cell count &gt; 10 cells/µl (100 vs 91% in the pre-plerixafor and plerixafor era, respectively). Failure to proceed to transplantation might therefore be linked to factors other than the mobilization regimen. Rates of successful engraftment and time to engraftment did not differ between the two time periods, in agreement with other reports which showed that plerixafor didn’t impact engraftment rates as long as the target CD34+ cell yield could be achieved [
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>, 
 <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]. However, the need for transfusions was higher in the plerixafor era as compared to the pre-plerixafor era. There is no clear explanation to this finding, but one hypothesis is that patients proceeding to transplantation were in a less favorable overall clinical status in the plerixafor era as compared to those in the pre-plerixafor era. In comparison, in France and Italy, the proportion of patients proceeding to transplantation remained constant with no large differences in transfusion requirements observed [SI, Fig. 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>, SI Tables 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3</xref> &amp; 
 <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">4</xref>].
</p>
