<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<fn-group>
 <fn fn-type="abbr">
  <p>Abbreviations: ALC = absolute lymphocyte count, ANC = absolute neutrophil count, APC = absolute platelet count, ctDNA = circulating tumor DNA, HER2 = Human Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor 2, NACT = neoadjuvant chemotherapy, NLR = neutrophil-to-lymphocyte ratio, pCR = pathologic complete response, PCR = polymerase chain reaction, PLR = platelet-to-lymphocyte ratio, RFS = recurrence-free survival, RT = radiation therapy, TILs = tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes, TNBC = triple negative breast cancer, WBC = white blood cells count.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>How to cite this article: Lusho S, Durando X, Bidet Y, Molnar I, Kossai M, Bernadach M, Lacrampe N, Veyssiere H, Cavaille M, Gay-Bellile M, Radosevic-Robin N, Abrial C. PERCEPTION Trial protocol: Comparison of predictive and prognostic capacities of neutrophil, lymphocyte and platelet counts and tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes in triple negative breast cancer. 
   <italic>Medicine</italic>. 2020;99:50(e23418).
  </p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="equal">
  <p>NRR and CA contributed equally to this work.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="financial-disclosure">
  <p>This research has not received any specific grant from any funding agency in the public, commercial, or not-for-profit sectors. The trial is managed by the Jean Perrin Centre, in Clermont-Ferrand, France.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>The PERCEPTION study will be carried out at the Jean Perrin Centre, in Clermont-Ferrand, FRANCE. The study protocol was approved by the Clermont-Ferrand Validation Committee and the Montpellier Committee for the Protection of Persons. Written, informed consent to participate will be obtained from all participants.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="COI-statement">
  <p>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</p>
 </fn>
 <fn fn-type="other">
  <p>Data sharing not applicable to this article as no datasets were generated or analyzed during the current study.</p>
 </fn>
</fn-group>
