<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="para360">This trial has a few limitations. In particular, the rarity of secondary CNS lymphoma makes it difficult to do randomised trials and only single-arm phase 2 trials seem to be feasible in this patient population. Importantly, the MARIETTA trial considered patients with CNS involvement at both initial diagnosis and relapse, including patients with high-grade transformed diffuse large B-cell lymphoma, and both with isolated CNS relapse and concomitant CNS–systemic disease, which might have generated an interpretation bias related to an apparent study population heterogeneity, reducing the strength of the reported associations. However, patient heterogeneity is a characteristic of this rare lymphoma, and the patients enrolled in this trial reflect the situation in routine practice, with the exception of patients older than 70 years who were excluded; thus, the use of the MARIETTA programme in older patients should be considered with caution. Moreover, studies clearly reporting the ratio between CNS involvement at presentation and at relapse in routine practice do not exist, which does not allow us to put the patient distribution in the present trial in context. However, the relatively large sample size of the MARIETTA trial allowed us to draw reliable conclusions on safety and activity in the whole study population and to distinguish different outcomes between patients with CNS disease at initial lymphoma diagnosis and patients who had CNS dissemination during or after upfront R-CHOP therapy, suggesting that these two secondary CNS lymphoma populations might benefit from different treatments. This finding is an important contribution considering that only one previous study focused on patients with CNS involvement at initial diagnosis of diffuse large B-cell lymphoma exists, which included only 16 patients with this condition.
 <xref rid="bib11" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>11</sup>
 </xref> An additional limitation was that no centralised review of imaging was done, and response and relapse assessment by local investigators of the 24 participating institutions was used as supportive evidence, which might have generated an interpretation bias. However, we can exclude a biased effect on the primary endpoint of the trial because progressive or relapsing disease is a clear condition to treating physicians, usually associated with relevant symptoms and general or neurological impairment. The MARIETTA programme was feasible, with 71% of MATRix–RICE courses delivered, and only four (5%) patients having permanent interruptions (
 <xref rid="sec1" ref-type="sec">appendix p 10</xref>) due to lethal sepsis. Although these rates seem to be a little better than that expected in routine practice, we cannot put these figures in context because retrospective studies on patients treated in everyday practice were not designed to answer this question. Finally, neurotoxicity was an uncommon event in patients treated with the MARIETTA programme; however, potential late cognitive decline cannot be excluded because assessment by neuropsychological tests was not included in the trial design.
</p>
