<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p id="para370">When putting the MARIETTA trial in context with previous trials, we note that the study population includes a relatively large proportion of patients with a poor prognosis (
 <xref rid="sec1" ref-type="sec">appendix p 12</xref>): 47% of patients had R-CHOP-refractory lymphoma, 80% of patients had concomitant systemic disease, and 56% had extra-CNS extranodal disease; all these are well known negative prognosticators, which makes it difficult to compare these results with previous trials (three multicentre, single-arm, phase 2 trials done in Germany,
 <xref rid="bib10" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>10</sup>
 </xref> Italy,
 <xref rid="bib11" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>11</sup>
 </xref> and the Netherlands
 <xref rid="bib12" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>12</sup>
 </xref>). The only study published at the time of design of the MARIETTA trial was used to estimate the present sample size.
 <xref rid="bib10" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>10</sup>
 </xref> In that trial, a methotrexate–ifosfamide combination followed by cytarabine–thiotepa combination and autologous HSCT had been adopted in 30 patients, reporting a complete response rate after induction of 23%, and a 1-year progression-free survival of 49% for the whole population and 58% for transplanted patients. Comparison between that study and the MARIETTA trial is limited by some relevant differences in selection criteria. In the previous trial,
 <xref rid="bib10" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>10</sup>
 </xref> the upper age limit was 65 years, with an upper limit of ECOG-PS of 2; patients with CNS involvement at initial lymphoma diagnosis were not considered, whereas patients with T-cell lymphomas were also enrolled. The SCNSL1 study
 <xref rid="bib11" ref-type="bibr">
  <sup>11</sup>
 </xref> used similar selection criteria to those used in the MARIETTA trial. The characteristics of the 38 patients enrolled in the SCNSL1 trial are similar to those recorded for the present study population (
 <xref rid="sec1" ref-type="sec">appendix p 12</xref>), with the exception of eligible histology (as a few patients with follicular lymphoma or mantle cell lymphoma were enrolled in the SCNSL1 trial) and, importantly, the proportion of patients with disease refractory to the previous line of treatment, which was almost three times greater in the MARIETTA trial.
</p>
