<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ack id="jns12267-sec-0009">
 <title>ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS</title>
 <p>We thank Sarah Greig, PhD, of Springer Healthcare Communications who prepared the outline and subsequent drafts of this manuscript. We also thank Doris Hinterberger and Elisabeth Clodi of Octapharma Pharmazeutika Produktionsges.m.b.H for their valuable input. Funding for this study, the medical writing assistance, and Open Access for this article was provided by Octapharma Pharmazeutika Produktionsges.m.b.H.</p>
 <sec id="jns12267-sec-0010" sec-type="COI-statement">
  <title>Conflict of interest</title>
  <p>H.‐P.H. has received honoraria for consulting, serving on steering committees and speaking from Baxter, Bayer Healthcare, CSL Behring, Kedrion, LFB, Octapharma, Syntimmune; H.D.K. has received honoraria for consulting, serving on steering committees and data safety monitoring boards, and has received research support from CSL Behring, Grifols Biotherapeutics, Sanofi Genzyme, Flexpharma and Octapharma; P.A.D. has received honoraria for consulting and serving on steering committees from Baxter, CSL Behring, Octapharma and Kedrion, and research support from Baxter, Grifols and Sanquin Blood supply; D.R.C. serves as consultant to Acetylon Pharmaceuticals Inc., Alcobra Pharma, Alnylam Pharmaceuticals, Annexon Biosciences, Akros Pharma, Biotest Pharmaceuticals Inc., Boehringer Ingelheim, Cigna Health Management Inc., CSL Behring, DP Clinical Inc., GlaxoSmithKline, Grifols SA, Karos Pharmaceuticals Inc., Neurocrine Biosciences, Novartis Corp., Octapharma AG, Pharnext SAS and Sun Pharmaceuticals, Syntimmune; is on a Data Safety Monitoring Board for Pfizer Inc., Ionis Pharmaceuticals, GlaxoSmithKline, Axovant Sciences Ltd.; has technology licencing agreements through Johns Hopkins University with Acetylon Pharmaceuticals Inc., AstraZeneca Pharmaceuticals, Calithera Biosciences, Genentech Inc., Neurocrine Biosciences, Merrimack Pharmaceuticals Inc., Seattle Genetics Inc., Shire Development LLC; and serves on the Board of Directors for the GBS‐CIDP Foundation International, Foundation for Peripheral Neuropathy, and The Peripheral Nerve Society; ISJ Merkies has received honoraria for serving on the steering committee for Talecris, Biotest, LFB Biopharmaceuticals, CSL Behring, Novartis and Grifols; and has received grants from the Talecris Talents Program, GBS CIDP Foundation International, Prinses Beatrix Spierfonds and the European Union Seventh Framework Programme.</p>
 </sec>
 <sec id="jns12267-sec-0011">
  <title>Author contributions</title>
  <p>The sponsor designed the clinical study in close cooperation with the steering committee (D.R.C., H.‐P.H., I.S.J.M., and P.A.D.) and the coordinating investigator (H.D.K.). This manuscript has been written in collaboration with the members of the steering committee and the coordinating investigator based on the study protocol (amended version 03; March 9, 2017). The authors obtained approval from the sponsor but made the final decision to submit the manuscript. All authors have reviewed the manuscript and approved the final version to be published.</p>
 </sec>
</ack>
