<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The increasing survival rates of women diagnosed with breast cancer requires an increased focus on measures to counteract persistent adverse effects of treatment. Neo-adjuvant treatment aims to decrease tumor burden before surgery and adjuvant treatment to inhibit proliferation in eventual remaining cancer cells after surgery. A common (neo-)adjuvant treatment for women with breast cancer is combined chemotherapy with anthracyclines and taxanes, given in 3 cycles of each chemotherapy type with a recovery period after each cycle.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]
 </sup> Anthracyclines have a cardiotoxic effect
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,
  <xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]
 </sup> and previous observational studies have shown approximately 10% decrease in maximal oxygen uptake (VO
 <sub>2max</sub>) during chemotherapy.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]
 </sup> VO
 <sub>2max</sub> is determined by both central- (e.g., cardiac function) and peripheral factors (e.g., skeletal muscle function) and reductions in VO
 <sub>2max</sub> are common in patients with breast cancer without any signs of impaired cardiac function.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]
 </sup> This suggests that there may be changes in peripheral factors affecting oxygen transport, however, this must be further elucidated. Direct negative effects of chemotherapy on skeletal muscles are documented in animal studies, where anthracyclines impair force-generating capacity and mitochondrial function in skeletal muscles.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>–
  <xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]
 </sup> These findings are supported by analysis on muscle biopsies from patients with prostate cancer,
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>]
 </sup> testicular cancer,
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]
 </sup> and in 2 small-scale studies on patients with breast cancer undergoing chemotherapy.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>,
  <xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]
 </sup> The effects of treatment with taxanes on skeletal muscle are less studied. However, muscle and joint pain, referred to as "taxane acute pain syndrome”
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]
 </sup> is commonly reported and occurs about 24 to 48 hours after treatment and lasts for about 5 to 7 days.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]
 </sup> Altogether, previous studies confirm the deleterious effects of chemotherapy on muscle size, mitochondrial structures, and muscle function. An alternative reason for these muscle changes could be reduced levels of physical activity, which is common in patients with cancer.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]
 </sup> Epidemiological studies have found that patients receiving chemotherapy decrease their level of physical activity during treatment, and this reduction may still be present after the end of the treatment period.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>,
  <xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]
 </sup> Regardless of cause, loss of skeletal muscle mass has been associated with reduced physical functioning and increased toxicity, that is poor tolerance to chemotherapy, and consequently worse prognosis.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,
  <xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]
 </sup>
</p>
