<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Over the past decades, physical activity has emerged as an important factor to improve cancer outcomes and international guidelines recommend patients to engage in regular physical activity.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]
 </sup> In women with breast cancer, physical exercise (i.e., planned, structured physical activity aiming to improve/sustain physical function and fitness
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]
 </sup>), has been shown to reduce the loss of muscle strength, which is commonly observed during and/or after treatment.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]
 </sup> Possible protective effects of physical exercise on skeletal muscle during chemotherapy for breast cancer have only been studied in 1 previous study. Mijwel and colleagues
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]
 </sup> showed that participating in a training program that combined high-intensity-intervals with either resistance training (RT-HIIT) or moderate-intensity aerobic exercise (AT-HIIT) during treatment prevented a decrease in muscle fiber size in both intervention groups in comparison to the control group (patients receiving usual care).
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>]
 </sup> In addition, participants in the RT-HIIT group showed a greater increase in muscle fiber size and satellite cell (SC) content in comparison to participants in the AT-HIIT. These results indicate that RT on its own could have a potentially protective effect on skeletal muscle function and size in breast cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy. Resistance training during chemotherapy may also improve treatment efficiency, quality of life and reduce cancer-related fatigue, and other side effects of treatment,
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,
  <xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]
 </sup> some of these improvements may be related to increased production of anti-tumor myokines in the exercising muscles.
 <sup>[
  <xref rid="R26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>]
 </sup> The effects of RT alone on muscle cellular outcomes during chemotherapy however, have not yet been investigated in women with breast cancer.
</p>
